import{_ as g,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as y,U as w,F as c,p,e as j,f,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},z={class:"poem-container"},A={class:"review"},T={class:"review-title"},N={class:"review-content"};function S(e,a,s,k,t,u){return i(),o("div",z,[n("div",A,[n("div",T,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",N,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const M=g(q,[["render",S],["__scopeId","data-v-abfecf09"]]),C=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"Kano jihar Fulani ce?","answer":"Tun bayan samun ‘yancin kai jihar Kano ta samu bunkasuwar tattalin arziki iri-iri, inda ta kafa kanta a matsayin cibiyar masana’antu, noma, da harkokin bankin Musulunci. Hausawa da Fulani su ne mafi yawan al’ummar Jihar Kano. Harshen Hausa shi ne yaren da ya mamaye jihar, kamar yadda yake a mafi yawan Arewacin Najeriya"},{"question":"Суроо: Булуттардын кандай түрлөрү бар жана алар кантип пайда болот?","answer":"Жооп: Булуттар сырткы көрүнүшүнө жана бийиктигине жараша цирус, кумулус, катмар сыяктуу түрдүү түрлөргө бөлүнөт. Алар жылуу, нымдуу аба көтөрүлүп, муздаганда жана суу тамчыларына конденсацияланганда пайда болот."},{"question":"Ọpẹlọpẹ awọn ṣọja, ọọdunrun ọmọleewe lawọn agbebọn tun fẹẹ ko lọ ni Kaduna","answer":"Ko jọ pe wahala awọn janduku agbebọn to n ji awọn ọmọleewe gbe lagbegbe Oke-Ọya yoo rọlẹ bọrọ tori kaka kewe agbọn dẹ, niṣe lo n le koko si i lọrọ naa da. Awọn agbebọn yii tun ti lọọ ji awọn ọọdunrun o le meje ọmọleewe (307) gbe laaarọ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, ọpẹlọpẹ awọn ṣọja ni o jẹ ki wọn ko wọn wọ’gbo, wọn ri awọn ọmọ naa gba pada.Ileewe ijọba Government Science Secondary School, to wa ni lagbegbe Ikara, nipinlẹ Kaduna, niṣẹlẹ naa ti waye, ibẹ lawọn agbebọn ya bo ni nnkan bii aago marun-un idaji ọjọ Aiku yii, wọn si ti ko awọn akẹkọọ ogo-wẹẹrẹ naa, ṣugbọn wọn lawọn kan lara awọn akẹkọọ naa ti dọgbọn tẹ aago idagiri tijọba ti ṣe sileewe wọn, gbara ti wọn ti ri ohun to n ṣẹlẹ. Aago yii tawọn agbofinro gbọ ni wọn lo jẹ kawọn ọlọpaa atawọn ṣọja sare dihamọra lọ sibi iṣẹlẹ naa, ti wọn si ṣe kongẹ bi awọn ọdaju ẹda yii ṣe fẹẹ ko awọn ọmọ naa lọ, ni wọn ba fija pẹẹta pẹlu wọn.Kọmiṣanna fun eto aabo abẹle ati ọrọ ile nipinlẹ Kaduna, Ọgbẹni Samuel Aruwan, lo sọrọ yii di mimọ lọjọ Aiku, o ni: “A dupẹ pe wọn ṣaṣeyọri o, ọpẹlọpẹ awọn ṣọja ileeṣẹ ologun ilẹ wa ti wọn tete gbe igbesẹ akin gbara ti olobo ti ta wọn lori iṣẹlẹ naa. Aijẹ bẹẹ, ọọdunrun o le meje (307) lawọn ọmọ wa tawọn agbebọn naa ti ji gbe, wọn tun fẹẹ ko wọn wọgbo lọ.“Awọn agbebọn naa ti sa lọ, nigba ti wọn ri awọn agbofinro. Ṣugbọn awọn ọlọpaa atawọn ṣọja ṣi n tọpasẹ wọn lọ lati mu wọn,” gẹgẹ bi Samuel ṣe sọ.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, awọn akẹkọọ bii mẹtadinlogoji ti wọn lawọn agbebọn naa ji gbe wọ’gbo lọ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to kọja yii, ṣi wa lakata wọn, wọn o ti i tu wọn silẹ. Ileewe Federal College of Forestry Mechanisation ni wọn ti ji wọn ko.Iya gidi ni wọn si fi n jẹ awọn akẹkọọ yii ninu igbo ti wọn gbe wọn lọ ninu fidio kan to jade nipa wọn. Bẹẹ lawọn ọmọ yii n bẹbẹ pe ki ijọba jọwọ, waa tu awọn silẹ ni igbekun awọn ajinigbe yii. Bọlọ ni awọn to jẹ obinrin ninu awọn akẹkọọ yii n sunkun, aṣọ nikan ni wọn si ro mọya ninu fidio to ṣafihan wọn naa, ọpọ ninu wọn ko wẹwu rara.Wọn lawọn agbebọn naa ni miliọnu lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹta (500m) lawọn maa gba ki wọn too da awọn akẹkọọ naa nide lakata wọn."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--पडलेले शेण माती घेऊन उठते","answer":"एखाद्या चांगल्या माणसावर काहीतरी ठपका आला आणि त्याने किती जरी निवारण केले तरी त्याच्या चारित्र्यावर थोडा का होईना डाग हा पडतोच"},{"question":"ਦਿਲੀ ਦਾ ਬੀਨਾ ਅਤੇ ਨਰਾਇਣ ਦਾ ਕੇਸ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਤੇ ਹੋਈ ਸਿਆਸਤ ।","answer":"ਮੰਡਾਵਾਲੀ ਥਾਣੇ ਦੇ ਐਸਐਚਓ ਸੁਭਾਸ਼ ਚੰਦਰ ਮੀਣਾ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕੋਲ ਕਰੀਬ ਡੇਢ ਵਜੇ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਤੋਂ ਫੋਨ ਆਇਆ ਕਿ ਤਿੰਨ ਬੱਚੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ।ਬੱਚੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਕੁਝ ਬੋਲਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ  ਕਿ ਨਾਰਾਇਣ ਦੇ ਉਸ ਛੋਟੇ ਜਿਹੇ ਕਮਰੇ ਦੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਕਈ ਲੋਕ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਸਨ। ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾਤਰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਬੀਨਾ 'ਪਾਗਲ' ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਕੁਝ ਬੋਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ।ਕਈ ਵਾਰ ਪੁੱਛਣ 'ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਐਨਾ ਕਿਹਾ ''ਅੱਜ ਸਵੇਰ ਤੋਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਚਾਹ ਪੀਤੀ ਹੈ\\"ਇਸ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਕੋਈ ਬੋਲਿਆ ''ਅਰੇ, ਜਿਹੜੀ ਔਰਤ ਆਪਣੀ ਬੱਚੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਬਾਰੇ ਸੁਣ ਕੇ ਵੀ ਚੁੱਪ ਰਹੀ ਉਹ ਕੀ ਬੋਲੇਗੀ।''ਸਾਨੂੰ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਉੱਥੇ ਖੜ੍ਹਾ ਹਰ ਸ਼ਖ਼ਸ ਉਸ  'ਪਾਗਲ' ਔਰਤ ਬਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਸੋਚ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ  ਅਤੇ ਨਾਰਾਇਣ ਕਮਰੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੰਦ ਸੀ, ਮੀਡੀਆ ਨੂੰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਣ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ।ਬਿਲਡਿੰਗ ਦੇ ਮਕਾਨ ਮਾਲਿਕ ਦੇ ਮੁੰਡੇ ਪ੍ਰਦੀਪ ਦੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਾਨੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, \\"ਇੱਥੇ ਜਿਹੜੇ ਲੋਕ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਤਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ। ਕੋਈ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਠੇਲਾ  ਚਲਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਕੁਝ ਹੋਰ...''\\"ਕੋਈ ਦੋ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਲਈ ਰਹਿਣ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਚਾਰ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਲਈ। ਕਈ ਵਾਰ ਤਾਂ ਕੁਝ ਲੋਕ ਇੱਕ ਜਾਂ ਦੋ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਲਈ ਹੀ ਰਹਿਣ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ। ਇੱਥੋਂ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਾਇਆ ਵੀ 1000-1500 ਹੈ। ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਐਨੇ ਘੱਟ ਕਿਰਾਏ ਲਈ ਰੈਂਟ ਐਗਰੀਮੈਂਟ ਤਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਵਾ ਸਕਦਾ...ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਆਈਡੀ ਵੀ ਦੇਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਡਰ ਹੈ।\\"ਚਿੜੀਆ ਘਰ ਵਰਗੀ ਹਾਲਤ ਸੀ...ਜਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਸੀ ਨਵੇਂ ਜਾਨਵਰ ਨੂੰ ਚਿੜੀਆ ਘਰ ਲਿਆਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਲੋਕ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਵਾਰ-ਵਾਰ ਦੇਖਣ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਕੁਝ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਹੀ ਨਜ਼ਾਰਾ ਇਮਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਕਮਰੇ ਦਾ ਸੀ।ਬੀਨਾ ਅਤੇ ਨਾਰਾਇਣ ਕਮਰੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੰਦ ਸਨ। ਮੀਡੀਆ ਨੂੰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਣ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ। ਪਰ ਵੱਡੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਹੀ ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ਾ ਖੋਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ਾ ਖੁੱਲਦਾ, ਨੇਤਾ ਅੰਦਰ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਅਤੇ ਮੁੜ ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ਾ ਬੰਦ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ। ਉਹ ਬਾਹਰ ਆਉਂਦੇ, ਬਾਈਟ ਦਿੰਦੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੇਰ ਲਈ ਸਭ ਸ਼ਾਂਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ।ਦਿੱਲੀ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮਨੋਜ ਤਿਵਾਰੀ ਨੇ ਬੀਨਾ ਅਤੇ ਨਾਰਾਇਣ ਨਾਲ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਮਾਮਲੇ 'ਤੇ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸਿਸਟਮ ਦੀ ਅਣਦੇਖੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਹੈ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ 'ਤੇ ਰਾਸ਼ਨ ਕਾਰਡ ਵੰਡਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਢਿੱਲ ਵਰਤਣ ਦਾ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮ ਲਗਾਇਆ ਅਤੇ ਕਿਹਾ,''ਮੈਂ ਅਰਵਿੰਦ ਕੇਜਰੀਵਾਲ ਨੂੰ ਕਹਾਂਗਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਖ਼ੁਦ ਆ ਕੇ ਹਾਲਾਤ ਦੇਖਣ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੁਣ ਤੱਕ ਆ ਜਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਸੀ।\\"ਉੱਥੇ ਹੀ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਉਪ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮਨੀਸ਼ ਸਿਸੋਦੀਆ ਨੇ ਨਾਰਾਇਣ ਅਤੇ ਬੀਨਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੁਆਵਜ਼ੇ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਆਖੀ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਦੇ ਵੀ ਹੁਕਮ ਦਿੱਤੇ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਲਾਪਰਵਾਹੀ ਦਾ ਮਾਮਲਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਸਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਕਮੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।''ਮਨੀਸ਼ ਸਿਸੋਦੀਆ ਨੇ ਬੀਨਾ ਦਾ ਬਿਹਤਰ ਇਲਾਜ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਭਰੋਸਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।(ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ।)"},{"question":"Miten pitkälle sääolosuhteita voidaan ennustaa Suomessa?","answer":"Tarkasti tiettyyn ajankohtaan ja paikkaan liittyvää säätietoa esimerkiksi lämpötilasta, tuulisuudesta, pilvisyydestä ja sateisuudesta voidaan ennustaa parhaimmillaan noin 10 vuorokaudeksi eteenpäin.Tätä pidemmälle voidaan ennustaa keskimääräisiä sääolosuhteita, muttei enää päivittäisen sään yksityiskohtia. Esimerkiksi Euroopan keskipitkien ennusteiden keskus ECMWF julkaisee kuukausiennusteita eli viikoittaisia keskimääräisiä sääennusteita neljän viikon jaksoille.Kausitasolla eli noin kolmen kuukauden ajanjaksolle ennustetaan yleensä kuukauden tai kolmen kuukauden keskiarvoa."},{"question":"Rispondi alla seguente domanda: Chi ha dipinto La Gioconda?","answer":"La risposte è Leonardo da Vinci, all'inizio del XVI secolo (1503-1506). Gli fu commissionata da un mercante, Francesco del Giocondo, per avere un ritratto di sua moglie Lisa Gherardini."},{"question":"Que sont les « Trois Glorieuses »","answer":"Le 27 juillet 3 plusieurs périodiques sont publiés sans autorisation et publient un texte de protestation, ayant pour conséquences : des ouvriers de la presse dans la rue, mandats d'arrêt contre des journalistes, presses détruites par les autorités. Il y a ainsi un extension du mouvement, particulièrement auprès des étudiants.Le 28 juillet, Paris sombre dans le chaos : les insurgés s'emparent de l'hôtel de ville et y font flotter le drapeau tricolore4. Cependant, Charles X refuse de retirer ses ordonnances.Le 29 juillet, les révolutionnaires l'emportent ; le même jour en soirée le roi retire ses ordonnances, mais trop tard : le 2 août, il devra abdiquer et partira en Exil."},{"question":"कॅनडाच्या पायाखालची जमीन सरकली! आता भारताने दिली ही डेडलाईन","answer":"नवी दिल्ली | 3 ऑक्टोबर 2023 : भारत आणि कॅनडातील संबंध (India-Canada Tension) आता निर्णायकी वळणावर पोहचले आहेत. कॅनडाने विचार केला नाही, असा खणखणीत इशारा भारताने दिला आहे. भारताच्या एका निर्णयाने कॅनडाच्या पायाखालची जमीन सरकली आहे. पंतप्रधान जस्टीन ट्रूडो यांच्या तोंडचे पाणी पळाले आहे. ट्रूडो यांचा बोलघेवडेपणा आता संपुष्टात येणार आहे. भारताला गृहीत धरु नका, हे भारताने एका निर्णयानेच जगाला दाखवून दिले आहे. खलिस्तान दहशतवाद्यांचा ( Khalistan Terrorist) उमाळा कॅनडाला महागात पडणार आहे. केंद्र सरकारने कॅनडाला चांगलाच इंगा दाखविण्याचे मनावर घेतल्याचे दिसून येत आहे. काय दिली डेडलाईन, काय दिला कॅनडाला इशारा?कॅनडाचा तिळपापडराष्ट्रविरोधी कारवाया करणाऱ्या दहशतवादी हरदीप सिंग निज्जर याची हत्या भारत सरकारच्या इशाऱ्यावरुन केल्याचे सबळ कारणं समोर आल्याचा आरोप कॅनडाने केला होता. पंतप्रधान जस्टीन ट्रूडो यांनी संसदेत हा आरोप केला होता. या बोलघेवड्या वक्तव्याचा भारताने चांगलाच समाचार घेतला. भारताने झटपट निर्णय घेत कॅनडाची अनेक आघाड्यावर कोंडी केली. त्यानंतर ट्रूडो यांचे स्वर नरमले. पण अजूनही भारताने माघार घेतली नाही. नवीन निर्णयामुळे कॅनडाचा तिळपापड उडाला आहे."},{"question":"தமிழில் கலைக்களஞ்சியம் அடிப்படையில் அமைந்த நூல்? ","answer":"விடை:  அபிதானகோசம் என்பது தமிழிலே முதன் முதலாகத் தோன்றிய இலக்கியக் கலைக்களஞ்சியமாகும். வடமொழி, தென்மொழி ஆகிய இரு மொழிகளிலும் இயற்றப்பெற்ற வேதங்கள், புராணங்கள், இதிகாசங்கள், தருமநூல்கள், இலக்கியங்களிற் காணப்பெற்ற தெய்வம், தேவர், இருடி, முனிவர், அசுரர், அரசர், புலவர், புரவலர் முதலிய விபரங்களை அகர வரிசையிலே தொகுத்தளிக்கும் முயற்சி அபிதானகோசம் ஆகும்."},{"question":"आशियातील पहिले अखंड गॅल्वनाइज्ड रबर उत्पादन सुविधा कोठे आहे?उत्तर :","answer":"आशियातील पहिले अखंड गॅल्वनाइज्ड रबर उत्पादन सुविधा गोविंदगड, भुतान आहे."},{"question":"(Ebukisisa leli pheshana aliphethe.) Yini yona lena? Hawu webantungibonani ngamehlo ami? Yincwadi yomshado lena baba.(Emangele.) Ngakuzwa ubabaza? Ngikubizele ukuthi uzofunda lencwadi hhayi lokhu osukukhuluma wena.Hhawu! Kodwa ngasho baba ukuthi lo nkosikazi wakwaMaKhungauchakijane. Kukhulu asigodlele khona. (Enikina ikhanda eyohlalaeduze komyeni wakhe.) Baba yincwadi yomshado lena. Ngempelaunelungelo lo mfana ukuzofuna umkakhe ngoba nabu ubufakaziobuqanda ikhanda.MaMhlongo noma ngingayile esikolweni futhi ngiphuma ezindaweniezisemakhaya kodwa ukhumbule ukuthi kuseGoli lapha, bakhonaochakijana abalala bengalele befuna indlela yokuziphilisa ngegazilabanye abantu. Wazi ngani ukuthi lo mfana ulithengile leli phephalomshado? Wazi ngani ukuthi kukhona imfihlo ayaziyongenkosikazi kaThamsanqa afuna ukusebenzisa ithuba elinjengaleli ukuthola imali? Ungakhohlwa ukuthi umakoti usebenzaebhange esidlekeni semali efunwa ngumuntu wonke, ubhedulubangwayo phela. (Alithathe alibukisise naye ingathi kukhonaamehlo akucoshayo kanti lutho ubona izimvemvane nje.)1. Chaza inhloso yokuba khona komlingiswa ongumuntu wokuqala kulo mdlalongenkathi kugqekezwa ebhange. ","answer":"Umbhali uhlose ukusixwayisa/ukusibonisa ukuthi uma kwenzeka isigamekoesithile kubakhona laba bantu abasibonayo isigameko kodwa bangaziwamuntu bese begcina bebe ngofakazi/uhlose ukuthi kube khona omunyeumuntu ozobikela amaphoyisa ngobugebengu obenzakalayo njengoba lomuntu ongaziwa wathi uma ebona ubugebengu kwaba nguye oshayelaamaphoyisa okwaholela ekuboshweni kukaNkululeko, abangani bakhe kanyenoPhindisiwe."},{"question":"පාෂාණ නැගීමේ විවිධ වර්ග මොනවාද?","answer":"වඩාත් ජනප්‍රිය කඳු නැගීමේ වර්ග නම්: - බෝල්ඩරිං: අඩු එල්ලෙන අභියෝග තරණය කිරීම, කඩා වැටීම් පෑඩ් සමඟ වැටීමට ඉඩ ඇත. - ක්‍රීඩා කඳු නැගීම (හෝ ගෘහස්ථ කඳු නැගීම): ස්ථාවර නැංගුරම් සහිත මාර්ගයක නැගීම - සම්ප්‍රදායික කඳු නැගීම: ස්ථාවර නැංගුරම් නොමැතිව ඇතුළු කර ඉවත් කරන ලද ආම්පන්න සමඟ නැගීම කඳු නගින්නන් අත්දැකීම් ලබා ගත් පසු, කඳු නගින්නන් බොහෝ දෙනෙකුට ඇලී සිටිය හැකි වුවද, ඔවුන්ට වඩාත් ආන්තික එළිමහන් භූමි තරණය කිරීමට හැකි වේ. ගල් ගැසීම හෝ ක්රීඩා කඳු නැගීම සඳහා."},{"question":"यशाची गुरूकिल्ली मिळवण्यासाठी करा या 10 गोष्टी","answer":"जेव्हा यशाचा विषय असतो तेव्हा प्रत्येकाला वाटतं की, मला भरपूर यश मिळावं. माझ्याकडे भरपूर पैसे असावेत, मला प्रसिद्धी मिळावी इ. पण ते स्वतःच्या वागण्यात आणि सवयींमध्ये योग्य ते बदल करण्यास तयार नसतात. याच कारणामुळे ते यशापासून नेहमी दूर राहतात. या लेखात आम्ही तुमच्यासाठी आयुष्याशी निगडीत 10 गोष्टी सांगणार आहोत. जे तुम्ही फॉलो केल्यास तुम्हाला यशाची गुरूकिल्ली नक्कीच गवसेल. कारण यश हे तुम्ही काय करता त्यावर अवलंबून असतं. जे तुम्ही करता त्याप्रमाणेच तुम्ही घडत असता. त्यामुळे तुमच्या सवयी बदलणं गरजेच आहे. फक्त गौतम बुद्ध यांची माहिती असून उपयोग नाही. त्यांच्यासारख्या अनेक महान व्यक्तींनी सांगितलेल्या गोष्टी दैनंदिन जीवनात आचरणात आणल्या पाहिजेत.1) यश आणि शिस्त (Success and Discipline)मित्रांनो कोणत्याही कामात शिस्त एक अशी गोष्ट आहे, जी तुम्हाला कोणत्याही परिस्थितीत यशस्वी बनवू शकते. मग तुमच्यामध्ये टॅलेंट असो वा नसो. यशासाठी शिस्त असणं गरजेच आहे. जेव्हा तुम्ही एखादं काम शिस्तपूर्णरितीने करता तेव्हा तुम्हाला मिळणारं यश हे अवर्णनीय असतं.शिस्त आपल्याला जीवनात पुढे जाण्याचा योग्य मार्ग दाखवते. जर एखादी व्यक्ती आपल्या कार्यात शिस्तप्रिय नसेल तर ती व्यक्ती कितीही प्रतिभाशाली किंवा मेहनती असली तरी तिला यश मिळू शकत नाही. शिस्तही तुम्हाला नेहमी जगापासून वेगळं बनवत असते. त्यामुळे प्रत्येक काम हे शिस्तपूर्ण पद्धतीने करावं. जोपर्यंत तुमच्यामध्ये शिस्त आहे तोपर्यंत तुमच्याजवळ यश असेल. जर तुम्ही शिस्तपूर्ण मार्ग सोडलात तर तुम्हाला यश गवसणार नाही.2) यश आणि आत्मशिक्षण (Success and Self Education)आपल्या पृथ्वीतलावर अनेक महान लोकं होऊन गेले आणि जितके महान पुरूष होऊन गेले तितक्यांनी आत्मशिक्षणाच्या साहाय्याने आपल्या जीवनात यश प्राप्त केलं. जसं गौतम बुद्ध यांची शिकवण. Self Education किंवा आत्मशिक्षणाने फक्त तुम्हाला शिकायला मिळतं असं नाही. तर तुमचा आत्मविश्वासही वाढतो आणि विचार करण्याची क्षमताही वाढते. ज्यामुळे तुम्हाला यश मिळण्याची शक्यता वाढते. आत्मशिक्षणाने तुम्ही तुमच्या अनेक प्रश्नांची उत्तर स्वतःच मिळवू शकता. कारण या परिस्थितीत तुमचा मेंदू वेगाने काम करतो. त्यामुळे यशासाठी नेहमी आत्मशिक्षणावर लक्ष केंद्रित करावे. जे तुम्हाला यश देईल आणि तुमच्या क्षेत्रात महान बनवेल.3) यश आणि ध्येय (Success and Goal)एखाद्यापुढे जर ध्येय नसेल तर जगात त्याची काहीच भूमिका नाही. तुम्ही ध्येयाशिवाय पुढे जाऊ शकत नाही. यशासाठी ध्येय किंवा लक्ष्य असणं फार महत्त्वाचं आहे. कारण तुमचं ध्येय ठरवतं असतं की, तुम्हाला तुमच्या आयुष्यात योग्य दिशा मिळेल. ज्यामुळे तुमची प्रगती वेगाने होते. जर एखाद्या कडे ध्येयच नसेल तर तो पुढे जाऊ शकत नाही. कारण त्याला कुठे जायचंय हे माहीतच नाही. आयुष्यात ध्येय असल्यास तुम्हाला आनंद मिळतो आणि तुम्ही ते साध्य करण्यासाठी उत्सुक असता. कारण तुमच्यापुढील मार्ग तुमच्यासमोर असतो. त्यामुळे तो तुम्ही भरकटू शकत नाही.जेव्हा तुम्ही ध्येय ठरवता तेव्हा तुम्ही तुमच्या वेळेचा योग्य उपयोग करता. ज्यामुळे तुम्हाला जास्त यश मिळतं. त्यामुळे जीवनात ध्येय असणं खूप आवश्यक आहे.4) यश आणि धाडस (Success and Risk)यशासाठी धाडसी निर्णय घेण्याची तयारी असणंही आवश्यक आहे. जर तुम्ही धाडसी निर्णय घेऊ शकला नाहीत तर तुम्ही आयुष्यात काहीच नवीन करू शकणार नाही. ज्यामुळे तुम्हाला एक साधारण व्यक्ती म्हणून आयुष्य कंठावं लागेल. कारण इतिहास त्याच व्यक्ती घडवतात ज्या काहीतरी नवीन करतात आणि नवीन गोष्ट तेव्हाच घडते जेव्हा धाडसी निर्णय घेतले जातात. नाहीतर एकमेंकाची नक्कल तर जगभरात केलीच जाते. त्यामुळे रिस्क म्हणजे धाडस करायला घाबरू नका. कारण रिस्क सगळीकडेच आहे. जर तुम्ही रिस्क घ्यायला घाबराल तर तुम्ही काहीच करू शकणार नाही.धाडसी निर्णयांनी तुम्ही एक हटके व्यक्तीमत्त्व बनता. ज्यामुळे तुम्हाला खूप यश मिळतं. जे साधारण व्यक्तीपेक्षा जास्त असतं. तुम्ही स्वतः तुमची सीमा तोडू शकता. धाडस करणं हे योग्य आहेच. पण एका गोष्टीची काळजी घ्या की, चुकीच्या गोष्टीसाठी कधीही धाडस करू नका. कारण चुकीचं काम कधीच करू नये.5) यश आणि आयुष्य नियोजन (Success and Time Management)तुम्ही स्वतःचं आयुष्य स्वतः डिजाईन करा आणि प्लॅन करा. नाहीतर कोणीतरी दुसरा ते तुमच्यासाठी करेल. आपलं आयुष्य हे आपल्या मनाप्रमाणे जगावं. जे तुम्हाला आवडतं, जे तुम्हाला व्हायचं आहे तेच करा. कारण मदारीच्या सांगण्यावर तर माकडही नाचतं. त्यामुळे स्वतःच्या आयुष्याचं नियोजच स्वतः करा. ज्यामुळे पुढे जाऊन तुम्हाला त्याचा त्रास होणार नाही.6) यश आणि वेळ (Success and Time)पैशापेक्षा जास्त मूल्य आहे ते वेळेचं. ज्या दिवशी तुम्हाला वेळेची किंमत कळेल. तेव्हा समजून जा तुम्ही यशाच्या मार्गावर आहेत. आपण एकवेळ हरवलेलं धन पुन्हा मिळवू शकतो पण गेलेली वेळ पुन्हा कोणत्याही परिस्थितीत पुन्हा येत नाही. त्यामुळे वेळेचा योग्य वापर करता आला पाहिजे. आयुष्यात यशस्वी होण्यासाठी वेळेचं नियोजन फार आवश्यक आहे. ज्यामुळे तुम्ही प्रत्येक कार्य वेळेवर करू शकाल. यशासाठी तुम्हाला वेळेचं मूल्य समजलं पाहिजे. ज्या दिवशी तुम्ही ते समजाल तेव्हा तुम्ही वेळ वाया घालवणं बंद कराल. वेळेची किंमत कळल्यावर तुम्ही कमी वेळात जास्त काम करू शकाल आणि स्वतःचा वेळ चांगल्या कामात घालवाल. परिणामी यश हे मिळेलच.7) यश आणि शरीराची काळजी (Success and Self Care)जोपर्यंत तुम्ही निरोगी आणि फिट आहात तोपर्यंत कोणत्याही क्षेत्रात तुम्ही यश मिळवू शकता. त्यामुळे आपल्या आरोग्याची विशेष काळजी घ्यायला हवी. आपल्या आरोग्य आणि शरीरासाठी तुम्ही काही गोष्टी करू शकता. जसं रोज कमीतकमी अर्धा तास व्यायाम करणे, चांगला आणि पौष्टिक आहार घेणे, वेळेवर नाश्ता आणि जेवण करणे, वाईट सवयी जसं धूम्रपान, तंबाखू सेवन आणि दारूपासून दूर राहावे आणि आपल्या डोक्यातील नकारात्मक विचारांना दूर करावे.मोठ्या यशासाठी आणि यशाचा आनंद घेण्यासाठी तुम्ही निरोगी राहणं आवश्यक आहे. नाहीतर तुमचं यश काहीच कामाचं नाही.8) यश आणि नशीब (Success and Destiny)कधी कधी तुमचं नशीब तुम्हाला साथ देऊ शकतं पण फक्त नशीबामुळे तुमचं आयुष्य चांगल होईल असं नाही. कारण यशासाठी मेहनत करणं गरजेचं आहे. मेहनतीशिवाय आयुष्यात काहीच मिळू शकत नाही आणि कठोर मेहनत करण्याऱ्या व्यक्तीला यश मिळवण्यापासून कोणीच थांबवू शकत नाही. कठोर मेहनतीला कोणताही पर्याय नाही. त्यामुळे यश मिळणं निश्चित आहे. नशीबाच्या भरोश्यावर बसू राहिलात तर तुम्ही प्रयत्न करणं सोडून द्याल. त्यामुळे नशीबाच्या भरोश्यावर बसू नका. हे मूर्खपणाचं ठरेल.9) यश आणि वाचन (Success and Reading)यशासाठी तुमच्या ज्ञानात भर पडणे आणि माहितीचीही गरज असते. जे तुम्हाला चांगल्या पुस्तकांच्या वाचनातून मिळेल. पुस्तकं वाचल्याने फक्त ज्ञानातच भर पडते असं नाहीतर विचार करण्याची क्षमताही वाढते आणि तुमच्यातील क्रिएव्हीटीही वाढते. पुस्तक वाचल्याने स्मरणशक्ती वाढते आणि तुम्ही प्रत्येक क्षेत्रात चांगल करू शकता. त्यामुळे चांगली आणि प्रेरणादायी पुस्तक वाचा.10) यश आणि जीवनाचे धडे (Success and Life Lessons)जीवनाचे धडे म्हणजेच वरील लेखात मांडलेले यशाला गवसणी घालण्यासाठी उपयुक्त 9 गोष्टी होय. ज्या तुमच्या आयुष्यात नक्की अंगीकारा. कारण फक्त या गोष्टी वाचल्याने काही होणार नाही. त्यांना रोजच्या जीवनात आचरणात आणण्याची गरज आहे. त्यामुळे प्रत्येकाने ही बाब नक्कीच जाणून घेतली पाहिजे की, जे तुम्ही शिकता आणि वाचता ते आयुष्यात आचरणातही आणा."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය රචනා  කළේ  කවුද?ඔබ හීනයක් වගේහාදු වැස්සක් අරන්සිරියහන අද්දරට වීවැතිරෙන්නෙපා සයනේමම සස්වාමිකයි ස්වාමි..මල් මකරන්ද දෝතට අරන්නෙතේ කදුලැලි දරන්මම මඟ බලා සිටියා...නෙතු ඝණදුරට තරුවක් වෙලාඔබ ‍එතැයි සිතා...සිල් බිදලන්න නොහැකි නිසාමම මග බලා සිටියා...මේඝ දුක් හද රැදුනාසඳ එළිය නිවුනාඅඳුර මැද තනිවීපහන් දොරකට සවන් දොර හැරුනාතරු ඇසත් පිපුණා...සඳ ලබන්නී මා...සරා සඳ ලඟ මා...","answer":"උපුල් ශාන්ත සන්නස්ගල"},{"question":"Khadro Cumar Dhuule: Heestii Dood","answer":"Dood kulma wadi karoDaacad baan ahaayooDaarteydaan dhax joogeeDulmi baad igu hayseeDambi baad iga qaadeeDood kulma wadi karoDaacad baan ahaayooDaarteydaan dhax joogeeDulmi baad igu hayseeDambi baad iga qaadeeDookheyga doqonkeeKaa doortay dunideeAdba ima daryeeshideeMaxaan kugu daalaaDookheyga doqonkeeKaa doortay dunideeAdba ima daryeeshideeMaxaan kugu daalaaDaawo kaama dooneeDuurkaad igu daysayeeDugaagaan la daris ahayeLa daris ahyeeDaawo kaama dooneeDuurkaad igu daysayeeDugaagaan la daris ahayeLa daris ahayeeDood kulama wadi karoDood dood kulama wadi karoDartaadaan u oomooDadkaygii u diideeeDunnidii ku seegeeDanba iima haysideeDartaadaan u oomooDadkaygii u diideeeDunnidii ku seegeeDanba iima haysideeDab aan ani ku joogaaWaligii dam’ee nooLaygu daaray kaligeyDagaal igu hayeeDab aan ani ku joogaaWaligii dam’ee nooLaygu daaray kaligeyDagaal igu hayeeDaawo kaama dooneeDuurkaad igu daysayeeDugaagaan la daris ahayeLa daris ahayeDaawo kaama dooneeDuurkaad igu daysayeeDugaagaan la daris ahayeLa daris ahayeeDugaagaan la daris ahayeLa daris ahayeeDugaagaan la daris ahayeLa daris ahayeeDugaagaan la daris ahayeLa daris ahayeeDugaagaan la daris ahayeLa daris ahayee"},{"question":"generate a poem \\"Ukutshona kukamendi by Sek Mqhayi\\" in Xhosa","answer":"sure here is the poem:Ukutshona kukaMendi by SEK Mqhayi:Ewe le nto kakade yinto yaloo ntoThina nto zaziyo asothukanga ntoSibona kamhlophe sithi mekumelweSitheth’ engqindweni sithi kufanelweXa bekunge njalo bekungayi kulungaNgoko ke Sotashe kwaqala ukulunga.Le nqanaw’ uMendi namhla yandisileNal’ igazi lethu lisikhonzisileAsinithumanga ngazo izicengoAsinithenganga ngayo imibengoBeku ngenga nzuzo zimakhwezikhweziBeku ngenga ndyebo zingange nkwekhweziSikwatsho nakuni bafel’ iAfrikaKwelase Jamani yase MpumalangaNelase Jamani yase NtsonalangaBekungenga mbeko eninayo kuKumkaniBekungenga ntobeko yenu kwiBritaneMhla nashiy’ ikhaya sithethile naniMhla nashiy’ iintsapho salathile kuniMhla sabamb’ izandla, mhla kwamanz’ amehloMhla balil’ oonyoko, bangqukrulek’ ooyihloMhla nazishiy’ intaba zezwe lenuMhla nayiy’ nikel’ imiv’ imilambo yezwe lenuasitshongo na kuni midak’ owethuUkuthi “kwelo zwe nilidini lethu”?Ngesi binge ngantoni ke kade?Idini lomzi liyintoni ke kade?Asi ngomathol’ amaduna omzi na?Asi zizithandwa zesizwe kade na?Ngoku kuthetha siyendeliselaSibhekis’ ezantsi, sihlahl’ indlelaAsi ngohabheli na idini lomhlaba?Asi ngoMesiya na elasezulwini?Thuthuzelekani ngoko zinkedama!Thuthuzelekani ngoko bafazana!Kuf’ omnye kade mini kwakhiw’ omnyeKukhonz’ omnye kade kuphil’ abanyeNgala mazwi sithi thuthuzelekaniNgokwenjenje kwethu sithi yakhekaniLithatheni eli qhalo labadalaKuba bathi “akuhlanga lungehlanga!”Awu! Zaf’ int’ ezinkulu zeAfrika!Isindiwe le nqanawe ‘de yazikaKwaf’ amakhalipha, amafa naNkosiAgazi lethetha kwiNkosi yeenkosiUkufa kwawo kunomvuzo nomvukaNdinga ndingema nawo ngemhla wovukoNdigqhame njengomny’ osebenzileyoNdikhanye njengomso oqaqambileyoMakube njalo!"},{"question":"ఆచార్య నాగార్జునుని గురించి మీకు తెలిసిన విషయాలను రాయండి.","answer":"నాగార్జునుడు బౌద్ధ మతాచార్యుడు. శాతవాహన రాజైన యజ్ఞశ్రీ శాతకర్ణికి మంచి మిత్రుడు. సుహృల్లేఖ, రత్నావళి అనే గ్రంథాలు వారి స్నేహబంధానికి గుర్తులు. ఆ గ్రంథాలలో ప్రకటించిన. భావాలు వారి ఆత్మీయతను తెలియజేస్తాయి. నాగార్జునుడు ధరణికోటలోనూ, నందికొండ ప్రాంతంలో గల బౌద్దారామాల్లో నివసించేవాడు. ఆయన విజయపురిలో శ్రీ పర్వత విద్యాపీఠం స్థాపించాడు. అక్కడ దేశ విదేశాల విద్యార్థులు విద్యార్జన చేసేవారు. ఆ విశ్వవిద్యాలయంలో 7700 మంది బౌద్ధ భిక్షువులుండేవారట. అక్కడ ఆచార్య బుద్ధ ఘోషుడు, ఆర్యదేవుడు, ధర్మకీర్తి మొదలైన తత్వవేత్తలు ధర్మశాస్త్రం, రాజనీతి, సాహిత్యం మొదలైనవి బోధించేవారు."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 川崎レナさんが「国際子ども平和賞」を日本人で初めてもらいました。川崎さんは大阪に住む17歳です。世界で活動をする団体が、子どもの権利のためにすばらしい活動をした人に、毎年この賞を贈っています。地球温暖化を止めるために活動をしているグレタ・トゥーンベリさんももらったことがあります。川崎さんは8歳のときに読んだ本で、世界には政治の理由で教育を受けることができない子どもがたくさんいることを知りました。そして14歳のときにNGOをつくって、子どもと政治家がオンラインで意見を言うことができるようにしました。若い人が政治や社会にもっと参加できるように活動をしています。川崎さんは「1人1人の意見が相手に届いて大切にされるように、頑張り続ける力をもらいました」とうれしい気持ちを話しました。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。"},{"question":"জাতীয়তাবাদ কী? ব্যাখ্যা করো।","answer":"ভাষা, ইতিহাস-ঐতিহ্য, সংস্কৃতি ও জাতিগত পরিচয়ের ভিত্তিতে যে ঐক্য গড়ে ওঠে তাই জাতীয়তাবাদ।ভৌগোলিক, ভাষাগত, বংশগত, সংস্কৃতি ও ঐতিহ্যগত, ধর্মীয় ইত্যাদি সম-আকাঙ্ক্ষা সম্পন্ন ঐক্যের দ্বারা আবদ্ধ জনসমাজের মধ্যে গভীর একাত্ববোধ জাতীয়তাবোধের সৃষ্টি করে। জাতীয়তাবোধের সঙ্গে স্বদেশপ্রেম যুক্ত হলে গড়ে ওঠে জাতীয়তাবাদ। উদাহরণ হিসেবে আমরা বাঙালি জাতীয়তাবাদের কথা বলতে পারি। বাংলা ভাষা, ইতিহাস-ঐতিহ্য, সংস্কৃতি ও বাঙালির জাতিগত পরিচয়ে জাতীয় ঐক্য গড়ে ওঠে। এ ঐক্যই বাঙালি জাতীয়তাবাদ।"},{"question":"hadalka aan cadeyn maxaa loo yaqaanaa","answer":"Hadalka aan Cadeyn Waxaa Looyaqaana Sarbeeb"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity.Fanambarana: \\"Tsapako fa misy manaraka ahy.\\"","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho tahotra. Maneho tahotra sy fiahiahiana amin’ny fanarahana azy ilay olona."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"hilatsaham-baratra eo am-pangerena, ka sady _ no _\\"","answer":" \\"ilatsaham-baratra eo am-pangerena, ka sady maty no mihosin-tay\\""},{"question":"ආසියාවේ පිහිටා ඇති විශාලතම වනාන්තරය","answer":"Sundarbans"},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto Matteo Marconcini (Arezzo, 26 de agosto de 1989) es un deportista italiano que compite en yudo. Ganó una medalla de plata en el Campeonato Mundial de Yudo de 2017, en la categoría de –81 kg.","answer":"El Campeonato Mundial de Yudo de 2017. "},{"question":"قم بكتابة مقال يجيب على هذا السؤال ما هي شركة هيونداي للصناعات الثقيلة ؟.","answer":"تقوم بتطوير وإنتاج مجموعة واسعة من الأنظمة الإلكترونية الدقيقة المتقدمة، بما في ذلك الصواريخ وأنظمة الأسلحة تحت الماء والرادارات والحرب الإلكترونية وإلكترونيات الطيران وأنظمة الاتصالات التكتيكية وأنظمة التحكم في الحرائق وأنظمة القتال البحرية والبصريات الكهربائية. وهي واحدة من الموردين الرئيسيين لأنظمة الأسلحة للقوات المسلحة لجمهورية كوريا، ومصدرة دولية لأنظمة الأسلحة."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"கோவில்கள் சாமிக்காகக் கட்டியதல்ல; மற்றெதற்காக என்றால் ஜாதியைப் பிரித்துக் காட்டி மக்களைத் தாழ்த்தவும் பணம் பறித்து, ஒரு கூட்டத்தார் பிழைக்க மக்களை அறியாமையில் வைத்து அடிமைகளாகவே கட்டப்பட்டதாகும்."},{"question":"Júpiter e Plutão são os correlatos romanos de quais deuses gregos?a) Ares e Hermesb) Cronos e Apoloc) Zeus e Hadesd) Dionísio e Demétere) Zeus e Ares","answer":"Alternativa c: Zeus e Hades.Na mitologia romana, Júpiter tem Zeus como seu correlato grego. Ele é considerado o pai dos deuses, sendo o deus dos céus, da chuva, da luz e do raio. Já Plutão, tem Hades como seu correlato grego, o deus do submundo e dos infernos."},{"question":"Wọn fẹẹ dana sun Yusuf at’ọrẹ ẹ n’Ilọrin, pọọsi obinrin  kan ni wọn ja gba","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti wọ afurasi kan, Yusuf Isiak, toun pẹlu Rasaq Sikiru, ja pọọsi Ọladele Ruth to n gbe ni Iyana Olodo, lagbegbe Airport, niluu Ilọrin, gba lọ sile-ẹjọ Magisreeti.Akọsilẹ ọlọpaa ṣalaye pe lasiko tawọn ọdọ kan n gbiyanju lati dana sun wọn lawọn ọlọpaa to wa ni tesan Adewọle doola wọn, ti wọn si wọ wọn lọ sile-ẹjọ.Agbẹjọro ijọba, Innocent Ọwọọla, sọ fun ile-ẹjọ pe Sikiru ko le foju bale-ẹjọ nitori pe o n gba itọju lọwọ nilewosan ọlọpaa.O rọ ile-ẹjọ ko gbe Isiak sahaamọ ọgba ẹwọn nitori pe ẹsun ole ni wọn fi kan an, ki i ṣe eyi ti wọn le gba beeli rẹ ṣaa.Ṣugbọn agbẹjọro olujẹjọ, Amofin Sulaiman, ni kile-ẹjọ ma ka ẹbẹ agbefọba naa si, o ni onibaara oun nilo itọju gidi nitori b’awọn araadugbo naa ṣe ṣe e baṣubaṣu.Adajọ H.D Muhammed gba oniduuro olujẹjọ naa pẹlu ẹgbẹrun lọna igba naira ati oniduuro meji, o sun ẹjọ si ọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu kẹta, ọdun yii."},{"question":"పుస్తక విక్రేతకు లేఖ","answer":"కొవ్వూరు,xxxxxమేనేజర్,వి.జి.యస్. పబ్లిషర్స్,విజయవాడ – 1.అయ్యా !,నేను ఈ క్రింద తెలియజేసిన పుస్తకాలను సాధ్యమైనంత త్వరలో రిజిష్టర్డ్ పోస్టుద్వారా పంపించవలసినదిగా ప్రార్థిస్తున్నాను. పుస్తకాలపై ఇచ్చే కమిషన్ తగ్గించి మిగతా పైకమును చెల్లించగలవాడను.1) 7వ తరగతి తెలుగు క్వశ్చన్ బ్యాంక్ – 10 కాపీలు2) 7వ తరగతి ఇంగ్లీషు క్వశ్చన్ బ్యాంక్ – 10 కాపీలు3) 7వ తరగతి గణితశాస్త్రం క్వశ్చన్ బ్యాంక్ – 10 కాపీలు4) 7వ తరగతి సామాన్యశాస్త్రం క్వశ్చన్ బ్యాంక్ – 10 కాపీలుఇట్లు,తమ విధేయుడు,జి.యస్. కుమార్,డోర్ నెం. 4-16-72,-కొవ్వూరు,ప.గో. జిల్లా.చిరునామా:మేనేజర్,వి.జి.యస్. పబ్లిషర్స్,తమ్మిన కృష్ణ వీధి,విజయవాడ – 520 001."},{"question":"మన రాష్ట్రంలోని శిల్పకళా సంపదను గూర్చి వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"రాయి, లోహం, కట్ట, మట్టి మొదలయిన వాటితో దేవతా విగ్రహాలనూ, మందిరాలనూ నిర్మించే విద్య శిల్పకళ.“కృష్ణాతీరంలో అమరావతిలో శాతవాహనుల నాటి అందమైన శిల్పాలు ఉన్నాయి. శిల్పుల చేతిలో బండరాళ్ళు వెన్నముద్దల్లా కరిగి, కావలసిన రూపం ధరిస్తాయి. అమరావతిలో, హంపిలో, అజంతా గుహల్లో, తెలుగు శిల్పుల ఉలి దెబ్బలచే రాళ్ళు, పూర్ణకుంభాలుగా, పద్మశాలలుగా, ధర్మచక్రాలుగా రూపం ధరించాయి. ఎల్లోరాలోని కైలాస దేవాలయం, శిల్పుల గొప్పతనానికి నిదర్శనం. అక్కడి విగ్రహాలు, దేవాలయాలు, ప్రాకారాలు, … ధ్వజస్తంభాలు, అన్నీ ఒకే రాతిలో చెక్కారు.మన శిల్ప. విద్యలో స్తంభాల నిర్మాణం గొప్పది. హంపి విఠలాలయంలోనూ, మధుర మీనాక్షి దేవాలయంలోనూ సప్తస్వరాలు పలికే రాతిస్తంభాలు నిర్మించారు. హనుమకొండలోని వేయిస్తంభాల గుడి, మన కాకతీయ చక్రవర్తుల పాలనలో శిల్పకళ పొందిన వైభవాన్ని తెలుపుతుంది.మైసూరు, హనుమకొండ, లేపాక్షి దేవాలయాల్లోని నంది విగ్రహాలు అందాలు చిందిస్తూ ఉంటాయి. ఆ నంది విగ్రహాలు, ప్రాణాలతో కూర్చున్న పెద్ద ఎద్దులవలె ఉంటాయి. దానిని చూసి ‘లేపాక్షి బసవన్న లేచి రావన్న’ అంటూ అడవి బాపిరాజు గారు గీతం రాశారు."},{"question":"Тил жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Тилди бузуп жаныңды жебе, калпак кийип кыргызмын дебе."},{"question":"1 ışık yılı uzunluğunda tek parça bir çubuğu çevirirsek veya hareket ettirirsek ne olur?","answer":"Gökyüzünde baktığımız yıldızların çoğu bize binlerce ışık yılı uzaklıktadır, gördüğümüz anda çoğu ölüdür. Bu demek değildir ki, biz görmüyoruz diye bu yaşanmadı. Yani aslında çubuğun ucu o an tepki verecektir fakat biz bunu 1 ışık yılı sonra görecek oluruz."},{"question":"ටෑන් අගය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ටෑන් හෙවත් ටැංජන අගය යනු යම්කිසි කෝණයක් සඳහා ගණනය කරනු ලබන ත්‍රිකෝණමිතික අනුපාතයකි. මෙය දත්ත ගොනු සඳහා වන මෘදුකාංගවල ද පැතුරුම්පත් සඳහා වන මෘදුකාංගවාල ද තවත්නොයෙක් පරිගණක භාෂාවල ද ත්‍රිකෝණමිතික ශ්‍රිතයක් ලෙසින් දක්නට ලැබේ. මෙම අනුපාතය තේරුම් ගැනීම සඳහා ඍජුකෝණී ත්‍රිකෝණයක් භාවිතා කළ යුතුය. යම්කිසි කෝණයක ටැංජන අගය යනු එම කෝණය සහිත ඍජුකෝණී ත්‍රිකෝණයක එම කෝණයට විරුද්ධ පාදය එහි බද්ධ පාදයෙන් බෙදූ විට ලැබෙන ප්‍රතිඵලයයි.ටැංජන අගය = විරුද්ධ පාදය / බද්ධ පාදය"},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Seen niróole mi ngi demee ni ku taal taalamn, ba janeer ba leeraale la ko wër, Yàlla fay leer ga, bàyyi leen cig lëndëm ba gisatuñu dara.","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Séen niróole mi ngi deme ni ku taal taalamn, ba janeer ba leeraale la ko wër, Yàlla fay leer ga, bàyyi léen ci'g lëndam ba gisatu ñu dara."},{"question":"Èske yon lè ki gen polisyon ka vin pwòp ankò?","answer":"Wi. Pandan konfinman COVID-19 la, nivo polisyon faktori yo ak machin yo nan Noudeli, ann End, te fè yon gwo bese. Kantite pousyè (PM2.5) ki nan lè a te bese anpil. Ti grenn pousyè sa yo (0.0025 mm oswa pi piti) ka lakòz maladi respiratwa ak lòt maladi ki pi grav. Amelyorasyon sa a se te jis pou yon ti tan, men sa montre kapasite atmosfè a genyen pou l repare tèt li byen vit lè gen anpil polisyon."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο: Οι δούλοι δεν είχαν δική τους περιουσία, ωστόσο οι αφέντες τους συχνά τους επέτρεπαν να συγκεντρώνουν χρήματα για να εξαγοράσουν την ελευθερία τους. Επιβιώνουν δε μέχρι και τις μέρες μας μαρτυρίες βάσει των οποίων, οι δούλοι είχαν δικές τους επιχειρήσεις πληρώνοντας κάποιο σταθερό ποσό στον κύριό τους. Η Αθήνα επίσης διέθετε ένα νόμο που καθιστούσε απαγορευτικό το χτύπημα ενός δούλου: αν κάποιος βιαιοπραγούσε κατά κάποιου που έμοιαζε με δούλο, κινδύνευε να χτυπήσει κάποιον πολίτη, καθώς πολλοί από αυτούς δεν ντύνονταν και πολύ καλύτερα. Οι υπόλοιποι Έλληνες μάλιστα εντυπωσιάζονταν από το γεγονός ότι οι Αθηναίοι επέτρεπαν στους δούλους τους να αντιμιλούν. Αθηναίοι δούλοι πολέμησαν μαζί με απελεύθερους στη Μάχη του Μαραθώνα","answer":"με τα μνημεία να αναφέρουν ρητά το γεγονός. Επίσης, πριν από τη Ναυμαχία της Σαλαμίνας, διατάχθηκε να προστατέψουν οι πολίτες τον εαυτό τους, τις γυναίκες τους, τα παιδιά και τους δούλους τους."},{"question":"Đảo Bình Ba nằm ở đâu?","answer":"Bình Ba là hòn đảo thuộc thành phố Cam Ranh, tỉnh Khánh Hòa, cách TP Nha Trang 60 km về phía nam. Đảo có diện tích khoảng 3 km2, với bãi biển hoang sơ, nước xanh trong vắt, di chuyển khá thuận tiện. Nhiều năm gần đây, Bình Ba là một trong những điểm đến nổi tiếng của khách du lịch trong nước. Đảo Bình Hưng, cách đất liền chỉ 1 km, là một trong \\"Tứ Bình\\" cùng Bình Ba và hai hòn đảo khác là Bình Lập và Bình Tiên.Trước đó, vào năm 2015, theo quyết định của Thủ tướng về quy chế đảm bảo an ninh, an toàn căn cứ quân sự Cam Ranh, đảo Bình Ba và Bình Hưng cùng khu vực mũi Hời đã không được phép phát triển du lịch. Tuy nhiên, nhiều năm qua các tour nhỏ và khách lẻ vẫn công khai thực hiện.Các dự án ở Khánh Hòa, Ninh Thuận liên quan đến khu vực căn cứ quân sự Cam Ranh phải có ý kiến của Bộ Quốc phòng trước khi trình Chính phủ phê duyệt."},{"question":"હરીન્દ્ર દવેની \\"મેં તો ઓઢણાં મંગાવ્યાં\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"મેં તો ઓઢણાં મંગાવ્યાં ભલી ભાતનાંને એણે આણ્યું કપાસનું ફૂલ રે…નેહથી મેં ઝાઝી વાત માંડી,તો વળતામાં આંખનો ઈશારો એણે કીધો,ઝાઝાં ફૂલો મેં જઈ દીધાં,વ્હાલાએ એક ફોરમનો પ્યાલો પાઈ પીધો,લાખેણી જીદ મારી ચાલી ના,એક એના સ્મિતમાં સો વાત થૈ કબૂલ રે…મેં તો ઓઢણાં મંગાવ્યાં ભલી ભાતનાંને એણે આણ્યું કપાસનું ફૂલ રે…સપનું મેં રાતભરી જોયું,ને એણે એક મીટ મહીં સમજાવ્યો સાર,લખ રે ચકરાવે હું ભમતી’તી,એણે લીધું હાથમાં સુકાન, બેડો પાર,એક રે સિતારો મેં માગ્યો’તો,આપ્યું એણે આખું આકાશ આ અમૂલ રે…મેં તો ઓઢણાં મંગાવ્યાં ભલી ભાતનાંને એણે આણ્યું કપાસનું ફૂલ રે…"},{"question":"નરસિંહ મહેતા ની \\"રામ સભામાં અમે \\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"રામ સભામાં અમે રમવાને ગ્યાં’તાં,પસલી ભરીને રસ પીધો રે..હરિનો રસ પુરણ પાયો..પહેલો પિયાલો મારા સદગુરૂએ પાયો જી,બીજે પિયાલે રંગની રેલી રે..ત્રીજો પિયાલો મારાં રોમે રામે વ્યાપ્યો,ચોથે પિયાલે થઈ છું ઘેલી રે.. રામ સભામાં..રસ બસ એક રૂપરસિયા સાથે,વાત ન સુઝે બીજી વાટે રે..મોટા જોગેશ્વર જેને સ્વપ્ને ન આવે,તે મારા મંદિરીયામાં મ્હાલે રે.. રામ સભામાં..અખંડ હેવાતણ મારા સદગુરૂએ દીધાં,અખંડ સૌભાગી અમને કીધાં રે..ભલે મળ્યા મહેતા નરસિંહના સ્વામી,દાસી પરમ સુખ પામી રે.. રામ સભામાં.."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'dulu sorak kemudian tohok'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud menggembar-gemburkan sesuatu pekerjaan yang belum pasti (terjadi, terbukti). Contoh ayat: Alin tidak suka dengan sikap dulu sorak kemudian tohok itu."},{"question":"¿Qué es el realismo mágico en la literatura universal?","answer":"El realismo mágico es un estilo literario que combina elementos realistas con elementos mágicos o surrealistas de una manera que parece completamente natural en el mundo de la historia. Autores como Gabriel García Márquez son conocidos por su uso del realismo mágico."},{"question":"ස්කන්ධ 5 යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ස්කන්ධ පහ නම් රූප, සංවේදන, සංජානන, මානසික ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සහ විඤ්ඤාණයයි."},{"question":"Su wanne Waƙoƙi ne na Ƙarni na Ishirin?","answer":"Su ne waƙoƙin da aka rubuta su bayan jihadin Shehu Usmanu Ɗanfodiyo. Waɗannan waƙoƙi rukuni biyu ne; rukunin farko su ne waɗanda aka ci gaba da rubuta su a cikin ajami kamar irin waƙoƙin sarkin Zazzau Aliyu Ɗan Sidi, da waƙoƙin Aliyu Namangi, da sauransu. Sai kuma rukuni na biyu waɗanda aka rubuta su da Hausar boko. A wannan rukuni akwai mawaƙa irin su Sa’adu Zungur, Mu’azu Haɗeja, da kuma Abubakar Ladan."},{"question":"Кандай жаңылмач билесиң ?","answer":"Бакатеректин түбүнө бака келет,Бакага терек керек, бакатерекке бака да керек,Ошон үчүн бака бакатерекке келүүчү болгон дешет."},{"question":"भारतातील सर्वाधिक कॉफीचे उत्पादन करणारे राज्य कोणते आहे?(A) कर्नाटक(B) तामिळनाडू(C) केरळ(D) महाराष्ट्र=> ","answer":"(A) कर्नाटक"},{"question":"Indro  misy fanehoan-kevitra:\\"Hita mihitsy hoe olona mainty fa jereo amin'izao fitondran-tenany izao.\\"Maneho fanavakavahana ara-tsaranga na fanafintohinana ve io fanehoan-kevitra io?","answer":"Maneho fanavakavaham-bolon-koditra atao amina olona mainty hoditra io fanehoan-kevitra io."},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 7 ਮਾਰਚਇਥੇ ਖੇਡਿਆ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ 12ਵਾਂ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਕੱਪ ਹਾਕੀ ਟੂਰਨਾਮੈਂਟ ਅੰਪਾਇਰਿੰਗ ਦੇ ਪੱਧਰ ਅਤੇ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਰੈਫਰਲ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਵਿਵਾਦਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਘਿਰ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਮਿਸਾਲ ਵਜੋਂ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨੇ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਰੈਫਰਲ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਰਲਵਾਂ-ਮਿਲਵਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਕਰਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਹੋਇਆ, ਉੱਥੇ ਲਾਭ ਵੀ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਲਾਭ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਮੈਚ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਜਦੋਂ ਉਸ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਹੋਏ ਗੋਲ ਨੂੰ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਗਿਆ। ਟੀਮ ਨੂੰ ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਦੱਖਣੀ ਅਫਰੀਕਾ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਮੈਚ ਵਿਚ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਉਦੋਂ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਦੋਂ ਪੈਨਲਟੀ ਕਾਰਨਰ ‘ਤੇ ਸੋਹੇਲ ਅੱਬਾਸ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕੀਤੇ ਗੋਲ ਨੂੰ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਰੈਫਰੀ ਨੇ ਨਾਮਨਜ਼ੂਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਟੂਰਨਾਮੈਂਟ ਵਿਚ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਈ ਹੋਰ ਵਿਵਾਦਗ੍ਰਸਤ ਫੈਸਲੇ ਰਹੇ। ਖਾਸ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਅੰਪਾਇਰ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪੈਨਲਟੀ ਕਾਰਨਰਾਂ ਉਪਰ ਗੋਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਨਜ਼ੂਰ ਜਾਂ ਨਾਮਨਜ਼ੂਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਕਾਫੀ ਰੌਲਾ ਪਿਆ। ਵੀਡੀਓ ਰੈਫਰੀ ਨੇ ਜਰਮਨੀ ਦੇ ਸਟਰਾਈਕਰ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਮੋਢੇ ਤੋਂ ਉਪਰ ਹਾਕੀ ਲਿਜਾ ਕੇ ਕੋਰੀਆ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਕੀਤੇ ਗੋਲ ਨੂੰ ਤਾਂ ਮੰਨ ਲਿਆ, ਪਰ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਦੀ ਟੀਮ ਨੂੰ ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਕੀਤੇ ਗੋਲ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਲਾਹਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਕੋਰੀਆ ਤੇ ਜਰਮਨੀ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਮੈਚ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ‘ਐਡਵਾਂਟੇਜ’ (ਚੱਲ ਰਹੀ ਖੇਡ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਰੁਕੇ ਲਾਹਾ) ਦੇਣ ਦੇ ਫੈਸਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਅੰਪਾਇਰ ਨੇ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਨਿਯਮ ਲਾਗੂ ਕਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਇਕਰੂਪਤਾ ਦੀ ਘਾਟ ਝਲਕਦੀ ਹੈ।ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੀ ਟੀਮ ਨੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ ਟਿੱਪਣੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਅਣਡਿੱਠ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ, ਪਰ ਰਿਚਰਡ ਚਾਰਲਸਵਰਥ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਕਰਮ ਨੂੰ ਨਜ਼ਰਅੰਦਾਜ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਖਾਸ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਟੂਰਨਾਮੈਂਟ ਦਾ ਡਾਇਰੈਕਟਰ ਵੀ ਚਾਰਲਸਵਰਥ ਦਾ ਹਮਵਤਨੀ ਹੈ। ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਸਪੇਨ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਆਪਣੀ ਟੀਮ ਦਾ ਮੈਚ ਦੇਖ ਰਹੇ ਚਾਰਲਸਵਰਥ ਨੇ ਸਟੈਂਡ ਵਿਚ ਖੜ੍ਹੇ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਟੀਮ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਦਿੱਤੇ 7 ਵਿਚੋਂ 3 ਪੈਨਲਟੀ ਕਾਰਨਰਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਇਤਰਾਜ਼ ਜਤਾਇਆ, ਜੋ ਨਾਵਾਜਬ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਅੰਪਾਇਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਫੈਸਲਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕਰੂਪਤਾ ਦੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਇਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਫੀਲਡ ਅੰਪਾਇਰਾਂ ਤੇ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਰੈਫਰਲ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਬੋਲਿਆ, ਪਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਇਕਰੂਪਤਾ’ ਉੱਤੇ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਕਈ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਖਿਡਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਰੈਫਰਲ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਦੀ ਘੋਖ ਕਰਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿਚ ਹੋਰ ਸੁਧਾਰ ਕਰਨ ‘ਤੇ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਤਾਂ ਕਿ ਖੇਡ ਦੀ ਰਫਤਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਿਤ ਨਾ ਹੋਵੇ। ਇਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਜਦੋਂ ਖੇਡ ਕਾਫੀ ਤੇਜ਼ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਗੇਂਦ ਇਕ ਪਾਸਿਓਂ ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਜਾਣਾ ਸਿਰਫ ਸਕਿੰਟਾਂ ਦੀ ਖੇਡ ਬਣ ਗਈ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਰੈਫਰਲ ਨਾਲ ਕੁਝ ਸਕਿੰਟਾਂ ਦੀ ਦੇਰੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਖੇਡ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਿਤ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ। ਵੀਡੀਓ ਅੰਪਾਇਰ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਖੇਡ ਵਿਚ ਆਉਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਅਜਾਈਂ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਲਈ ਟੀਮਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਾਰਮ-ਅਪ ਲਈ ਘੱਟ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ। ਸ਼ਨਿੱਚਰਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਤੇ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਮੈਚ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਟੀਮਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਾਰਮ-ਅਪ ਲਈ ਸਿਰਫ 21 ਮਿੰਟ ਮਿਲੇ।ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਤੇ ਹਾਕੀ ਵਿਚ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਅੰਪਾਇਰਿੰਗ ਦੀ ਤੁਲਨਾ ਕਰਨਾ ਵੀ ਜਾਇਜ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਵਿਚ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਅੰਪਾਇਰ ਦੇ ਫੈਸਲੇ ਨਾਲ ਖੇਡ ਦੀ ਰਫਤਾਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਕੋਈ ਫਰਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦਾ, ਪਰ ਹਾਕੀ ਵਿਚ ਤਾਂ ਕੁਝ ਸਕਿੰਟਾਂ ਦੀ ਦੇਰੀ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਬਦਲ ਦੇਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਕੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਭਾਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਮੈਚ ਦਾ ਵਾਰਮਅੱਪ ਸਮਾਂ ਘੱਟ ਮਿਲਿਆ?","answer":"ਟੀਵੀ ਰੈਫਰਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਦੂਜੇ ਮੈਚਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਸਮਾਂ ਬਰਬਾਦ ਕਰਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਭਾਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਮੈਚ ਨੂੰ ਘੱਟ ਵਾਰਮਅੱਪ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ।"},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： ミャンマーで軍がクーデターを起こしてから、2月1日で2年になりました。今も120万人以上が、家に住むことができなくて避難しています。日本にいるミャンマー人などの団体は、避難している人のために寄付のお金を集めています。団体は去年12月、そのお金で米や野菜を買って、ミャンマーに届けました。避難している女性は「避難する人が多くて、住む場所や食べ物、薬などが足りません」と話しました。団体によると、集まるお金は、クーデターのすぐあとの30％ぐらいに減っています。団体は「多くの人はウクライナを心配しているようです。ミャンマーの人にも力を貸してほしいです」と話しました。寄付はインターネットのクラウドファンディングで3月19日まで集めています。","answer":"ミャンマーのクーデターから2年　寄付で集まるお金が減っている"},{"question":"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ ਤ੍ਰੈ ਗੁਣ ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹੁ ਹੈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਚਉਥਾ ਪਦੁ ਪਾਇ ॥ ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਮੇਲਾਇਅਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਸਿਆ ਮਨਿ ਆਇ ॥ ਪੋਤੈ ਜਿਨ ਕੈ ਪੁੰਨੁ ਹੈ ਤਿਨ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਮੇਲਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਭਾਈ ਰੇ ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਸਾਚਿ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ ਸਾਚੋ ਸਾਚੁ ਕਮਾਵਣਾ ਸਾਚੈ ਸਬਦਿ ਮਿਲਾਉ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ ਜਿਨੀ ਨਾਮੁ ਪਛਾਣਿਆ ਤਿਨ ਵਿਟਹੁ ਬਲਿ ਜਾਉ ॥ ਆਪੁ ਛੋਡਿ ਚਰਣੀ ਲਗਾ ਚਲਾ ਤਿਨ ਕੈ ਭਾਇ ॥ ਲਾਹਾ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਮਿਲੈ ਸਹਜੇ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੨॥ ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਮਹਲੁ ਨ ਪਾਈਐ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਪਰਾਪਤਿ ਹੋਇ ॥ ਐਸਾ ਸਤਗੁਰੁ ਲੋੜਿ ਲਹੁ ਜਿਦੂ ਪਾਈਐ ਸਚੁ ਸੋਇ ॥ ਅਸੁਰ ਸੰਘਾਰੈ ਸੁਖਿ ਵਸੈ ਜੋ ਤਿਸੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਸੁ ਹੋਇ ॥੩॥ ਜੇਹਾ ਸਤਗੁਰੁ ਕਰਿ ਜਾਣਿਆ ਤੇਹੋ ਜੇਹਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ ਏਹੁ ਸਹਸਾ ਮੂਲੇ ਨਾਹੀ ਭਾਉ ਲਾਏ ਜਨੁ ਕੋਇ ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਏਕ ਜੋਤਿ ਦੁਇ ਮੂਰਤੀ ਸਬਦਿ ਮਿਲਾਵਾ ਹੋਇ ॥੪॥੧੧॥੪੪॥","answer":"ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹੁ। ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਕਮਾਈ ਕਰੋ, ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜੇ ਰਹੋ।1। ਰਹਾਉ।(ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਤ੍ਰਿਗੁਣੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ (ਪਸਰ ਰਿਹਾ) ਹੈ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਉਸ ਆਤਮਕ ਦਰਜੇ ਨੂੰ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈ ਸਕਦਾ। ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾਇਆ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ। ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਨੇਕੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।1।ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਸਮਝੀ ਹੈ। ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਤਿਆਗ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਚਰਨੀਂ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਤੁਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਣ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ) ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (-ਰੂਪ) ਲਾਭ ਹਾਸਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।2।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਦਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭਦਾ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਤੂੰ ਭੀ) ਅਜੇਹਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਲੱਭ ਲੈ, ਜਿਸ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਿਲ ਪਏ। (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਲੱਭ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਹ ਕਾਮਾਦਿਕ ਦੈਂਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਉਸਨੂੰ ਨਿਸਚਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ।3।ਕੋਈ ਭੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਗੁਰੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਸਰਧਾ ਬਣ ਕੇ ਵੇਖ ਲਏ, ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੇ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿਚ ਰਤਾ ਭਰ ਭੀ ਸ਼ੱਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਜਿਸ ਸਿੱਖ ਦਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਲ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ) ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਉਸ ਸਿੱਖ ਅਤੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ) ਜੋਤਿ ਇੱਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਸਰੀਰ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਦੋ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ।4।11। 44।"},{"question":"Inona no fiantsoan'ny Ntaolo ny amin'ny 09 ora  maraina fahiny ?","answer":"Ny fiantsoan'ny Ntaolo ny amin'ny 09 ora maraina  fahiny dia : \\"Mivoaka omby\\". "},{"question":"Akẹkọọ fasiti Al-Hikmah lẹdi apo pọ pẹlu agunbanirọ lati ja ileewe naa lole miliọnu mẹsan-an naira","answer":"Akẹkọọ kan to wa nipele 400Level, ni fasiti Al-Hikmah, niluu Ilọrin, Idris Shuaibu Suleiman ati agunbanirọ kan to sin ijọba nipinlẹ Jigawa, Nazim Usman Gomna, lajọ EFCC wọ lọ sile-ẹjọ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, lori ẹsun pe wọn lẹdi apo pọ lati ja ileewe naa lole miliọnu mẹsan-an naira.Afurasi mejeeji ni wọn wọ lọ siwaju Adajọ Sikiru Oyinloye, tile-ẹjọ giga ipinlẹ Kwara to fikalẹ silu Ilọrin.Idris ati Nazim ni wọn fẹsun kan pe wọn fọgbọn jibiti wọ ori ikanni ayelujara ileewe Al-Hikmah lati wọ owo ileewe tawọn akẹkọọ ba san sinu akanti wọn.Nazim to jẹ akẹkọọ-jade nipa imọ kọmputa ni wọn lo n bawọn ro idan naa lori ẹrọ ayelujara, o lo akanti Idris to jẹ akẹkọọ ni fasiti naa lati maa fi gba owo to yẹ ko lọ sinu apo ileewe naa sapo ara wọn.Akọsilẹ EFCC ṣalaye pe laarin oṣu kẹta si ikarun-n, ọdun 2020, lawọn mejeeji wuwa ọdaran naa.Nigba tile-ẹjọ ka ẹsun wọn si wọn leti, awọn mejeeji lawọn ko jẹbi.Agbẹjọro EFCC, Sẹsan Ọla, rọ ile-ẹjọ lati gba wọn sahaamọ ọgba ẹwọn titi di ọjọ tigbẹjọ yoo bẹrẹ.Ṣugbọn, Amofin A.T Kamaldeen ati Ismail Mustapha to ṣoju awọn olujẹjọ naa bẹ ile-ẹjọ lati gba oniduuro awọn onibaara wọn.Adajọ Oyinloye gba beeli ọkọọkan ni miliọnu mẹta aabọ naira ati oniduuro kọọkan niye kan naa.Adajọ ni oniduuro naa gbọdọ maa gbe ilu tile-ẹjọ naa wa, onitọhun yoo fi nọmba ẹrọ ibanisọrọ rẹ ati adirẹsi ile to n gbe silẹ, yoo si tun ko aworan pelebe rẹ kalẹ fun ile-ẹjọ.Bakan naa, ile-ẹjọ paṣẹ fun awọn olujẹjọ naa lati ko iwe-irinna wọn kalẹ, wọn ko si gbọdọ lọ si irinajo kankan lai gba aṣẹ ile-ẹjọ titi tẹjọ naa yoo fi pari. O ni wọn gbọdọ maa yọju sile-ẹjọ ni gbogbo ọjọ tigbẹjọ wọn ba waye, bi bẹẹ kọ wọn yoo padanu anfaani beeli toun fun wọn."},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Taorian'ny ezaka maharitra sy ny fanoloran-tena dia nahavita niantoka ny asa nofinofiny izy.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Tamin'ny fanoloran-tena tsy tapaka sy ny asa mafy dia nahatratra ny asa notadiaviny foana.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"يحصل مرض السكري بسبب مشكلة في أي عضو من أعضاء الجسم الآتية:[٣] الكبد. القلب. البنكرياس. الكلى.","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة: البنكرياس"},{"question":"Apakah  peranan Gochujang dalam masakan Korea?","answer":"Gochujang ialah perasa pedas berlauk dalam masakan orang Korea yang diperbuat daripada cili merah, nasi pulut, kedelai tertapai dan garam. Adunan bahan-bahan ini secara tradisinya diawet dengan dibiarkan menapai bertahun-tahun lamanya dalam tempayan tembikar (onggi) besar di suatu ruangan khas di belakang rumah yang bertapak batu tinggi. Proses penapaian ini menguraikan pulut menjadi gula memberikan rasa manis pada tapaian akhir."},{"question":"ਸ੍ਰੀਨਗਰ, 27 ਫਰਵਰੀਜੰਮੂ ਕਸ਼ਮੀਰ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੋਪੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਬਲਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਏ ਇਕ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿਚ ਜੈਸ਼-ਏ-ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ। ਮ੍ਰਿਤਕਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨੀ ਨਾਗਰਿਕ ਵੀ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੈ। ਪੁਲੀਸ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਸ਼ੋਪੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਮੀਮੇਂਦਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਹੋਣ ਬਾਰੇ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਮਿਲਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਬਲਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਨੂੰ ਘੇਰਾ ਪਾ ਲਿਆ ਤੇ ਤਲਾਸ਼ੀ ਮੁਹਿੰਮ ਆਰੰਭੀ। ਇਸੇ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਬਲਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਗੋਲੀਬਾਰੀ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਵਾਬੀ ਕਾਰਵਾਈ ਵਿਚ ਦੋ ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ। ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਾਲੀ ਥਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਲਾਸ਼ਾਂ ਬਰਾਮਦ ਕਰ ਲਈਆਂ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਜੈਸ਼ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਪੁਸ਼ਟੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ। ਮ੍ਰਿਤਕ ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਨਾਖ਼ਤ ਸੈਦਾਪੋਰਾ ਪਾਯੀਨ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਦੇ ਸੁਹੇਲ ਨਜ਼ੀਰ ਮੀਰ ਵੱਜੋਂ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਜਦਕਿ ਦੂਜਾ ਪਾਕਿ ਨਾਗਰਿਕ ਹੈ। ਪੁਲੀਸ ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਇਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਸਾਜ਼ਿਸ਼ ਘੜਨ ਤੇ ਕਈ ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀ ਹਮਲਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਜਾਮ ਦੇਣ ਲਈ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰ ਹਨ। ਮ੍ਰਿਤਕ ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀਆਂ ’ਤੇ ਕਈ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਟਿਕਾਣਿਆਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਹਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਯੋਜਨਾ ਘੜਨ ਤੇ ਆਮ ਲੋਕਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਵੀ ਜਬਰ ਢਾਹੁਣ ਦਾ ਦੋਸ਼ ਹੈ। ਪੁਲੀਸ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਅਪਰੇਸ਼ਨ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਬਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਇਆ। ਪੁਲੀਸ ਬੁਲਾਰੇ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਾਲੀ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਤੋਂ ਹਥਿਆਰ ਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਅਸਲਾ ਵੀ ਬਰਾਮਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਹਮਲੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਬਲਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਈਂ ਵੱਡੀਆਂ ਕਾਰਵਾਈਆਂ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਕੀ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਹਨ?","answer":"ਨਹੀਂ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਤੋਂ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Rocinante là cái tên rất kêu Don Quixote đặt cho con vật mà ông ta cưỡi khi làm hiệp sĩ. Đó là con gì?","answer":"Rocinante là một con ngựaĐể có tiền đi hành hiệp, Don Quixote bán nhà và vay một số tiền khổng lồ từ một người bạn. Ông ta đem bộ áo giáp của cha để lại đã bị han rỉ và thủng lỗ chỗ ra đánh bóng và sử dụng.Don Quixote phong cho con ngựa gầy còm cao lênh khênh cái tên rất kêu Rocinante, nghĩa là con ngựa mạnh nhất trong các con ngựa. Để đúng \\"mốt\\" của một hiệp sĩ lang thang phải có một người tình xinh đẹp, ông ta nghĩ đến một phụ nữ nông dân mà mình thầm yêu từ hồi tuổi trẻ và đặt cho bà cái tên Công nương Dulcinea del Toboso, nghĩa là người đàn bà đẹp nhất trong những người đàn bà.Lần ra đi thứ nhất, Don Quixote nói với những người lái buôn phải khen Dulcinea del Toboso là người đẹp nhất trần gian và kết thúc bằng một cuộc giao đấu của ông ta với những người này vì họ không chịu thừa nhận, khi mà họ chưa từng gặp người phụ nữ nông dân kia.Hậu quả Don Quixote bị đánh nát người rồi được một nông dân đưa về nhà chăm sóc.Don Quixote sau đó lại ra đi, lần này có thêm một giám mã là bác nông dân cục mịch Sancho Panza. Hai thầy trò hiên ngang cất bước, thầy là hiệp sĩ cao lòng khòng, cặp mắt mơ màng nghĩ về người tình Dulcinea del Toboso. Trò là gã lùn tịt, bụng phệ, cưỡi trên lưng con lừa mập lùn tên là Dapple, mộng tưởng khi thầy công thành danh toại sẽ ban cho cai trị một vài hòn đảo mà ông chiếm được."},{"question":"قم بتقييم الجملة المحددة ولاحظ صحتها النحوية.","answer":"الجملة صحيحة نحويا."},{"question":"日本では女性が男性にチョコレートなどを渡すことで習慣化している、バレンタインデーは何月何日でしょう？","answer":"2月14日です。"},{"question":"La mejor universidad del mundo es la universidad de la vida según alguien que tiene mucha experiencia. ¿Cómo se podría resumir este párrafo?","answer":"La experiencia vivencial es mejor que cualquier aprendizaje teórico."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: MV hoành tráng \\"DDU DU DDU DU\\" phát hành tháng 6.2018 khiến cả Kpop choáng ngợp bởi mức độ hoành tráng, \\"đắt sắt ra miếng\\". Tính đến tháng 7.2022, MV đã vượt mốc 1,9 tỉ lượt truy cập – mang lại số tiền khủng cho Blackpink. MV có hình ảnh, màu sắc rực rỡ. Đạo cụ đắt đỏ. Được biết, tất cả bối cảnh quay MV đều được dàn dựng thật 100%, không dùng đến kỹ xảo để \\"biến hình\\". Chiếc xe tăng nạm đá làm đạo cụ cho sự xuất hiện của Jennie, tuy không được tiết lộ cụ thể về con số đầu tư, nhưng nhìn đã thấy sự lộng lẫy và chịu chơi của YG Entertainment. Hiệu ứng của chiếc xe tăng nạm đá lấp lánh đã làm nổi bật sự lộng lẫy, sang chảnh của Jennie trong từng khung hình. Jennie còn chia sẻ, xe tăng đính đá lấp lánh đó có người lái, chứ không phải mô hình dựng lên. Sau 4 năm, MV \\"DDU DU DDU DU\\" vẫn là thành tích nổi bật bậc nhất của Blackpink. Năm 2019, nhóm ra mắt \\"Kill this love\\", hiện MV này cũng đã đạt 1,6 tỉ lượt xem. Đây cũng là MV được dàn dựng bối cảnh công phu, 100% là thật. Những phân cảnh ấn tượng như đoạn nhảy trong bẫy sắt trái tim hay hiệu ứng nổ với những mảnh vỡ bay lên, đều được thực hiện thật. Tháng 6 năm 2020, Blackpink ra mắt MV \\"How you like that\\" tiếp tục gây choáng ngợp với màu sắc rực rỡ, hình ảnh đẹp mắt, âm nhạc bắt tai. Tính đến tháng 7.2022, MV \\"How you like that\\" đã đạt 1,1 tỉ lượt xem. Ngay khi ra mắt, MV đã xô đổ nhiều thành","answer":"tích về lượt xem khủng. MV cũng nhận được nhiều lợi ngợi khen về sự đầu tư lớn của YG dành cho hình ảnh, phục trang, bối cảnh đắt đỏ. Thời trang đắt giá Hiếm có nhóm nhạc nào, tất cả các thành viên đều sở hữu giá trị thương hiệu cá nhân đắt giá như Blackpink. Điều này giải thích vì sao, sau 2 năm không ra sản phẩm mới, Blackpink vẫn là cái tên hot, vẫn là nhóm nhạc nữ hàng đầu Kpop, sở hữu giá trị thương mại không nhóm nhạc nào sánh kịp. Jennie, Lisa, Jisoo và Rose đều có thế mạnh về thời trang, là gương mặt đại diện cho nhiều nhãn hàng, là những mỹ nhân dẫn đầu xu thế thời trang ở Kpop. Mỗi MV đều là sàn diễn thời trang đắt đỏ của cả 4 mỹ nhân, từ Jennie, Lisa, Rose đến Jisoo. Tất cả trang phục của họ trình diễn ở các MV đều là hàng hiệu đến từ những thương hiệu danh tiếng. Đơn cử như ở \\"How you like that\\", những phục trang cùng tông với màu hồng chủ đạo khiến mỗi khung hình đều rực rỡ, mỗi sự xuất hiện của 4 mỹ nhân đều tràn ngập sắc màu, đều nổi bật theo cách riêng, không ai bị lu mờ, bị lấn ép. Những phục trang đắt đỏ không chỉ đẹp mắt, thời thượng, dẫn dắt xu hướng, còn giúp cho 4 cô gái của Blackpink cá tính và quyền lực."},{"question":"UDoolley wayecinga ukuba naye ulumkile, mhlawumbi ulumke kakhulu kunaye. Emva kwethutyana uDooley waqonda ukuba umzingeli wakhe wayemqhubela ngasentabeni yeGoth kunye nokugcinwa.","answer":"Imigaqo ayicacanga."},{"question":"Жердин атмосферасында экинчи орунда турган газ кайсы?","answer":"Кычкылтек (O2)."},{"question":"De quel événement important parle ce texte: À partir du Grand Prix d'Espagne, McLaren progresse en qualifications et devance les Sauber mais, après cinq Grands Prix, n'a pas inscrit le moindre point. À Monaco, alors qu'Alonso abandonne, Button inscrit les premiers points de son équipe en terminant huitième. Les Grands Prix du Canada et d'Autriche se soldent par un nouveau double abandon. En Grande-Bretagne, Fernando Alonso profite de la pluie pour marquer son premier point en terminant dixième. Au Grand Prix de Hongrie, marqué par de nombreux incidents de course, Alonso termine cinquième et Button neuvième, réalisant sa meilleure performance de la saison ; c'est la seule fois de l'année où les deux voitures terminent dans les points. Malgré cette progression, McLaren ne marque que dix points supplémentaires sur le reste de la saison (avec Jenson Button neuvième en Russie et sixième aux États-Unis). Sans la moindre victoire, la moindre pole position, le moindre podium, le moindre meilleur tour, le moindre tour en tête, et avec 27 points, McLaren Racing obtient son pire résultat depuis 1980 en se classant neuvième du classement des constructeurs. Button (seizième) et Alonso (dix-septième) réalisent leurs pires résultats depuis 2008 et 2001.","answer":"Ce texte est au sujet du Grand Prix d'Espagne."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: \\"Phải biết đặt đúng nơi, đúng chỗ thì mới tôn lên giá trị nghệ thuật của hình vẽ. Cứ gặp đâu vẽ đó như thế này thì mọi người sẽ có cái nhìn ác cảm về giới graffiti\\", Hoàng Vũ (27 tuổi, ngụ huyện Nhà Bè) bức xúc nhìn những vết sơn bậy trên cầu Thủ Thiêm 2. Là người yêu thích bộ môn vẽ tranh tường nhưng Hoàng Vũ không hài lòng khi thấy cây cầu mới khánh thành bị bôi bẩn. Chàng trai này mong cơ quan chức năng sớm khôi phục hiện trạng cho cây cầu và tăng cường an ninh quanh khu vực để không xảy ra tình trạng tương tự. Ghi nhận của Zing tại lối đi bộ xuống cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 (đoạn hướng về quận 1), chi chít vết vẽ bằng sơn. Tương tự, hai đoạn đầu dây văng trên cầu cũng bị bôi bẩn. Không chỉ vậy, đường đi bộ lên cầu cũng ngập rác thải. Xung quanh các trụ và cột điện thắp sáng của cây cầu bị dán nhiều tờ rơi. Đây chỉ là một trong số hàng chục công trình công cộng tại TP.HCM bị sơn, vẽ bậy. Tham quan, hóng mát vào cuối tuần, Thanh Thùy (27 tuổi, ngụ TP Thủ Đức) lắc đầu ngao ngán khi nhìn thấy hình vẽ tựa mặt người màu trắng, nổi bật lên ngay lối đi bộ lên cầu. Thùy nói thường xuyên qua khu vực này đạp xe thể dục và lần đầu thấy xuất hiện những hình thù thế này. \\"Ở TP.HCM, có nhiều nơi bị bôi bẩn nhưng với cây cầu mới xây như Thủ Thiêm 2 thì nhìn rất phản cảm. Mong cơ","answer":"quan chức năng sớm tìm ra thủ phạm, xử lý theo pháp luật để tạo tính răn đe những người khác\\", Thùy bức xúc. Cùng quan điểm, chị Hoàng Giang (ngụ quận Gò Vấp) nhìn nhận cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 có nhiều khách nước ngoài, khách du lịch tới tham quan. Một biểu tượng mới bị bôi bẩn sẽ ảnh hưởng đến hình ảnh thành phố. Chị này đề xuất xử phạt nghiêm cá nhân thiếu ý thức. \\"Một vài cá nhân không có ý thức đã làm ảnh hưởng chung đến không gian công cộng của thành phố\\", chị Giang nói. Theo Đại diện đơn vị quản lý, cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 mới bị bôi bẩn trong những ngày gần đây. Đơn vị sẽ trích xuất camera trên cầu xác minh và đề nghị công an làm rõ. Trước đó, sau khánh thành một tháng, hơn 40 nắp chắn rác trên cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 từng bị mất trộm. Người lấy trộm sau đó bị công an tạm giữ. Hiện, nắp chắn rác đã được thay mới để đảm bảo an toàn cho người đi đường. Sau sự việc, Công an quận 1 (TP.HCM) đã gắn camera trên cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 để theo dõi an ninh trật tự ở khu vực này. Hình ảnh cũng được lưu lại để phục vụ công tác khi cần thiết. Tình trạng bôi bẩn, vẽ bậy trên các bức tường nơi công cộng, toà nhà... diễn ra nhiều nơi ở TP.HCM. Hồi giữa tháng 6, tàu metro số 1 đặt tại depot Long Bình, TP Thủ Đức, bị sơn vẽ nhiều hình thù khác nhau. Theo Nghị định 144 của Chính phủ, hành vi phun sơn, viết, vẽ lên tường, cột điện hoặc các công trình công cộng mà không được phép của cơ quan có thẩm quyền sẽ bị phạt tiền lên tới 5 triệu đồng. Luật sư Hà Hải (Phó chủ nhiệm Đoàn Luật sư TP.HCM) còn nhìn nhận người vẽ bậy có thể bị xử lý hình sự tội Hủy hoại, Cố ý làm hư hỏng tài sản được quy định tại Điều 178 Bộ luật Hình sự... Ngược lại, nhiều tuyến đường, khu phố được các nghệ sĩ graffiti lên kế hoạch thực hiện kỳ công đã mang một màu áo mới, đem đến nhiều giá trị nghệ thuật. Đánh giá về graffiti, nghệ sĩ Đỗ Thế Thành cho rằng ranh giới giữa nghệ thuật và bôi bẩn rất mong manh. Môn nghệ thuật này được thực hiện hợp pháp sẽ góp phần tạo ra các tác phẩm tốt, khiến người khác có cái nhìn thiện cảm. Ngược lại, nếu vẽ tranh graffiti bất hợp pháp tại khu vực công cộng sẽ rất phản cảm."},{"question":"ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਬਾਰੇ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਕੀ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹੋ ? ਵਿਸਤਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਲਿਖੋ ।","answer":"ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਇੱਕ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਦੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਇਕ ਦਮ ਹੀ ਇਸੇ ਪੱਧਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਹੁੰਚਿਆ ਬਲਕਿ ਇਸਦਾ ਹੌਲੀ-ਹੌਲੀ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ । ਇਸਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਣ ਲਈ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਇਸਦਾ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਆਦਿਮ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਕਰਨਾ ਪਵੇਗਾ ।ਆਦਿਮ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿਚ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੇ ਲੈਣ-ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਵਟਾਂਦਰੇ ਦੀ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਸੀ ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਲਾਭ (Profit) ਦਾ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਇਆ ਸੀ । ਲੋਕ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਲਾਭ ਲਈ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ । ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਿਨਾਂ ਲਈ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ ਜਦੋਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਘਾਟ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ ਜਾਂ ਫਿਰ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧੀ ਲਈ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ । ਵਪਾਰਕ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਸੇਵਾ ਅਤੇ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੇ ਦੇਣ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਕਰਦੀ ਸੀ । ਆਰਥਿਕ ਕਾਰਕ; ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ-ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰੀ, ਨਿਵੇਸ਼, ਵਿਆਜ ਤੇ ਲਾਭ ਦੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਆਦਿਮ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ।ਮੱਧ ਵਰਗੀ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਪਾਰ ਤੇ ਵਣਜ ਥੋੜੇ ਜਿਹੇ ਉੱਨਤ ਹੋ ਗਏ । ਚਾਹੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਪਾਰ ਵਟਾਂਦਰੇ ਦੀ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਉੱਤੇ ਆਧਾਰਿਤ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਹੌਲੀ-ਹੌਲੀ ਪੈਸਾ ਵਪਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਇਕ ਮਧਿਅਮ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ । ਇਸ ਨੇ ਵਪਾਰ ਤੇ ਵਣਜ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਉਤਸ਼ਾਹ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਪੈਸੇ, ਸੋਨੇ, ਚਾਂਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਟੋਕਨ ਦੀ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ ਵੱਧ ਗਈ 1 ਪੈਸਾ ਚਾਹੇ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ, ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਦਾ ਸੂਚਕ ਸੀ । ਇਸ ਦਾ ਉਤਪਾਦਕ ਸ਼ਕਤੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲੱਛਣ ਉੱਤੇ ਪੂਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਸੀ । ਸਿੱਮਲ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਪੈਸੇ ਦੀ ਸੰਸਥਾ ਦੇ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਵਸਥਿਤ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਹਰ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਡੂੰਘੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਪਏ । ਇਸ ਨੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਤੇ ਨੌਕਰ ਨੂੰ ਅਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਤੇ ਸੇਵਾਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਵੇਚਣ ਤੇ ਖਰੀਦਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਵੀ ਅਸਰ ਪਾਇਆ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਵਪਾਰ ਦੇ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਪਾਸਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਰਸਮੀ ਰਿਸਤੇ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਗਏ । ਸਿੰਮਲ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਪੈਸੇ ਨੇ ਸਾਡੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਾਸਫੀ ਵਿਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਲਿਆ ਦਿੱਤੇ । ਇਸ ਨੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ Practical ਬਣਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਹੁਣ ਅਸੀਂ ਹਰੇਕ ਚੀਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਪੈਸੇ ਵਿਚ ਤੋਲਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਏ । ਸਮਾਜ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਤੇ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਗੈਰ ਰਸਮੀ ਅਤੇ ਅਵਿਅਕਤਕ ਹੋ ਗਏ । ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇ ਵੀ ਠੰਢੇ ਹੋਏ ।ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਦੌਰ ਵਿਚ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਗਤੀਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਤਾਕਤਾਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸੰਚਾਲਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਸਨ । ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਯੂਰਪੀ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਰਾਜਤੰਤਰੀ ਸਰਕਾਰਾਂ ਅਧੀਨ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਵੱਧਣ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਬਿੰਬ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਗਤੀਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਰਾਜਨੀਤਿਕ ਸੱਤਾ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸੰਚਾਲਿਤ ਸਨ ਤਾਂ ਕਿ ਰਾਜੇ ਦਾ ਲਾਭ ਤੇ ਖਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਵੱਧ ਸਕੇ । ਦੇਸ਼ ਵਪਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਦੇਖ-ਰੈੱਖ ਵਿਚ ਚਲਦਾ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਇਕ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਸੰਗਠਨ ਦੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਲਾਭ ਕਮਾਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੱਗੇ ਹੋਏ ਸਨ । ਉਤਪਾਦਕ ਸ਼ਕਤੀਆਂ ਵੀ ਵਪਾਰਕ ਕਾਨੂੰਨਾਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸੰਚਾਲਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਦਯੋਗਿਕ ਕ੍ਰਾਂਤੀ ਆਈ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਤਰੀਕਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ । ਵਪਾਰਕ ਨੀਤੀਆਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਭਲਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਸਫਲ ਰਹੀਆਂ । ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ Laissez faire ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਅਪਣਾਈ ਗਈ । ਇਸ ਨੀਤੀ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਮਾਮਲਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਦਖਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ । ਇਸ ਨੀਤੀ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਹਿੱਤ ਦੇਖ ਸਕਦਾ ਸੀ । ਉਸ ਉੱਤੇ ਕੋਈ ਬੰਧਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ । ਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਦਖ਼ਲ ਦੇਣਾ ਬੰਦ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ | ਸਮਰ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਵਪਾਰ ਤੇ ਵਣਜ ਉੱਤੇ ਲੱਗੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਬੰਧ ਹਟਾ ਲੈਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ, ਵਟਾਂਦਰੇ ਤੇ ਪੈਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਪਾਬੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਟਾ ਲੈਣੀਆਂ ਚਾਹੀਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਐਡਮ ਸਮਿਥ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਚਾਰ ਸਿਧਾਂਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਕੀਤਾ ।1. ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਹਿੱਤ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ2. ਦਖ਼ਲ ਨਾ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ।3. ਪ੍ਰਤੀਯੋਗਤਾ ਦਾ ਸਿਧਾਂਤ ਅਤੇ4. ਲਾਭ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਣਾ ।ਇਹਨਾਂ ਸਿਧਾਂਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਪਿਆ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨਿਯਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਅਧੀਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਦਯੋਗਿਕ ਕ੍ਰਾਂਤੀ ਕਰਕੇ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਤੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੀ ਮਲਕੀਅਤ ਦੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿਚ ਆਈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ । ਉਦਯੋਗਿਕ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਕਰਕੇ ਘਰੇਲੂ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਕਾਰਖਾਨਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵਿਚ ਬਦਲ ਗਿਆ । ਕਾਰਖਾਨਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਕੰਮ ਛੋਟੇ-ਛੋਟੇ ਹਿੱਸਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਵੰਡਿਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਹਰੇਕ ਮਜਦੂਰ ਥੋੜਾ ਜਾਂ ਛੋਟਾ ਜਿਹਾ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਸੀ । ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵੱਧ ਗਿਆ | ਸਮੇਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਵੱਡੇ-ਵੱਡੇ ਕਾਰਖਾਨੇ ਲੱਗ ਗਏ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਕਾਰਖਾਨਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ, ਨਿਗਮ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਗਏ । ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਕਿਰਤ ਵੰਡ, ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ੀਕਰਣ ਤੇ ਲੈਣ-ਦੇਣ ਵੀ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿਚ ਆਇਆ ।ਇਸ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਤੇ ਲੈਣ-ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਧਨ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਲੋਕ ਸਨ ਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਕੋਈ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ । ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਬਿਲਕੁੱਲ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਰਾਜ, ਧਰਮ, ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਪਾਬੰਦੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਅਜ਼ਾਦ ਸੀ । ਫੈਕਟਰੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਕੁੱਝ ਵੀ ਕਰਨ ਨੂੰ ਅਜ਼ਾਦ ਸਨ । ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਵ ਲਾਭ ਸੀ । ਉਹਨਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਬਗੈਰ ਲਾਭ ਦੀਆਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦਾ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਬੰਧਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ । ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦਾ ਤਰੀਕਾ ਲਾਭ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਦਖ਼ਲ ਨਾ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਅਪਣਾਈ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਮਾਲਕ ਦਾ ਸਾਥ ਦਿੱਤਾ ।ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਦੇ ਲੱਛਣ (Features of Capitalism)(i) ਵੱਡੇ ਪੱਧਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ (Large Scale Production) – ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਮਹੱਤਵਪੂਰਨ ਲੱਛਣ ਹੈ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦਾ ਵੱਧਣਾ । ਉਦਯੋਗਾਂ ਦੇ ਲੱਗਣ ਨਾਲ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵੱਡੇ ਪੈਮਾਨੇ ਤੇ ਹੋਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ । ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਉਦਯੋਗਿਕ ਕ੍ਰਾਂਤੀ ਕਰਕੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਆਇਆ ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਪੱਧਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਮੁਮਕਿਨ ਹੋਇਆ । ਵੱਡੇ-ਵੱਡੇ ਕਾਰਖਾਨਿਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਕਿਰਤ ਵੰਡ ਤੇ ਵਿਵੇਸ਼ੀਕਰਣ ਦੇ ਵੱਧਣ ਨਾਲ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵੀ ਵੱਧ ਗਿਆ । ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਸੀ ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਅਤੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਪੱਧਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਉਪਭੋਗ ਅਤੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਮੁਨਾਫ਼ਾ ।(ii) ਨਿੱਜੀ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ (Private Property) – ਨਿੱਜੀ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਤੇ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ ਆਧਾਰ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਆਧਾਰ ਹੈ । ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਰੇਕ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਮਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਹੱਕ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਰੱਖਣ ਦਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਹੈ । ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੇ ਹੱਕ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਨਿੱਜੀ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਕਰਕੇ ਹੀ ਵੱਡੇ-ਵੱਡੇ ਕਾਰਖਾਨੇ, ਉਦਯੋਗ, ਨਿਗਮ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿਚ ਆਏ ਅਤੇ ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਧਿਆ ।(iii) ਪ੍ਰਤਿਯੋਗਿਤਾ (Competition) – ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਯੋਗਿਤਾ ਇੱਕ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਤੱਤ ਤੇ ਨਤੀਜਾ ਹੈ । ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਪੂੰਜੀਪਤੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਵੇਖਣ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ । ਮੰਗ ਨੂੰ ਨਕਲੀ ਤੌਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਵਧਾ ਕੇ ਅਤੇ Supply ਨੂੰ ਘਟਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਡੇ ਪੂੰਜੀਪਤੀ ਜਿੱਤ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਛੋਟੇ ਪੁੰਜੀਪਤੀ ਹਾਰ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।(iv) ਲਾਭ (Profit) – ਮਾਰਕਸ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਲਾਭ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਟਿੱਕ ਸਕਦਾ । ਪੂੰਜੀਪਤੀ ਵੱਡੇ ਪੈਮਾਨੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਦਾ ਨਿਵੇਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਕਿ ਲਾਭ ਕਮਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕੇ । ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਲਾਭ ਦੇ ਲਈ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਨਾ ਕਿ ਸਮਾਜ ਕਲਿਆਣ ਜਾਂ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤਾਂ ਪੂਰੀਆਂ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਲਈ ।(v) ਕੀਮਤ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ (Price System) – ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਿਚ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਵ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਲਾਭ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੀ ਕੀਮਤ ਉਸ ਉੱਪਰ ਲੱਗੀ ਲਾਗਤ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਹੀਂ, ਸਗੋਂ ਉਸ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਿਰਧਾਰਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰੀ ਵੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਨਿਸ਼ਚਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਕੰਮ ਦੀ ਕੀਮਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸਦੀ ਬਜ਼ਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਮੰਗ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੀ ਕੀਮਤ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਬਜ਼ਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੰਗ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਿਰਧਾਰਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਰਤ ਦੀ ਕੀਮਤ ਵੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਕਾਰਖਾਨੇ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਨਿਰਧਾਰਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।(vi) ਮੁਦਰਾ ਤੇ ਉਧਾਰ (Money and Credit) – ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਅਰਥ-ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੈਸੇ ਤੇ ਉਧਾਰ ਦੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਪੂੰਜੀਪਤੀ ਕਰਜ਼ੇ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਅਤੇ ਵਪਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਵਧਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਹ ਉਧਾਰ ਸਾਹੂਕਾਰਾਂ, ਬੈਂਕਾਂ ਆਦਿ ਤੋਂ ਲਏ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਕਰਜ਼ੇ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵਧਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਲਾਭ ਤੇ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਨੂੰ ਵਧਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਕਰਜ਼ੇ ਦਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਆਜ ਵੀ ਦੇਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।(vii) ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰੀ (wages) – ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰ ਦੀ ਦਸ਼ਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਤਰਸਯੋਗ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਦਾ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰਾਂ ਪਤੀ ਇੱਕੋ ਹੀ ਮੰਤਵ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਹ ਹੈ ਘੱਟ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਪੈਸੇ ਦੇ ਕੇ ਵੱਧ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਕੰਮ ਲਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕੇ । ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਪੂੰਜੀਵਾਦ ਵਿਚ ਸ਼ੋਸ਼ਣ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"බුදු දහමේ එන  විපාක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ත්‍රිරාශිය ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"ඔවුනොවුන්ට ද ඔවුනොවුන්ට හා චිත්තජ රූප ප්‍ර‍තිසන්ධි කර්මජ රූපයන්ට ද ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වන විපාක සිත් සතිස ය, චෛතසික අට තිසය යන ප්‍ර‍වෘත්ති ප්‍ර‍තිසන්ධි නාමස්කන්ධයෝ විපාක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ධර්මයෝ ය.ඔවුනොවුන්ගෙන් ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ලබන විපාක සිත් සතිස ය, චෛතසික අටතිසය යන නාමස්කන්ධයෝ ය, ඒ නාමස්කන්ධයන් විසින් සුදුසු පරිදි උපදවන විඥප්ති රූප වර්ජිත චිත්තජ රූපයෝය, ප්‍ර‍තිසන්ධි කර්මජ රූපයෝය යන මොහු විපාක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්න ධර්මයෝ ය.කුසල් සිත් එක් විස්සය, අකුසල් සිත් දොළොසය, ක්‍රියා සිත් විස්සය, චෛතසික දෙපනසය යන නාමස්කන්ධයෝ ය, ඒ නාමස්කන්ධයන් විසින් උපදවන චිත්තජ රූපයෝ ය, බාහිර රූපය, ආහාරජ රූපය, සෘතුජ රූපය, අසංඥ සත්ත්ව කර්මජ රූපය, ප්‍ර‍වෘත්ති කර්මජ රූපය යන මොහු විපාක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයාගේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යනීක ධර්මයෝ ය."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Vid olympiska sommarspelen 2016 i Rio de Janeiro tävlade Chierighini i tre grenar. Han slutade på 8:e plats på","answer":"100 meter frisim. Chierighini var även en del av Brasiliens lag som slutade på 5:e plats på 4x100 meter frisim och på 6:e plats på 4x100 meter medley."},{"question":"Zer da historiaren historiografia, eta nola ulertzen du historia idazten den modua?","answer":"Historiografia da historia idazten den modua aztertzen duen ikerketa. Historiografiak ulertzen ditu historia idazteko metodoak eta ikuspegiak."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--मेल्या म्हशीला मणभर दूध","answer":"मेल्यावर गुणगान करणे"},{"question":"Àwọn ajínigbé tó jí àwọn akọrin gbé ní ìpínlẹ̀ Ondo ti ń kàn sí wa lórí ohun tí wọ́n fẹ́ - Àlùfáà Ìjọ","answer":"Ni aipẹ yii lawọn ajinigbe ji awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ akọrin ijọ CAC Odubanjo Regional headquarters to wa lagbegbe Oke Igan, Ẹringboni ilu Akurẹ ti i ṣe olu ilu ipinlẹ Ondo gbe.Ninu ọrọ ti Alufaa ijọ naa, ba BBC News Yoruba sọ, o ni aluduru ijọ wọn lo n ṣe oku obi rẹ kan ti wọn fi lọ.Igba ti wọn n pada bọ lawọn ajinigbe naa dabu wọn lọna ti wọn si ko wọn wọ inu igbo lọ.Alufaa naa ni ọkan lara awọn eeyan to sunmọ ijọ naa lo kọja lagbegbe ti iṣẹlẹ naa ti ṣẹlẹ to si ri ọkọ bọọsi ijọ naa lo wa ta alufaa wọn kan lolobo.O ni agbegbe kan ti wọn n pe ni Ẹlẹgbẹka ni opopona Ọwọ-idoani si Ifọn ni wọn ti ji wọn gbe.Alufaa ijọ naa ni ọkan lara awọn ti wọn ji gbe naa, to si tun jẹ pasitọ ni ijọ naa lo pe to si ni awọn ajinigbe ọhun n beere owo.“Ajinigbe yẹn gba foonu lọwọ rẹ, o sọ fun emi gan pe aadọta miliọnu lawọn fẹ gba bayi bayii. Mo wa ni pe ko mu suuru pe a maa de ọdọ wọn.”Awọn mẹjọ sa asala bọ mọ awọn ajinigbe naa lọwọBakan naa la gbọ pe ninu awọn eeyan ogun ti awọn ajinigbe yii ji gbe, mẹjọ ninu wọn ti moribọ mọ awọn ajinigbe naa lọwọ.Ni bi a ṣe n sọrọ yii, mejila ninu awọn akọrin naa lo wa ni ahamọ awọn ajinigbe ọhun.Alufaa ijọ naa ni awọn mẹjọ naa wa ni agọ ọlọpaa to wa ni ilu Ipele nipinlẹ Ondo kan naa.Ileeṣẹ Ọlọpaa, Alufaa ijọ CAC ṣalaye igbesẹ to n waye lati ṣeto itusilẹ awọn akọrin naaNigba to n ṣalaye lori igbesẹ ti ijọ n gbe lori iṣẹlẹ naa bayii, alufaa ijọ CAC Oke Igan, Ẹringboni ilu Akurẹ naa ṣalaye pe awọn ọmọ ijọ ti wolẹ adura lati igba to ti bẹrẹ.O ni awọn ṣọja, ọlọpaa atawọn amọtẹkun lo ti gbọ si iṣẹlẹ naa ti wọn si ti n gbe igbesẹ.Bakan naa ni Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ni ipinlẹ Ondo, DSP Funmilayọ Ọdunlami, ni awọn ti bẹrẹ igbesẹ kaakiri inu igbo ti wọn ko wọn wọ.O ni awọn fijilante atawọn araalu wa lara awọn to n ṣeto ati ṣe awari awọn ti wọn ji gbe naa.Bakan naa lo fi idaniloju han pe gbogbo awọn to ku ni ahamọ awọn ajinigbe naa ni wọn yoo tu silẹ laipẹ."},{"question":"ディケンズの小説「二都物語」の主人公である弁護士の名前は何でしょう？","answer":"シドニー・カートンです。"},{"question":"Mene Ma’anar Muciya ?","answer":"MUCIYA tana nufin abinda ake tuka towo dashi."},{"question":"Apakah bunga kebangsaan Malaysia?","answer":"Bunga Raya"},{"question":"Apakah faedah buah-buahan tempatan? ","answer":"Buah-buahan tempatan seperti pisang, rambutan, tembikai dan sebagainya sangat berkhasiat kerana dapat membekalkan vitamin dan serat kepada kita. Buah-buahan tempatan ini juga mudah didapati di mana-mana tempat dengan harga yang murah dan berpatutan. Tambahan pula, buah-buahan tempatan sungguh sedap dan segar berbanding buah-buahan import.  Hasil penjualan buah-buahan tempatan ini dapat menjana pendapatan yang lumayan dan boleh meningkatkan sosioekonomi  rakyat di negara kita."},{"question":"أين تقع صخرة آيزر؟","answer":"تقع صخرة آيزر في أستراليا."},{"question":"من أول الأنبياء الذي قال الشعر؟","answer":"– سيدنا آدم عليه السلام."},{"question":"Gwa m nkenke maka steeti Lagos","answer":"Ȯra Lagos (Lagos State) bu state no n'ime Naigeria. Isi ya bu Ikeja. Lagos State bu ala obere na obodo Naigeria, dika Kano State. Lagos, obodo no n'ime ya nwere imerime madu, bu obodo ukwu nke abuo no na Naigeria.Emepụtara ya na 27 Mee 1967. A na-ahọpụta ya dịka steeti nke abụọ kacha nwee mmadụ na Naịjirịa."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи","answer":"Албетте, мына сизге кызыктуу факты: \\"Сага жардам бере аламбы?\\" Тасман деңизинин жээгиндеги Сиднейде жашоо менен эсептешүү үчүн популярдуу жайга айланган тик аска бар.  Анын жанында Дон Ричи жашаган үй бар, ал расмий маалыматтарга ылайык, 160 адамды суицидден сактап калган. Дон жардын жанынан өтүп бара жаткан адамдарды көрүп, өзүн-өзү өлтүрүп алуунун белгилерин байкаса: \\"Мен сизге жардам бере аламбы?\\"-деп сурап,уйуно чайга чакырчу"},{"question":"சுந்தரம்பிள்ளையைப் போற்று முகமாகத் தமிழக அரசு நிறுவியது யாது?(1) பல்கலைக்கழகம்                                        (2) அரசவைக் கவிஞர் பணி(3) அறக்கட்டளை                                                  (4) பேராசிரியர் பணி","answer":"(1) பல்கலைக்கழகம்      "},{"question":"నియమావళి గురించి నీకేమి తెలుసు ? దానిలోని అంశాలను వ్రాయండి. ","answer":"కంపెనీ నమోదు చేసేటప్పుడు రిజిస్ట్రారు వద్ద దాఖలు చేయవలసిన పత్రాలలో రెండవది నియమావళి. కంపెనీ ఆంతరంగిక వ్యవహారములు సమర్థవంతముగా నిర్వహించుటకు కొన్ని నియమాలు, నిబంధనలు అవసరము. ఆ నియమ నిబంధనలు గల పత్రమే నియమావళి. కంపెనీ నియమావళి ఆంతరంగిక వ్యవహారములకు చుక్కాని వంటిది. నిర్వహణాధికారులకు ఈ నియమావళి మార్గదర్శకముగా ఉంటుంది. కంపెనీకి వాటాదారులకు మధ్య గల సంబంధాన్ని ఇది స్పష్టపరుస్తుంది. ఇది డైరెక్టర్లు, నిర్వహణాధికారులు, వాటాదారులు, ఋణపత్రధారులు అధికారాలను విధులను, బాధ్యతలను స్పష్టముగా నిర్వచిస్తుంది.కంపెనీ నియమావళిని వివిధ పేరాలుగా విభజించి, వరుసగా సంఖ్యలు వేసి, ముద్రించవలెను. సంస్థాపనా పత్రము మీద సంతకాలు చేసినవారు నియమావళి మీద సాక్షి సమక్షములో సంతకాలు చేయవలెను.ప్రైవేటు కంపెనీలు, వాటాపరిమిత కంపెనీలు, పూచీ పరిమిత కంపెనీలు, అపరిమిత కంపెనీలు నియమావళిని తప్పని సరిగా తయారు చేసుకొనవలెను. పబ్లిక్ కంపెనీ తన సొంత నియమావళిని తయారుచేసుకోవచ్చు. లేకపోతే కంపెనీల చట్టము షెడ్యూల్ 1లో Table A అనే ఆదర్శ నియమావళి వర్తిస్తుంది.నియమావళిలో ఉండే అంశాలు :వాటా మూలధనము దాని తరగతులు, వాటాల సంఖ్య, వాటాల విలువ, వాటాదారుల హక్కులు, వాటా పిలుపులు.వాటాల బదిలీ, వాటాల జప్తు, తిరిగి జారీచేసే విధానము.డిబెంచర్లు, స్టాకు జారీ.వాటా మూలధనము మార్చుట, మూలధన తగ్గింపు.డైరెక్టర్ల నియామకము, వారి అధికారాలు, బాధ్యతలు, పారితోషికము.మేనేజింగ్ డైరెక్టర్ నియామకము.కంపెనీ సమావేశాలు – తీర్మానాలు.డివిడెండ్లు, రిజర్వులు, లాభాలను మూలధనంగా మార్చుట.ప్రాథమిక ఒప్పందాలు ఆమోదించే తీరు.కంపెనీ అధికార ముద్ర.కంపెనీ లెక్కలు, వాటి తనిఖీ.సభ్యుల ఓటింగ్ పద్దతి.సమావేశానికి కోరం నిర్ణయించుట.బ్యాంకు ఖాతాల నిర్వహణ.కనీసపు చందా.మధ్యవర్తిత్వము.కంపెనీని రద్దు చేసే విధానము."},{"question":"A Inglaterra venceu quantas Copas do Mundo?","answer":"A Inglaterra conquistou 1 Copa do Mundo (1966)."},{"question":"ਵਿਆਹ ਕਿਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਸੰਸਥਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਵਿਆਹ ਇੱਕ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਸਕ੍ਰਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਸੰਸਥਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Viết đoạn văn về năng lực suy nghĩ của con người","answer":"Ngày nay xã hội phát triển ko ngừng. Con người lun phải cập nhật những kiến thức mới nhất. Và cách tiếp thu kiến thức tốt nhất là học. bên cạnh việc học thì chúng ta còn phải kết hợp vs làm bài tập. vậy tại sao phải kết hợp cả 2? khi học thì ta đã tiếp thu thêm 1 phần kiến thức. học càng nhiều thì lượng kiến thức càng lớn. làm sao có thể ghi nhớ hết tất cả kiến thức đó? học mà cho có câu có chữ thì chỉ là học suông, ko có thực chất. giả sử những môn như toán, lý, hóa,... , nếu như chỉ học lí thuyết mà ko làm bài tập thì liệu ta có thể hình dung được cách làm bài hay ứng dụng những j đã học vào đời sống thực tế hay ko?khi chúng ta tập trung suy nghĩ chúng ta có thể tìm ra những cách giải quyết mới. nếu ko làm bài tập thì sau 1 thời gian bạn sẽ quên đi những kiến thức đã học vì bạn ko rèn luyện nó và ko hoàn thiện nó. chúng ta cũng có thể đặt vấn đề ngược lại. nếu như chỉ chú trọng việc làm bài tập thì liệu bạn có thể làm tốt chúng khi ko học lí thuyết? ko học lí thuyết thì làm sao có kiến thức để mà làm bài tập. thực tế đã cho ta thấy điều đó! có 1 số bạn hs ko rèn luyện những kiến thức thu thập được bẳng cách làm bài tập. sau một thời gian thì những kiến thức đó dần dần mất đi. còn những bạn hs rèn luyện và ôn lại kiến thức đó thì sẽ làm bài tốt hơn, nhuần nhuyễn hơn. qua đó ta càng thấy việc học và làm bài tập có mối quan hệ chặt chẽ vs nhau. Càng suy nghĩ sẽ càng làm bạn thông minh hơn "},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Tsy basy mipoaka, tsy tafondro mirefotra nefa feno ra Madagasikara.\\"","answer":"Valiny : RA amin'ny anarana. Satria ny anarana Malagasy ny ankamarony miantomboka amin'ny ra daholo."},{"question":"WAKAMarubucin ‘Waƙar Zambon ƙazama’ ta zaɓaɓɓun Waƙoƙin Da Da Na Yanzu na D. Abdulkadir ya nuna cewa mata ƙazamai suna nuna ƙazantarsu taA)jiki da abinciB)gida da abinciC)jiki gida da abinciD)jiki gida da waje","answer":"C.Bayani:Kamar yadda ya zo a bauti na 10 zababbun wakokin Da doone yanRan girkinki ba akoshi do jibi, Shi namom miji ki cinye a tsame."},{"question":"Describe the function of a neuron.","answer":"A neuron is a nerve cell responsible for transmitting electrical and chemical signals throughout the body, facilitating communication between the brain and other body parts."},{"question":"Qeex xayawanka Sagaarada?","answer":"Sagaaradu waa habar dugaaga kamid ah ugaarta duurjoogta ah?"},{"question":"Ireto misy fehezanteny roa:-Fehezanteny voalohany: Mainty sy fotsy ny saka an'i Julie.-Fehezanteny faharoa: Ny saka an'i Julie dia volondavenona avokoa. Mifanaraka ve ireo fehezanteny roa ireo?","answer":" Tsia, mifanohitra izy ireo."},{"question":"Kaşe-imza ıslak imza yerine geçer mi?","answer":"KAŞE İMZA ISLAK İMZA OLMADIĞINDAN GEÇERSİZDİR."},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri kanun labarai dan wannan labari mai zuwa:Baya ga Abuja, babban birnin tarayya, jihohin Kaduna da Bauchi ne kan gaba a yawan masu fama da cutar coronavirus a yankin arewa, ko da yake, Katsina wadda aka fara sanar da bullar annobar ranar Talata 7 ga wata, tana kokarin kamo su. Yanzu dai akwai mutum biyar da aka tabbatar sun kamu, bayan sake samun mutum 1 mai fama da cutar a ranar Lahadi. Gwamnatin jihar Katsina dai ta shelanta kulle Daura, mahaifar shugaban kasar, inda aka samu mutum na farko da ya kamu da cutar. Sai dai babu jimawa kuma sai aka ji annobar ta bulla karon farko cikin Kano, jiha mafi yawan jama'a a Najeriya kuma cibiyar hada-hadar kasuwanci don haka ne ma ake da damuwa sosai game da al'amarinta. Gwamna Abdullahi Umar Ganduje ya ce yana duba yiwuwar rufe wasu kasuwanni kuma zai yi ganawa da malaman Kano don sanin yadda za su bullowa lamarin taruka irin na Sallar Juma'a da haduwar ibada a coci-coci. Jimillar mutanen da suka kamu da cutar koronabairas a daukacin yankin sun kai 80 zuwa ranar Lahadi, a cewar hukumar dakile cutuka masu yaduwa ta Najeriya. Abuja ce ke da mafi yawam mutanen da ke fama da annobar a yankin, an fara samun bullar wannan cuta a babban birnin ranar 20 ga watan Maris, bayan gwajin da aka yi wa Mohammed Atiku. Ga alama har yanzu d'an na Atiku Abubakar, jigon dan siyasa a Najeriya yana ci gaba da jinya a cibiyar kebe marasa lafiya ta Gwagwalada a Abuja. Wasu sun rika yaba wa jarumtarsa ta fitowa ya yi wannan bayani, wasu kuma sun rika zargin dan Atikun da rashin kebe kansa bayan ya dawo daga wata tafiya kasashen waje. A ranar Litinin 23 ga watan Maris ne Hukumar dakile cutuka masu yaduwa ta ba da sanarwar samun mutum na farko da ya rasu sakamakon wannan annoba a Najeriya, lamarin da ya faru a Abuja. Hukumar NCDC ta ce mutumin dan shekara 67 ya dawo gida Najeriya ne bayan ya je ganin likita kasar Burtaniya, a cewarta mamacin (Injinya Sulaiman A-ci-mugu) ya yi fama da wadansu kwantattun cutuka kafin rasuwarsa. A ranar 7 ga watan Afrilu kuma, Gwamna Masari na jihar Katsina ya sanar cewa Allah Ya yi wa mutum na farko da ya kamu da coronavirus a jiharsa, Dr Aliyu Yakubu rasuwa. Ya ce likitan wanda ke garin Daura, an ba da rahoton ya yi tafiya zuwa Lagos, kuma bai dade da komawa gida ba, sai ya kamu da rashin lafiya inda ya kai kansa asibitin rundunar sojan sama na Daura kafin cikawarsa. Wasu na kuka wasu na dariya Akasarin manyan mutanen da cutar ta harba da farko-farko sun fito ne daga jihohin arewa, inda a ranar Talata 24 ga watan Maris, hukumar NCDC ta sake fitar da bayanin cewa an samu mutum biyu da cutar ta harba a yankin, kuma karon farko cutar ta bulla a wata jiha, baya ga Abuja. Gwamna Bala Mohammed na jihar Bauchi shi ne jagoran wata jiha da covid-19 ta fara kamawa a Najeriya, ko da yake a yanzu ya warke har ma ya ci gaba da harkokinsa. Sai dai ya zuwa ranar Lahadi, akwai mutum biyar a jihar ta Bauchi da ke ci gaba da jinya sakamakon wannan annoba, ban da Gwamna Bala Mohammed da ya warke. Haka shi ma, Mallam Abba Kyari shugaban ma'aikatan fadar shugaban Najeriya yana can yana ci gaba da jinya a jihar Legas, bayan an ba da rahoton kamuwarsa ranar 24 ga watan Maris. Fitattun mutane irinsu Atiku Abubakar sun jajanta masa lokacin da rade-radin ya cika gari cewa annobar ta shafe shi bayan wata tafiya da ya yi zuwa kasar Jamus. Haka kuma har yanzu babu wani rahoto da ke nuna cewa Malam Nasir El-Rufa'i, mutum na farko da ya kamu da cutar a jihar Kaduna ranar Asabar 28 ga watan Maris, ya samu sauki. Yana cikin gwamnonin da suka fi zafafa daukar matakai don ganin annobar ba ta riski al'ummarsu ba. El-Rufa'i dai ya dauki matakin kulle jiharsa ba shiga ba fita, tare da hana tarukan biki da na ibada ciki har da Sallar Juma'a da ibadu a coci-coci da masallatai. Zuwa yanzu, akwai mutum shida da ke fama da cutar a jihar ta Kaduna, kuma daga bayanan hukumomi, ba a samu rasuwa sakamakon wannan annoba a jihar ba, kamar kuma yadda ba a samu wanda ya warke ba. Mutum na baya-bayan nan da ya kamu da cutar, namiji da ke aikin gadi a unguwar Mando, bayanai sun ce an gano yana fama da corona ne bayan ya dawo daga tafiyar da ya yi zuwa jihar Legas, wadda ta fi yawan masu cutar a fadin Najeriya. Binuwai ita ce jiha ta farko da wannan cuta ta fara bulla a yankin Arewa ta Tsakiya, inda hukumar NCDC ta ce zuwa ranar Asabar 28 ga watan Maris, adadin masu cutar a daukacin Najeriya ya kai 97. Baya ga Binuwai cutar ta shiga jihar Kwara ranar 6 ga watan Afrilu, inda aka sanar da kamuwar mutum biyu. Ran 09 ga watan Afrilu, an ba da sanarwar mutum na farko da annobar ta harba a cikin jihar Neja. Tabawa ranar samu Laraba 1 ga watan Afrilu a iya cewa tana cikin ranaku da aka fi samun mutanen da aka tabbatar sun sake kamuwa da annobar mafi yawa a arewacin Najeriya, inda adadin ya karu zuwa mutum 43. Hukumar dakile cutuka ta ce an samu karin mutum bakwai da cutar ta shafa a Abuja, sai mutum 1 a jihar Kaduna da kuma karin wani a Bauchi. Bayan sanar da kamuwar karin mutum uku a jihohin Kwara da Katsina a ranar Lahadi 12 ga Afrilu, adadin masu fama da cutar a daukacin yankin yanzu ya kai 80. Nesa ta zo kusa Sai dai wani karin ci gaba da aka samu a baya-bayan nan a yankin arewacin Najeriya shi ne bude sabbin cibiyoyin gwada cutar kovid-19. Hukumar dakile cutuka masu yaduwa ta fada a ranar Asabar 11 ga wata cewa an yi nasarar bude cibiyoyin gwaji guda biyu a jihohin Kano da Filato. Karon farko ke nan da aka samu irin wadannan cibiyoyin gwajin cutuka irinsu coronavirus a daukacin yankin arewa. Kafin yanzu sai dai a dauki samfur a kai shi zuwa Abuja ko Legas don tantancewa. Hukumar ta kuma ce aiki na ci gaba da gudana don ganin an samu irin wadannan cibiyoyin gwaje-gwaje a biranen Maiduguri da Sokoto da kuma Kaduna. Mutane nawa ne suka warke a arewa? A ranar Alhamis, 9 ga wata, jami'an gwamnatin Bauchi, sun fitar da sanarwar cewa Gwamna Bala Mohammed ya warke har ma an sallame shi daga wurin da aka kebe shi. Haka zalika, a ranar Lahadi 12 ga Afrilu, an ga bayanin da wani mashawarcin shugaban Najeriya kan harkar shafukan sada zumunta, Bashir Ahmad ya fitar da ke cewa an sallami karin mutum hudu bayan warkewarsu daga cibiyar Gwagwalada. Duka-duka dai zuwa yanzu alkaluman hukumar NCDC na cewa mutum 85 ne suka warke a daukacin Najeriya. Zuwa yanzu akwai tabbacin annobar ta bulla a jihohin da suka hadar da Babban Birnin Tarayya - 56 Bauchi - 6 Kaduna - 6 Binuwai - 1 Kwara - 4 Katsina - 5 Neja - 1 Kano - 1","answer":"Tabbas, ga kanun labarai don rubutun da aka bayar - Coronavirus: Ina annobar ta kai a arewacin Najeriya"},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இளைஞர்களின் சகவாசத்தாலேயே எனது உணர்ச்சி முதுமையை அடையவில்லை."},{"question":"काठमाडौं उपत्यकामा सांस्कृतिक एकता र साम्प्रदायिक सद्भाव प्रवर्द्धन गर्न मध्ययुगीन नेवार पर्वहरूको भूमिका व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"मध्यकालीन नेवार चाडहरू काठमाडौं उपत्यकामा सांस्कृतिक एकता र साम्प्रदायिक सद्भाव प्रवर्द्धन गर्न, विविध समुदायहरू बीच साझा पहिचान र परम्पराको भावनालाई बढावा दिन महत्त्वपूर्ण थिए।"},{"question":"如何防止自己被PUA？","answer":"答：防止自己被PUA，首先要提高自己的警惕性，学习和了解PUA的常见手法。其次，要建立自信和自尊，不轻易受他人影响。最后，要保护好自己的个人信息，避免被他人利用。"},{"question":"Ayu-bés/yi","answer":"week/s\\t"},{"question":"ለሚከተለው ጥያቄ መልስ ስጥ። ቀስተ ደመና ውስጥ ስንት ቀለሞች አሉ?","answer":"ሰባት ቀለሞች አሉ::"},{"question":"ṣé wọ́n máa ń sọ èdè Faransé ní Quebec?","answer":"Bẹẹni."},{"question":"مون کي هن درجي ۾ trivia جو هڪ مثال ڏيو: وڊيو گيمز","answer":"ڪهڙي سيريز ۾ وڌيڪ رانديون آهن، غالب ۽ جادو يا بادشاهه جي ڳولا؟ طاقت ۽ جادو"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي سور القرآن الكريم التي بدأت بلفظ الحمد في أول آياتها؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة الفاتحة والأنعام والكهف وسبأ وفاطر."},{"question":"O que significa o ditado popular: \\"Quem parte e reparte e não fica com a melhor parte ou é tolo ou não sabe da arte\\"?","answer":"Esta expressão é usada quando alguém é tolo caso não fique com a melhor parte ao distribuir algo, seja comida ou atividade exercida.Exemplo: “Já que ninguém se dispôs, eu dividi o trabalho e fiquei com a conclusão. Quem reparte e não fica com a melhor parte, ou é tolo ou não sabe da arte…”"},{"question":"Hal talo oo qoraalka lagu wanaajiyo.","answer":"Hal talo oo qoraalka lagu wanaajiyo.• Ha kala duwanaadaan weedhahaaga qaabdhismeedkooda iyo dherarkoodu.Haddaad mar kasta ku bilowdo weedho isku mid ah iyo weedho dherarkoodu isku mid yahey; waxaa hubaala in akhristayaashaada ku keenayso caajis weyn.Ku tuur marmar weedho gaaban! Tani, waxa ay keenaysaa in akhristaha dareenkiisu joogo; fariinta aad gudbineysaana u muuqan meyso mid dheer. Mid kaken oo kadeed ah, lana fahmeyn micnaha ay u taagan tahey!"},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase: Christian Langeweg foi um jogador de xadrez dos Países Baixos com diversas participações nas Olimpíadas de xadrez. Langeweg participou de todas as edições de 1960 a 1970 e as edições de 1978 e 1980. Conquistou a medalha de ouro em 1966 no quarto tabuleiro, prata em","answer":"1980, novamente no quarto tabuleiro, e bronze em 1970 no terceiro tabuleiro."},{"question":"ደአማት የተባለው መንግስት የተቋቋመው በየት አካባቢ ነበር?","answer":"አሁን ያለው ሰሜን ኢትዮጵያና ኤርትራ።"},{"question":"Miwani","answer":"Miwani ni kifaa amabacho huvaliwa machoni ili kumuwezesha mtu mwenye matatizo ya macho kuweza kuona. baadhi ya watu hutumia miwani kama urembo, kuzuia vumbi machoni au kuzuia mwanga wa jua. "},{"question":"Cite um exemplo de pergunta para a categoria: Geografia","answer":"Quais são os Grandes Lagos da América do Norte?"},{"question":"Dime cuál es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Cuál novela de Stephen King no ocurre en Maine?","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es la ubicación geográfica en las novelas de Stephen King, específicamente, la pregunta busca identificar cuál de sus novelas no tiene lugar en el estado de Maine, la cual corresponde al libro \\"El resplandor\\" (The Shining)."},{"question":"صنبور: ماء. لديهما علاقة معينة. اختر كلمتين لهما علاقة مشابهة:(أ) جرح: دم(ب) منطاد: هواء(ج) سكينة: قطع(د) منفاخ: بالون","answer":"الإجابة (أ) كما الماء يخرج من الصنبور، يخرج الدم من الجروح."},{"question":"Dama soxla layalkay.","answer":"I need a lawyer.\\t"},{"question":"కింది వాక్యముని ఆధునిక వ్యవహార శైలిలోకి మార్చండి. (ఈ మార్పులు చేసేటప్పుడు “ము” వర్ణాలు, బిందు పూర్వక ‘బు’ కారాలు, అంబు) యడాగమాలు, క్రియా స్వరూపాలు (చేయును, జరుగును, చూడుము వంటివి మారతాయి. గమనించండి.)కొందరు పన్యాముల మూలమున నాపని చేయుదురు. ","answer":"కొంతమంది ఉపన్యాసాల ద్వారా, ఆ పని చేస్తారు. "},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para este parágrafo - Em 2008, Jo Cox trabalhou na campanha eleitoral","answer":"do então senador Barack Obama à presidência dos Estados Unidos."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn tun paayan marundinlogoji ni Jos","answer":"Ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an alẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, ni awọn agbebọn tun kọ lu awọn eeyan abule Yelwan Zangam, nitosi Fasiti Jos, ti wọn si pa eeyan marundinlogoji nipakukpa.Niṣe ni awọn agbebọn naa bẹrẹ si i yinbọn leralera mọ gbogbo awọn ara abule naa ti wọn n sa asala fun ẹmi wọn nigba ti wọn ya bo ibẹ. Bẹẹ ni wọn tun dana sun awọn to wa ninu ile mọbẹ. Nigba ti oloju yoo si fi ṣẹ ẹ, eeyan marundinlogoji lo ti ba iṣẹlẹ naa lọ.ALAROYE gbọ pe ki awọn agbebọn naa too wọ abule ọhun ni wọn ti kọkọ ba biriiji to wọ ibẹ jẹ, ki awọn abule to tun  wa nitosi abule naa ma le raaye waa sọ pe awọn fẹẹ gba wọn silẹ.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe wahala to ti n waye niluu naa, paapaa ju lọ ni ijọba ibilẹ Bassa ti mu ki wọn kede konilegbele ni agbegbe Ila Oorun ati Guusu agbegbe naa, ṣugbọn eyi ko di awọn eeyan naa lọwọ, wọn tun ya wọn abule yii, wọn si fọpọ ẹmi eeyan ṣofo."},{"question":"Yek'usazigqaja,Uhamba laph'uthanda khona.Utetemuk'uchiz'ukotshi.Yek'ugqigqizel'ugqagqamuka,Ugqamuka kuhle kwamalangabi,Uhambela phezul'uzithwele,Wadilika kuhle kobondaBaph'owawungumshungu nabo?Nibakhulu nakunoMdali,Ngab'ukhon'ongangaye?Namuhla ulothil'uluphele,Uthithibel'okwenkukhu,Uyothile wayetha,Wathobel'umthetho.Wawungaz'ukuthi koba nje,Namuhla usothulini,Ulothisiwe wathotshiswa.Ufunde kanzima,Wafunda ngokubona,Yeka usagqagqamuka uzigqaja.1. Chaza kafushane ukuthi imbongi yayikusiphi isimo ngenkathi ibhala lenkondlo. ","answer":"Yayicasukile/Yayicikekile ngoba iyamazi lo muntu esahambela phezuluengabazi abantu kodwa manje akasenalutho useyinto edabukisayo."},{"question":"Kumuu ahaa qaadimkii Nabi Muuse C.S?","answer":"Wuxuu ahaa Yuushac."},{"question":"이 단락에 이어질 말을 완성시키시오. - 셰리 플레처는 2008년 올림픽 여자 100m 스프린트에서 그레나다 출신의 유일한 참가자였다.","answer":"이벤트 그녀는 8 월 15 일 예선 경기에서 미국 최종 우승자 로린 윌리엄스 등 7 명의 경쟁자를 상대로 두 번째 열에 참가했다. 플레처는 11.65초로 대회를 마쳤고, 5위를 차지했다. 그녀는 프랑스 출신의 크리스틴 아론보다 0.28초 느리게 대회를 마쳤다. 전체적으로 플레처는 예선 라운드에서 랭크된 85명의 선수 중 40위를 차지했으며, 영국 출신의 러너 로라 터너와 베트남 출신의 러너 티 <unk> 우와 동률을 이뤘다. 예선 라운드에서 1위를 차지한 나이지리아의 다모라 오사요미 (Damola Osayomi) 는 추가 라운드에 진출하지 못한 플레처보다 0.52초 더 빠르다."},{"question":"கேள்வி: பதினெண் கீழ்க்கணக்கு நூல்கள் பற்றி விவரி .","answer":"விடை:தமிழகத்தில் சங்கம் மருவிய காலத்தில் இயற்றப்பட்ட 18 நூல்களைச் சேர்த்து பதினெண் கீழ்க்கணக்கு நூல்கள் என வழங்கப்படுகின்றன. இவை ஒவ்வொன்றும் தனித்தனியான வெவ்வேறு புலவர்களால் பாடப்பட்டவை.நூல்வகைகள்பதினெண்கீழ்க்கணக்கு நூல்கள் குறித்த வாய்பாட்டுப் பாடல்:\\"நாலடி நான்மணி நானாற்ப தைந்திணைமுப்பால்கடுகம் கோவை பழமொழி மாமூலம்இன்னிலைய காஞ்சியோ டேலாதி என்பவேகைந்நிலைய வாம்கீழ்க் கணக்கு.\\"இந்தப் பாடல் குறிப்பிடும் நூல்கள்நாலடியார்நான்மணிக்கடிகைஇன்னா நாற்பது (நானாற்பதில் ஒன்று)இனியவை நாற்பது (நானாற்பதில் ஒன்று)கார் நாற்பது (நானாற்பதில் ஒன்று)களவழி நாற்பது (நானாற்பதில் ஒன்று)ஐந்திணை ஐம்பது (ஐந்திணை தொகுப்பில் ஒன்று)ஐந்திணை எழுபது (ஐந்திணை தொகுப்பில் ஒன்று)திணைமொழி ஐம்பது (ஐந்திணை தொகுப்பில் ஒன்று)திணைமாலை நூற்றைம்பது (ஐந்திணை தொகுப்பில் ஒன்று)முப்பால் (திருக்குறள்)திரிகடுகம்ஆசாரக் கோவைபழமொழி நானூறுசிறுபஞ்சமூலம்கைந்நிலைமுதுமொழிக் காஞ்சிஏலாதிஇந்தப் பாடலில் கைந்நிலை என்பது ஒழுக்கத்தைக் குறிக்கும்.வாய்ப்பாட்டுப் பாடலில் பாட வேறுபாடுநாலடி நான்மணி நானாற்ப தைந்திணைமுப்பால்கடுகம் கோவை பழமொழி மாமூலம்இன்னிலைய காஞ்சியுட னேலாதி யென்பதூஉம்,கைந்நிலையு மாங்கீழ்க் கணக்குஇந்தப் பாடலில் இனிய நிலையை உடைய காஞ்சி என்று அடைமொழியாகக் கொள்ளப்பட்டுக் கைந்நிலை என்பது தனி நூலாகக் கொள்ளப்படும்.இன்னிலை, கைந்நிலை, நூல்களில் எது பதினெண்கீழ்க்கணக்கு தொகுப்பில் சேரவேண்டும்இன்னிலை அறம், பொருள், இன்பம், வீடு என்னும் நாற்பொருள் மேல் 45 வெண்பாப் பாடல்களைக் கொண்ட நூல். இதன் ஆசிரியர் பொய்கையார். \\"இன்னிலை\\" நூலைத் திரு.வ.உ.சிதம்பரம் பிள்ளை அவர்கள் அச்சிற் பதிப்பித்தார்.\\"கைந்நிலை\\" என்ற நூலை இயற்றியவர் மாறோக்கத்து முள்ளிநாட்டு நல்லூர்க் காவிதியார் மகனார் புல்லங்காடனார். இதனை ஆசிரியர் திரு. அனந்தராமையர் அவர்கள் அச்சில் பதிப்பித்தார். இதில் குறிஞ்சி, முல்லை, மருதம், நெய்தல், பாலை என்னும் ஐந்திணை மேல் பாடப்பட்ட 60 பாடல்கள் உள்ளன.பகுப்புஇன்னிலை சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ள நிலையில் இத்தொகுதியில் அடங்கியுள்ள நூல்களுள் பெரும்பாலானவை நீதி நூல்களாகும். பதினொன்று நூல்கள் இவ்வகையைச் சார்ந்தவை. ஆறு நூல்கள் அகத்திணை சார்பானவை. ஒன்று புறத்திணை நூல். இந் நூல்கள் அனைத்தும் சிறு பாடல்களால் ஆனவை. கூடிய அளவாக நான்கு அடிகளை மட்டுமே கொண்டவை.நீதி நூல்கள்நாலடியார்நான்மணிக்கடிகைஇன்னா நாற்பதுஇனியவை நாற்பதுதிருக்குறள்திரிகடுகம்ஏலாதிபழமொழி நானூறுஆசாரக்கோவைசிறுபஞ்சமூலம்முதுமொழிக்காஞ்சிஅகத்திணை நூல்கள்ஐந்திணை ஐம்பதுதிணைமொழி ஐம்பதுஐந்திணை எழுபதுதிணைமாலை நூற்றைம்பதுகார் நாற்பதுகைந்நிலைபுறத்திணை நூல்களவழி நாற்பது"},{"question":"Mark Zuckerberg ","answer":"Mark Elliot Zuckerberg tí wọ́n bí ní May 14, 1984 jẹ́ ọlọ́pọ̀lọpọ̀ okòwò ilẹ̀ Amẹ́ríkà, onímọ̀ ẹ̀rọ kọ̀m̀pútà, oníṣòwò ayélujára, àti olùrànlọ́wọ́. Ó dá iṣẹ́ ìtàkùn ayélujára Facebook àti ilé-iṣẹ́ òbí rẹ̀ Meta Platforms sílẹ̀ (tẹ́lẹ̀ Facebook, Inc.), èyí tí ó jẹ́ alága àgbà, olórí aláṣẹ àti olùpín ìṣàkóso.Zuckerberg lọ sí Ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga Harvard University, níbi tí ó ti ṣe ìfilọ́lẹ̀ Facebook ní oṣù Kínní ọdún 2004 pẹ̀lú àwọn akẹgbẹ́ rẹ̀ Eduardo Saverin, Andrew McCollum, Dustin Moskovitz àti Chris Hughes. Wọ́n kọ́kọ́ ṣe ìfilọ́lẹ̀ rẹ̀ ní àwọn ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ kọ́lẹ́ẹ̀jì tí wọ́n yàn nìkan, ojú òpó náà fẹ̀ ní kíákíá àti nígbẹ̀yìn kọjá àwọn kọ́lẹ́ẹ̀jì, ó dé bílíọ̀nù kan àwọn aṣàmúlò ní ọdún 2012. Zuckerberg mú ilé-iṣẹ́ náà jáde ní gbangba ní oṣù karùn-ún ọdún 2012 pẹ̀lú ìpín tó pọ̀. Ní ọdún 2007, ní ọmọ ọdún 23, ó di olówó bílíọ̀nù tí ó kéré jùlọ lágbàáyé. Ó ti lo owó rẹ̀ láti ṣètò ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ìgbìyànjú ìrànlọ́wọ́, pẹ̀lú ìdásílẹ̀ Chan Zuckerberg Ìpilẹ̀ṣẹ̀.Zuckerberg ti ṣe atokọ bi ọkan ninu awọn eniyan ti o ni ipa julọ ni agbaye ni awọn igba mẹrin ni 2008, 2011, 2016 ati 2019 lẹsẹsẹ ati yan bi ipari ni 2009, 2012, 2014, 2015, 2017, 2018, 2020, 2021 ati 2022. Ìwé ìròyìn Time pè é ní Person of the Year ní ọdún 2010, ní ọdún kan náà nígbà tí Facebook kọjá àwọn aṣàmúlò tó lé ní ìdajì bílíọ́nù. Ní oṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2016, Zuckerberg wà ní ipò kẹwàá lórí àtòjọ Forbes ti The World's Most Powerful People. Nínú àtòjọ Forbes 400 ti àwọn ọlọ́rọ̀ jùlọ ní orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà ní ọdún 2023, ó wà ní ipò 8 pẹ̀lú ọrọ̀ 106.0 bilionu. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí Oṣù Kẹwàá ọdún 2023, Forbes ṣe ìṣirò iye owó Zuckerberg ní 112.0 bilionu, tí ó sọ ọ́ di ẹni kẹsàn-án tí ó lówó jùlọ ní àgbáyé.Fíìmù kan tí ó ń ṣàfihàn iṣẹ́ ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ Zuckerberg, àwọn ìṣòro òfin àti àṣeyọrí àkọ́kọ́ pẹ̀lú ojú òpó náà, The Social Network, ni wọ́n gbé jáde ní ọdún 2010 ó sì gba ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ Academy Awards.Òkìkí Zuckerberg àti ìdàgbàsókè kíákíá nínú ilé-iṣẹ́ ìmọ̀-ẹ̀rọ ti fa àkíyèsí òṣèlú àti òfin. Ìdásílẹ̀ Facebook ní í ṣe pẹ̀lú Zuckerberg nínú ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ẹjọ́ nípa ìṣẹ̀dá àti ìní ojú òpó wẹ́ẹ̀bù àti àwọn ọ̀rọ̀ ìkọ̀kọ̀ aṣàmúlò. Ní ọdún 2013, ó dá ẹgbẹ́ alátìlẹ́yìn fún àwọn aṣíkiri sílẹ̀ FWD.us. Ni Oṣu Kẹrin Ọjọ 10 ati 11, 2018, Zuckerberg jẹri niwaju Igbimọ Aṣofin Amẹrika lori Iṣowo, Imọ-jinlẹ, ati Gbigbe nipa lilo data ti ara ẹni nipasẹ Facebook ni ibatan si irufin data Facebook-Cambridge Analytica."},{"question":"Iza no anaran'ny mpanamboatra fiara japoney izay mamokatra modely malaza toy ny Civic, Accord ary CR-V?","answer":"Ny anaran'ny mpanamboatra fiara japoney mamokatra modely malaza toy ny Civic, Accord ary CR-V dia Honda."},{"question":"الجملة الأولى: تعمل بريور في مجال التواصل الإبداعي والتعاوني الاجتمعي وتستخدم رؤيتها لتشجيع الآخرين في العملية الفنية. الجملة الثانية: تعمل (بروير) في مجال التوعية الاجتمعية الفنية ، باستخدام رؤيتها لتشجيع الآخرين في عملية الإبداع والتعاون. السؤال: هل تعبر الجملة الأولى والجملة الثانية عن نفس المعنى؟ (نعم أم لا)","answer":"لا"},{"question":"Haz una carta para un aumento salarial por haber cumplido los objetivos","answer":"[Fecha de hoy]RemitenteDestinatarioSeñor,Respetuosamente me dirijo a usted, para solicitarle el aumento salarial correspondiente al acuerdo pactado previamente entre la empresa [NOMBRE_EMPRESA] y yo. Este acuerdo quedo debidamente plasmado en el contrato que firmamos el día [FECHA_CONTRATO,] en el cual se dejaba claro que una vez se cumplieran ciertos objetivos, la empresa procedería a aumentar mi salario en “porcentaje o valor del aumento” de lo que devengo actualmente.Espero que, con la seriedad que los distingue y teniendo en sus manos el justificante de los objetivos cumplidos, se lleve a cabo el correspondiente aumento de mi salario y podamos seguir trabajando juntos por el bienestar de la empresa.Atentamente,Firma[Tu Nombre] "},{"question":"Menene sura mafi tsawo a cikin Alqur'ani?","answer":"Surar Al-Baqara wato surar saniya."},{"question":"පැමිණිල්ල යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"පැමිණිල්ල යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය විත්තිය වේ. "},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: യോഗാസനങ്ങളുടെയും ശ്വസന വ്യായാമങ്ങളുടെയും പരമ്പരാഗത ഇന്ത്യൻ കല ഏതാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: യോഗാസനങ്ങളുടെയും ശ്വസന വ്യായാമങ്ങളുടെയും പരമ്പരാഗത ഇന്ത്യൻ കലയാണ് ഹഠയോഗ. പ്രാചീന ഭാരതത്തിലെ ഒരു പ്രധാന ദർശനമാണ്‌ യോഗം. ചിത്തവൃത്തികളെ അടക്കി നിർത്തുക എന്നതാണ്‌ യോഗം. പ്രാചീന ഭാരതീയ തത്ത്വചിന്തകനായ പതഞ്ജലി യാണ്‌ യോഗസൂത്രം എന്ന ആധികാരിക ഗ്രന്ഥത്തിന്റെ കർത്താവ്. ഷഡ് ദർശനങ്ങൾ എന്ന് വിളിക്കുന്ന ആറ് പ്രാചീന ഭാരതീയ തത്ത്വചിന്തകളിൽ ഒന്നാണിത്. സാംഖ്യത്തോട് പലതരത്തിലും സാമ്യം പുലർത്തുന്ന ഒരു ദർശനമാണിത്. സിന്ധു നദീതട സംസ്കാരം നിലനിന്നിരുന്ന കാലത്തും യോഗ അഭ്യസിച്ചിരുന്നു എന്ന് സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്ന തെളിവുകൾ ഉണ്ട്. ഇന്ന് പാശ്ചാത്യലോകത്ത് യോഗ എന്ന പേരിൽ അറിയപ്പെടുന്നത് ഈ സിദ്ധാന്തത്തിന്റെ ആധുനിക രൂപമാണ്‌. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'gulai terlampau serai maung rasanya'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perbuatan (perkataan) yang terlampau akhirnya akan menjadi sia-sia"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da Roménia?","answer":"0,821."},{"question":"Wie lautet der Vorname von Kahn?","answer":"Es gibt mehrere bekannte Persönlichkeiten, die hier gemeint sein könnten. Eine Möglichkeit wäre Oliver Kahn, vormaliger Fußball-Profi und langjähriger Nationaltorhüter."},{"question":" Em qual filme, a protagonista é humilhada com um balde de sangue derrubado sobre sua cabeça durante o baile da escola?","answer":"A atriz Fernanda Montenegro, em 1999, por sua atuação no filme "},{"question":"Nitori awọn adigunjale to wọle, ọlọpaa ti mu awọn oṣiṣẹ kan nile MKO Abiọla","answer":"Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, Hakeem Odumosu, ti kede pe iwadii nla n lọ lori ọrọ awọn adigunjale kan ti wọn wọ ile oloogbe Moshood Kaṣimawo Abiọla loru mọju ana, ti wọn si ko awọn nnka olowo iyebiye lọ. Ọga ọlọpaa yii pata funra rẹ lo lọ sile awọn Abiọla lati foju ara rẹ ri ohun to ṣẹle nibẹ gan-an.Nibẹ ni wọn ti ṣalaye fun un pe ọna inu irà kànáà kan to wa lẹyin ile awọn Abiọla lawọn adigunjale naa ba wọle, nitori niṣe ni wọn da ogiri fẹnsi lu, ti wọn si faya fa bii ejo wọ inu ile wọn. Nigba ti awọn kan wọ inu ile, awọn mi-in duro sita lati maa ṣọna fun wọn. Awọn mẹta ni wọn wọle, ẹni kan naa lo si mu ibọn dani ninu wọn.Odumosu ni, bi iku ile ko pani, tode ko le paayan, o ṣee ṣe ki ọrọ naa ni ọwọ awọn araale ninu. Boya ni ko jẹ eyi ni wọn fi ko awọn bii mẹta kan ninu awọn ọṣiṣẹ ile Abiọla yii, ti wọn ni wọn fura si wọn pe irin wọn ko mọ, wọn yoo tori ẹ fọrọ wa wọn lẹnu wo, ki wọn le mọ bi wọn mọ nipa iṣẹlẹ naa tabi wọn ko mọ.Tundun, Ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ Abiọla, sọ pe nigba tawọn ole naa de, gbogbo ile ni wọn bẹre si i tu, ti wọn n wa oriṣiriṣi nnkan ti wọn le ji lọ. Nigbẹyin, awọn ole naa ko awọn ohun-ini bii goollu olowo nla ati ọpọlọpọ owo rẹpẹtẹ lọ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe wọn ko ṣe ẹnikẹni leṣe."},{"question":"Ilan ang 9 sa pagitan ng 1 at 100?","answer":"20"},{"question":"नेपाल राष्ट्र बैंकको उद्देश्य के हो ?","answer":"नयाँ नेपाल राष्ट्र बैंक ऐन, 2058 (2002) द्वारा बैंकको कार्य र उद्देश्यहरू पुन: परिभाषित गरिएको छ, जसले बैंकको उद्देश्यहरू निम्नानुसार राख्दछ:   * आर्थिक स्थायित्व र अर्थतन्त्रको दिगो विकासका लागि मूल्य र भुक्तानी सन्तुलनको स्थायित्व कायम गर्न आवश्यक मौद्रिक तथा विदेशी विनिमय नीति तर्जुमा गरी व्यवस्थापन गर्ने,   * बैंकिङ तथा वित्तीय क्षेत्रको स्थायित्व कायम गरी वित्तीय सेवाको पहुँच अभिवृद्धि गरी बैंकिङ तथा वित्तीय प्रणालीप्रति जनताको विश्वास अभिवृद्धि गर्ने,    * सुरक्षित, स्वस्थ र प्रभावकारी भुक्तानी प्रणाली विकास गर्ने,"},{"question":"ما فئة هذا السؤال : من الذي ترشح للرئاسة في 2012، وتخرج من جامعة بريجام يانج؟.","answer":" فئة هذا السؤال هي : السياسة"},{"question":"Rabe-Raben Jimla guda nawa ne?","answer":"Masana Harshen Hausa sun rarraba jimloli zuwa rabe-rabe da dama gwargwadon fahimta. A wannan rubutun za mu taƙaitu da guda uku kamar haka:Sassauƙar Jimla.Sarƙaƙƙiyar Jimla.Harɗaɗɗiyar Jimla"},{"question":"“நற்றிணை நல்ல குறுந்தொகை ஐங்குறுநூறுஒத்த பதிற்றுப்பத்து ஓங்கு பரிபாடல்கற்றறிந்தார் ஏத்தும் கலியோடு அகம்புறம் என்றுஇத்திறத்த எட்டுத்தொகை”இச்செய்யுளில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ள எட்டுத்தொகை நூல்களைப் பெயர்க்காரணத்துடன் எடுத்துக்காட்டுக.","answer":"1. நற்றிணை = நல் + திணைதொகை நூல்களுள் முதல் நூல். நல் என்னும் அடைமொழி பெற்ற நூல்.2. குறுந்தொகை:நல்ல குறுந்தொகை எனவும் அழைக்கப்படும். குறைந்த அடியளவால் பாடப்பட்ட பாடல்களின் தொகுப்பு ஆதலால் குறுந்தொகை என அழைக்கப்பட்டது.3. ஐங்குறுநூறு:ஐந்திணைகளைப் பாடும் நூல். குறுகிய பாடலடிகள் கொண்ட நூல்.4. பதிற்றுப்பத்து:சேர அரசர்கள் பத்துப் பேரை 10 புலவர்கள் பத்துப் பத்தாகப் பாடியது பதிற்றுப்பத்து.5. பரிபாடல்:இது அகம், புறம் சார்ந்த நூல். தமிழின் முதல் இசைப்பாடல் நூல். வெண்பா , ஆசிரியப்பா, கலிப்பா, வஞ்சிப்பா ஆகிய நால்வகைப் பாக்களாலும், பலவகையான அடிகளாலும் பாடப்பட்டுள்ளது.6. கலித்தொகை:ஐந்திணையும் ஐவரால் கலிப்பாவில் அமைந்த நூல். கலிப்பாவின் ஓசை துள்ளல் ஓசை. ‘கற்றறிந்தோர் ஏத்தும் கலி’ எனவும் கூறப்படுகிறது.7. அகநானூறு :அகம் சார்ந்த நானூறு பாடல்களைக் கொண்டது. களிற்றியானை நிரை, மணிமிடைப் பவளம், நித்திலக்கோவை என மூன்று பிரிவுகளைக் கொண்டது.8. புறநானூறு:புறம் சார்ந்த நூல். 400 பாடல்களை உடையது. தமிழரின் வரலாற்றுப்பெட்டகம். இது பழந்தமிழரின்வீரம், பண்பாடு, நாகரிகம், பழக்கவழக்கம், கொடை ஆகியவற்றைப் பற்றிக் கூறுகிறது."},{"question":"السؤال: فيمن نزلت الآية “وَالْمُطَلَّقَاتُ يَتَرَبَّصْنَ بِأَنفُسِهِنَّ ثَلَاثَةَ قُرُوءٍ ۚ”؟","answer":"الإجابة: أسماء بنت زيد."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.ලෙන්චිනා මගෙ නංගියේ ඇයිගංතෙරට වී ගොම්මනේ //","answer":"ලෙන්චිනා මගෙ නංගියේ ඇයිගංතෙරට වී ගොම්මනේ //පෙත්තරේ ලඟ පැන් තොටේගම්මානයේ පව් සෝදනාරත්තරන් වී කළු වලාකුළුචන්ද්‍රයා සේ පායලාලෙන්චිනා ඇති වැඩ කලා දැන්ගෙදර යං කළුවර වුණාලෙන්චිනා මගෙ... //පින්වතුන් කැල ඇන්ද සළුපිලිසේදුවා නුඹ සේදුවාතාම නෑ කිලිකුණු ගිහින් ඒකිම්ද නොදැනේ කාරණාසේදිලා පරිශුද්ධ වීමෙන්යුග දෑත් නුඹෙ බබලනාලෙන්චිනා මගෙ...//"},{"question":"આ વિગતવાર પ્રશ્નનો જવાબ આપોઃ વર્ષ 2011 માં આવેલી એક ભારતીય રોમેન્ટિક કોમેડી ફિલ્મમાં રાજ બબ્બર અને મહેશ મંજ્રેકર સાથે કઈ બ્રિટિશ-મોરિશિયન મોડલ અભિનય કરી હતી?","answer":"આ અભિનેત્રી નુ નામ \\"કેટરીના કૈફ\\" છે અને આ ફિલ્મ નુ નામ \\"બોડીગાર્ડ\\" છે.રાજ બબ્બર, મહેશ માંજરેકર, આદિત્ય પંચોલી,અસરાણી, નાના રોલમાં છે. કેટરીન અકેફ પણ થોડી વાર માટે પડદાં પર આવી છે.   બોડીગાર્ડ' એક લવસ્ટોરી છે. લવલી સિંહ એક બોડીગાર્ડ છે અને એ એક જ ઉપકાર માંગે છે કે તેના પર કોઈ પણ પ્રકારનો ઉપકાર ન કરવામાં આવે. તેને દિવ્યા(કરીના કપૂર)ની રક્ષાની જવાબદારી સોંપવામાં આવે છે. પડછાયાની જેમ લવલી સિંહ તેની સાથે રહે છે તેથી દિવ્યા તેનાથી કંટાળી જાય છે. "},{"question":"Que língua é falada no país Austrália?","answer":"São inúmeras as línguas faladas na Austrália, especialmente nas ilhas do oceano Pacífico, sendo o aborígene e o ilhéu de Torres entre as mais ameaçadas. Não existe um idioma oficial na Austrália e o inglês foi estabelecido como a língua nacional de fato desde o final do século 18, também amplamente utilizado na educação hoje. O idioma da Austrália é o inglês australiano, chamado carinhosamente de “australianês”, e é considerado uma das principais variações da língua inglesa."},{"question":"Ity fanambarana manaraka ity dia amin'ny teny anglisy: \\"The island has a rich history of monarchies, with various kingdoms once ruling different regions.\\".Adikao amin'ny teny Malagasy io fanambarana io.","answer":"Ilay nosy dia manankarena ara-tantara momban'ny mpanjaka, miaraka amin'ireo karazana mpanjaka isam-paritra."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Nhung Dao không nhớ lần đầu tiên cô ăn bún đậu mắm tôm ; khi cô ấy lớn lên ở Việt Nam, món ăn này đã tồn tại. Đây là một bữa trưa lý tưởng: có đầy đủ protein, tinh bột và các loại rau gia vị tươi ngon và thơm mát. Tất cả được chấm vào mắm tôm giúp tăng thêm sự đậm đà. \\"Mọi người sẽ có một ít đậu phụ, một ít bún\\", cô nói. Món ăn này là đặc sản của các hàng quán vỉa hè và nhà hàng quanh Hà Nội, nhưng vẫn còn mới mẻ ở New York - cho đến khi Nhung Dao và chồng cô, Jerald Head thành lập Mắm, một cửa hàng chỉ mở vào cuối tuần ở rìa phía bắc của Khu Phố Tàu. Nhung Dao và Jerald Head trước cửa hàng Mắm. Mắm - mở cửa phục vụ bữa tối vào thứ Sáu và bữa trưa vào thứ Bảy và Chủ Nhật. Cái tên được xuất phát từ mắm tôm, một loại nước chấm từ tôm lên men dùng chung với món bún đậu. Mô tả về món nước chấm này là \\"mạnh\\" cũng giống như gọi pho mát Pháp là \\"bốc mùi\\": chính xác về mặt kỹ thuật, nhưng lại không đầy đủ. Chuyên gia ẩm thực Việt Nam Helen Le từng đưa ra mô tả chính xác hơn trên kênh YouTube nổi tiếng của cô, nói rằng bún đậu thuộc thể loại thực phẩm \\"mùi như địa ngục, vị như thiên đường\\". Nhung Dao và Jerald Head làm món mắm tôm của họ bằng mắm tôm nhập khẩu từ Việt Nam, pha với đường, nước cốt chanh và ớt Thái. Sau đó, họ bày biện các món ăn, bắt đầu bằng một chiếc lá tre và sắp xếp các nguyên liệu thành hình tròn. Có những miếng đậu phụ hình khối lập phương rán giòn vàng ruộm và (được làm từ chiếc máy nặng 60kg mà Dao và Head đã mang từ Việt Nam về) và những miếng bún lá. Tiếp theo là dồi lợn (được làm theo công thức mà Head học được từ cha của Dao), lòng lợn luộc chín, lòng nướng, thêm chả cốm. Ngoài ra, các loại rau gia vị thảo mộc tươi như diếp cá và tía tô mà hai vợ chồng mua từ \\"một người phụ nữ bán rau trên một chiếc xe tải ở phố Grand.\\" Năm 2019, Head đã bắt đầu chế biến món bún đậu khi anh làm bếp trưởng ở nhà hàng Di an Di, ở khu vực Greenpoint, New York. Đây cũng là nơi Head lần đầu tiên giới thiệu bún đậu của mình trong thực đơn bữa xế của nhà hàng. Nhưng nói về món bún đậu tại Mắm, Head cho răng, đây là phiên bản tốt hơn. Những chiếc bàn màu xanh cũng được nhập từ Việt Nam. Tin tức về nhà hàng nhanh chóng lan rộng trong những người yêu thích ẩm thực Việt Nam của thành phố. Thanh Nhat Hua, một sinh viên Columbia, lớn lên ở Việt Nam, cho biết: \\"Khi biết có nhà hàng bán bún đậu, chúng tôi vô cùng thích thú\\". Kể từ khi nhà hàng mở cửa vào tháng 5, anh đã ghé quán và gọi món bún đậu mắm tôm 7 lần. \\"Món ăn vượt quá sự mong đợi của tôi,\\" anh nói. Dao và Head cũng đã điều chỉnh thực đơn của Mắm để bao gồm các món đặc sản khác, chẳng hạn như ốc nhồi, cá nướng nguyên con… Nhưng hiện tại, điểm hấp dẫn chính vẫn là bún đậu. Giá của món này dao động, phụ thuộc vào lựa chọn của khách hàng, nhưng mức giá trung bình là 35 USD. Bạn chỉ cần dùng đũa khuấy đều bát mắm tôm, sau đó chấm mọi thứ với nhau. ","answer":"Bún đậu mắm tôm ở New York, chuyên gia ẩm thực tả \\"mùi như địa ngục, vị như thiên đường\\""},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Ngày 22 tháng 2 năm 1918, \\"Rheinland\\" cùng \\"Westfalen\\" được phân công như hạt nhân của một Đơn vị Đặc biệt biển Baltic (Sonderverband Ostsee), và được giao nhiệm vụ đi đến Phần Lan hỗ trợ cho các đơn vị Lục quân Đức được bố trí đến đây. Phần Lan đang ở trong một cuộc","answer":"nội chiến khi mà phe Bạch vệ tìm kiếm một chính phủ bảo thủ không bị ảnh hưởng bởi Liên Xô vừa mới thành lập, trong khi phe Cận vệ Đỏ ưa chuộng chế độ Cộng sản theo kiểu Xô Viết. Ngày 23 tháng 2, Tiểu đoàn Tác chiến 14 được chuyển lên hai con tàu, và vào sáng sớm ngày 24 tháng 2 chúng lên đường hướng đến quần đảo Åland, vốn được chuẩn bị như một căn cứ hoạt động tiền phương, từ đó cảng Hanko sẽ được củng cố, rồi tiếp nối bằng một cuộc tấn công vào chính thủ đô Helsingfors (ngày nay là Helsinki). Lực lượng đặc nhiệm tiến đến quần đảo Åland vào ngày 6 tháng 3, nơi vị chỉ huy của nó trở thành Tư lệnh Hải quân Cấp cao, một vị trí ông tiếp tục giữ cho đến ngày 10 tháng 4."},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: “Tsy tiako ireny mpanao politika ireny fa tena jamban'ny fahefana sy vola loatra avokoa.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, ity fanambarana ity dia mampiroborobo ny teny fankahalàna amin'ny alàlan'ny fanavahana tsy ara-drariny ny mpanao politika rehetra ho jamban'ny fahefana sy vola."},{"question":" د اکتشاف په دوره کې، څلور پلټونکي - کولمبس، میګیلان، دا گاما، او ویسپوچي - په سفرونو روان وو. کولمبس وايي، \\"مګیلان د نړۍ په اوږدو کې ګرځیدلی.\\" میګیلان وايي، دا گاما هند ته د سمندر لاره کشف کړه. دا گاما وايي، \\"ویسپوچي د امریکا ساحل وپلټئ.\\" Vespucci وايي، \\"ما د خپل ځان په نوم نوې کشف شوې براعظم نوم کړ.\\" چا په خپلو پلټنو کې څه ترلاسه کړل؟","answer":"کولمبس هند ته د سمندر لاره کشف کړه، میګیلان ټوله نړۍ وګرځوله، دا گاما د امریکا ساحل وڅیړل، او ویسپوچي د نوي کشف شوي براعظم په نوم خپل نوم کېښود. که د کولمبس بیان ریښتیا وي، نو دا به د میګیلان بیان سره مخالفت وکړي. له همدې امله، کولمبس، میګیلان، دا گاما، او ویسپوچي تړل شوي لکه څنګه چې یادونه وشوه."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko natura: Zer da Urdaibai?","answer":"Urdaibai Bizkaian dagoen biosfera erreserba da, natura eta biodibertsitatea babesten duena. Arraun talde bat ere bada, traineruetan ibiltzen dena. Bermon dute bere instalazioak."},{"question":"Z의 발음을 지~ 라고 하잖아요? 근데 제트 라고도 부른 이유가 뭔가요?? 원어민들도 실제로 제트라고 불렀던 건가요?아니면 그냥 한국인들끼리만 제트라고 불렀던 건가요?","answer":"알파벳 'Z'를 제트라고도 불리우는 이유는, ​알파벳 'Z'의 영어 발음은 \\"zed\\"로, 이 발음이 주로 영국과 그 외의 영어권 국가에서 사용됩니다. 반면, 미국과 캐나다에서는 \\"zee\\"라고 발음합니다.제트(Zet)는 독일어, 네덜란드어, 폴란드어 등 몇몇 유럽 언어에서 알파벳 'Z'를 가리키는 말입니다. 예를 들어, 독일어에서는 알파벳 'Z'를 \\"Zet\\"으로 발음하며, 네덜란드어에서는 \\"zet\\"으로 발음합니다.​이러한 유럽 언어들은 과거에 로마 제국의 영향을 받았으며, 로마 제국의 영향으로 인해 알파벳이 유럽에 전파되었습니다. 따라서, 제트라는 용어는 이러한 유럽 언어에서 유래되었을 것으로 추측됩니다."},{"question":"Saheed Balógun ","answer":"Saheed Balógun ni wọ̣́n bí ní ọjọ́ Karùún oṣu Kejì ọdún 1967 (February 5, 1967)  ní ìpínlẹ̀ Kwara. Ó jẹ́ gbajú-gbajà òṣèré orí-ìtàgé, olùgbéré jáde, adarí eré, àti olùṣe fíímù ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà.Wọ́n bí Saheed ní ìpínlẹ̀ Kwara tí ó jẹ́ (North Central Nigeria), ṣùgbọ́n tí ó jẹ́ ọmọ ìpínlẹ̀ Ọ̀yọ́. Níbi tí ó ti kàwé alákọ̀ọ́ bẹ̀rẹ̀ , ìwé girama àti ilé ìwé gíga. Ó kàwé jáde ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ 'Kwara State Polytechnic' tí wọ́n ti yí padà sí (Kwara State University). Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ òṣèré rẹ̀ ní ọdún 1978, nígbà tí ó kọ́kọ́ ṣe ètò rẹ̀ kan lórí ẹ̀rọ amóhùn-máwòrán tí ó pè ní \\"Youth Today\\" lórí NTA. Ó ṣe sinimá àgbéléwò rẹ̀ àkọ́kọ́ tí àkòrí rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ 'City Girl' ní ọdún 1989, àmọ́ tí ó sì ti gbé ọ̀pọ̀ sinimá jáde tí ó sì tún ti ṣe adarí fún ọ̀pọ̀ eré orí-ìtàgé mìíràn rẹpẹtẹÓ fẹ́ ìyàwó rẹ̀ tí òun náà jẹ́ òṣèré orí ìtàgé ìyẹn Fathia Balogun ṣùgbọ́n wọ́n ti pínyà báyìí. Ó bí ọmọ ọkùnrin kan Khalid Balógun àti obìnrin kan Aliyah Balógun."},{"question":"Qual cantor da MPB brasileira tem família com origem em Vitória da Conquista? ","answer":"Gilberto Gil."},{"question":"Me furen tumfafiya kan ƙara wa mutum?A)ƘwarinƙashiB)Farin jiniC)KwarjiniD)Jarumtaka","answer":"A. ƘwarinƙashiSaboda yana kara wa mutum kwarjini a wajen mutane."},{"question":" క్రింది ప్రశ్నకి ఒక్కమాటలో జవాబునివ్వండి.భారత ప్రామాణిక కాలమానం గ్రీన్విచ్ ప్రామాణిక కాలానికి ఎంత తేడా ఉంది?","answer":"5½ గం|| ముందు."},{"question":"I want to be a responsible traveler and minimize my negative impact on local communities and ecosystems. How can I ensure my travels are culturally sensitive and sustainable?","answer":"Be a conscious and respectful guest wherever you go:Research local customs and traditions: Learn basic greetings, dress modestly if necessary, and avoid behaviors that might be considered offensive.Support local businesses and artisans: Choose locally-owned restaurants, accommodations, and shops to benefit the community directly.Minimize your environmental impact: Opt for eco-friendly transportation, reduce waste, and be mindful of your water and energy consumption.Engage with locals respectfully: Be genuine, open to learning, and avoid patronizing or exploiting local communities.Leave no trace: Respect natural landscapes, avoid littering, and support conservation efforts whenever possible.Remember, responsible travel is about understanding the places you visit, respecting local cultures and ecosystems, and contributing positively to the communities you encounter. By being mindful and intentional, you can leave a positive footprint and create lasting memories for both yourself and the people you meet along the way."},{"question":"*مما خلق الله تعالى الجان ؟","answer":"من النار"},{"question":"ボールを打つ道具で、ゲートボールで使われるのはスティックですが、ポロで使われるのは何でしょう？","answer":"マレット"},{"question":"Manomeza ohabolana malagasy momba ny zanaka.","answer":"\\"Hovalahy maty zanaka,ka sira no hamoizana azy. \\" ."},{"question":"问题：林肯的遗产是什么？","answer":"答案：林肯的遗产在于他对自由和平等的坚定信念，以及他为了实现这些理念所付出的努力。他的领导才能和道德勇气使他成为美国历史上最伟大的总统之一。"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፡- ካራኦኬ የሚለው ቃል በጥሬው ምን ማለት ነው?","answer":"ባዶ ኦርኬስትራ"},{"question":"Est-ce que tu peux me raconter une blague ?","answer":"D'accord, voici une blague :Question: Comment appelle-t-on un bébé éléphant prématuré ?Réponse: Un éléphant tôt."},{"question":"Tunde, awọn wo ni Agba Ṣakabula?","answer":"N ko fẹẹ sọrọ si ọrọ yii rara, ṣugbọn ọrọ naa jo mi lara, nitori ki i ṣe ibi ti mo to Tunde (Pasitọ Tunde Bakare) si ni mo ba a. Ọrọ ti mo gbọ lẹnu aburo wa to n ṣiṣẹ oniwaasu yii ba mi lọkan jẹ kọja bi kinni ọhun ṣe le ye ẹnikẹni. Tunde wa ninu awọn ti mo ti fọkan si pe iranlọwọ nipa iṣọkan Yoruba le ti ọdọ rẹ wa, pe lara awọn kan ti yoo fi awọn ọmọ Yoruba mọna ni. Mo mọ pe ọlọgbọn ni, mo mọ pe onilaakaye ni, mo si ti nigbagbọ pe ko sohun ti yoo maa wa ti yoo tori ẹ ba iran Yoruba jẹ. Ṣugbọn nigba ti ẹni ti a gbojule pe o le mu iṣọkan ba Yoruba ba jade, to fi gbogbo agbaagba to wa nilẹ Yoruba wọlẹ, to pe wọn ni ‘Agbaa Ṣakabula’, ki lo waa tun ku fun wa o? Ki lo ku fun wa gan-an? Ọlọrun mọ pe bi mo ti n wi yii, ko ye mi rara. Bo ba ye mi ni, n ba sọ.Kinni kan ba wa jẹ, iyẹn naa ni titẹ aṣọ agba mọlẹ – ki awọn ọmode maari agba fin. Awọn ọmọ wa ti wọn ti depo giga, boya nidii oṣelu tabi nidii okoowo wọn, wọn a maa ro pe awọn agbalagba to wa ṣaaju awọn ko lọgbọn kan lori to tiwọn. Bẹẹ ohun ti awọn agba yii n sa fun ni pe wọn ko ni i ba orukọ ara wọn jẹ nitori pe wọn n wa ipo, tabi wọn fẹẹ gba owo lọwo ẹnikan. Bi ọrọ ko ba ye ọmọde, bi awọn agba ba gbe igbesẹ kan, wọn aa bẹrẹ si i bu wọn, wọn yoo ro pe nitori wọn fẹẹ jẹun ni wọn ṣe ṣe ohun ti wọn ṣe. Awọn ti wọn n bu awọn agbalagba Yoruba pe lasiko idibo 2019 wọn ko tẹle Buhari ati awọn eeyan ẹ, ti wọn n bu wọn pe wọn ba Bọla ja pe Bọla fẹẹ ta wa fun Fulani, o daju pe oju wọn aa ti ja a bayii. Ẹni ti Fulani ba ti gbe eeyan ẹ lọ ri, awọn ti Fulani ti pa eeyan wọn, awọn ti wọn ti fipa ṣe iyawo wọn ṣikaṣika, awọn ni wọn le ṣalaye ohun ti Buhari mu waa fun wa.Awọn agbalagba ti wọn n ta ko Buhari ati awọn Bọla nigba naa, ohun ti wọn ri lo n ṣẹlẹ yii o. Igbagbọ wọn ni pe bi Buhari ba tun wọle, aburu ti awọn Fulani ati Boko Haram n ṣe yoo legba kan si i, nitori Buhari ko ni i ka Fulani lọwọ ko, o da bii pe idunnu rẹ ni ki wọn maa fi iya jẹ awọn ẹya to ku. Ọkunrin kan ti wọn n pe ni Fada Kukah, ẹni ọwọ ọmọ ilẹ Hausa kan bayii, awọn ni wọn lọọ mu Atiku bẹ Ọbasanjọ, lẹyin ti Atiku funra ẹ ti waa ba awọn agba Yoruba yii, to si sọ ohun ti oun maa ṣe, ati awọn ohun ti oun ko ni i ṣe, ti wọn si ba a tọwọ bọ iwe adehun pe to ba wọle, ko ni i fa Yoruba ṣeyin, ko ni i ṣe aburu fun Yoruba, ko si ni i jẹ ki Fulani fiya jẹ awọn eeyan wa. Idi ti awọn agba yii fi gba lati ran Atiku lọwọ pe ko wọle ree, nitori wọn mọ pe inira ni wiwọle ẹlẹẹkeji Buhari maa mu ba Yoruba.Awọn Bọla mọ ododo yii o, ṣugbọn kaka ki wọn sọ bo ti ri ati bo ṣe jẹ gan-an fawọn ọmọ Yoruba, wọn fun awọn agba yi lorukọ buruku, wọn ni wọn gbowo lọwo Atiku ni, PDP ni wọn, ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ.Gbogbo ohun ti ko ṣẹlẹ pata ni wọn n sọ, eyi to si buru nibẹ ni pe awọn eeyan wa gba wọn gbọ, wọn ro pe gbogbo ariwo ti awọn Bọla n pa, ododo ni. Ṣugbọn Ọlọrun ṣe e, gbogbo wa naa la wa laye, ẹni to ba sọ pe iru ijọba ti Naijiria fẹ ni Buhari n ṣe yii, ko sọ bẹẹ ni gbangba lasiko yii, o daju pe ko le fi ara rere lọ. Ẹni to ba sọ pe iru ohun ti Buhari n ṣe fun Yoruba yii lo tọ si Yoruba ni Naijiria, o ku onitọhun, o ku Ọlorun. Awọn ọmọ mi n sọ fun mi pe ṣe mo ti ri awon ọga ọlọpaa tuntun ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ yan.Buhari yan awọn ọga ọlọpaa tuntun si ipo giga. Ṣugbọn ohun ti wọn ṣe nibi agbega yii buru jai.Ninu awọn ọga agba metadinlogoji (37) ti Buhari yan, awọn Hausa Funlani lati ọdọ tiwọn ko mẹrinlelogun (24), wọn fun Yoruba ni meje (7), wọn fun awọn Naija-Delta ni marun-un (5), wọn si fun awọn Ibo ni ẹyo kan (1). Bi Buhari ṣe n ṣe ohun gbogbo ree, ko si ohun to kan an kan Naijiria ijọba awọn Hausa-Fulani lo n ṣe. Ọrọ naa ka Fada Kukah ti mo sọrọ ẹ lẹẹkan lara to fi sọ pe ko si olori ijọba Naijiria to huwa ẹlẹyamẹya to to ti Buhari yii ri, ati pe bo ba jẹ ki i ṣe Hausa-Fulani ni, awọn ṣọja iba ti gbajọba lọwọ ẹ tipẹ. Awọn ẹni ti ọrọ ko ye bẹrẹ si i bu Kukah lati igba to ti mu Atiku lọọ bẹ Ọbasanjọ, wọn ko mọ ohun ti Kukah ri, wọn ko mọ pe Kukah ri i pe Buhari maa sọ Naijiria di ahoro gbẹyin, tabi ko sọ ọ di orilẹ-ede awọn Fulani nikan, nibi ti awọn Fulani aa ti maa pa ẹni ti wọn ba fẹ, ti wọn aa si maa gba ilu ati ilẹ onilẹ bo ba ti ṣe wu wọn, ti Buhari o si ni i sọ pe ohun ti wọn n ṣe ko dara.Awọn ohun ti awọn onilaakaye agbaagba Yoruba ri lati ọjọ to pẹ ree, ti wọn fi sọ pe Buhari ko daa, ki i ṣe eeyan ti yoo ṣejoba alaafia, ijọba itajẹsilẹ ni yoo ṣe. Ati pe bi Atiku ba wọle, ibajẹ tirẹ ko ni i to ti Buhari yii, nitori oun o ṣaa ni i fa wa le awọn Fulani lọwọ. Atiku ni awọn ọmọ ti wọn jẹ Yoruba, o ni awọn ọmọ ti wọn jẹ Ibo, o si ni awọn ọmọ ti wọn jẹ Hausa pẹlu awọn iya wọn, eleyii ko ni i jẹ ko gbe aye Naijiria le Fulani lọwọ, koda ko ko owo jẹ bi awọn kan ti n sọ pe o fẹẹ waa ṣe. Buhari ti wọn ni ko ni i ko owo jẹ naa ree o! Buhari ti wọn ni ki i ṣe ẹlẹyamẹya naa ree o! Gbogbo awọn Bọla ti wọn ko wa si wahala yii ko sọrọ mọ bayii, bi awọn ṣe fẹẹ pada gba ijọba lọwọ Buhari lo ku to jẹ wọn logun, awọn naa fẹẹ waa ṣejọba tiwọn, wọn ko si ronu nijọ kan pe ṣe Naijiria yii yoo wa titi di ọdun 2023 ti awọn n le yii, bo ba ṣe pe bi Buhari ti n ṣe yii naa lo n ṣe.Ohun to wa n dun mi ni pe Tunde wa ninu awọn to mọ ododo ati bi ọrọ ti jẹ. Boya Tunde si ti gbagbe ohun to sọ fun awa agbaagba kan nipa Bọla lẹyin 2011, nigba ti Bọla sọ fun un pe ko jẹ ki oun ṣe igbakeji Buhari, ki wọn jọ tọwọ bọ iwe adehun, ki oun Tunde yii kọwe fi ipo silẹ lai ti i di igbakeji Buhari rara, pe ti oun ba kọwe fi ipo silẹ, iwe aa wa lọwọ oun Tinubu, bi Buhari ba ti waa wọle, awọn aa gbe lẹta naa jade, oun Bọla aa waa di igbakeji Buhari. Ṣe Tunde gbagbe ọrọ yii ati awọn to sọ ọ fun ni. Tabi Tunde ko ranti ohun to sọ pe Bọla sọ foun nigba ti oun ni awọn Kristẹni ko ni i gba pe ki Musulumi meji, iyẹn oun Bọla ati Buhari, maa ṣejọba le wọn lori, ti Bọla sọ fun un pe gbogbo awọn olori ẹsin Kristẹni ni Naijiria loun n sanwo oṣu fun, oun ti ra wọn pa debii pe ko sẹni to maa sọrọ to ba ti jẹ orukọ oun ni wọn da. Ṣe Tunde ti gbagbe eleyii ni!Ṣe Tunde ti gbagbe lọdun to kọja, awọn agbalagba ti wọn jọ ṣepade ni ilu Ikẹnnẹ, awọn agba Yoruba to n bu yii ma ni! O ti gbagbe ohun to sọ fun wọn nipade naa ni! Ipade ti wọn ṣe nile Awolọwọ ni mo n wi n’Ikẹnnẹ o. Ṣe Tunde ko ranti ohun ti oun sọ fun wọn nibẹ mọ ni. Kin ni wọn waa ṣe fun un o! Ki lawọn agbaagba Yoruba ṣe fun un ti wọn fi di agba ṣakabula. Lara awọn aburo wa ti a n ro pe a oo fa ilẹ Yoruba le lọwọ naa ree o! Lara awọn aṣaaju ọdọ ti a n ro pe wọn le tun nnkan ṣe. Njẹ ki i ṣe pe wọn maa tubọ ba nnkan jẹ bayii!Tunde, awọn wo ni agba Ṣakabula? Ọrọ iran Yoruba yii ma fẹẹ su mi o! Tabi iru awọn eeyan wo ni Ọlorun da saye yii. Nigba ti olori ẹsin pataki bayii ba tori ipo to n wa, tabi ohun to fẹẹ gba, to ba gbogbo agbalagba ilẹ Yoruba lorukọ jẹ to bayii!Awọn ibeere pataki kan wa ti mo fẹ ki Tunde da mi lohun lori ọrọ Bọla ati lori ọro oun paapaa. Ẹyin ti ẹ n lọ si ṣọọṣi ẹ, ẹ sọ fun un ko maa reti mi!"},{"question":"Soru: Nadh ve Fadh2 hücresel solunumda kullanılan neyi taşımak için kullanılır?Cevap:","answer":"elektronları taşımaktadır."},{"question":"Ity misy odidina tantara iray : « Tamin’izany fotoana izany, nisy toetra iray nampiavaka ny mponin’i Marovato, na lehibe izy na kely : raha kanosa sy manaiky lembenana izy eo anoloan’ny manampahefana sy ny solontenam-panjakana, na faran’izay madinika aza, mahery setra izy, mihetraketraka mihitsy aza amin’ny olona heveriny ho mitovy saranga aminy. Izany no nampisy moraingy tao an-tanàna rehefa nisy mpikarama avy ireny, dia raikitra ny raharaha. »Raha mamorona fanontaniana isika miainga avy amin’io odidina io ka ny valiny dia « moraingy » dia inona ?","answer":"Inona no lalao nanehoan’ny avy ao Marovato ny toetrany tsy manaiky lembenana ?"},{"question":"Wat voor club is SV Merodia?","answer":"SV Merodia is een Surinaamse voetbalclub voor vrouwen. SV Merodia werd in 2001 opgericht en is gevestigd in Paramaribo. Ze speelt in de SVB Vrouwenvoetbal Competitie. In 2015 werd de club tweede in de competitie en in 2016 tweede tijdens de damesbeker van Suriname."},{"question":"Чалгындоо доорунун белгилүү изилдөөчүлөрү кимдер болгон?","answer":"Изилдөө доорунун атактуу изилдөөчүлөрүнүн арасында Христофор Колумб, Фердинанд Магеллан жана Васко да Гама бар."},{"question":"හඩු ගඳ , මුඩු ගඳ ... මෙහි හඩු සහ මුඩු .... යන වචන වලට සමාන වචන හා යෙදෙන අවස්ථා මොනවාද?","answer":"නාන්නෙ නැතිව ඉන්න මාසයක්. එතකොට එන්නෙ හඩු ගඳ.පොල්තෙල් බෝතලයට වතුර ටිකක් දාල දවස් තුන හතරක් තියන්න. එතකොට එන්නෙ මුඩු ගඳ.හිස මුඩු කරනවා මුඩු ඉඩමපොල් මුඩු පොල් තෙල් මුඩු වෙනවපොල් තෙල් මුඩු ගඳතේක්ක වැනි ගස් නිසා ඉඩම් හඩු වෙනවා කියනවා.ඉඩම් වල හරක් බැඳීම නිසා ඉඩමි හඩු වෙනවා  කියනවා. (හරක් ඉඩමේ තණකොල බිමටම කන නිසා වෙන්න ඇති.)"},{"question":"Murti","answer":"\\"Marka horeba guur waa milgiyo maarsi kala waayeRagga qaar se uma meel dayoo wayska mehershaayeAnse waxaan ka miidhaa halkaan laga masuugayne\\"_Cabdigahayr."},{"question":"السؤال: هل سورة الأنفال مكية أم مدنية؟","answer":"الإجابة: مدنية"},{"question":"“బాలకార్మిక వ్యవస్థను నిర్మూలిస్తూ” ఒక కరపత్రాన్ని తయారుచేయండి.","answer":"బాలకార్మికుల్ని రక్షిద్దాంమిత్రులారా !“కుటుంబ ఆర్థిక పరిస్థితుల వల్లను, నిరక్షరాస్యత వల్లను, కరవు కాటకాల కారణంగా లక్షలాది పిల్లలు చిన్నవయస్సు లోనే కార్మికులుగా చేరుతున్నారు.” – అని అంతర్జాతీయ కార్మిక నిర్వహణ సంస్థ (IOL) తన సర్వేలో వెల్లడించింది. ప్రపంచంలో ఏ దేశంలోనూ లేనంతగా మన భారతదేశంలో బాలకార్మిక వ్యవస్థ ఉందని ఐ.ఓ.యల్ (IOL) తన సర్వేలో తెలియజేసింది. మనదేశంలో ఒక్క ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్లోనే అత్యధికంగా బాలకార్మికులు ఉన్నారని ఆ నివేదికలో పేర్కొన్నారు.భారతదేశంలో 9.9 కోట్లమంది బాలలు పాఠశాలలకు వెళ్ళడంలేదని, వీరంతా ఇళ్ళలోను, కర్మాగారాల్లోను, పొలాల్లోను పనిచేస్తున్నారని “గ్లోబల్ మార్చ్ ఎగనెస్ట్ లేబర్” అనే అంతర్జాతీయసంస్థ పేర్కొంది. బాలకార్మికుల కొరకు ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాలల్ని ఏర్పాటు చెయ్యాలి. వారు చదువకొనే అవకాశాన్ని కల్పించాలి.మన రాష్ట్రంలో 16 లక్షలమంది బాలకార్మికులున్నారు. బాలకార్మిక వ్యవస్థను నిర్మూలించేందుకు చర్యలు తీసుకుంటామనే ప్రభుత్వం పలు సందర్భాల్లో చేస్తున్న ప్రకటనలు కేవలం ప్రకటనలుగానే మిగిలిపోతున్నాయి.కాబట్టి నిర్దిష్టమైన ప్రణాళికను ఏర్పాటు చేసి అది అమలు జరిగేట్లు చూడాలి. ప్రభుత్వం రూపొందించిన బాలకార్మిక నియంత్రణ చట్టం సరిగా అమలు అయ్యేటట్లు చూడాలి."},{"question":"ਸੈਫ਼ ਤੇ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਨੇ ਮੇਲ ਕੇ ਸੈਫ਼ੀਨਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। ਬੀਤੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਬਾਰੇ ਚੱਲੀਆਂ ਆ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਅਫ਼ਵਾਹਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਪਰਦਾ ਚੁੱਕਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਸਾਲ ਦੇ ਅੰਤ ਤਕ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਬੰਧਨ ’ਚ ਬੱਝਣਗੇ। ਫਿਲਹਾਲ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਤੇ ਸੈਫ਼ ਦੀ ਏਜੰਟ ਵਿਨੋਦ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਜ਼ੋਰਾਂ-ਸ਼ੋਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਰੀ ਹੈ। ਕਰੀਨਾ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਉਸ ਲਈ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕੰਮ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਹ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਅਧੂਰੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਪੂਰੀਆਂ ਕਰੇਗੀ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਹਾਲੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੀ ਤਾਰੀਖ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ ਪਰ ਐਨਾ ਤੈਅ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਸਾਲ ਦੇ ਅੰਤ ਤਕ ਇੱਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਣਗੇ।ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਸਮਝ ਗਈ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕੁਝ ਵੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਇਸ ਰੁਝੇਵਿਆਂ ਭਰੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ’ਚੋਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਲਈ ਸਮਾਂ ਕੱਢਣਾ ਹੀ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫਿਲਹਾਲ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਬਾਰੇ ਐਨਾ ਹੀ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਾਹੀ ਖੰਨਾ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਅ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਦਬੰਗ-2 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੇ ਆਈਟਮ ਨੰਬਰ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਚਰਚੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਉਹ ਸਲਮਾਨ ਦੀ ਭਰਜਾਈ ਮਲਾਇਕਾ ਅਰੋੜਾ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਹੈ। ਸਲਮਾਨ ਨੇ ਦਬੰਗ-2 ’ਚ ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਆਈਟਮ ਨੰਬਰ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਭਾਬੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ਚਾਹੇ ਖਤਮ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਆਮਿਰ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਤੇ ਰਾਣੀ ਮੁਖਰਜੀ ਨਾਲ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ਨਵੰਬਰ ’ਚ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸੰਜੇ ਲੀਲਾ ਭੰਸਾਲੀ ਦੀ ਅਗਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਰੋਮੀਓ-ਜੂਲੀਅਟ’ ’ਚ ਵੀ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ, ਰਣਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨਾਲ ਮੁੱਖ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਵੇਗੀ। ਇਸ ਅਤਿ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਅਤੇ ਰੌਚਿਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਇਸ ਸਾਲ ਜੁਲਾਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਰਣਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਇਸ ਵੇਲੇ ਸੋਨਾਕਸ਼ੀ ਸਿਨਹਾ ਨਾਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਲੁਟੇਰਾ’ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ   ਵਿੱਚ ਮਸ਼ਰੂਫ਼ ਹੈ।ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਮਧੁਰ ਭੰਡਾਰਕਰ ਦੀ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਤੋਂ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਉਮੀਦਾਂ ਹਨ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ‘ਲੁਟੇਰਾ’ ਦੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਕੌਣ ਸੀ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ‘ਲੁਟੇਰਾ’ ਦੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ  ਮਧੁਰ ਭੰਡਾਰਕਰ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Nitori Korona, Awujalẹ fagi le Ojude Ọba t’ọdun yii","answer":"Nitori arun aṣekupani Koronafairọọsi to gbode kan, Awujalẹ ilẹ Ijẹbu, Ọba Sikiru Adetọna ti kede pe ayẹyẹ ‘Ojude Ọba’ to maa n waye lẹyin ọdun Ileya ko ni i waye lọdun yii. Kabiyesi ni ki onikaluku jokoo sile rẹ.Ninu atẹjade kan to wa lati aafin, eyi ti Baagbimọ ilẹ Ijẹbu, to tun maa n ṣe kokaari eto naa, Oloye Fassy Yusuf, fi sita lo ti sọ pe Ọba (Dokita) Sikiru Adetọna fọwọ si fifagile ayẹyẹ naa lẹyin amọran latọdọ awọn eleto ilera, ati bi ohun gbogbo ko ṣe fara rọ lori ọrọ ajakalẹ arun Korona to gbode kan."},{"question":" Iza no anaran'ilay mpanoratra Amerikana malaza, nanoratra ilay tantara mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"The Great Gatsby\\"?","answer":"F. Scott Fitzgerald no anaran'ilay mpanoratra Amerikana malaza, nanoratra ilay tantara mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"The Great Gatsby\\"."},{"question":"Katmandou mooy gëblag man réew ?","answer":"Katmandou mooy gëblag réewum Népal."},{"question":"Waa maxay faa’iidada Caafimaad ee laga helo Mooska?","answer":"Moosku wuxuu ka mid yahay khudaarta ugu badan ee dalkeenna laga helo, isla markaana qiimo ahaan ugu jaban. Haddii aad ogaato faa’iidooyinka caafimaad ee mooska, waxaa hubaal inay isbeddeli doonto habka aad u aragto. Cunidda moosku waxay kordhisaa tayada faya-qab iyo caafimaad ee aadanaha.Sidoo kale mooska waxaa laga helaa macdanno kala duwan sida fitamiinnada B6, C, macdanta magnesium, copper, protein iyo dufan.faaiidooyinka laga hello waxaa ka mid ah1. Wuxuu isu-miisaama dheecanada jidhka “hormones”: mooska waxa ku jira xaddi badan oo maaddooyinka Potassium iyo Vitamin B6 ah kuwaas oo sare u qaada soo saarista xaddiga dheecaan walba ee loo baahanyahay.2. Dhiig-karka: Mooska waxaa aad ugu badan maadda potassium, waxaana ku yar cusbada. Hay’adda maamusha cuntada iyo daawada ee dalka Mareykanka ayaa u oggolaatay shirkadaha mooska ka shaqeeya inay si rasmi ah u sheegtaan in mooska uu awood u leedahay inuu yareeyo khatarta dhiig-karka iyo shalalka.3. Wuxuu caawiya Luminta miisaanka dheeriga ah: Moosku waxa uu sahlaa saarista iyo luminta baruurta aan loo baahnayn ee jidhku kaydiyo.4. Wuxuu la dagaallama cudurrada: Moosku waxa uu yareeya sumowga jidhka waxana uu jidhka ka nadiifiyaa wasakhda.5. Waxa laga helaa tamar “Energy”: Mooska waxaa ku jira 3 nooc oo sokor dabiici ah oo kala ah fructose, glucose iyo sucrose kuwaas oo ka caawiya jidhku in uu helo tamar ku filan.6. Waxa uu daweeyaa gaaska: moosku waxa uu ka hortagaa gaaska iyo nabarrada ku samaysma caloosha iyo mindhicirrada. Sidoo kale moosku waxa uu daweeyaa gaaska iyo nabarada caloosha.7. Waa u daawo calool istaagga: Maadaama moosku ka midyahay cunnooyinka ama khudaarta qolofta amaba diirka leh “Fiber” waxa uu daweeyaa calool istaagga. Cun 2xabo oo moos ah maalin walba oo ka takhallus calool istaaga."},{"question":"Haz un plan de tres lugares para ir a Boyacá","answer":"1. El Puente de Boyacá: En este pequeño puente que atraviesa Tunja, luchó el ejército boyacense en 1819, derribando a las tropas españolas; ganando la independencia de Colombia en la“Batalla de Boyacá”.2. Un plan muy popular es dar un paseo por el Pueblito Boyacense en Duitama de calles empedradas y casitas coloridas; el cual alberga réplicas en miniatura de Monguí, Tibasosa, Villa de Leyva, Tenza, Ráquira, Sáchica y El Cocuy. Es considerado \\"La Perla de Boyacá\\".3. Los Termales de Paipa: En Paipa podrás conocer su hermoso Patrimonio Histórico como La Casona del Salitre y el Pantano de Vargas, una escultura que representa la ruta libertadora que le dio a la Gran Colombia su libertad el 7 de Agosto de 1819."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa waxyaalaha Sababa xanuunka yiridka (Gingivitis) iyo habka loo daweeyo ?","answer":"Yiridku waa barar ku dhaca ciridka, caadi ahaan waxaa keena infekshan bakteeriya ah, taas oo hadaan la daweyn sababi karta ilkaha oo ka dhaca qofka. Yiridka waxa uu badanaa ku dhacaa dadka aysan wanaagsaneen nadaafadda ilka hooda, ama aan si fiican u cadeyn ilkahaWaa maxay astaamaha YiridkaYiridka caadi ahaan waa mid aan lahayn xanuun badan oo la dareemo, dhaqtarkaaga ilkaha waa inaad sida ugu dhaqsiyaha badan ula socodsiisa amaba ula xariirta hadii aad isbadal ku aragtidCalaamadaha yiridka waaxaaa ka mid ahCirridka oo casaan noqdaCirridka oo si fudud ku dhiigaCirridka oo barara amaba ilkaha gadaal uga sikadaNeefta afka oo ur aan baxeyn lehCiriidka oo yara birqaIlkaha oo liiqliiqdaIlkaha dareenkooda oo  kordhaYaa Halis Ugu Jiro YiridkaWaxaa halis ugu jiro yiridka dadkaAan cadaysanTubaakada cunaDa’da ahQaba af qallaylkaQaba  Kansarka amaba kuwa Aids qabaIsticmaala daawooyinka u daran ilkahaDhaawac ciridka lehAan caafimaadka ilkahooda ku dadaalin.Maxaa Sababa?Yiridku waxaa keena huurada oo an afka laga suulin. Huurada oo aan laga suulin amaba afka oo an lacadayn si joogta ah waxa ay sababi kartaa in qashin, bakteeriyo iyo xab ay galaan ilkaha iyo ciridka dhaxdooda amaba inta u dhaxayso ilkaha taas oo horseedi karta ilkaha oo dhaca isl markaana burbura dhamaantood. waxaa jira xalaado badan oo kordhiya yiridka waxaa ka mid ahSonkorowHargabka iyo ifiladaWaqtiga uurkaCudurada kale ee ku dhaca afkaSidee Looga Hortagi Karaa?Yiridka waxaa looga hortagi karaa in la joogteeyo cadeynta ilkaha taas oo ay tahay in lagu dadaalo in laga suuliyo afka huurada iyo wasaqda gali karta ilkaha dhaxdooda ama in ta u dhaxaysa ilkaha iyo cirridka si joogta ah mar amaba marwalba oo aad cunno cunto. Ha hilmaamin mar 6dii biloodba inaad  booqato dhaqtarka ilkaha si aad u ogaato xaaalda ikahaagaDaawayntaDhakhtar ilkood u tag haddii aad isku aragto astaamaha kor ku xusan mid ka mid ah. Dhakhtarku ilkaha ayuu huurada ka nadiifinayaa, wuxuuna kuu sheegi doonaa nooca xanuunka ciridka ee ku haya iyo sida loo daaweyn karo.Daawada dabiiciga ah:Haddii aad isku aragtay ciridkaaga oo sii qodmayo, kana durkay ilkaha sida sawirka kore ka muuqata welina aad xal u la’dahay, daawadii cadayga ee dhakhaatiirta kugula taliyeenne ay shaqayn waysay, waxaan kuu hayaa laba talo oo aad isbadal degdeg ah iskaga dareemi doontid Ilaahay idinkiis:Jooji adeegsiga burushka iyo daawooyinka lagu cadaysto “Macjuunta”, kuna badalo geedka rumayga ee lagu cadaysto.Habeenkii inta aadan jiifan, ku luqluqo malab saafi ah, ilkaha iyo ciridka oo idilne wada gaarsii sidaasne ku seexo adigoo wax biyo ah ka daba cabin.Haddii aad wadid talooyinkaas muddo 2 illaa 3 usbuuc ah insha’llah waxaad dareemi doontaa caabuqii yiridka oo yaraaday iyo ciridkii oo bararka joojiyay, bilaabayne inuu dib u soo koro."},{"question":"Qual é a importância dos dados abertos no sistema de transportes de São Paulo?","answer":"Dados abertos são fundamentais para promover a transparência e a prestação de contas. Eles permitem que cidadãos, pesquisadores e organizações monitorem e avaliem a eficiência, segurança e sustentabilidade do sistema de transportes. Além disso, dados abertos podem ajudar na inovação, possibilitando que terceiros desenvolvam soluções e serviços que melhorem a mobilidade urbana."},{"question":"Diniho ity teny manaraka ity: “Babariana daholo ny olona amin’io kolontsaina io.” Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, misy teny feno fankahalana manoloana ny fiaviana ara-kolontsaina ilay fanambarana."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bawah angin\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud negeri-negeri di sebelah Timur. Contoh ayat: Kapal itu belayar ke negeri bawah angin."},{"question":"Maak de volgende zin af: Op de","answer":"Europese kampioenschappen zwemmen 2006 in Boedapest was een achtste plaats op de 200 meter vrije slag haar beste resultaat."},{"question":"Taiza no voalohany nanaovana ny anaran'ny mpianatr'i Jesosy  hoe \\"Kristiana\\" ?","answer":"Tany Antiokia no voalohany nanaovana ny anaran'ny mpianatr'i Jesosy  hoe \\"Kristiana\\" . Ao amin'ny bokin'ny Asan'ny Apostoly toko faha 11 , andininy faha 26 no misy azy ."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" tafita vao rendrika toa ny........................................ \\" ","answer":"\\"  tafita vao rendrika toa ny boka miapita rano \\" "},{"question":"د برتانوي امپراتورۍ د خپلو استعمارونو په کلتورونو او ټولنو څه ډول اغیزه وکړه، او د دغو ملتونو په هویت باندې د استعماري واکمنۍ اوږدې مودې پایلې څه وې؟","answer":"د برتانیې امپراتورۍ د خپلو استعمارونو په کلتورونو او ټولنو ژوره اغیزه درلوده. استعماري واکمنۍ ډیری وختونه د برتانوي موسسو، حقوقي سیسټمونو، او تعلیمي جوړښتونو د تطبیق لامل شوي، چې د مستعمره هیوادونو په هویت اغیزه کوي. د کلتوري یوځای کولو بهیر، د ځایی ژبو او دودونو له مینځه وړلو سره، تلپاتې پایلې درلودې. د استعمار میراث د پخوانیو استعمارونو ټولنیز، سیاسي او اقتصادي منظرو ته دوام ورکوي، د هویت، ملتپالنې، او د استعمار وروسته پراختیا پورې اړوند پیچلو مسلو کې مرسته کوي."},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:وأضاف في تصريحات أعقبت تمرير القانون: \\"علينا وضع حد للإنفاق الحكومي والتضخم\\".وعرقلت الخلافات بين الحزبين","answer":"الديموقراطي والجمهوري التوصل لاتفاق مبكر نتيجة تباين وجهات النظر بشأن عدة قضايا من بينها مستوى الإنفاق الحكومي وتمويل أوكرانيا."},{"question":"Igbakeji gomina Ọṣun ṣabẹwo si abule Wasinmi ti wọn ti pa eeyan mẹfa ninu mọlẹbi kan naa","answer":"Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Wale Ọlọkọde, ti sọ pe ko si ootọ ninu ahesọ kan to n lọ kaakiri pe wahala awọn agbẹ pẹlu awọn Fulani darandaran lo yọri si iku eeyan mẹfa niluu Waasinmi, nijọba ibilẹ Irewọle.Ọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu kẹta, ọdun yii, lawọn agbebọn ya wọ Gaa Fulani to wa niluu naa, ti wọn si pa awọn mẹfa ti wọn jẹ mọlẹbi kan naa.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, fi sita lorukọ kọmiṣanna rẹ, lo ti ṣalaye pe lọgan tiṣẹlẹ naa ṣẹlẹ ni awọn ọlọpaa ilu Ikire atawọn oṣiṣẹ alaabo mi-in ti lọ sibẹ, ṣugbọn bi awọn agbebọn ọhun ṣe foju kan wọn ni awọn agbofinro ni wọn fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ.O ni ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa n ṣiṣẹ takuntakun lọwọ lati tanmọlẹ sidii iṣẹlẹ naa, ko si si ibi ti awọn amookunṣika naa le sa lọ ti ọwọ ko ni i tẹ wọn.Kọmiṣanna fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe ọrọ naa ko ni i ṣe pẹlu ija ẹlẹyamẹya rara, o si kilọ fun awọn ti wọn n dana irọ naa lati kiyesara nitori ko si idagbasoke kankan to le waye nibi ti aibalẹ aya ti ija ẹlẹyamẹya maa n fa ba ti wa.Bakan naa ni Igbakeji gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun, Benedict Alabi, ṣabẹwo sibi iṣẹlẹ naa, to si ṣapejuwe rẹ gẹgẹ bii eyi to buru pupọ.Alabi, ẹni ti awọn kọmisanna ba kọwọọrin sọ fun awọn agbofinro pe wọn gbọdọ ṣawari awọn ti wọn wa nidii iṣekupani naa, ki wọn si foju winna ofin.O tun fi awọn araalu lọkan balẹ pe ko sewu fun ẹmi ati dukia wọn nitori lọsan-an loru lawọn agbofinro yoo maa ṣiṣẹ nibẹ lati ri awọn ọdaran naa mu ati lati dena iru iwa bẹẹ lọjọ iwaju."},{"question":"다음 문단을 완성시키시오.티거 2 전차가 전투에서 최초로 쓰인 것은 1944년 7월 18일의 노르망디 전투였고, 운용 부대는 (Schwere Panzerabteilung 503)였다. 동부전선에서 처음 쓰인 것은 1944년 8월 12일 제501중전차대대(sPzAbt 501)에서였으며, 소련의 비스툴라 강의 에 투입되었다. 후에 티거 2 전차는 특히","answer":"아르덴 반격과 1945년 소련의 폴란드와 동프러시아 공세, 독일의 헝가리 공세, 1945년 4월의 베를린 동부의 젤로브(Seelow) 고지, 마지막으로 베를린에서 등장하였다."},{"question":"ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ਤੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਤੇ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ?","answer":"ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ਤੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ-ਕੇਂਦਰੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ, ਸੰਯੁਕਤ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਸਤਰਿਤ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"පහත ගීතයට තනු නිර්මාණය කලේ කවුද?ඔබේ නමින් සෑය බඳිමි - විමානයෙන් බසිනු මැනවි...//ස්වර්ණමාලියේ රූබර ස්වර්ණමාලියේ...ස්වර්ණමාලියේ..ඔබේ නමින් සෑය බඳිමි - විමානයෙන් බසිනු මැනවි...උණා නීල වර්ණ වරල දෑලේ මල් ගැවසීයේනගා ඉන්ද්‍රචාප දෙබැම ඇසින් විදුලි මවන ලියේවනා ලමැද කිණිහිරි පෙති රත්නතිලක පැලදි ලියේසිනා සිසි විමානයෙන් බසින්න ස්වර්ණමාලියේඅතේ ගිගිරි නාද සලඹ නුරා හඬින් හඬන ලියේකරේ පද්ම කැකුළු මාල හංස තුඩින් පිපෙන ලියේකනේ තෝඩු මිණ ඝන රන් මූණ ‍ඔපය කරන ලියේපමා නොවී විමානයෙන් බසින්න ස්වර්ණමාලියේබාල චන්ද්‍ර පටුනලලත අලක පඬුන් රඟන ලියේආල වඩන දන්ත කැකුළු කුන්ඩ සමන් පිපෙන ලියේදෑල දෑත ස්වර්ණදාම පාන හඬට සැලෙන ලියේකෝල නොවී විමානයේ බසින්න ස්වර්ණමාලියේස්වර්ණමාලියේ රූබර ස්වර්ණමාලියේ....ස්වර්ණමාලියේ...","answer":"පණ්ඩිත් අමරදේවයන් මෙම ගීතයට හඬ මුසුකරයි."},{"question":"શોનું ભાવિ શું છે - ગ્રેની એનાટોમી?","answer":"ગ્રેની એનાટોમી હાલમાં તેની 19મી સીઝનમાં છે અને તે હજુ પણ મજબૂત ચાલી રહી છે. આ શોને 20મી અને 21મી સિઝન માટે રિન્યૂ કરવામાં આવ્યો છે અને શક્ય છે કે તે હજુ પણ વધુ સમય સુધી ચાલુ રહી શકે. જો કે, શોનું ભાવિ આખરે તેની સતત લોકપ્રિયતા અને તેના નિર્માતાઓના સર્જનાત્મક નિર્ણયો પર નિર્ભર રહેશે."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì?  Tôi đã rất sốc trước những lời nói đó. (Ảnh minh họa) Vợ chồng tôi cưới nhau sau 3 năm yêu nhau. Chúng tôi sau ngày cưới đã vun vén để mua trả góp được căn nhà chung cư nhỏ. Cuộc sống tưởng chừng đã hạnh phúc viên mãn khi có với nhau được cậu con trai 5 tuổi. Thế nhưng mấy tháng trước chồng tôi bất ngờ qua đời vì đột quỵ. Khi đó, con trai tôi vừa bước qua sinh nhật 5 tuổi. Tôi đau đớn vô cùng trước sự ra đi đột ngột của chồng. Nỗi đau mất đi chồng của mình là cú sốc quá lớn. Tôi không thể chấp nhận được, nhưng vì con và bố mẹ chồng phải gắng gượng không làm điều dại dột. Sống cùng với bố mẹ chồng mấy năm nay, ông bà đối xử với tôi rất tốt. Ông bà đối xử với tôi chẳng khác gì con gái trong nhà. Sau ngày chồng tôi mất được mấy tháng, bố mẹ chồng có khuyên tôi nên tái hôn. Thậm chí, ông bà còn trực tiếp tìm người giới thiệu cho tôi. Ban đầu tôi nghĩ là ông bà thương tôi còn trẻ nên không muốn để tôi ở vậy vì chuyện của con trai mình. Ông bà thậm chí còn bảo sẽ giữ con trai tôi lại chăm sóc để tôi không phải vướng bận gì. Nếu như tôi mang theo con nhỏ sẽ rất phiền phức khi có mối quan hệ mới. Trước những tâm tư của bố mẹ chồng, tôi đã rất cảm động vì nghĩ bố mẹ chồng thương mình. Tôi chỉ muốn sống trong những kỉ niệm với chồng, chăm sóc cho con và bố mẹ chồng nên chưa bao giờ nghĩ đến chuyện tái hôn. Tôi cương quyết từ chối lời đề nghị ấy. Tưởng rằng ông bà sẽ không còn nhắc tới chuyện này nữa. Tạm lắng mọi chuyện một thời gian, gần đây ông bà lại nhắc lại. Nhất là khi có sự xuất hiện của một người họ hàng ở xa về chơi đã cho tôi thấy được một sự thật choáng váng. Trong câu chuyện giữa bố mẹ chồng tôi cùng với người họ hàng ấy, tôi láng máng nghe được nói tôi có tướng sát phu nên chồng tôi mới chết yểu. Vì tôi mà bố mẹ chồng không còn có người con trai phụng dưỡng bố mẹ. Bố mẹ chồng muốn đuổi tôi ra khỏi nhà. Tôi đã rất sốc trước những lời nói đó. Vào buổi chiều hôm đó tôi đã nói thẳng với ông bà là dù tôi có đi khỏi nhà này, tôi cũng dứt khoát phải mang theo con trai chứ không bao giờ rời xa con. Tôi cũng đề nghị ông bà chia đôi căn nhà đang ở đứng tên vợ chồng tôi. Sau khi định giá căn nhà, tôi sẽ lấy một nửa, còn trả lại cho bố mẹ chồng một nửa. Thế nhưng bố mẹ chồng nhất quyết không đồng ý. Họ nói đó là máu thịt duy nhất của con trai họ nên phải ở cùng ông bà nội và cũng không muốn đưa tiền cho tôi. Sau khi chồng tôi mất, tôi không thể nghĩ là bố mẹ chồng lại có thể thay đổi chóng mặt như vậy. Mọi chuyện càng lúc càng trở nên căng thẳng. Cuối cùng việc thương lượng giữa đôi bên vô hiệu. Để giải quyết mọi việc, giờ tôi phải nhờ đến pháp luật. Tôi chỉ cảm thấy thương cho con, thương cho bản thân mình và cả người chồng đã mất trước sự việc đau lòng này. Nguồn: https://giadinh.suckhoedoisong.vn/bo-me-chong-thuc-ep-toi-tai-hon-khi-chong-vua-moi-qua-doi-biet...Nguồn: https://giadinh.suckhoedoisong.vn/bo-me-chong-thuc-ep-toi-tai-hon-khi-chong-vua-moi-qua-doi-biet-duoc-ly-do-toi-thuc-su-soc-nang-172220729215927746.htm ","answer":"Bố mẹ chồng thúc ép tôi tái hôn khi chồng vừa mới qua đời, biết được lý do tôi thực sự sốc nặng"},{"question":"ما هو عدد الاسنان لدى القط؟","answer":"\\tالجواب: أربعون سن."},{"question":"Nakumpleto ni Pedro ang mga pagsasanay sa pahina 279, 256, 264, 259, at 192. Paano mo isusulat ang mga numerong ito sa pataas na pagkakasunud-sunod?","answer":"192, 256, 259, 264, 279."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai beting dipalu ombak\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kehidupan yang tidak tenteram, senantiasa diganggu orang."},{"question":"Алыкул Осмоновтун калемине таандык ырлардан жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"АДАМЗАТМүрөктүн суусу жөн суулардай шылдырап,Агып жатса мал кечпес жашыл аралда.Көк арчадай өңдөн азбас болсун деп,Өзүм ичпей, ичирер элем адамга.Мүрөктүн суусун ичирейин дегеним:Адам деген картайгыч тура бечара.Замзамдын суусу кайнар суудай шарактап,Ташып жатса куш жете албас ыраакта.Эти калың пилдей күчтүү болсун деп,Бүт агымын бурар элем адамга.Замзамдын суусун агызайын дегеним:Адам деген чарчагыч тура бечара.Олуя табып Улукман аке дарысы,Жазгы гүлдөй тепселип жатса талаада.Жүрөк оору, өпкө оорунун сообу үчүн,Өзүм ичпей ичирер элем адамга.Дары чөптү ичирейин дегеним:Адам деген оорукчан тура бечара.Ак шайы көйнөк, күмүш кемер сыяктуу,Адамдын жаны сатылып турса базарда.Дагы жыргап, дагы жашап көрсүн деп,Өзүм албай берер элем адамга.Жандарына жан кошоюн дегеним:Адам деген көп өлгүч тура бечара."},{"question":" वाचन यादीमध्ये (Reading List) व्हिडिओ गेम जोडणारा पहिला देश कोणता?उत्तर : ","answer":" वाचन यादीमध्ये (Reading List) व्हिडिओ गेम जोडणारा पहिला देश पोलंड."},{"question":"Виріши задачу та дай відповідь на запитання. Умова: Петрик записував зростання свого цуценя щороку. Коли цуценя подарували, його зріст був 20 см. Через рік — 36 см, через два роки — 44 см, через три роки — 48 см. Питання: Який зріст (в см) буде у цуценя Петрика через п'ять років після дарування, якщо закономірність зміни росту збережеться?","answer":"Рішення: Простежимо зміну зросту цуценяти (в см) кожного року. Через рік, цуценя викросло на 36-20 = 16 см. Через два роки - на 44 - 36 = 8 см. Через три роки - на 48 - 44 = 4 см. Оскільки зріст собаки змінився на 16 см, 8 см, та 4 см кожного року відповідно, можемо зробити висновок що кожного року собака зростає у 2 рази менше ніж попереднього року. Отже, за 4 рік собака виросте на 4 / 2 = 2 cм, її зріст буде 48 + 2 = 50 см. А за 5 рік - собака зросте на 2 / 2 = 1 см, а отже її фінальний зріст буде 50 + 1 = 51 см.Остаточна відповідь: через 5 років зріст собаки буде 51 см."},{"question":"青楼在中国历史上的地位是什么？","answer":"答：青楼在中国历史上是社会生活的一部分，它们不仅提供性服务，还是音乐、舞蹈、诗词和绘画等艺术形式的重要场所。"},{"question":"අන්දකයිප්පු, කියන්නේ මොකක්ද ?","answer":"ආන්ද්‍ර දේශයෙන් ගෙන්වන කයිප්පුකයිප්පු යනු ලාකඩ වැනි මැලියමකි. එය බුලත් සමඟ කෑම ට ගනී. මදක් වැඩි වූවොත් මත්වේ අධිකව කැවුනොත් සිහිවිකල් වේ"},{"question":" ਜਨਰਲ ਡਾਇਰ ਕੌਣ ਸੀ?","answer":"1919 ਦੇ ਖੂਨੀ ਸਾਕੇ ਉੱਤੇ 1969 ਵਿਚ ਲਿਖੀ ਗਈ ਕਿਤਾਬ 'ਜਲ੍ਹਿਆਂਵਾਲਾ ਬਾਗ' ਦੇ ਲੇਖਕ ਵੀਐੱਨ ਦੱਤਾ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਜਲ੍ਹਿਆਂਵਾਲਾ ਬਾਗ ਖ਼ੂਨੀ ਕਾਂਡ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਜਾਮ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਰਤਾਨਵੀਂ ਫੌਜੀ ਅਫ਼ਸਰ ਜਨਰਲ ਡਾਇਰ ਦਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਨਾਂ ਰੈਡੀਨਾਲਡ ਐਡਵਰਡ ਹੈਰੀ ਡਾਇਰ ਸੀ।ਜਲ੍ਹਿਆਂਵਾਲਾ ਕਾਂਡ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਭਾਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਬ੍ਰਿਟੇਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਤਿੱਖੀ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਬਹੁਗਿਣਤੀ ਭਾਰਤੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸ ਕਾਂਡ ਨੇ ਬਰਤਾਨਵੀਂ ਹਕੂਮਤ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਰੋਹ ਜਗਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਸੀ।ਵੀਐੱਨ ਦੱਤਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਲੇਖ 'ਜਲ੍ਹਿਆਂਵਾਲਾ ਬਾਗ : ਕਤਲੇਆਮ ਤੇ ਪਰਿਣਾਮֹ' ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਖਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਡਾਇਰ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦਾ ਭਾਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ ਕਰੀਬ ਇੱਕ ਸਦੀ ਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਦਾਦਾ ਜੌਹਨ ਐਡਵਰਡ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 7 ਜੁਲਾਈ 1831 ਨੂੰ ਕੋਲਕਾਤਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਵਸ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।ਜਨਰਲ ਨੇ ਮੁੱਢਲੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਸ਼ਿਮਲਾ ਦੇ ਬਿਸ਼ਪ ਕਾਟਨ ਤੋਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਕਾਲਜ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਆਇਰਲੈਂਡ ਤੋਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ। ਡਾਇਰ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਜੰਗੀ ਮੁਹਿੰਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਰਗਰਮ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਭਾਰਤ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਜਲੰਧਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਡਾਇਰ ਨੂੰ ਬ੍ਰਿਗੇਡ ਕਮਾਂਡਰ ਲਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਸਾਲ 1919 ਦੇ ਮਾਰਚ -ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਲੋਕ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਨੂੰ ਦਬਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਉਹ ਜਲੰਧਰ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ 10 ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ ਨੂੰ ਫੌਜੀ ਦਸਤਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ ਪਹੁੰਚਿਆ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Làm tròn số  69,283 đến chữ số thập phân thứ hai ta đượcA. 69,28B. 69,29C. 69,30D. 69,284","answer":"Trả lời:Vì số 69,283 có chữ số thập phân thứ ba là 3 < 5 nên làm tròn đến chữ số thập phân thứ hai ta được 69,283 ≈ 69,28Đáp án cần chọn là: A"},{"question":"கேள்வி: பெரிய புராணம் என்கிற நூலின் ஆசிரியர் யார்? ","answer":"பதில்: பெரியபுராணம் அல்லது திருத்தொண்டர் புராணம் என்பது சேக்கிழார் அவர்களால் பெருங்காப்பிய இலக்கணங்கள் பலவும் கொண்டதாக இயற்றப்பெற்ற சைவ காப்பியமாகும். சுந்தரமூர்த்தி சுவாமிகளின் திருத்தொண்டத் தொகை எனும் நூலை முதல் நூலாகக் கொண்டும். சுந்தரமூர்த்தி சுவாமிகளைக் காப்பிய தலைவராகக் கொண்டும், அவர் போற்றிய சைவ அடியார்களின் வாழ்க்கை வரலாற்றினையும் இந்நூலை சேக்கிழார் விவரிக்கிறார்.சேக்கிழார் என்பவர் 12-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் வாழ்ந்த சிவனடியார் ஆவார். இவர் இரண்டாம் குலோத்துங்க சோழனின் அரசவையில் முதன்மை அமைச்சராக இருந்தவர். சோழன் சீவகசிந்தாமணி எனும் காமரசம் அதிகமுள்ள சமண நூலைப் படிப்பதனால், சோழனையும் மக்களையும் நல்வழிப்படுத்த சிவபெருமானின் அடியார்களான அறுபத்து மூன்று நாயன்மார்களின் வரலாற்றை விளக்கும் திருத்தொண்டர் புராணத்தினை இயற்றியவர் ஆவார்.பெரியபுராணத்தைப் பாட தில்லையில் சிவபெருமானே 'உலகெலாம்' என்று அடியெடுத்துக் கொடுத்தாக நம்பிக்கையுண்டு. சிவத்தொண்டின் காரணமாகவும், மதிநுட்பத்தின் காரணமாகவும் இவர் உத்தம சோழப் பல்லவன், தொண்டர் சீர் பரவுவார், தெய்வப்புலவர், தெய்வச்சேக்கிழார் போன்ற பட்டங்களைப் பெற்றவர். உமாபதி சிவாச்சாரியார் என்பவரால் சேக்கிழார் புராணம் எனும் நூலும், மீனாட்சிசுந்தரம் பிள்ளை அவர்களால் சேக்கிழார் பிள்ளைத்தமிழ் எனும் நூலும் சேக்கிழாரை முன்வைத்து இயற்றப்பட்டுள்ளது.பெயர்க்காரணம்சே என்பதற்குக் காளை என்றும் சேக்கிழார் என்றால் காளைக்கு உரியவர் என்று பொருள் தருவதாகும். காளையை வைத்து உழவுத்தொழில் செய்து வந்தோர்களில் அமைச்சராகவும், சிவனடியாராகவும் சிறந்து விளங்கியமையால் இயற்பெயரான அருண்மொழித்தேவர் என்பது மறைந்து சேக்கிழார் என்பதே பெயராக அறியப்படுகிறது.[சான்று தேவை]வரலாறுகீழ்வருகின்ற சேக்கிழார் வரலாறு சேக்கிழார் புராணம் எனும் உமாபதி சிவாச்சாரியாரால் எழுதப்பெற்ற நூலை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டதாகும். இந்நூலில் வருகின்ற சில செய்திகளையும், இந்த நூலின் ஆசிரியர் உமாபதி சிவாச்சாரியார் என்பதையும், மா. இராசமாணிக்கனார் எனும் ஆய்வாளர் மறுத்துள்ளார்.பிறப்புபொ.ஊ. 12-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் தொண்டை நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த புலியூர்க் கோட்டத்தில் உள்ள குன்றத்தூர் என்னும் ஊரில் வேளாளர் மரபில் வெள்ளியங்கிரி மற்றும் அழகாம்பிகை ஆகியோருக்கு முதல் மகனாகச் சேக்கிழார் பிறந்தார்.[சான்று தேவை] இவருக்குப் பெற்றோர் அருண்மொழித்தேவர் என்று பெயரிட்டனர். இவருக்குப் பாலறாவாயர் என்ற தம்பியும் இருந்தார்.இளமைப் பருவம்சோழநாட்டு அரசனான இரண்டாம் குலோத்துங்க சோழன் அநபாயசோழருக்குக் கடலினும் பெரியது எது? உலகினும் பெரியது எது? மலையினும் பெரியது எது? என்ற கேள்விகள் தோன்றின. அநபாய சோழரின் அமைச்சராக இருந்த சேக்கிழாரின் தந்தை இந்தக் கேள்விகளுக்கு விடைதெரியாது தவித்த பொழுது, சேக்கிழார் விடையை அளித்தார். அதனை மன்னரிடம் கூறியமையால் சேக்கிழாருக்கு அமைச்சர் பதவியை அநபாய சோழர் அளித்தார்.சேக்கிழார்க்கு உத்தம சோழப் பல்லவன் என்ற சிறப்புப் பட்டத்தினைத் தந்தார் அரசன். சேக்கிழார் திருநாகேசுவரம் கோயில் இறைவன் மீது பற்று வைத்திருந்தார். அதனால் குன்றத்தூரில் திருநாகேசுவரம் என்ற பெயரிலேயே கோயிலொன்றினைக் கட்டினார்."},{"question":"Awọn ajinigbe tun ji ọba alaye gbe ni Kogi","answer":"Ọrọ awọn agbebọn yii ti waa kọja sisọ bayii, bi awọn kan ṣe n bọ loko ẹru wọn ni wọn tu n ji awọn mi-in gbe. Ni nnkan bii aago marun-un aabọ aarọ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, yii, ni wọn tun ji Adele ọba kan, Alaaji Shaibu Usman, Eje ti ilu Ankpa, nipinlẹ Kogi lọ. Mọṣalaaṣi ilu naa to wa ni Ankpa, ni ọba naa n lọ lati kirun ti wọn fi dena de e, ti wọn si gbe e lọ sibi ti ẹnikẹni ko ti i mọ di ba a ṣe n sọ yii. ALAROYE gbọ pe wọn ti dena de ọkunrin naa nitosi mọṣalaaṣi yii ko to debẹ, bi ọba alaye naa si ṣe n wọbẹ bayii ni wọn gbe e, ti ko si ti i sẹni to mọ ibi to wa, bẹẹ lawọn ajinigbe yii ko ti i kan si awọn mọlẹbi lati mọ ohun ti wọn n fẹ gan-an.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Kogi, Ayuba Edeh, fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, bẹẹ lo ni gbogbo ipa lawọn yoo ṣa lati ri ọba alaye yii gba pada lọwọ awọn ajinnigbe naa."},{"question":"පරම්පරාවෙන් ලැබෙන අයිතිය  යන්නට තනි වචනයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"උරුමය "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'hutang darah'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Hutang darah bermaksud menuntut bela atas sesuatu kejadian. Contoh ayat: \\"Ismail berhutang darah denganku, kerana dia telah menyebabkan kematian adikku\\", kata Ehsan."},{"question":"Туура аналогияны таңда.Үшүү : тоңуу(А) иретсиз : баш аламан (Б) соолуу : кууроо(В) чочуу : кыйкыруу (Г) оңдоо : бузуу","answer":"1)Эталондук(үлгү) жуп: үшүү : тоңуу;2)Үлгү жуптагы байланыштын түрү : Интенсивдүүлүк(даража) байланышы;3)Интенсивдүүлүк(даража) байланышындагы аналогиянын түрү:Күчөтмө даражадагы аналогиялар;Үлгү жуптагы окшоштукта үшүүнүн күчөтүлгөн даражасы тоңуу болот, ошондой эле бул сөздөр кыймыл-аракетти билдирет. Иретсиз : баш аламан окшоштугунда да ушундай байланыш болгону менен бул сөздөр кыймыл-аракетти билдирбейт, андыктан бул вариантты туура жооп катары албайбыз. Кууроо соолунун күчөтүлүшү, башкача айтанда, соолуган нерсени суулабаса, ал куурап калат. Чочуу : кыйкыруу окшоштугунда даража байланышы жок, чочуган адам кыйкырат. Демек, мында себеп жана натыйжа байланышы бар. Ошол сыяктуу эле (Г) варианты да себеп жана натыйжа байланышында түзүлгөн"},{"question":"من كان المدير الرئيسي للفريق الذي فاز ببطولة سوبر بول السابعة؟","answer":"دون شولا"},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase:  Davis foi o Oficial-chefe do navio \\"Nimrod\\" durante a","answer":"Expedição \\"Nimrod\\" de Ernest Shackleton, em 1908–1909. Foi Capitão do \\"Aurora\\" e imediato na Expedição da Australásia na Antártica de Douglas Mawson, em 1911–1914."},{"question":"विश्व युद्ध 2 कब और कैसे शुरू हुआ था?","answer":"विश्व युद्ध 2, 1939 में आरम्भ हुआ था, जब जर्मनी ने पोलैंड पर हमला किया।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਮਨਿ ਬਿਲਾਸੁ ਬਹੁ ਰੰਗੁ ਘਣਾ ਦ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਭੂਲਿ ਖੁਸੀਆ ॥ਛਤ੍ਰਧਾਰ ਬਾਦਿਸਾਹੀਆ ਵਿਚਿ ਸਹਸੇ ਪਰੀਆ ॥੧॥ਭਾਈ ਰੇ ਸੁਖੁ ਸਾਧਸੰਗਿ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਲਿਖਿਆ ਲੇਖੁ ਤਿਨਿ ਪੁਰਖਿ ਬਿਧਾਤੈ ਦੁਖੁ ਸਹਸਾ ਮਿਟਿ ਗਇਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਜੇਤੇ ਥਾਨ ਥਨੰਤਰਾ ਤੇਤੇ ਭਵਿ ਆਇਆ ॥ਧਨ ਪਾਤੀ ਵਡ ਭੂਮੀਆ ਮੇਰੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਕਰਿ ਪਰਿਆ ॥੨॥ਹੁਕਮੁ ਚਲਾਏ ਨਿਸੰਗ ਹੋਇ ਵਰਤੈ ਅਫਰਿਆ ॥ਸਭੁ ਕੋ ਵਸਗਤਿ ਕਰਿ ਲਇਓਨੁ ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਖਾਕੁ ਰਲਿਆ ॥੩॥ਕੋਟਿ ਤੇਤੀਸ ਸੇਵਕਾ ਸਿਧ ਸਾਧਿਕ ਦਰਿ ਖਰਿਆ ॥ਗਿਰੰਬਾਰੀ ਵਡ ਸਾਹਬੀ ਸਭੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਸੁਪਨੁ ਥੀਆ ॥੪॥੨॥੭੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 42 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਕਈ ਕਿਸਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਚਾ-ਮਲ੍ਹਾਰ ਹੋਵੇ, ਜੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੀਆਂ) ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਭੁੱਲੀ ਰਹੇਜੇ ਅਜੇਹੀਆਂ ਬਾਦਿਸ਼ਾਹੀਆਂ ਮਿਲੀਆਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਹੋਣ ਕਿ ਸਿਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਛਤਰ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿਣ, ਤਾਂ ਭੀ (ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਇਹ ਸਭ ਮੌਜਾਂ) ਸਹਮ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਈ ਰੱਖਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।੧।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ (ਹੀ) ਸੁਖ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਸਿਰਜਨਹਾਰ ਨੇ (ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਚੰਗੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਦਾ) ਲੇਖ ਲਿਖ ਦਿੱਤਾ (ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਤਸੰਗ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ) ਦੁੱਖ ਸਹਮ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਧਰਤੀ ਦੇ ਜਿਤਨੇ ਭੀ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਥਾਂ ਹਨ (ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਥਾਂ ਭਉਂ ਭਉਂ ਕੇ ਵੇਖ ਆਇਆ ਹੋਵੇ ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਬਹੁਤ ਧਨਾਢ ਹੋਵੇ, ਬਹੁਤ ਭੁਇਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੋਵੇ, ਤਾਂ ਭੀ (ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ) ‘ਮੇਰੀ ਭੁਇਂ’ ਆਖ ਆਖ ਕੇ ਦੁਖੀ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਡਰ-ਖ਼ਤਰਾ-ਝਾਕਾ ਲਾਹ ਕੇ (ਲੋਕਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ) ਆਪਣਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਚਲਾਏ, ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਬੜੀ ਆਕੜ ਵਾਲਾ ਸਲੂਕ ਕਰੇਜੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਹਰੇਕ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਵੱਸ ਵਿਚ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੋਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਭੀ (ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਂਜਿਆ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ) ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ (ਸੁਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ, ਤੇ ਆਖ਼ਰ) ਮਿੱਟੀ ਵਿਚ ਰਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਤੇ ਤੇਤੀ ਕ੍ਰੋੜ ਦੇਵਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਬਣ ਜਾਣ, ਸਿੱਧ ਤੇ ਸਾਧਿਕ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਖਲੋਤੇ ਰਹਿਣਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਇਤਨੀ ਵੱਡੀ ਹਕੂਮਤਿ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ, ਕਿ ਭਾਰੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰੀ ਭੀ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਏ,ਤਾਂ ਭੀ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਸੁਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ, ਤੇ) ਇਹ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ (ਆਖ਼ਰ) ਸੁਪਨਾ ਹੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੨।੭੨।\\""},{"question":"Karın Guruldaması gaz mıdır?","answer":"Bebeğinizin karın gurultusu genel olarak sindirim sistemi ile alakalıdır. Bebeğiniz, anne sütüne veya mamaya alışıyorken midesinde gaz ve basınç olabilir. Bu gaz ve basınç da karın guruldamasına neden olur. Bebeğinizin karnında meydana gelen guruldamaya neden olur."},{"question":"ことわざで「川流れ」したり、「なまずを押さえ」たり、「駒」が出てくるウリ科の植物は？","answer":"ヒョウタンです。"},{"question":"Ẹ kilọ fun Matawalle ko yee sọsọkusọ o-Gani Adams","answer":"Pẹlu ibinu ni Aarẹ Ọna-kakanfo ilẹ Yoruba, Oloye Gani Adams, fi sọrọ si Gomina ipinlẹ Zamfara, Muhammed Matawalle, o ni ẹni ba moju gomina naa ko kilọ fun un pẹlu irọ buruku to n pa kiri pe awọn eeyan apa Guusu ilẹ wa n pa awọn ara Ariwa, iyẹn awọn ara Oke-Ọya, ati pe wọn gbọdọ dawọ eleyii duro ti wọn ko ba fẹ ki awọn Hausa naa gbẹsan iwa yii lara awọn eeyan wọn to wa nilẹ Hausa.Gani ni afi ki wọn tete kilọ fun ọkunrin naa gidigidi, ko ma fi ọrọ ẹlẹyamẹya ṣe oṣelu to le da wahala silẹ.Gani Adams ni afi ẹni ti yoo ba purọ lo ku, lo maa sọ pe awọn ẹya Guusu kọju ija si awọn eeyan Oke-Ọya. O ni gbogbo awọn ara Oke-Ọya to wa ni ilẹ Yoruba ni wọn n ṣiṣẹ aje wọn nibi ti ko sẹni to di wọn lọwọ. Aarẹ ni ko si ẹni to le di ẹnikẹni to ba n ṣiṣẹ rẹ lọna to tọ lọwọ, afi awọn ti wọn ba jẹ arufin nikan ni ilẹ Yoruba ko ni i faaye gba.O ni oun ko mọ ibi ti Matawalle ti ri iroyin to n gbe kiri, nitori gbogbo awọn ti wọn jẹ atọhunrinwa ti wọn huwa ọdaran paapaa, ko sẹni to fọwọ kan wọn, awọn agbofinro ni wọn fa wọn le lọwọ.Ọkunrin naa ni ‘Mo n sọrọ lorukọ gbogbo ọmọ Yoruba pe ko sẹnikẹni to di awọn eeyan Oke-Ọya lọwọ. A ko di awọn ti wọn n ṣiṣẹ aje wọn lọna ẹtọ lọwọ, oju si gba mi ti pe odidi gomina le ma sọ iru ahesọ ti ko lẹsẹ nilẹ yii kaakiri.’O waa rọ ọ lati yee lo ọrọ ẹlẹyamẹya lati fi maa wa ojurere ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC to n gbero lati darapọ mọ bayii. O ni ki Matawalle rọra kọja sinu ẹgbẹ APC to n lọ lai da wahala kankan silẹ, ki wọn le baa maa fi ojurere wo o, ki wọn si le fun un ni anfaani lati tun dupo lọdun 2023.Bakan naa ni Aarẹ Adams koro oju si ọrọ kan ti Minisita fun ọrọ abẹle nile wa tẹlẹ, Abdurahman Dambazzau, sọ pe ko si iyatọ laarin awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ Oodua OPC, ati ẹgbẹ awọn ọmọ Ibo IPOB, pẹlu Boko Haram.Aarẹ ni bo tilẹ jẹ pe agbẹnusọ ẹgbẹ OPC ti fun ọkunrin yii lesi ọrọ rẹ, sibẹ, o yẹ ki awọn agbaagba ilẹ Hausa maa ko awọn eeyan naa ni ijanu ki wọn yee maa sọsọkusọ kiri.Bakan naa ni ẹgbẹ agba Yoruba, YCE ti bu ẹnu atẹ lu ọrọ ti gomina ipinlẹ Zamfara sọ yii, wọn ni ọrọ ti ko mu ọgbọn dani, ti ko nitumọ, ti ọkunrin naa ko si ni ẹri kan lati fi gbe e lẹsẹ lo n sọ kiri. Ẹgbẹ naa ni ọrọ to le da ogun silẹ ni gomina naa n sọ."},{"question":"Dezuo Ilu a:Ekwughi ekwu mere ọnụ .","answer":"Egeghi ege mee ntị.Ihe ilu a na akọwa bụ na okwu ezuworo onye mara ihe"},{"question":"سوال: وہ کون سی چیز ہے جس میں چابیاں ہیں لیکن تالے نہیں کھول سکتے؟","answer":"جواب: ایک پیانو۔ ایک پیانو میں چابیاں ہوتی ہیں جو میوزیکل نوٹ تیار کرتی ہیں، لیکن وہ تالے نہیں کھولتی ہیں۔"},{"question":"Completa la siguiente frase: Fue figura clave de la selección alemana campeona mundial de 1990 y capitaneó a su selección campeona de la…","answer":"Eurocopa 1996, además de en los mundiales de 1994 y 1998. Tras su retiro en 1998, se radicó en Estados Unidos."},{"question":"i) A = B అయిన n(A) = n(B)ii) n(A) = n(B) అయిన A = B అయినA) i మాత్రమే సత్యంB) ii మాత్రమే సత్యంC) i మరియు ii లు సత్యంD) పైవి ఏవీ కావు","answer":"A) i మాత్రమే సత్యం"},{"question":"Apakah maksud peribahasa \\"kain sehelai sepinggang habis\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah mengalami kerugian dalam perniagaan atau kerana kecurian."},{"question":"උත්තම යනු තද්ධිතයක් නොවේද?","answer":"තුම් +තම තද්ධිත තමයි"},{"question":"મને સુમિત ભરોડિયા એક પ્રેરક વક્તા વિશે કહો.","answer":"સુમિત ભરોડિયા: સુમિત ભરોડિયા એક યુવાન અને ગતિશીલ ગુજરાતી પ્રેરક વક્તા અને ઉદ્યોગસાહસિક છે જે પ્રેરણા માટેના તેમના નવીન અભિગમ માટે જાણીતા છે. તેઓ 'સુમિત ભરોડિયા મોટિવેશનલ સેમિનાર' સંસ્થાના સ્થાપક છે, જે વ્યક્તિગત વિકાસ અને વ્યવસાયિક સફળતા પર વર્કશોપ, સેમિનાર અને તાલીમ કાર્યક્રમોનું આયોજન કરે છે."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa hamse cumar binu qadaam imisa malmod ayey kala dabeyen so kali daga dinta islamka?","answer":"Waxay Kala dabeyeen sadax malmood.."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ॥ਓਇ ਜੁ ਦੀਸਹਿ ਅੰਬਰਿ ਤਾਰੇ ॥ਕਿਨਿ ਓਇ ਚੀਤੇ ਚੀਤਨਹਾਰੇ ॥੧॥ਕਹੁ ਰੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ ਅੰਬਰੁ ਕਾ ਸਿਉ ਲਾਗਾ ॥ਬੂਝੈ ਬੂਝਨਹਾਰੁ ਸਭਾਗਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸੂਰਜ ਚੰਦੁ ਕਰਹਿ ਉਜੀਆਰਾ ॥ਸਭ ਮਹਿ ਪਸਰਿਆ ਬ੍ਰਹਮ ਪਸਾਰਾ ॥੨॥ਕਹੁ ਕਬੀਰ ਜਾਨੈਗਾ ਸੋਇ ॥ਹਿਰਦੈ ਰਾਮੁ ਮੁਖਿ ਰਾਮੈ ਹੋਇ ॥੩॥੨੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 329 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਉਹ ਤਾਰੇ ਜੋ ਅਕਾਸ਼ ਵਿਚ ਦਿੱਸ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ,  ਕਿਸ ਚਿੱਤ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਚਿੱਤਰੇ ਹਨ? ।੧।ਦੱਸ, ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ! ਅਕਾਸ਼ ਕਿਸ ਦੇ ਸਹਾਰੇ ਹੈ? ਕੋਈ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਸਿਆਣਾ ਬੰਦਾ ਹੀ ਇਸ (ਰਮਜ਼ ਨੂੰ) ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਇਹ ਜੋ) ਸੂਰਜ ਤੇ ਚੰਦ੍ਰਮਾ (ਆਦਿਕ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਚਾਨਣ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ (ਇਹਨਾਂ) ਸਭਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਜੋਤਿ ਦਾ (ਹੀ) ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਖਿਲਰਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।੨।ਹੇ ਕਬੀਰ! (ਬੇਸ਼ੱਕ) ਆਖ—(ਇਸ ਭੇਤ ਨੂੰ) ਓਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਮਝੇਗਾ, ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿਚ (ਭੀ) ਕੇਵਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਜੋ ਮੂੰਹੋਂ ਭੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਉਚਾਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ) ।੩।੨੯।\\""},{"question":"Buatlah kalimat lanjutan dari penggalan teks di bawah ini agar menjadi sebuah paragraf yang koheren sesuai topik atau judul yang diberikan.Paragraf yang dibuat harus dapat menjawab pertanyaan: \\"Apa fungsi kesenian tari?\\"Topik: Kesenian Tradisi Sumatera Barat.Tari rakyat adalah seni tari yang ...","answer":"lahir dan berkembang di tengah rakyat, bersifat sederhana, spontan, dan akrab serta mudah menyesuaikan diri dengan situasi dan kondisi masyarakat. Pertumbuhan seni Minangkabau merupakan bagian dari permainan rakyat yang lahir di waktu senggang karena duduak bapamainan, tegak bapatintang. Oleh sebab itu, fungsi tari pada permulaannya adalah sebagai perintang hati atau sebagai hiburan. Namun, sesuai dengan perkembangannya, di antara tari itu ada yang menggambarkan penghormatan kepada tamu seperti tari gelombang, tari tan bentan yang menggambarkan kepahlawanan putra minang di zaman lampau, dan tari tupai jenjang yang berisikan ajaran tentang moral tingkah laku, maka tari di Minangkabau bukan hanya berfungsi sebagai hiburan, tetapi juga sosial dan komunikatif."},{"question":"கேள்வி : விண்வெளியில் வைரம் தயாரித்த முதல் நாடு எது ?","answer":"பதில் : ஜப்பான்."},{"question":"\\"Көк бөрү\\" деген эмне?","answer":"Көк бөрү – ат үстүндө ойнолуучу улуттук оюн.“Көк бөрү” оюнунун жаралышы алыскы тарыхка барып такалып, тамыры терең. Көчмөндөр коомунда эркектер элди тамак аш менен камсыз кылуу максатта ууга чыгып, мал жандыктар аксакал, аялдар жана жаш балдардын карамагында калган. Ошол учурда карышкырлар айылга кирип келип, малдарды кырып, айыл элине коптөгөн кыйынчылыктарды алып келген күндөр арбын болгон. Аңчылыктан кайтып келген эр жигиттер мындай көрүнүшкө жини келип, чымыр, шамдагай, күлүк аттары менен карышкырлардын үүрүнө ууга чыгышкан.Үүрдү кубалап жеткен соң качып бараткан карышкырды жерден эңип, бири бирине ыргытышып, кайра бөрүнү талаша бири-биринин колунан жулушуп ойношкон.Алыскы доордо оюндун негизги багыты, жоого даярданууга багытталган. Оюн учурунда аттарда, ат үстүндөгү эр жигиттер да чыйралып, эр жүрөктүүлүккө, топту жарып кирүүгө тарбияланат."},{"question":"Wacece gwamna mace ta farko a Najeriya?","answer":"Dame Virginia Ngozi Etiaba."},{"question":"\\"इन्टरनेट अफ थिंग्स (IoT)\\" र स्मार्ट शहर र पूर्वाधारमा यसको सम्भावित प्रभावको व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"IoT ले आपसमा जोडिएका यन्त्रहरू र वस्तुहरूको सञ्जाललाई जनाउँछ जसले डेटा सञ्चार र साझेदारी गर्न सक्छ। यसमा वास्तविक-समय डाटा सङ्कलन र व्यवस्थापन मार्फत स्मार्ट सिटी पूर्वाधार विस्तार गर्ने क्षमता छ।"},{"question":"问：什么是酸奶？","answer":"答：酸奶是一种通过牛奶发酵制成的乳制品，具有醇厚的口感和酸甜的味道。"},{"question":"Америка Кошмо Штаттары менен Советтер Союзунун алгачкы космонавттары","answer":"Нил Армстронг жана Юрий Гагарин"},{"question":"බන්ධනාගාරයක එකවරම කළ හදිසි සෝදිසියක දී හමු වුණ කවුරුත් නොහිතපු දෙය","answer":"ඊයේ (28) පස්වරුවේ පැරණි බූස්ස බන්ධනාගාරයේ 'ඒ' හා 'ඩී' වාට්ටු තුළ හදිසි සෝදිසි කිරීමක් සිදු කර තිබෙනවා.එහිදී ජංගම දුරකථන ඇතුළු උපාංග කිහිපයක් පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය විසින් සොයාගෙන ඇත.එනම් ඉතා සූක්ෂ්ම ලෙස සඟවා තිබු ජංගම දුරකථන දෙකක්, සිම් කාඩ් පත් දෙකක්, පිටත ආවරණය ඉවත් කරන ලද දුරකථන චාර්ජර් 02ක් පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකාය මඟින් සොයාගෙන ඇත.කෙසේ වෙතත්, එම දුරකථන සහ උපාංග ඉදිරි විමර්ශන කටයුතු සඳහා පොලිස් විශේෂ කාර්ය බළකායේ අණ දෙන නිලධාරීවරයාගේ කාර්යාලය වෙත භාර දී තිබෙනවා."},{"question":"Lily Banda","answer":"Lily Banda (tí wọ́n bí ní 16 Oṣù Kẹẹ̀jọ, Ọdún 1990) jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin àti akọrin ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Màláwì.Banda jẹ́ eni tí ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní ní ìfẹ́ sí orin kíkọ láti ìgbà tí ó wà lọ́mọ ọdún mẹ́rin. Nígbà tí yóó fi pé ọmọ ọdún mẹ̀fa, ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní kọrin níbi àwọn ayẹyẹ ní ilé-ìwé rẹ̀. Banda bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ ìṣe rẹ̀ ní ọdún 2010 gẹ́gẹ́ òṣìṣẹ́ rédíò àti tẹlifíṣọ̀nù. Ṣùgbọ́n ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ orin kíkọ rẹ̀ lábẹ lílo Alex gẹ́gẹ́ bi orúkọ ìdí-iṣẹ́ rè. Banda gbé àkọ́kọ́ àpapọ̀ àwọn orin rẹ̀ jáde ní Oṣù Kíní Ọdún 2014. Ní ọdún 2015, ó yí orúkọ ìdí-iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ padà sí Lily, èyítí n ṣe orúkọ àbísọ rẹ̀. Ó gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti African Union kan ní ọdún 2015, ó sì tún rí yíyàn fún àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti Afrima ní ọdún 2018.Ní ọdún 2019, ó kọ orin àdákọ kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ \\"Bad at Love\\". Wọ́n túmọ̀ orin náà sí èdè Swàhílì tó sì jẹ́ gbígbé jáde ní Oṣù Kíní Ọdún 2020. Banda ṣiṣẹ́ pọ̀ pẹ̀lú Alfred Ochieng àti Aliza Were láti túmọ̀ orin náà.Ní ọdún 2019, Banda kópa nínu eré tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ The Boy Who Harnessed the Wind, èyítí ó dá lóri àkọsílẹ̀ William Kamkwamba. Ó tún kópa gẹ́gẹ́ bi Aicha Konate nínu abala ẹ̀kejì ti eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Deep State ní ọdún 2019. Ó kópa gẹ̀gẹ̀ bi atúmọ̀-èdè ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Málì kan tí àwọn kan gbìmọ̀ láti dáa lọ́nà àti láti ṣekú paá.Banda maa n ri ara fun awọn ẹtọ awọn obinrin. O ngbe ni Lilongwe."},{"question":"مجھے والدین کی محبت کے بارے میں ایک گیت لکھیں۔","answer":"ماں باپ کی محبت، ان کے بغیر کچھ بھی نہیں،دل کی گہرائیوں میں، ان کی محبت ہے چھپی۔جب دنیا کی لڑائیوں میں، ہم بے پناہ ہوتے ہیں،ماں باپ کی دعاؤں میں، ان کی محبت ہے سرچھپی۔ماں باپ کی محبت، لاکھوں کی قیمت ہے،یہ پیار کی کہانی، ہر دل کی زبانی۔محنتوں کی راتوں میں، وہ روشنی کی طرح ہوتے ہیں،ہمیشہ ساتھ ہوتے ہیں، دل کی باتوں کو سمجھتے ہیں۔جب دنیا کی تنگیوں میں، ہم کمزور ہوتے ہیں،ماں باپ کی حمایت میں، ان کی محبت ہے بے مثال۔ماں باپ کی محبت، لاکھوں کی قیمت ہے،یہ پیار کی کہانی، ہر دل کی زبانی۔جنت میں بھی پارسائیوں کو، ان کی محبت کا احترام ہے،ماں باپ کی دیکھ بھال میں، سکون اور سکوا ہے چھپا۔ماں باپ کی محبت، لاکھوں کی قیمت ہے،یہ پیار کی کہانی، ہر دل کی زبانی۔"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaan Nabiga markuu ka soo hijrooday Makka ee uu Madiina imaaday saxaabiga uu ku deggay magaciisa?","answer":"Hijradii Nabiga (S.C.W) ee Madiina wuxuu Nabigu (S.C.W) ku degay guriga Abuu-Ayuub (Khaalid ibnu Zayd) Al-Ansaari oo ahaa reer Banii Najjaar."},{"question":"今日、２００３年３月３０日の六曜は何でしょう？","answer":"大安です。"},{"question":"வினா: பண்புத்தொகையைச் சான்றுடன் விளக்குக.","answer":"விடை: பண்புத்தொகை:• அளவு, நிறம், வடிவம், சுவை ஆகியவற்றை உணர்த்தும்.• பண்புப்பெயருக்கும் அது தழுவி நிற்கும் பெயர்ச்சொல்லுக்கும். இடையில் ‘மை’ என்னும் பண்பு விகுதி மறைந்து வரும்.• ஆகிய, ஆன என்னும் பண்பு உருபுகள் மறைந்து வரும்.சான்று: செங்காந்தள், வட்டத்தொட்டி."},{"question":"Bối cảnh của câu chuyện trong bài Buổi học cuối cùng Ngữ văn lớp 7 là gì?","answer":"Bối cảnh của truyện là thời kì sau chiến tranh, hai vùng An-dát và Lo-ren của Pháp bị nhập vào nước Phổ. Các trường học ở hai vùng này bị bắt bỏ tiếng Pháp, chuyển sang học tiếng Đức. Bối cảnh riêng của câu chuyện là quang cảnh và diễn biến của buổi học tiếng Pháp cuối cùng."},{"question":"\\"Simbah bali saka pasar mlaku.\\"Ukara ing nduwur kui yen diubah basa krama inggil dadi...A. Simbah bali saking pasar mlampahB. Simpah wangsul saka peken mlakuC. Simbah wangsul saking peken mlampahJawaban: ","answer":"Jawaban: C. Simbah wangsul saking peken mlampah"},{"question":"කොපී ලුවක් ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් නිෂ්පාදනය කරන රටවල් නම් කරන්න.","answer":"කොපී ලුවක් ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් නිෂ්පාදනය කෙරෙනුයේ සුමාත්‍රා, ජාවා, බාලි, සූලාවේසි යන ඉන්දුනීසියානු දිවයින් තුල සහ නැගෙනහිර ටිමෝරයෙහිය. පිලිපීන දිවයින් තුලද මෙය පුළුල් වශයෙන් කැලයෙහිදී එකතු කිරීම හෝ ගොවිපොළ තුල නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීම හෝ කරන අතර, කෝඩියේරා ප්‍රදේශයෙහිදී කපී මොටී ලෙසින්ද, ටගාලග් ප්‍රදේශ වලදී කපී අලමිඩ් ලෙසින්ද, මින්ඩනාවෝ ප්‍රදේශයෙහි කපී මේලෝ හෝ කපී මූසං ලෙසින්ද, සුලූ කොදෙව් පෙළෙහි කහාවා කුබීං ලෙසින්ද හැඳින්වෙයි. කෑ ෆේ චොන් යන වියට්නාම නම මුගටි කෝපි ලෙසින් දළ පරිවර්තනය කල හැක."},{"question":"നീന്തലിന്റെ ഗുണങ്ങളുടെ ഒരു പട്ടിക ഉണ്ടാക്കുക. ","answer":"നീന്തലിന് മാനസികവും ശാരീരികവുമായ ആരോഗ്യം പ്രോത്സാഹിപ്പിക്കാൻ സഹായിക്കുന്ന നിരവധി ഗുണങ്ങളുണ്ട്. മാനസികമായി, നിങ്ങളുടെ മനസ്സിനെ ശുദ്ധീകരിക്കാൻ നീന്തൽ മികച്ചതാണ്, മാത്രമല്ല നിങ്ങളുടെ ശരീരത്തിലുടനീളം എൻഡോർഫിനുകൾ പുറപ്പെടുവിക്കുമെന്ന് തെളിയിക്കപ്പെട്ടിട്ടുണ്ട്, ഇത് ഒരു വ്യായാമത്തിന് ശേഷം ഉന്മേഷദായകവും സന്തോഷപ്രദവുമായ അനുഭവം നൽകുന്നു. ശാരീരികമായി, നീന്തൽ കാർഡിയോ ഫിറ്റ്നസ് നേടുന്നതിനുള്ള ഒരു മികച്ച മാർഗമാണ്, അതേസമയം ഏത് പ്രായത്തിലും ശക്തിയും വഴക്കവും ഉണ്ടാക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Manetry\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Manetry\\" dia \\"Mampidina\\"."},{"question":"من ادخل الخوارزمي في الإسلام ؟\\t","answer":"قتيبة بن مسلم رضي الله عنه"},{"question":"问题：自然语言处理是什么？","answer":"答案：自然语言处理是人工智能的一个分支，研究如何使计算机能够理解、处理和生成自然语言的方法和技术。"},{"question":"सरकारहरूले कसरी नक्कली मुद्रा विरुद्ध लड्न र पैसाको अखण्डता सुनिश्चित गर्ने?","answer":"सरकारहरूले नक्कलीहरूलाई रोक्न कडा कानून प्रवर्तन र जनचेतना अभियानहरू सहित बैंकनोटहरूमा होलोग्राम, विशेष मसी, र क्रम संख्याहरू जस्ता सुरक्षा सुविधाहरू प्रयोग गर्छन्।"},{"question":"Tras los días de la Revolución de 1830, se vuelve a incrementar la presión en torno a los defensores del positivismo y los liberales en general. Elegido para el desarrollo del Consejo Politécnico, y siendo astrónomo del Bureau des Longitudes en 1839, Poinsot sólo puede encontrar el puesto de Asesor Real sobre Instrucción Pública en el arranque del mandato de Siméon Denis Poisson en 1840 como decano de la Facultad de Ciencias de París. Que es lo más importante?","answer":"Revolución de 1830"},{"question":"Que língua é falada na Croácia?","answer":"O idioma oficial da Croácia é o croata. Uma língua eslava meridional e que utiliza o alfabeto latino. Outras línguas nativas são faladas por menos de 5% da populaçãodo país."},{"question":"أريد أن أتعلم الشعر. أنشيء قصيدة قصيره من بحر الطويل.","answer":"حسناً بالتأكيد: أَرومُ اِنتِصافي مِن رِجالٍ أَباعِدٍوَنَفسِيَ أَعدى لي مِنَ الناسِ أَجمَعاإِذا لَم تَكُن نَفسُ الفَتى مِن صَديقِهِفَلا يُحدِثَن في خِلَّةِ الغَيرِ مَطمَعا."},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Moldavie nékk","answer":"Réwum Moldavie mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Europe"},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kur ir kada buvo paskelbta pirmoji žinoma konstitucija?","answer":"Atsakymas: Pirmoji žinoma konstitucija, žinoma kaip Magna Carta Libertatum, buvo paskelbta Anglijoje 1215 m. birželio 15 d. Šis dokumentas buvo pirmasis, kuris ribojo monarcho valdžią ir pripažino piliečių teises."},{"question":"\\"බලි අරින්නා\\" මෙහි අර්ථය පහදා දෙන්න","answer":"බලි යන්නෙහි තේරුම පූජාව හෙවත් බිලි දීමයි.අතීතයේ යම් යම් ගැටලු වෙනුවෙන් අභිචාර ක්‍රමයක් ලෙස බලි දීම් පැවති අතර විටෙක එය විකාරරූපී දෙයක් විය.ඒ අරුතින් විකාරරූපී ලෙස කටයුතු කරන්නාද බලි අරින්නෙකු ලෙස හැදින්වීම සිදුවිය"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai ayam putih terbang siang, hinggap di kayu merasi bertali benang bertambang tulang\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perkara baik yang cukup keterangan dan saksi"},{"question":"Nitori ọrọ ti ko to nnkan, awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ OPC gun Chidi lọbẹ pa ni Bariga","answer":"Ahamọ awọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ lawọn baale ile mẹrin kan ti n jẹwọ ẹṣẹ wọn bayii, Fatai Taiwo, ẹni ogoji ọdun, Sunday Onilede, ẹni ọdun marundinlogoji, Rasaki Hazan, ẹni ọdun marundinlogoji ati Ibrahim Abdullahi, ẹni ọdun mọkandinlọgbọn, ọmọ ẹgbẹ OPC (Oodua Peoples Congress) lawọn mẹrẹẹrin.Ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn ni pe lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide to kọja yii, ọrọ kan ṣe bii ọrọ laarin wọn pẹlu Ọgbẹni Chidi Tochukwu, o si di ariyanjiyan gidi, lawọn mẹrẹẹrin ba ki Chidi mọlẹ, wọn lu u nilukulu, wọn tun gun un lọbẹ, lọrọ ba ja si iku.Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, DSP Olumuyiwa Adejọbi, sọ pe Ojule kẹrindinlaaadọrin, Opopona Arọbadede, lagbegbe Bariga, ipinlẹ Eko, ni oloogbe to jẹ ẹni ọdun marundinlogoji naa n gbe, ṣugbọn wọn ni Opopona Temple, ni Bariga, kan naa niṣẹlẹ ọhun ti ṣẹlẹ.O lawọn aladuugbo gbọ nigba tawọn ọmọ OPC yii n ṣe fa-a-ka-ja-a pẹlu Tochukwu lori ọrọ kan, ṣugbọn ko sẹni to fura pe ariyanjiyan wọn le la ti lilu lọ, debi tọrọ maa di ti a n yọ ọbẹ sira ẹni.Iboosi ti Tochukwu ke nigba ti wọn gun un lọbẹ, to si bẹrẹ si i pọkaka iku, lo mu kawọn eeyan sare debẹ, wọn si gbe ọkunrin naa digbadigba de ọsibitu Jẹnẹra Bariga, awọn dokita si sapa lori rẹ, ṣugbọn ẹpa ko boro mọ, ọkunrin naa dagbere faye.Awọn aladuugbo naa ko jẹ kawọn afurasi apaayan yii ribi sa lọ, wọn pe awọn ọlọpaa teṣan Bariga lori aago, awọn ni wọn waa fi pampẹ ofin gbe gbogbo wọn.Ọrọ yii ti detiigbọ kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa Eko, Hakeem Odumosu, o si ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn taari wọn sakata awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, Yaba. Ibẹ ni gbogbo wọn wa, ti wọn n ran wọn lọwọ lẹnu iwadii wọn.Alukoro ni abọ eleyii lawọn n duro de, ki wọn le foju awọn afurasi ọdaran yii bale-ẹjọ laipẹ."},{"question":"నన్నయభట్టు గురించి తెలపండి?","answer":"నన్నయ 11వ శతాబ్దంలో రాజమహేంద్రవరాన్ని పరిపాలించిన రాజరాజ నరేంద్రుని ఆస్థానకవి. ఉభయభాషా కావ్యరచనా శోభితుడు. ఆదికవి, శబ్ధశాసనుడు అనే బిరుదులు కలిగినవాడు. రాజరాజు కోరికపై వ్యాస భారతాన్ని తెలుగులోకి అనువదించాడు. రెండున్నర పర్వముల వరకే నన్నయ్య భారతరచన సాగింది. ఆంధ్రశబ్ధ చింతామణి, ఇంద్రవిజయం, లక్షణసార వంటి ఇతర గ్రంథాలు రచించాడు."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నకు జవాబు ఇవ్వండి:  భారతదేశంలో ఆంగ్ల విద్యను ఎవరు ప్రవేశపెట్టారు?","answer":" లార్డ్ మాకే"},{"question":"* ماذا يسمى صوت البوم؟وصوت الغراب؟","answer":"صوت البوم: نعيق/صوت الغراب:نعيق"},{"question":"Faça uma pergunta trivia sobre o tópico música.","answer":"Qual é o nome do filho do membro mais velho do One Direction? Freddie Reign Tomlinson"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Đồng Tháp là tỉnh nằm trong vùng trọng điểm về sản xuất lương thực - thực phẩm, đứng thứ ba cả nước về tổng sản lượng lúa. Thủy sản được coi là ","answer":"thế mạnh thứ hai sau cây lúa, đứng đầu cả nước về sản lượng cá tra xuất khẩu.Tỉnh có hệ thống sông, ngòi, kênh, rạch chằng chịt; nhiều ao, hồ lớn. Sông chính là sông Tiền chảy qua tỉnh với chiều dài 132 km. Dọc theo hai bên bờ sông Tiền là hệ thống kênh rạch dọc ngang. Đường liên tỉnh giao lưu thuận tiện với trên 300 km đường bộ và một mạng lưới sông rạch thông thương."},{"question":"કડાઈ પનીર ની રેસીપી બતાવો.","answer":"કડાઈ પનીરસામગ્રી:250 ગ્રામ પાનીર, ક્યુબ્સ માં કાપેલું 2 ટેબલસ્પૂન તેલ 1 ડુંગળી, ઝીણી સમારેલી2 ટામેટાં, ઝીણી સમારેલાં 1 લીલાં મરચાં, ઝીણા સમારેલાં (વિકલ્પ)1 આદુ-લસણની પેસ્ટ 1 ટેબલસ્પૂન ધાણાજીરું 1/2 ટેબલસ્પૂન લાલ મરચું પાઉડર (સ્વાદ અનુસાર)1/2 ટેબલસ્પૂન ગરમ મસાલો1/2 ટેબલસ્પૂન ધાણા પાઉડર1/4 ટેબલસ્પૂન હળદર1/4 ટેબલસ્પૂન જીરું 1/2 કપ પાણી1/4 કપ કોથમીર, સમારેલીબનાવવાની રીત:1. એક કડાઈમાં તેલ ગરમ કરો. જીરું નાખી તરછટી પડે ત્યાં સુધી રાંધો.2. ધાણાજીરું નાખી સુગંધ આવે ત્યાં સુધી સાંતડે ચલાવો.3. ડુંગળી નાખી ગોલ્ડન બ્રાઉન થાય ત્યાં સુધી સાંતડે શેકશો.4. આદુ-લસણની પેસ્ટ નાખી સુગંધ આવે ત્યાં સુધી સાંતડે ચલાવો.5. ટામેટાં અને લીલાં મરચાં (વિકલ્પ) નાખી બધું બરાબર મિક્સ કરી લો.6. ઢાંકીને 5-7 મિનિટ સુધી ચડવા દો, જેથી ટામેટાં પોચી જાય.7. હવે, બધા મસાલા - લાલ મરચું પાઉડર, ગરમ મસાલો, ધાણા પાઉડર, હળદર - નાખી બરાબર મિક્સ કરી લો.8. 1/2 કપ પાણી નાખી ગ્રેવીને ઘટ્ટ થવા દો.9. પનીરના ક્યુબ્સ નાખી 2-3 મિનિટ સુધી ચડવા દો.10. કોથમીરથી ગાર્નિશ કરી ગરમ ગરમ પીરસો.ટીપ્સ:ગ્રેવીને વધુ ટેસ્ટી બનાવવા માટે, ટામેટાંને પીસીને પણ વાપરી શકો છો.જો તમને સ્વાદ વધારે ગમતો હોય, તો તમે 1 ટેબલસ્પૂન ક્રીમ અથવા મલાઈ પણ નાખી શકો છો."},{"question":"Bir palet briket kaç metrekare?","answer":"Örneğin 1 adet 10'luk (10 cm kalınlığında) Ytong paletin içinde 72 adet Ytong Blok bulunur ve 10,8 m2'dir. 1 palet 15'lik (15 cm kalınlığında) palette ise 48 adet Ytong Blok vardır ve 7,2 m2'dir. 20 cm için ise bu değerler 36 adet ve 5,4 m2'dir."},{"question":"Que material de guerra o Chile exportou para os Aliados durante a 1a guerra?","answer":"Após a crise econômica chilena dos anos 1870, diversas empresas europeias, principalmente britânicas, instalaram-se no extremo norte do país explorando e exportando nitratos. A riqueza produzida pelo \\"ouro branco\\" sustentava cerca de 75% dos ingressos fiscais e a totalidade da economia nacional."},{"question":"Apakah maksud hati kecil?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah perasaan hati yang sesungguhnya. Contoh ayat: Aida menyembunyikan hati kecil yang sebenarnya terhadap peristiwa tersebut."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berapa tinggi terbang bangau, akhirnya hinggap ke belakang kerbau juga\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sejauh mana manusia bermigarsi atau merantau, pasti suatu ketika akan pulang ke kampung halaman."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਗਾਵਿ ਲੇਹਿ ਤੂ ਗਾਵਨਹਾਰੇ ॥ਜੀਅ ਪਿੰਡ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਨ ਅਧਾਰੇ ॥ਜਾ ਕੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਸਰਬ ਸੁਖ ਪਾਵਹਿ ॥ਅਵਰ ਕਾਹੂ ਪਹਿ ਬਹੁੜਿ ਨ ਜਾਵਹਿ ॥੧॥ਸਦਾ ਅਨੰਦ ਅਨੰਦੀ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਗੁਨ ਨਿਧਾਨ ਨਿਤ ਨਿਤ ਜਾਪੀਐ ॥ਬਲਿਹਾਰੀ ਤਿਸੁ ਸੰਤ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਜਿਸੁ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਮਨਿ ਵਾਸੀਐ ॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਜਾ ਕਾ ਦਾਨੁ ਨਿਖੂਟੈ ਨਾਹੀ ॥ਭਲੀ ਭਾਤਿ ਸਭ ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਹੀ ॥ਜਾ ਕੀ ਬਖਸ ਨ ਮੇਟੈ ਕੋਈ ॥ਮਨਿ ਵਾਸਾਈਐ ਸਾਚਾ ਸੋਈ ॥੨॥ਸਗਲ ਸਮਗ੍ਰੀ ਗ੍ਰਿਹ ਜਾ ਕੈ ਪੂਰਨ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੂਖ ਨ ਝੂਰਨ ॥ਓਟਿ ਗਹੀ ਨਿਰਭਉ ਪਦੁ ਪਾਈਐ ॥ਸਾਸਿ ਸਾਸਿ ਸੋ ਗੁਨ ਨਿਧਿ ਗਾਈਐ ॥੩॥ਦੂਰਿ ਨ ਹੋਈ ਕਤਹੂ ਜਾਈਐ ॥ਨਦਰਿ ਕਰੇ ਤਾ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਪਾਈਐ ॥ਅਰਦਾਸਿ ਕਰੀ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰ ਪਾਸਿ ॥ਨਾਨਕੁ ਮੰਗੈ ਹਰਿ ਧਨੁ ਰਾਸਿ ॥੪॥੫॥੯੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 395 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਦ ਤਕ ਗਾਵਣ ਦੀ ਸਮਰਥਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹੁਜੋ ਤੇਰੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਤੇਰੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਤੇਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਤੂੰ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੁਖ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲਏਂਗਾ(ਤੇ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਭਾਲ ਵਿਚ) ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਪਾਸ ਮੁੜ ਜਾਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਏਗੀ ।੧।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਉਸ ਮਾਲਕ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਦੇ ਨਾਮ) ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਜਪਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਸਾਰੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਸਦਾ ਆਨੰਦ ਦਾ ਸੋਮਾ ਹੈ (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਉਸ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਜਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੋਈ ਦਾਤਿ ਕਦੇ ਮੁੱਕਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ (ਤੇ ਜੋ ਜੋ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹ) ਸਾਰੇ ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ ਦੇ ਰਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਰੋਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾ ਸਕਦਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਉਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਸਦਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਵਿਚ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਸਾਰੇ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਭਰੇ ਪਏ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਦੁੱਖ ਕੋਈ ਝੋਰੇ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੇ ਤੇ ਤੇ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲਿਆਂ ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਦਰਜਾ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਥੇ ਕੋਈ ਡਰ ਦਬਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਹਰੇਕ ਸਾਹ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।੩।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਸਾਥੋਂ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਵੱਸਦਾ, ਕਿਤੇ (ਦੂਰ) ਲੱਭਣ ਜਾਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਨਹੀਂ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹ ਆਪ ਮੇਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਕਰੇ ।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਕੋਲ ਹੀ ਅਰਦਾਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਆਖਦਾ ਹਾਂਹੇ ਗੁਰੂ! ਤੇਰੇ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਮੰਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸਰਮਾਇਆ ਮੰਗਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੫।੯੯।\\""},{"question":"एयरोस्पेस इन्जिनियरहरूले विमानको डिजाइनमा कसरी योगदान गर्छन्?","answer":"एयरोस्पेस इन्जिनियरहरू विमान र अन्तरिक्ष यानको डिजाइन, विकास र परीक्षणका लागि जिम्मेवार हुन्छन्। तिनीहरू वायुगतिकी, प्रोपल्सन प्रणाली, र संरचनात्मक डिजाइनमा ध्यान केन्द्रित गर्छन् उडान वाहनहरूको सुरक्षा र दक्षता सुनिश्चित गर्न।"},{"question":"‘நேதாஜி சுபாஷ் சந்திரபோஸின் பொன்மொழிகள் யாவை?","answer":"நேதாஜி சுபாஷ் சந்திர போஸ் பொன்மொழிகள்:1.சுதந்திரம் கொடுக்கப்படுவதில்லை. 2.நீங்கள் உங்களின் குருதியை கொடுங்கள். 3.நமக்கென்று ஓர் இராணுவமும் அமைக்கப்பட்டு விட்டதனால், நமக்கென்று ஒரு சுதந்திர அரசை அமைப்பது சாத்தியமும், அவசியமும் ஆயிற்று. 4.கலங்காத உள்ளம் படைத்தவர்களே இறுதி வெற்றிக்கு உரியவர்கள்!5.ஒரு சிந்தனைக்காக மனிதன் இறக்கலாம்."},{"question":"ශතකයක් නොලබා තම ක්‍රිකට් දිවිය තුළ වැඩිම ලකුණු වාර්තා කළ ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ජාතික ශේන් වෝන්"},{"question":"ਦੁਬਈ, 25 ਫਰਵਰੀਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਫੌਜੀ ਜਨਰਲ ਪਰਵੇਜ਼ ਮੁਸ਼ੱਰਫ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਜੰਗ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਵਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਰੱਦ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜੇਕਰ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਲੋਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਉੱਪਰ ਇੱਕ ਬੰਬ ਸੁੱਟਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਲੋਂ 20 ਬੰਬ ਸੁੱਟ ਕੇ ਮੁਲਕ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਦੁਬਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰੈੱਸ ਕਾਨਫਰੰਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਇੱਕ ਸਵਾਲ ਦੇ ਜਵਾਬ ਵਿਚ ਜਨਰਲ ਮੁਸ਼ੱਰਫ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘‘ਇਹ ਏਨਾ ਸੌਖਾ ਨਹੀਂ। ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਨਾ ਕਰੋ। ਅਜਿਹੇ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਫੌਜੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਕੰਮ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।’’ਮੁਸ਼ੱਰਫ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਬਿਆਨ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਗੁਆਂਢੀ ਮੁਲਕਾਂ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ 14 ਫਰਵਰੀ ਦੇ ਫਿਦਾਈਨ ਹਮਲੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਵਧੇ ਤਣਾਅ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ। ਦੱਸਣਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜੰਮੂ ਕਸ਼ਮੀਰ ਦੇ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਵਿਚ ਸੀਆਰਪੀਐੱਫ ਦੇ ਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਭਰੀ ਬੱਸ ਉੱਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਜੈਸ਼-ਏ-ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਸੰਗਠਨ ਨੇ ਫਿਦਾਈਨ ਹਮਲਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ 42 ਜਵਾਨ ਸ਼ਹੀਦ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਸਨ।ਮੁਸ਼ੱਰਫ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘‘ਜੇਕਰ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਇੱਕ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਬੰਬ ਨਾਲ ਹਮਲਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਗੁਆਂਢੀ ਮੁਲਕ 20 ਬੰਬ ਸੁੱਟ ਕੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦਾ ਹੱਲ ਕੇਵਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜਾਂ ਤਾਂ ਅਸੀਂ 50 ਬੰਬ ਸੁੱਟੀਏ ਤਾਂ ਜੋ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਾਪਸ 20 ਬੰਬ ਨਾ ਸੁੱਟ ਸਕੇ।’’‘‘ਕੀ ਅਸੀਂ 50 ਬੰਬ ਸੁੱਟਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਮਲੇ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਹਾਂ?’’ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਸਵਾਲ ਕੀਤਾ।ਭਾਰਤ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਬੰਬ ਸੁੱਟ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਭਾਰਤ 20 ਬੰਬ ਸੁੱਟ ਕੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"banyak orang banyak ragamnya\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud banyak orang banyak tingkahnya (fiilnya, lakunya)."},{"question":"Inona ny hatao hoe \\"vintana\\"?","answer":"Hoy ny raki-bolana hoe ny \\"vintana\\" dia anjara (soa na ratsy) heverina ho avy amin'ny kisendrasendra na miankina amin'ny tonon'andro nahaterahana.Hoy RAZAFITSALAMA : \\"Marihina fa ny teny hoe vintana ary kintana dia iray fototra no hiaviany : diniho ny teny indonesiana hoe \\"bintang\\" izay samy adika hoe kintana sy vintana. Maneho izany fa arakaraka ny filahatra sy fisehoan'ny antokon-kintana no hamantarana ny vintana.\\" tao amin'ny boky Finoana sy fomba malagasy."},{"question":"Qual é o erro de acentuação na seguinte frase? \\"Você pode me emprestar seu lapís?\\"","answer":"Erro de acentuação: \\"lapís\\" deve ser \\"lápis\\"."},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yazın:  1848 Macar Devrimi","answer":"yıllarında kendini başbakan ilan etti. Fakat birkaç gün sonra isyanın Viyana'da patlak vermesi üzerine istifa etmek zorunda kaldı. 11 Ekim günü Viyana isyancılar tarafından ele geçirildi ve şehrin düşmesiyle birlikte şehri terk etti."},{"question":"Bác Hưng uốn một dây thép thành móc treo đồ có dạng hình thoi với độ dài cạnh bằng 30 cm. Bác Hưng cần bao nhiêu xăng-ti-mét dây thép để làm móc treo đó?","answer":"Lời giải:Độ dài dây thép để làm móc treo chính là chu vi của hình thoi có độ dài cạnh bằng 30 cm. Do đó bác Hưng cần số xăng-ti-mét dây thép để làm móc treo là:4 . 30 = 120 (cm)Vậy bác Hưng cần số xăng-ti-mét dây thép để làm móc treo là 120 cm."},{"question":"روبوٹ کیا ہوتا ہے؟ اس کے بارے میں تھوڑا بتایے:","answer":"جدید دور میں روبوٹ سے مراد ایک میکانیکی یا غیر ماہیتی، مصنوعی سازندہ (agent) ہے۔ بالعموم روبوٹ ایک ایسے میکانیکی و برقی نظام کو کہا جاتا ہے جس کی حرکات و سکنات اور شکل و صورت سے یوں لگے جیسے اس میں خود سے قوت ارادہ یا قوت تغیر موجود ہو۔ غیر ماہیتی روبوٹ سے مراد سافٹ ویئر سازندے (soft ware agents) ہیں، جن کے لیے ”بوٹ” کی اصطلاح استعمال کی جاتی ہے۔ یہاں یہ بات قابل ذکر ہے کہ ہر خودکار نظام یا آلے کو روبوٹ نہیں کہا جاتا۔ ایک خودکار آلے اور روبوٹ کا فرق سمجھنے کے لیے روبوٹ کی مندرجہ ذیل خصوصیات کو مد نظر رکھنا ہوتا ہے۔روبوٹ کو مصنوعی طور پر بنایا جاتا ہے، یہ قدرتی طور پر موجود نہیں ہوتا۔ وہ نہ صرف اپنے ماحول کو محسوس کر سکتا ہے بلکہ اس میں تبدیلی بھی لا سکتا ہے۔ اس میں کسی قسم کی ذہانت موجود ہونی چاہیے، جس کو بروئے کار لا کر وہ اپنے ماحول میں تبدیلی لانے کا لائحہ عمل منتخب کرے اور پھر اس لائحہ عمل کو اپنے افعال کے ذریعے عملی جامہ پہنا سکے۔ مزید یہ کہ اس کو پروگرام کیا جا سکے، یعنی اس کی ذہانت و انتخاب میں بدرجہِ صلاحیت تبدیلی لائی جا سکتی ہے۔ اس میں جنبش و حرکت کی صلاحیت ہو جس سے وہ نقل و حمل کر سکے۔"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai kucing tidur di bantal\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perihal kehidupan yang senang dan mewah."},{"question":"将棋の桂馬とよく似た動きをするチェスの駒の名前は何でしょう？","answer":"ナイト"},{"question":"أكمل ما يلي: معركة سندويتش كانت مناوشة بحرية وقعت في عام 1460 في حرب الوردتين","answer":". في هذه المعركة البحرية أصبح السير والربان ريتشارد نيفيل، إيرل وارويك السادس عشر من أنصار أسرة يورك، فهُزم فيها أسطول اللانكاسترين وألقي القبض على عدد من سفنهم. هناك القليل فقط من المعلومات والتفاصيل عن هذه المعركة البحرية."},{"question":"Miten rinovirusinfektioita hoidetaan?","answer":"Rinovirusinfektioon ei ole lääkitystä vaan hoito on oireenmukaista."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي آمن به كل قومه؟","answer":"الإجابة: يونس عليه السلام."},{"question":"ما هي المدينة التي كانت حاضرة الدولة الأموية؟","answer":"دمشق"},{"question":"சீவக சிந்தாமணி -விளக்குக","answer":"சீவக சிந்தாமணி என்பது சங்க காலத்துக்குப் பின்னர் தோன்றிய ஐம்பெருங்காப்பியங்களுள் ஒன்று. சோழர் காலத்தில் எழுதப்பட்டது. திருத்தக்கதேவர் என்னும் சமண முனிவரால் இயற்றப்பட்ட இக் காப்பியம் சீவகன் என்பவனின் அக வாழ்க்கையை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்டது. சமய இலக்கியங்களே அதிகம் படைக்கப்பட்ட அக்காலத்தில், மக்களிடத்திலும் மன்னனிடமும் கூட இதற்கான தேவையும், ஆதரவும் இருந்ததாகத் தெரிகிறது.சிலப்பதிகாரம், மணிமேகலை என்னும் தமிழில் தோன்றிய முதல் இரு காப்பியங்களாகக் கருதப்படும், கதையை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்ட இலக்கியங்களைத் தொடர்ந்து மூன்றாவதாக உருவான கதை கூறும் தமிழ் இலக்கியம் இது. எனினும் முன்னையவற்றைப் போலன்றிச் சீவகசிந்தாமணி விருத்தப்பாக்களால் ஆனது. இதனால் விருத்தப் பாக்களால் ஆன முதல் தமிழ்க் காப்பியமாகவும் இது திகழ்கின்றது.நூலாசிரியர்இக்காப்பியத்தை இயற்றிய திருத்தக்கதேவர் சமண முனிவராவார். இவர்,திருத்தகு முனிவர்திருத்தகு மகா முனிவர்என்று அழைக்கப் பெறுவார். இவர் சைன ஆசாரியர் சங்கங்களில் ஒன்றாகிய திரமிள சங்கத்து அருங்கலான்வயத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர் என்பர். திருத்தக்கதேவர் சோழர் குடியில் பிறந்தவர். இளமையிலேயே கல்வி கேள்விகளில் சிறந்து விளங்கியவர். வடமொழிப் பயிற்சி மிக்கவர். காமம், பொய், கொலை, கள், சூதாடல் என்ற ஐவகைத் தீமையும் அகற்றியவர். சமணத் துறவியாக வாழ்ந்தவர். விருத்தமெனும் பாடல்களைக் கொண்டு பெருங்காப்பியம் பாடியவர்களில் இவர் முதன்மையானவர்.நூலின் வேறு பெயர்கள்மணநூல்முக்தி நூல்காமநூல்இயற்கை தவம்முதல் விருத்தப்பா காப்பியம்தமிழ் இலக்கிய நந்தாமணிமுடி பொருள் தொடர்நிலைச் செய்யுள்எனப் பல்வேறு பெயர்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது சீவக சிந்தாமணி.நூல் உணர்த்தும் உண்மைகள்அமைச்சரை ஆராய்ந்து தெளிதல் வேண்டும்.பெண்வழிச்சேறல் பெருந்துன்பம் விளைவிக்கும்.தன்ஆட்சியர் கட்டளைப்படி நடத்தல் வேண்டும்.பகையை வெல்லக் காலமும், இடமும் வரும் வரை யாரிடமும் தன் எண்ணத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தக் கூடாது.எல்லா உயிர்களிடத்தும் அன்பு செலுத்த வேண்டும்.நன்றி மறவாது இருத்தல் வேண்டு.கதைச் சுருக்கம்மன்னனுக்கு மகனாக, அரசியின் வயிற்றில் உருவானவன் சீவகன். எனினும் விதி வசத்தால் சுடுகாட்டில் பிறக்கிறான். பின்னர் கந்துக்கடன் என்னும் வணிகன் ஒருவனின் வீட்டில் வளர்கின்றான். அச்சணந்தி என்னும் ஆசானிடம் கல்வி பயின்ற இவன் சிறந்த தோற்றப்பொலிவு கொண்டவன், மிகுந்த அறிவு நிரம்பியவன், பல்வேறு கலைகளிலும் வல்லவன், சிறந்த வீரன். இவன் எட்டு மங்கையரை மணந்து கொள்கிறான். அந்த எட்டு மகளிர்க்கும் எட்டு வகை குணங்கள் இருந்ததாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது. இதனால் இந்நூலுக்கு மணநூல் என்ற சிறப்புப்பெயரும் உண்டு. இவ்வாறு பல மணம் புரிந்தவன் ஆனாலும், இவன் ஒரு காமுகனாக அன்றிச் சிறந்த மன அடக்கம் கொண்டவனாகவே சித்திரிக்கப்படுகிறான். இவ்வாறு பல பெண்களை மணம்புரிந்ததன் மூலம், பணபலத்தையும், படைபலத்தையும் பெருக்கிக் கொண்டு அரசபதவியை அடைகிறான். 30 ஆண்டுகள் நீதியுடன் ஆட்சி செய்த சீவகன், ஆட்சிப் பொறுப்பை மகனிடம் அளித்துவிட்டுத் துறவறம் பூண்டு முத்தி பெறுகிறான்."},{"question":"Berikan saya rangka yang mempunyai isi-isi penting untuk karangan yang bertajuk Usaha Memupuk Perpaduan Kaum Di Malaysia.","answer":"Isi -isi pentingnya adalah seperti berikut:1. Menyatukan institusi pendidikan dari peringkat rendah 2. Menyambut hari perayaan bersama-sama melalui rumah terbuka 3. Memperkasa aktiviti sukan dan rekreasi dalam komuniti 4. Mempergiat aktiviti sukarelawan dan kebajikan 5. Menerbitkan drama atau filem yang mempunyai elemen perpaduan kaum dengan lebih banyak 6. Membendung diskriminasi antara kaum dalam peluang pendidikan, pekerjaan dan ekonomi."},{"question":"ඇනෙලිඩා වංශයේ සතුන් ගැන දැන ගනිමු.","answer":"සීලෝමය නැමැති දේහ කුහරය මුලින්ම විකසනය වූ සත්ත්ව වංශය වන්නේ ඇනෙලිඩාවන්ය. ගැඩවිලා, කූඩැල්ලා, පත්තෑපණුවා යන සතුන් මෙම වංශයට අදාල සතුන්ය."},{"question":"\\"نسل تعصب یا نسل پرستی\\" پر مضمون مکمل مضمون ","answer":"نسلی تعصب یا نسل پرستیسفید نسلوں پر غور کریں کہ وہ فطرت کے لحاظ سے دوسری نسلوں سے برتر ہیں اور صرف وہی ہیں۔ تہذیب کے معمار۔ بنی نوع انسان کے عظیم اساتذہ کی جلد سفید نہیں تھی۔ نسلی تعصب ہمیشہ سے موجود ہے لیکن اب یہ زیادہ خطرناک ہے۔ رہوڈیشیا (زمبابوے) اور جنوبی افریقہ میں سفید فاموں نے وحشیوں جیسا سلوک کیا۔ نسلی تعصب بہت نقصان کا باعث بنے گا جیسا کہ ماضی میں ہوا ہے۔ ہندوستان میں، مہاتما گاندھی کی بہترین کوششوں کے باوجود، نسلی منافرت عروج پر ہے۔، یہ خوش قسمتی ہے کہ پوری دنیا میں لوگ آواز اٹھا رہے ہیں۔ نسلی تعصب کے خلاف ان کی آواز۔ اسے دنیا کے تمام ممالک کی اجتماعی کوششوں سے دور کیا جا سکتا ہے۔یہ عقیدہ کہ انسانیت فطرتاً، ایسوں اور ذیلی نسلوں میں بٹی ہوئی ہے۔ بعض نسلیں فطری طور پر نفسیاتی وقف میں دوسروں سے برتر ہیں، رنگین تعصب کے مفروضے کی بنیاد بنتی ہیں۔ نسلی برتری کو متعدد وجوہات سے منسوب کیا گیا ہے، لیکن کسی بھی صورت میں نسلی فرق کا مفروضہ اسے بنیادی مقامی اختلافات پر منحصر کرتے ہوئے، زیور نوعیت کا تصور کرتا ہے۔ ایک مخالف نظریہ اس بات پر اصرار کرتا ہے کہ نفسیاتی خصوصیات میں ظاہری اختلافات حیاتیاتی نہیں ہیں بلکہ ثقافت اور سماجی ماحول کی وجہ سے ہیں۔ تاریخ سے پتہ چلتا ہے کہ نسلی برتری کا عقیدہ بہت پرانا اور اچھی رات کا عالمگیر ہے: حالیہ برسوں میں، اس نے بہت سے نسلی گروہوں کے لیے ایسی زبردست حقیقت اور متعصبانہ اہمیت اختیار کر لی ہے کہ وہ اپنے دفاع میں مر جائیں گے۔ اس کے علاوہ،سفید فام نسلوں کو برتر سمجھا جاتا ہے کیونکہ ان کے پاس اپنے نظریات کا احترام کرنے کی وجہ ہے۔ وہ سمجھتے ہیں کہ وہ تہذیب کے حقیقی معمار ہیں اور ان خیالات نے سفید فام آدمی کے بوجھ کے تصور کو جنم دیا ہے۔ یہ تصور بے شرمی کے ساتھ اعلان کرتا ہے کہ سفید فام تہذیب کو ایشیائی اور افریقیوں سے اپنے آپ کو بچانے کے لیے قانونی رکاوٹوں کی ضرورت ہے۔ اصل گورے کا بوجھ رنگین یا کالے لوگوں پر گستاخی کے ساتھ غلبہ حاصل کرنا نہیں بلکہ منافقت سے باز آنا ہے۔ یہ سچ ہے کہ سفید فام آدمی کو ہر انسان کو اپنے برابر سمجھنا سیکھنا چاہیے۔جلد کی سفیدی کے بارے میں کوئی راز نہیں ہے۔ یہ ثابت ہو چکا ہے کہ مساوی مواقع ملنے پر آدمی، چاہے وہ کسی بھی رنگ یا ملک کا ہو، دوسرے جیسا ہی اچھا ہے۔بنی نوع انسان کے سب سے بڑے اساتذہ تمام ایشیائی تھے اور ان کی جلد سفید نہیں تھی۔ لیکن یہ افسوسناک ہے کہ زمبابوے اور جنوبی افریقہ میں گوروں نے وحشیوں جیسا سلوک کیا اور نیگروز، ہندوستانیوں اور دیگر ایشیائی باشندوں کو خوفناک یہودی بستیوں میں رہنے پر مجبور کرنے کے لیے قوانین بنائے۔ یہ امریکہ کے بارے میں بھی سچ ہے جو دنیا کی سب سے مہذب قوم ہونے کا اعلان کرتا ہے جہاں جنوبی علاقوں میں شہری حقوق کے بل کو اب بھی کاغذ کے ٹکڑے کے طور پر سمجھا جاتا ہے۔ زمبابوے نے اپریل 1980 میں سفید فام اقلیتی حکومت کے خلاف ایک تلخ جدوجہد کے بعد آزادی حاصل کی۔عدم تشدد عقلمندوں کا خواب ہے جب کہ تشدد انسان کی تاریخ ہے۔ بیسویں صدی میں، انسانی نسلوں کے گروہوں کی طرف سے تشدد کیا جاتا رہا ہے جو سفید ہونے پر فخر کرتے ہیں، گویا محض رنگ ہی کسی نسل کی برتری کی علامت ہے۔ یہ انسانی معاشرے میں ایک بہت بڑا بدنما داغ ہے کیونکہ؛ انسان اور انسان کے درمیان امتیاز کی کوئی معقول بنیاد نہیں ہو سکتی۔عالمی تاریخ کا مطالعہ ہمیں رنگوں کے تعصب کی مختلف وجوہات بتاتا ہے۔ یاد رہے کہ مختلف یورپی طاقتوں نے افریقہ میں اپنی کالونیاں قائم کیں۔ استعمار کی اس پالیسی کا نتیجہ نسلی امتیاز برائی ہے۔ پرتگالی فخر کرتے ہیں کہ پرتگالی املاک میں کوئی نسلی مسئلہ نہیں ہے۔ یہ سراسر غلط ہے۔ پرتگالی کالونیاں سختی سے پولیس کے تحت ہیں۔ مقامی باشندوں کی زندگی مکمل طور پر کنٹرول میں ہے۔ پولیس کے پاس ہر اس شخص تک پہنچنے کا ایک طریقہ ہے جسے پاس لے جانا ہوتا ہے۔ اسے فرمانبردار ہونا چاہیے اور فساد سے بچنا چاہیے۔ اگر وہ ایسا کرنے میں ناکام رہتا ہے یا بغاوت کا رجحان ظاہر کرتا ہے تو اسے بے دردی سے سزا دی جاتی ہے اور یہاں تک کہ جلاوطن کر دیا جاتا ہے۔ زمبابوے اور جنوبی افریقہ میں نسل پرستی کو بے رحمی سے رواج دیا گیا۔ معاشی، بڑے اجارہ دار کاروباری خدشات کا کنٹرول، جو کبھی افریقہ پر حکومت کرتا تھا، عملی طور پر کوئی تبدیلی نہیں ہوئی. مقامی لوگ پیداواری زمینوں سے محروم تھے۔ انہیں ایسی شرائط پر انتہائی کم اجرت پر جبری مشقت کا نشانہ بنایا گیا جو غلامی کی یاد دلاتے ہیں۔سائنسی طور پر ترقی یافتہ نسلیں سوچتی ہیں کہ انہیں پسماندہ ممالک کے لوگوں پر غلبہ حاصل کرنے، حکومت کرنے اور ان کا استحصال کرنے کا حق ہے۔ نسلی تعصب ظاہر کرتا ہے کہ انسان میں جانور اب بھی برقرار ہے۔ جانور خوشبو سے اپنے ریوڑ کے ارکان کو پہچانتے ہیں۔ یا نظر سے لیکن وہ ایک عجیب جانور کے قریب جانے پر شک کے ساتھ رد عمل کا اظہار کرتے ہیں یہاں تک کہ اگر ان کی اپنی نسل میں سے کسی کو معلوم ہو۔ انسانوں میں اب بھی حیوانی رویے کی بہت سی خصلتیں پائی جاتی ہیں۔نسلی تعصب بے مثال انسانی مصائب کا باعث بنے گا جیسا کہ ماضی میں ہوا ہے۔ یہ نسلی تعصب کی وجہ سے تھا کہ ہٹلر کے ماتحت نازیوں کے ہاتھوں یہودیوں کا بڑے پیمانے پر قتل عام ہوا۔ جرمنوں کا خیال تھا کہ وہ ایک اعلیٰ نسل ہیں۔ جب یہودیوں نے اپنی ریاست اسرائیل قائم کی تو ان کے خلاف جو تعصب اب بھی رائج ہے، اب عربوں کی طرف سے ہے۔ عربوں اور اسرائیل کے درمیان اس نسلی تعصب کا نتیجہ تین جنگوں کی صورت میں نکلا جب پہلی بار 1948 میں عربوں نے اسرائیل پر حملہ کیا لیکن انہیں شکست ہوئی، دوسری 1956 میں جب اسرائیل نے مصر پر حملہ کیا اور تیسری جون 1967 کے مغربی ایشیائی بحران میں۔نیگرو کہلانے والی آبادی کے ایک بڑے حصے کے ساتھ ذیلی انسانوں جیسا سلوک کیا جاتا ہے، ان کے بچوں کو نام نہاد سفید فام اسکولوں، کالجوں، عوامی مقامات، ریستورانوں اور پارکوں میں داخلہ دینے سے انکار کر دیا جاتا ہے۔ تمام جمہوری ادارے شیطانی افسانے لگتے ہیں۔ جب حبشی اپنے انسانی حقوق کو جھانکتے ہیں تو انہیں نام نہاد اعلیٰ نسل کے پولیس والوں سے گولیاں لگتی ہیں۔ یہ سب سے ترقی یافتہ اور نام نہاد انتہائی مہذب ملک امریکہ میں تھا جہاں عظیم رہنما مارٹن لوتھر کنگ کو قتل کر دیا گیا تھا، یہ جدید تہذیب پر سب سے بڑا دھبہ تھا۔ اس انتہائی ترقی یافتہ ملک میں بھی تعاون اور رہائش کا جذبہ نہیں ہے۔ جنوبی افریقہ میں نسلی تعصب کی بدترین قسم رائج تھی۔ دنیا کے سرکردہ ممالک نے اس ملک کا معاشی بائیکاٹ کیا تاکہ اسے اپنی غلطیوں کا احساس ہو سکے۔ اس مسئلے نے دولت مشترکہ کے ممالک کی توجہ بہت قریب سے مبذول کرائی ہے۔ نیو گنی، موزمبیق اور اعلیٰ طاقتوں کی بہت سی دوسری جیبیں نسلی تعصب کی لپیٹ میں ہیں۔ یہاں تک کہ انگلینڈ میں نسلی تشدد کے کئی واقعات سامنے آئے ہیں۔یہاں تک کہ ہندوستان میں، جو کہ لارڈ بدھ، سنت رویداس اور مہاتما گاندھی کے طور پر نسلی ہم آہنگی کے علمبرداروں کا مادر وطن رہا ہے، نسلی تعصبات عروج پر ہیں۔ گاندھی جی کو ایک فرقہ پرست جنونی نے قتل کر دیا تھا۔ گاندھی جی نے اپنی ساری زندگی پسے ہوئے طبقات اور درج فہرست ذات کے لوگوں کی ترقی کے لیے جدوجہد کی۔ اس نے انہیں خدا کے لوگ - ہرجن کہا۔ لیکن آج بھی راسخ العقیدہ معاشرہ ان ہریجنوں کو جگہ نہیں دے سکا ہے۔ ان کے ساتھ اب بھی غیر انسانی سلوک کیا جاتا ہے اور انہیں معاشرے کے نام نہاد اعلیٰ طبقے سے دور رکھا جاتا ہے۔یہ بات خوش آئند ہے کہ پوری دنیا میں بڑے پیمانے پر لوگ نسلی تعصب کے خلاف اپنی آواز بلند کر رہے ہیں۔ اقوام متحدہ کے تمام رکن ممالک نے نسل پرستانہ پالیسیوں کی مذمت کی ہے۔ اس کے خلاف مختلف قسم کی پابندیاں تجویز کی گئی ہیں۔ امریکہ میں لوگوں کے روشن خیال طبقے نے اپنے ہی ملک میں ریاستوں کے بونے کے نسلی تعصبات کی شدید مذمت کی ہے۔ یہ 15 دسمبر 1989 کو نیویارک میں پہلی برے کے لیے تھا، جب سے بھارت نے جنوبی افریقہ میں رنگ برداری کے خلاف آواز اٹھائی، اقوام متحدہ کی جنرل اسمبلی نے نسلی علیحدگی پر قائم پریٹوریا حکومت کو ختم کرنے کے لیے اقدامات کرنے پر اتفاق کیا۔ایک تاریخی ووٹنگ میں جنوبی افریقہ کی پارلیمنٹ نے 17 جون کو ووٹ دیا۔ 199.1 ریاستی قانون کے طور پر نسل پرستی کو ختم کرنا۔ جنوبی افریقہ کے صدر نے جلد کے رنگ کی بنیاد پر معاشرے میں تمام رکاوٹوں کو دور کرنے کا عہد کیا ہے۔ اس تاریخی فیصلے کے بعد صدر نے اقوام متحدہ اور امریکہ سے جنوبی افریقہ کے خلاف پابندیاں ہٹانے کی اپیل کی۔ساتویں ناوابستہ سربراہی اجلاس نے ایک قابل ذکر کامیابی حاصل کی۔ فلسطینی عوام کی اپنے وطن کے لیے جدوجہد کو تقویت دینے کے لیے ہندوستان کی سربراہی میں آٹھ رکنی کمیٹی قائم کی گئی۔ کانفرنس کو نمیبیا کی لومڑی کی آزادی کا نام دیا گیا۔ آٹھویں ناوابستہ سربراہی اجلاس ایک قدم آگے بڑھا۔ سمٹ نے دنیا بھر میں توجہ مبذول کروائی، خاص طور پر اس لیے کہ یہ ایک \\"فرنٹ لائن\\" افریقہ اسٹیٹ (زمبابوے) کے دارالحکومت (ہرارے) میں منعقد ہوئی، جو کہ سفید فام نسل پرست جنوبی افریقہ کی سرحدوں کے قریب ہے، سمٹ کے دوران نو رکنی \\"افریقہ\\" (Action for Resisting Invasion, Colonialism and Apartheid) فنڈ قائم کیا گیا۔ اس فنڈ کا مقصد جنوبی افریقہ میں فرنٹ لائن ریاستوں اور تحریک آزادی کی مدد کرنا تھا۔ اس فنڈ کے دیگر اہم کام سپلائی کو برقرار رکھنا، امدادی اقدامات کی منصوبہ بندی کرنا اور ہموار نقل و حمل کو یقینی بنانا تھا۔نمیبیا کے باشندے بھی گوروں کی نسل پرستانہ حکومت سے لڑ رہے تھے اور ان کی آزادی کی جدوجہد جاری تھی۔ زیادہ تر یورپی اور مغربی ممالک نمیبیا میں تیزی سے کاروبار کر رہے تھے اور اقوام متحدہ کی عائد کردہ پابندیوں کی صریح خلاف ورزی کرتے ہوئے اس کی قدرتی دولت کا استحصال کر رہے تھے۔ اقوام متحدہ کی جنرل اسمبلی نے 1973 میں جنوب مغرب کہا۔ افریقی عوامی تنظیم (SWAPO) نمیبیا کے لوگوں کے حقیقی نمائندوں کے طور پر۔ تین سال بعد عالمی ادارے نے نامیبیا کو یہ اعزاز دیا۔ آزادی حاصل کرنے کا حق۔NAM .کوآرڈینیٹنگ بیورو نے اپریل 1985 میں اقوام متحدہ کی سلامتی کونسل پر زور دیا کہ وہ اس بات کو یقینی بنانے کے لیے اقوام متحدہ کے چارٹر کے تحت مناسب کارروائی شروع کرے۔ جنوبی افریقی اپنی سابقہ ​​قراردادوں کی تعمیل کرتے ہیں۔ ستمبر 1986 میں جنرل اسمبلی نے ناوابستہ قرار داد منظور کی جس میں نمیبیا کی آزادی سے متعلق اپنی 1978 کی قرارداد پر فوری عمل درآمد کا مطالبہ کیا گیا۔74 سال کی طویل جدوجہد کے بعد، نمیبیا نے بالآخر آزادی حاصل کی: 20-21 مارچ 1990 کی درمیانی رات کو جنوبی افریقیوں کی حکومت تھی۔ ہندوستان، نمیبیا کے ساتھ سفارتی تعلقات قائم کرنے والے پہلے ممالک میں شامل تھا۔"},{"question":"Jelaskan bidang kuasa Yang di-Pertuan Agong dalam Perlembagaan Persekutuan?","answer":"Kuasa Eksekutif, Yang di-Pertuan Agong bertindak mengikut nasihat Jemaah Menteri."},{"question":"O ṣẹlẹ, wọn so mariwo ọpẹ mọ ẹnu ọna ọfiisi ọga ileewe n’Iliṣan","answer":"Kijokijo lawọn tiṣa ati olukọ ileewe Iṣanbi Comprehensive High School, Iliṣan Rẹmọ, nipinlẹ Ogun, n sa kiri l’Ọjọbọ, ọjọ kẹẹẹdọgbọn, oṣu kẹta yii, nigba ti wọn de ileewe naa, ti wọn ba mariwo ọpẹ tawọn kan so mọ ẹnu ọna abawọle ọfiisi ọga agba, ti ẹnu ọna naa si waa da bii abawọle ile oriṣa.Ko sẹni to mọ bi mariwo yii ṣe de ẹnu ọna, nitori ko si nibẹ nigba ti wọn n lọ sile l’Ọjọruu, afi bi wọn ṣe deleewe lọjọ keji ti wọn ba mariwo lẹnu ọna. Koda, iyalẹnu gbaa lo jẹ fun ọga ileewe naa, Abilekọ Olu James, mama naa ko le wi nnkan kan, niṣe lọkan rẹ poruru.ALAROYE gbọ pe ọkan ninu awọn olukọ ileewe yii na akẹkọọ kan to wa nipele aṣekagba lọjọ Iṣẹgun ọsẹ naa. Wọn ni akẹkọọ yii fibinu pada sile, o lọọ pe ẹgbọn rẹ kan wa lati gbeja rẹ, n lẹgbọn naa ba bẹre si i dalẹru, lo n pariwo pe ki ni wọn n lu aburo oun nileewe fun.Afi bo ṣe di l’Ọjọbọ ti wọn ba mariwo lẹnu ọna ọfiisi ọga agba, ti ko si sẹni to mọgba ti wọn so o mọbẹ, tabi ẹni to so o gan-an.Oluwo Iliṣan Rẹmọ, Oloye Fagorala, lo pada waa yọ mariwo ọpẹ naa kuro lẹnu ọna ọhun, lẹyin to pe awọn ede to nilo si i ko too ja a kuro.Ẹsẹkẹsẹ ni ileewe naa pe ipade pajawiri fun awọn obi ati olukọ (PTA meeting), bẹẹ lawọn ọlọpaa wa lati Iliṣan ati Ṣagamu, ti wọn jọ jiroro lori ohun to fa iṣẹlẹ yii, ati bi iru rẹ ko ṣe ni i waye mọ."},{"question":"පරිගණක දෘඪාංග යනු මොනවද ?","answer":"පරිගණක පද්ධතියක ඇති භෞතික උපාංග දෘඪාංග ලෙස හැඳින්වේ.  ාම්වා පහත පරිදි වර්ග කළ හැකිය.ආදාන උපාංගප්‍රතිදාන උපාංගමතක උපාංගපාලන හා සැකසුම් උපාංගජාලකරණ උපාංගමෙම සියලු උපාංග සම්බන්ධ වන්නේ මව් පුවරුව (mother board) නම් පරිපථයටයි."},{"question":"Дүйнөдөгү эң чоң жарым арал?","answer":"Планетабыздагы эң чоң жарым арал бул - Аравия жарым аралы."},{"question":"సామల సదాశివ రచనలను సంగ్రహంగా తెలుపండి ?","answer":"సామల సదాశివ ఆదిలాబాద్ జిల్లా దహగాం మండలంలోని తెలుగు పల్లెలో మే 11, 1928న జన్మించాడు. ఈయన తల్లిదండ్రులు సామల చిన్నమ్మ, నాగయ్యలు. సదాశివ విభిన్న భాషా సంస్కృతుల కళావారధి, వీరు సంస్కృతం, హిందీ, ఉర్దూ, ఆంగ్లం, ఫార్సీ, మరాఠీ తెలుగు భాషలలో పండితుడు. వీరి తొలి రచనలలో ప్రభాతము అనే లఘు కావ్యం, సాంబశివ శతకం, నిరీక్షణము, అంబపాలి, సర్వస్య దానము, విశ్వామిత్ర మొదలుగునవి ఉన్నాయి.హిందూస్థానీ సంగీత కళాకారుల ప్రతిభపై, ‘మలయమారుతాలు’ ప్రముఖుల జ్ఞాపకాలు, ఉర్దూ, భాషా కవిత్వ సౌందర్య ఉర్దూకవుల కవితా సామాగ్రి మొదలగునవి ప్రసిద్ధ గ్రంథాలు.అన్జద్ రుబాయిలు తెలుగు అనువాదానికి ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్ ప్రభుత్వం ఉత్తమ అనువాద పురస్కారాన్ని ఇచ్చింది. వీరి ‘స్వరలయలు’ గ్రంథానికి కేంద్రసాహిత్య అకాడమీ అవార్డు లభించింది. కాకతీయ, తెలుగు విశ్వవిద్యాలయాలు వీరిని గౌరవ డాక్టరేట్ తో సత్కరించాయి. వీరి రచనలపై విశ్వవిద్యాలయాలలో పలు పరిశోధనలు జరిగాయి."},{"question":"ஆத்திப் பூ மாலையை அணிந்தவர்கள்  யார் ?   ","answer":"சோழர்.சேர சோழ பாண்டியர் போரின் போது அடையாளம் தெரிவதற்காகச் சூடிக் கொள்ளும் பூ போந்தை, ஆர், வேம்பு. இவற்றில் சோழர் அணிந்து கொள்ளும் பூ ‘ஆர்’. இந்த ஆர் என்னும் பூ ‘ஆத்திப் பூ’ என்பதில் கருத்து மாறுபாடு இல்லை.ஆத்திப் பூ என்பதை அடையாளம் காட்டுவதில் அறிஞர்கள் மாறுபடுகின்றனர்.சிவபெருமான் சூடும் ஆத்தி‘ஆத்தி சூடி’ என அறநூல் பாடிய பிற்கால ஔவையார் குறிப்பிடுகிறார்.பூவரசம்பூ போன்ற அமைப்புடன், ஆனால், அதில் நான்கில் ஒரு பங்கு அளவினதாக வெள்ளை நிறத்திலும் மஞ்சள் நிறத்திலும் பூக்கும் மலரினை இக்காலத்தில் அறிஞர்கள் ஆத்தி எனக் காட்டுகின்றனர்.சோழர் சூரிய குலத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள் என்பது பிற்காலத்தில் தோன்றிய கருத்தென்றுச் சிலர் சொல்வர். இந்தக் கருத்தில்கூடச் சோழன் சிவபெருமானின் குலம் என்று கொள்ளப்படவில்லை.இவ்வாறு தமிழர்களின் சமயங்களில் ஒன்றான சைவ சமயத்தின் இறைவன் சிவபெருமான் ஆத்தி மலரை விரும்பிச் சூடுவதாக ஒரு கருத்தும் உள்ளது.சோழர் சூடும் ஆர் என்னும் ஆத்திதாமற்பல் கண்ணனார் என்னும் புலவர், சோழன் மாவளத்தானோடு சூதாடிய பொழுது தாமற்பல் கண்ணனார் சூதாட்டத்தில் வட்டை மறைத்துவைத்துத் தன்னை ஏமாற்றியதாக எண்ணிய சோழன் சினமுற்று, அவ்வட்டை அவர் மீது எறிந்தான். அதனால், கோபமுற்ற தாமற்பல் கண்ணனார், மாவளத்தானைப் பார்த்து மன்னா உன் செய்கையைப் பார்த்தால், நீ சோழ மன்னனுக்குப் பிறந்தவனாக எனக்குத் தோன்றவில்லையே, ஆத்திமாலை சூடிய உன் முன்னோரெல்லாம் பார்ப்பனர்கள் நோவுமாறு எந்தச் செயலையும் செய்யமாட்டர்களே என்று இகழ்கிறார்.கோவூர் கிழார் என்னும் புலவர், தங்களுக்குள் இருந்த பகை காரணமாக சோழன் நலங்கிள்ளிக்கும் சோழன் நெடுங்கிள்ளிக்கும் இடையே போர் மூண்ட பொழுது, சோழனே உன்னுடைய மாலை ஆத்திப் பூக்களால் தொடுக்கப்பட்டது, உன்னோடு போர் புரிபவனின் மாலையும் ஆத்திப் பூவால் தொடுக்கப்பட்டதுதான். உங்கள் இருவரில் ஒருவர் தோற்றாலும் தோற்பது சோழனின் குடிதான் எனவே போரைத் தவிர்க்க என்று இருவருக்கும் அறிவுரை கூறுகிறார்.சாத்தந்தையார் என்னும் புலவர் சோழ மன்னன் கோப்பெரு நற்கிள்ளி நாரால் நெருக்கமாகத் தொடுக்கப்பட்ட ஆத்தி மாலையையும் இரவலர்க்கு ஈகை செய்துவிடும் கவிந்த கையை உடைய வீரன் என்று குறிப்பிடுகிறார்.[6] மேலும் அவர், ஆத்தி மாலை சூடிய பெரியோன் கோப்பெரு நற்கிள்ளி ஊரைத் தன்வசமாக்கிக்கொள்ள வந்த மற்போர் வீரனுடன் போர் நடத்தினான் என்றும் குறிப்பிடுகிறார்.சோழன் சூடும் ‘ஆத்தி’ எது – என்பதை நற்றிணைப் பாடல் ஒன்று நமக்குப் படம் பிடித்துக் காட்டுகிறது. ஆர் என்பது ஆத்தி-மலர். தமாலம் என்பது வெற்றிலைக் கொடி. அது படர்ந்த மரம் 'ஆர்'. வெற்றிலையைக் கொடிக்காலில் ஆத்தி மரத்தில் படரவிடுகின்றனர்.தமாலம் கொடி வெற்றிலைக் கொடி எனச் கொள்வதற்குச் சிலப்பதிகார அடிகளும் துணை நிற்கின்றன"},{"question":"Laaarọ kutu Mọnde, awọn obinrin meji ku lasiko ti wọn n lọ sọja l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Idi iṣẹ ẹni la ti n mọ ni lọlẹ lawọn obinrin meji kan ti wọn pade iku ojiji lọjọ Mọnde ọsẹ yii fi ọrọ wọn ṣe ti wọn fi tete mu ọna ọja ti wọn ti n ra ẹja pọn niluu Abẹokuta. Ṣugbọn niṣe ni mọto ti wọn wọ lọọ kọ lu tirela to bajẹ sọna, l’Abule Adedẹrọ, bi wọn ṣe dagbere faye niyẹn.Aago mẹfa idaji ku iṣẹju mẹẹẹdogun niṣẹlẹ yii waye, ni Mọnde, ọjọ keje, oṣu kẹfa yii.  Kọbapẹ ni mọto ayọkẹlẹ Nissan tawọn obinrin naa wọ ti gbe wọn pẹlu awọn ero ọkọ mi-in, ilu Abẹokuta ni wọn si n lọ.Igba ti wọn de Abule Adedẹrọ, loju ọna marosẹ Eko s’Abẹokuta ni dẹrẹba lọọ kọ lu tirela to bajẹ sọna, nigba naa lawọn obinrin meji yii dagbere faye, awọn mẹta mi-in si fara pa.Alukoro TRACE, Babatunde Akinbiyi, ṣalaye nipa ijamba naa. O ni dẹrẹba ọkọ Nissan naa lo n sare ju, ti ko wo ti pe ilẹ ko ti i mọ daadaa. Ere to pọ ju yii ati airiran daadaa nigba ti ilẹ ko ti i mọ to lo ni o fa a ti asidẹnti yii fi waye.Owo to le ni ẹgbẹrun lọna igba naira ni wọn ba lara awọn obinrin meji to doloogbe yii, owo ti wọn fẹẹ lọọ fi ra ẹja ti wọn n ta ni.Wọn ba ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọjọ din diẹ naira (153,620) lara ọkan, wọn si ba ẹgbẹrun lọna mẹtadinlọgọrin (77,000) lara ẹni keji. Awọn mọlẹbi wọn ni wọn ko owo naa fun gẹgẹ bi Alukoro TRACE ṣe sọ.Mọṣuari ọsibitu Ijaye ni wọn gbe awọn oku meji naa lọ.Ajọ TRACE waa kilọ fawọn awakọ ti mọto wọn ba bajẹ soju ọna lati maa gbe e kuro lọna kia, ko ma baa maa da ijamba silẹ bii eyi.Bakan naa ni wọn rọ awọn awakọ pe ki wọn yee sare asapajude loju popo, paapaa lasiko ti wọn ko ba riran daadaa bii idaji kutu ati ọwọ alẹ."},{"question":"Explain the concept of dynamic programming.","answer":"Dynamic programming is a problem-solving technique where a complex problem is solved by breaking it into simpler overlapping subproblems, and solutions to subproblems are stored to avoid redundant computations."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত শিরোনাম এবং সারাংশের উপর ভিত্তি করে একটি নিবন্ধ তৈরি করুন |শিরোনাম :সিরিয়ায় যুদ্ধ শেষ হলেও কি তারা দেশে ফিরতে পারবে?সারাংশ:ভয়াবহ যুদ্ধের কারণেই বাড়িঘর ছেড়ে বাস্তুচ্যুত হয়েছে সিরিয়ার বহু মানুষ। কিন্তু যুদ্ধ শেষ হলেও কি তারা ফিরতে পারবে?","answer":"গৃহযুদ্ধ শুরুর পর সিরিয়া ছেড়েছে দেশটির অন্তত ৫০ লাখ মানুষসিরিয়ায় ২০১১ সালে গৃহযুদ্ধ শুরুর পর থেকে এ পর্যন্ত দেশ ছাড়তে বাধ্য হয়েছে প্রায় পঞ্চাশ লাখ মানুষ। মূলত তাদের বেশিরভাগই আশ্রয় নিয়েছে প্রতিবেশী দেশগুলোতে। সবচেয়ে বেশি সংখ্যক শরণার্থী এখন তুরস্কে যার সংখ্যা প্রায় ৩৫ লাখ। আর লেবাননে আছে আরও প্রায় দশ লাখ। আর পাঁচ লাখেরও মতো শরণার্থীর জায়গা হয়েছে জার্মানিতে। এছাড়া ইউরোপের আরও কয়েকটি দেশে আছে অল্প কিছু শরণার্থী। আরো পড়ুন:যুদ্ধবিরতি সমঝোতার পরও সিরিয়ায় হামলা সিরিয"},{"question":"ما هي اللغة التي يتحدث بها معظم سكان فيينا؟","answer":"معظم سكان فيينا نمساويون يتكلمون اللغة الألمانية. كما يعيش فيها عدد من التشيكيين والمجريين، ولكن معظمهم يتكلمون اللغة الألمانية إضافة إلى لغاتهم القومية. يلبس سكان فيينا أزياء شعبية في مناسبات خاصة."},{"question":"మార్కెట్ గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"సాధారణంగా మార్కెట్ అంటే వస్తువుల క్రయ, విక్రయాలు జరిగే ప్రదేశం అని భావిస్తాం. కాని అర్థశాస్త్రంలో మార్కెట్ అంటే అమ్మకందార్లు, కొనుగోలుదార్లు కలిసి ధరలు నిర్ణయించుకోవటానికి ఉపయోగపడే యంత్రాంగం."},{"question":"ශ්‍රි ලංකා ගුවන් විදුලි සංස්ථාව පිළිබඳ කෙටි විස්තරයක් සපයන්න.","answer":"ශ්‍රි ලංකා ගුවන් විදුලි සංස්ථාව ශ්‍රි ලංකා රජයේ නිල ගුවන්විදුලි විකාශන ආයතනයයි.  එය සිංහල, දෙමළ සහ ඉංග්‍රීසි භාශා වලින් ගුවන්විදුලි සේවා පවත්වාගෙන යයි. මුල් කාලයේදී රේඩියෝ සිලෝන් ලෙස හැඳින්වූ ශ්‍රී ලංකා ගුවන් විදුලි සංස්ථාව (ශ්‍රී. ලං. ගු. වි. සං.) දකුණු ආසියාවේ ඇති පැරණිම ගුවන් විදුලි ආයතනය වන අතර එය \\"කොළඹ ගුවන්විදුලිය\\" යන නාමයෙන් 1925 වසරේ​දී ආරම්භ කරන ලදී."},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:એવું શું છે જેને ચાર પગ હોવા છતાં પણ ચાલી શકતું નથી?","answer":"ટેબલ"},{"question":"మానవ కండరాలలో అవాయు శ్వాసక్రియ వల్ల ఏ రసాయనం ఏర్పడుతుంది?","answer":"మానవ కండరాలలో అవాయు శ్వాసక్రియ వల్ల ఏర్పడే రసాయనం : లాక్టిక్ ఆమ్లం"},{"question":"Funda le ndaba ekhuluma ngokudlala amamarimba, bese uphendula imibuzo.Ziningi izinto ezishiwo ngokuthi ama-marimba avela kanjani. Ulwazi olukhona lukhombisangokusobala ukuthi ama-marimba aqala eminyakeni eminingi kakhulu eyedlule e-Afrika.Ngokuhamba kwesikhathi ahamba aze afika eMelika okuyilapho kwavela ama-marimba esimanjenjengoba esedume kangaka nje. Igama lama-marimba livela ezilimini ezimbili zase-Afrika. Namuhla,ama-marimba awuhlobo lwezinsimbi zomculo ezisemthwethweni emazweni afana ne-Guatemala,ne-Nicaraga, ne-Costa Rica kanye nase-Mexico.Izikole eziningi zase-Afrika ziyawasebenzisa kakhulu ama-marimba esimanje kulesi sikhathi esiphilakuso. Sekuyinto ejwayelekile ukubona abafundi bedlala ama-marimba emakhonsathini ezikoleehlukahlukene. Okunye okuhle ukubona ukuthi indlela adlalwa ngayo inokuhambisana nezinyeizinhlobo zemiculo ethandwa ngabantu abasha. Lokhu kuhle ngoba kuyabaheha abantu abasha.Kuningi okungashiwo ngama-marimba ngeqhaza alibambayo empilweni. Isibonelo salokhu ukuthikubalulekile ukuwagcina ngendlela efanele ama-marimba ukuze angalimali. Njengoba enziwengezingodo, kumele agcinwe endaweni eyomile. Isidingo sokunakekela ama-marimba ngale ndlelasikufundisa ukunakekela into oyisebenzisayo ukuze ukwazi ukuyisebenzisa nangolunye usuku.Yingakho-nje kukuhle ukuthi ama-marimba asedumile kakhulu ezikoleni.Ukudlala ama-marimba kuyinto engenziwa abantu abadala nabancane. Abantu bathi kululaukudlala ama-marimba ngoba asikho isidingo sokufundela umculo. Ungafunda ukudlala iculo elilulangokushesha kuma-marimba uma uqhathanisa nezinye izinsimbi zomculo ezidinga amakhonoasezingeni eliphezulu.Ngale ndlela, ukudlala ama-marimba kuyasiza ukusondeza abantu abahlukene ndawonye. Umuntuoqalayo kungamthatha isikhathi esingangehora nje kuphela ukuthi akwazi ukudlala iculo kumamarimba kanye nabantu abanesikhathi eside bewadlala futhi asebenesipiliyoni. Ngakho-ke umausafunda ukuwadlala angeke uzizwe sengathi uyahluleka noma ubambezela abanye odlala nabo.Kunalokho uzizwa uyingxenye yeqembu ngokushesha. Konke lokhu kwenza abantu abanamakhonoahlukene ukuba bakwazi ukuba ndawonye badlale umculo, futhi kukhuthaza ukusebenzisananokubambisana.Njengoba ama-marimba ehlanganisa abantu ngale ndlela, awubi nomzwangedwa noma isizungulapho udlala ngoba usuke uhlanganyele nabanye. Ukufunda nabanye abantu kuyinto ekhuthazayoikakhulukazi lapho kumnandi khona. Kungabasiza nalabo abanamahloni ukuba bazitholebesendaweni lapho behlanganyela nabanye abantu ngaphandle kwengcindezi. Ngakho-ke, ukudlalalo mculo wama-marimba kungaba indlela enhle yokuzenzela abangane abasha ngendlela emnandi.2 Livela kuphi igama lama-marimba?","answer":"e-Afrika "},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ɗari ɗaya da tamanin da biyar a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 185"},{"question":"ਮੈਂ ਫੁੱਲ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਨੱਕ ਥੱਲ੍ਹੇ ਰੱਖ ਲਿਆ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਫੁੱਲ ਦੀਆਂ ਪੱਤੀਆਂ ਉੱਤਰ ਗਈਆਂ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਫੁੱਲ ਨੂੰ ਸੁੰਘਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਫੁੱਲ ਨੂੰ ਸੁੰਘਿਆ।"},{"question":"Ìṣesósíálístì","answer":"Ìṣesósíálístì (Socialism) je ero okowo ati oloselu to duro lori ini igboro tabi ikanna ati ibojuto alafowosowopo awon ona imuwaye ati ipin awon alumoni.Ninu sistemu okowo sosialisti, imuwaye je latowo ajose igboro awon olumuwaye lati muwaye taarata awon ohun iwulo (kuku awon ohun pasiparo), lona eto ipinu inawo, ipikakiri opo, ati lilo awon ona imuwaye. Isesosialisti je akojopo awon eto awujo ati okowo toduro lori sistemu isiro eyin eto owo, bi asiko ise, awon eyo okun tabi isiro iru ara."},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة عامه من بحر الوافر.","answer":"قُصور الشام مَحكمة المَبانيوَلا قَصر كَقَصر بَني الكَريمينَزَلناهُ بِمقرتح الأَمانيعَلى ما نَشتهيهِ مِن النَعيمنُساجل فيهِ مُطربة المَزايامِن الأَخلاق وَالطَبع السَليم"},{"question":"السؤال: ما أقسام المعاصي؟","answer":"الإجابة: كبائر وصغائر"},{"question":"ከየትኞቹ የስሜት ምድቦች መካከል የሚከተለውን ትዊት ይመድባሉ? አዎንታዊ, አሉታዊ ወይም ገለልተኛየከፍተኛ ሊግ አራተኛ ሳምንት ውጤቶች  ምድብ ሀ  እሁድ ታኅሳስ 26 ቀን 2012  ለገጣፎ ለገዳዲ 3-0 ወልዲያ ደሴ ከተማ 1-0 ኤሌክትሪክ ሰ/ሸ/ደ/ብርሀን 0-1 ደደቢት አክሱም…","answer":"የተሰጠውን ትዊት እንደሚከተለው እከፋፍለው፡ ገለልተኛ።"},{"question":"Cudurada ku dhaca dadka da'da ah?","answer":"#Cudurada_Kudhaca_Dadka_Dada_Ah Marxalada gabowga waxa kudhaca jirka dadka dada ah isbadalo waweyn. Taaso sababi doonta cuduro. #Qormadan waxan kugula wadagi doona cudurada kudhaca qofka dada marku noqdo.  #Faafi ➡️ CUDURKA PARKINSON Cudurkan qofka uu kudhaco waxa hoos udhacaya unugyada maskaxda ee sosara Dopamine. Dopamine wa maado laga soo dayo maskaxda kana masula dhaqdhaqa ama socodka. 🔹️ calamadaha lagu arko qofka qaba 📌 Jareeys gacmaha ah. Inta badan waa aragta qof wayeela oo gacmaha iska  jareynayan. ( wa calamada ugu muhimsn) 📌 socod yar. Wa aragta qof talabada anan kala dheereyn karin. 📌 murqaha oo adkada. Qofka markan aadna wa uxanunan waxyna xadidaan socodka qofka. 📌 Hadalka qofka oo isbadala.qofka hadal kiisa wuxu noqona mid jilicsan oo hadana boobsisa. 📌 isbadal kudhaca wax qorista qofka. Waxa ku adkada qofka inuu wax qoro fartisana waxey u muqta wax yaris ah.🔜 cudurkan maran sifahfahsan uga hadli doonaa I.a ➡️ CUDURKA ALZHEIMER KA Alzheimer waxu kala midyahay parkinson inu kudhaco maskaxda. Cudurkan wuxu kudhaca unugyada dareenka wada ee maskaxda wuxuna sababa ineey yarato maskaxda waxa uuna sigaara ugu dhaca qeybta kamasul ka ah luqadaha,xasusta inta badan wuxu kudhaca dadka 60 dhfy 🔹️ calamadaha lagu arko qofka qaba 📌 xasuusta ayaa ka lunta qofka 📌 wax kala garashada ayu wayaa. Tusale makala saari karo wajiyada 📌 qofka waxa lagu arka dhibatoyin xaga hadalka, aqriska , wax qorista ah 📌 dabeecada qofka oo isbadasha. Qofka wxa kalumaya rabista wxu noqda mid caro badan sido kale wuxu noqda mid walwal badan 🔜 maran sifahfahsan uga hadli doonaa cudurkan i.a ➡️ MAQAL KA OO YARAADA Yaraan shaha maqalka ee lasocda wayeel nimada wxa sababa adkanshaha xididada dhiiga quudiya qeybta gudaha ee dhagta. Wana dhibatoyinka ugu badan ee dadka wayelka ka shegtan. 🔹️ calamadaha lagu garto 📌 inta badan qofku kor ayuu u hadlaa marka la shekeysanyo 📌 xaladaha qaar qofka wuxu kacbtaa buuq dhagaha ah ama haldhag ah. ➡️ CUDURADA WADNAHA Weeynan shaha muruqaha wadnaha. Wa cudur kubadan dadka dada ah taaso keeni donta qofka jirkisa inu daciifo. 🔹️ calamadaha lagu garto qofka 📌 qofka inu dareemo neeftu ineey kudhageyso gaar ahan marka uu wax qabto haba yaradane. ➡️ CUDURKA NEEFTA Wa dhibaato kajirta hawo mareenada neef sashada waxeyna timada marka hawa mareenda kajirto xajiin taas oo sababeen walxaha keena xajinta 🔹️ calamadaha lagu garto qofka 📌 neef sashada oo kudhibta 📌 xabad xanuun ama xabadka oo jiq ah 📌 qofac  hurdo xumo 🔜 neefta wa kahadli doona si fahfahsan I.a walal. ➡️ CUDURKA SOKORTA (macaanka)Baaritano lasameyay waxa lagu ogaday in 25%dadka kaweyn 65 sano eey lanool yihin cudurka macaanka.waana halis weyn oo wajaheysa caafimad ka dadka dada ah. Waxa wanagsan in cudurka macaanka waqti hore labaaro daawna loqato si lola socdo. 🔜 cudurka macaanka ruxisa wa wadagi doona si dhameestiran I.a Mahadsanid."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.\\"වළලද්දි කොළ පාටයි ගොඩ ගද්දි කහ පාටයි\\"","answer":"කෙසෙල් කැන"},{"question":"Ayat 1: Pada tahun 1996, Jawatankuasa Veteran memilih Bill Foster dari abad ke-19 dan Ned Hanlon dari liga Negro, Jim Bunning dan Earl Weaver. Ayat 2: Pada tahun 1996, Jawatankuasa Veteran Ned Hanlon dari abad ke-19 dan Bill Foster dari Negro Ligen, serta Jim Bunning dan Earl Weaver memilih. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Tidak"},{"question":"Escreva uma pergunta da categoria Video Games","answer":"Qual é o nome do jogo de Elder Scrolls que não é para apenas um jogador? Elder Scrolls Online"},{"question":"乔峰是哪个门派的人？","answer":"在金庸小说里，乔峰是丐帮的帮主。"},{"question":"หนังสือพิมพ์ฉบับแรกของไทยคืออะไร","answer":"หนังสือพิมพ์ฉบับแรกของไทย คือ หนังสือจดหมายเหตุฯ บางกอกรีคอร์เดอร์ ออกโดยหมอบรัดเลย์ (Dan Beach Bradley) มิชชันนารีชาวอเมริกัน จัดพิมพ์เมื่อวันที่ 4 กรกฎาคม พ.ศ.2387"},{"question":"ઈન્દિરા એકાદશીની કથાનુ વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"સતયુગમાં માહિષ્મતી નગરીમાં રાજા ઈન્દ્રસેન રાજ કરતો હતો. ધર્મથી સાસન ચલાવતા આ રાજા પાસે એક દિવસ નારદ મુનિ આવે છે. રાજા એમનું સ્વાગત કરે છે. નારદ મુનિ રાજાને 'તમારી પ્રજા તો સુખી છે ને ?' એમ પૂછે છે. રાજા જવાબ આપે છે કે પ્રજાનું સુખ એ જ મારો ધર્મ છે. આ સાંભળી નારદ કહે છે કે આપના પિતાજીને હું યમલોકમાં મળ્યો હતો. તેઓ ત્યાં સામાન્ય લોકોની સેવા કરતા હતા. એમણે મને કહ્યું કે હું કોઈક સંજોગોમાં અહીં દુ:ખમાં દિવસો પસાર કરું છું. જો મારો પુત્ર વિધિવત્ ઈન્દિરા એકાદશીનું વ્રત, પૂજન અને ઉપવાસ કરશે તો મારી મુક્તિ થશે. આથી રાજાએ મુનિને આ વ્રત કેવી કરવાનો સમય, વિધિની જાણ મેળવવા વિનંતી કરી.આ વિધિ અનુસાર ભાદરવા વદ દશમના દિવસે જળાશયમાં સ્નાન કરી શ્રદ્ધાપૂર્વક પિતૃઓને પ્રસન્ન કરવા અને રાત્રે ભૂમિશયન કરવું. બીજે દિવસે એકાદશી વ્રત આદરવું. તે દિવસે સવારે ઊઠીને પિતૃ‌ઓને પ્રસન્ન કરી, ઉપવાસ કરવો તથા સઘળા ભોગનો ત્યાગ કરવો. મધ્યાહ્ન સમયે શાલિગ્રામનું પૂજન કરી યોગ્યજનોને ભોજન કરાવી દક્ષિણા આપવી. રાત્રે જાગરણ કરી પ્રભુનું ધ્યાન ચિત્તમાં ધરી રાત્રિ પસાર કરવી."},{"question":" Quem é a única brasileira a ter sido indicada ao Oscar de Melhor Atriz?","answer":"O cinema."},{"question":"ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਅਰਵਿੰਦ ਕੇਜਰੀਵਾਲ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹੋ ?","answer":"ਅਰਵਿੰਦ ਕੇਜਰੀਵਾਲ (ਜਨਮ 16 ਅਗਸਤ 1968) ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਆਸਤਦਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਮਾਜ ਸੁਧਾਰਕ ਹਨ। ਇਹ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ 8ਵੇਂ ਅਤੇ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵੀ ਉਹ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਰਹਿ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ। 28 ਦਸੰਬਰ 2013 ਨੂੰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਅਹੁਦੇ ਦੀ ਸਹੁੰ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਸੀ। ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਜਨੀਤਕ ਗਤੀਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਇਹ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਰੇਵੇਨਿਊ ਸਰਵਿਸ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਸਮਾਜਕ ਕਰਮਚਾਰੀ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿਆਦਾ ਪਾਰਦਰਸ਼ਤਾ ਲਿਆਉਣ ਲਈ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ 2006 ਵਿੱਚ ਉੱਤਮ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਲਈ ਰਮਨ ਮੈਗਸੇਸੇ ਇਨਾਮ ਨਾਲ ਸਨਮਾਨਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਦਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ, 2005 ਜਾਂ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਅਰਥਾਤ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਕਨੂੰਨ ਦੇ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਮੀਨੀ ਪੱਧਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਸਰਗਰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ, ਅਤੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਜਨਤਾ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਜਵਾਬਦੇਹ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਗਰੀਬ ਨਾਗਰਿਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਾਚਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਲੜਨ ਲਈ ਸਮਰਥ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਹੇਤੁ ਸਮਾਜਕ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ।== ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿਧਾਨਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ 2015 ==ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੇਜਰੀਵਾਲ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ 'ਚ ਆਮ ਆਦਮੀ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਹੂੰਝਾ-ਫੇਰ ਜਿੱਤ ਵਿਖਾਉਂਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ ਕਾਮਯਾਬੀ ਹਾਸਿਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ 70 ਵਿੱਚੋਂ 67 ਸੀਟਾਂ ਜਿੱਤੀਆਂ। ਇਹ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਕ ਜਿੱਤ ਸੀ।ਪਰ ਕੇਜਰੀਵਾਲ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੀ ਜਨਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤੇ ਵਾਅਦੇ ਪੂਰੇ ਕਰਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਸਮਰਥ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਉਹ ਜਨਤਾ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਆਪਣੀ ਅਸਫਲਤਾ ਤੇ ਪਰਦਾ ਪਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮੋਦੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਲਝਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਕਦੀ ਲੈਫ ਗਵਰਨਰ ਜੰਗ ਨਾਲ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਈ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਭਿ੍ਸਟਾਚਾਰ ਦੇ ਦੋਸ਼ਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਉਲਝ ਰਹੇ ।"},{"question":"Àwọn iṣẹ́ wo ní ó pò jù lọ ni ayé àtijọ́ ní ilé Yorùbá?","answer":"Iṣẹ́ Àgbè ati Ìṣe Ọdẹ "},{"question":"Scrivi una versione più complessa della frase:\\"Era uno studente molto intelligente con un profondo interesse per la giustizia sociale\\".","answer":"Naturalmente, una versione più complessa della frase è \\"Era uno studente molto intelligente con un profondo interesse per la giustizia sociale e un linguista dotato sin da piccolo, ha imparato a parlare perfettamente il francese e poi il tedesco e lo spagnolo\\"."},{"question":"Кандай элдик ырлардан билесиз?","answer":"Тектирге эле чыккан буудайды 🌾,Теңселтип ай шамал 🍃 ыргайбы?Теңчилик ай ушул заманда ээй,Теңтуштар ай ойноп жыргайлы ээээй."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari ɗaya da saba'in da uku a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 173"},{"question":" Qual foi o primeiro país a permitir o voto feminino?","answer":"Nova Zelândia."},{"question":"व्यक्तिच्या जीवनातील आवश्यक संस्कारापैकी शेवटचे संस्कार कोणते ?","answer":"व्यक्तिच्या जीवनातील आवश्यक संस्कारापैकी शेवटचे संस्कार अंतिम संस्कार"},{"question":"නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය පිරිණමන විෂය ක්ෂේත්‍රය​න් මොනවාද ?","answer":"නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය පිරිණමන විෂය ක්ෂේත්‍රය​න් පහත දක්වා ඇත.1. භෞතික විද්‍යාව2. රසායණ විද්‍යාව3. වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාව4. සාහිත්‍යය5. සාමය6. ආර්ථික විද්‍යාව"},{"question":"Natrium klorida, yang biasa dipanggil \\"garam meja\\", mengadungi natrium dan klorin yang telah digabungkan secara kimia. Istilah mana yang terbaik menggambarkan natrium klorida? Pilih dari yang berikut. (I) Asid; (II) Atom; (III) Unsur; (IV) Kompaun;","answer":"(IV) Kompaun"},{"question":"Adewale Ayuba ṣile olowo nla, o tun di Aarẹ Bọbaṣelu n’Ikẹnnẹ","answer":"Titi dasiko yii lawọn eeyan ṣi n rọjo ikini ku oriire ati adura sile gbajumọ onifuji nni, Oloye Adewale Ayuba, ẹni to ṣile olowo nla niluu Ikẹnnẹ Rẹmọ, lọjọ Ẹti to kọja yii, to si tun joye Ọtunba Aarẹ Bobaṣelu Ikẹnnẹ.Awoṣifila nile ti Ayuba kọ yii, miliọnu rẹpẹtẹ ni wọn lo pari ẹ, niṣe lo ṣe rekete ti gbogbo ogiri ile ọhun n dan gbinrin.Ọda funfun ni wọn fi kun un, wọn si fi awọ pupa resuresu (brown) kun apa kan niwaju rẹ. Ile duro lori ilẹ naa lọ ni, bii ẹsiteeti lo ri.Awọn eeyan sọ pe Ayuba diidi waa fa ile nla yii kalẹ niluu abinibi rẹ ni, nitori ile labọ isinmi oko.Nipa ti oye Ọtunba Aarẹ Bobaṣelu Ikẹnnẹ ti  Ọba Adeyinka Ọnakade, Alakẹnnẹ Ikẹnnẹ fi i jẹ, Adewale Ayuba dupẹ lọwọ Kabiyesi, gẹgẹ bi ọba paapaa ṣe sọ pe ika to tọ simu la fi n romu lọrọ oye toun fi oṣere yii jẹ.Adewale Ayuba dupẹ lọwọ gbogbo awọn to waa ba a ṣẹyẹ mejeeji yii, o ṣalaye bi inu rẹ ṣe dun to, o si gbadura pe nnkan ayọ ko ni i tan nile tiwọn naa.Awọn oṣere ilẹ wa meji, Alaaja Salawa Abẹni ati Ọgbẹni Dele Odule, wa nibi ayẹyẹ ọhun, bẹẹ si lawọn ọtọkulu ilu loriṣiiriṣii wa nibẹ pẹlu.Awọn pasitọ ijọ Ridiimu ti Adewale Ayuba n lọ lo gbadura sile naa, wọn fi adura ran an lọwọ nipa ti oye to jẹ pẹlu, wọn si fi ohun gbogbo le Oluwa lọwọ fun oludasilẹ Bonsue Fuji, Oloye Adewale Ayuba to ṣile nla, to tun joye tuntun n’Ikẹnnẹ Ereke."},{"question":"Эртең менен ойгону ыкмасы...","answer":" Кофе ичиңиз. Эгер сизди жеңил ойготууга кофе жардам берсе, анда кечинде термоско кофе даярдап алып керебетиңиздин жанына коюп коюңуз. Эртең менен ойгонгондо бир кружка ичип алсаңыз натыйжасын берет."},{"question":"உங்களுடன் பயிலும் மாணவர் ஒருவர் பள்ளிப் படிப்பைப் பாதியில் நிறுத்தி வேலைக்குச் செல்ல விரும்புகிறார். அவரிடம் கற்பதன் இன்றியமையாமையை எவ்வகையில் எடுத்துரைப்பீர்கள்?","answer":"கல்வி என்பது நம் வாழ்க்கையில் முன்னேறக் கூடிய ஒரு ஏணிப்படி அதைக் கற்றால் நம் வாழ்க்கையில் வெற்றி பெறலாம். நம் தாய் தந்தை தான் படிக்கவில்லை நாம் படித்து அவர்களின் வாழ்க்கைத் தரத்தை உயர்த்த வேண்டும் எண்ணமும் செயலும் உயர்வாக இருந்தால், நாம் உயர்வாக இருக்க முடியும். நம் பெற்றோர்களின் ஆசைகளை நாம் நிறைவேற்ற வேண்டும். கல்வி கற்பதன் மூலம் நாம்வாழ்க்கையில் எவ்வளவு சோதனைகள் வந்தாலும் அதைச் சமாளிக்க முடியும். வாழ்க்கையில் எவ்வளவு தடைகள் வந்தாலும் அதைச் சமாளித்து இந்த வருடம் படிப்பை நீ முடித்து விடு. இந்த வருடப் படிப்பை முடித்து விட்டால் அடுத்த வருடம் வேலைக்குச் சென்று கொண்டே கூட நீ படித்து விடலாம். எந்த சூழ்நிலை வந்தாலும் படிப்பை மட்டும் பாதியில் விட்டு விடக்கூடாது என்பதில் நீ உறுதியாக இருக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"క్రింది సమితి Aని ఉద్దేశించి ఈ క్రింది నీయబడిన ప్రవచనాల నుండి సరైన జవాబు గుర్తించండి. A = {1, 2, 3, 4}i) n(A) = 4ii) సమితి ‘A’ కి గల ఉపసమితుల సంఖ్య 16A) i సత్యం, ii అసత్యంB) i అసత్యం , ii సత్యంC) i మరియు ii లు రెండూ సత్యంD) i మరియు ii లు రెండూ అసత్యం","answer":"C) i మరియు ii లు రెండూ సత్యం"},{"question":"如何在Bilibili上发布视频？","answer":"答：在Bilibili上发布视频需要注册成为会员，并通过实名认证。然后，你可以上传自己制作的视频，并添加标题、描述和标签。"},{"question":"فشار څنګه په رواني روغتیا اغیزه کوي، او د فشار سره د معاملو لپاره اغیزمن میکانیزمونه کوم دي؟","answer":"فشار د ننګونو حالتونو ته فزیکولوژیکي او رواني غبرګون دی، او په رواني روغتیا یې اغیزې کیدی شي ژور وي. اوږدمهاله فشار د رواني روغتیا مختلف اختلالاتو سره تړاو لري ، پشمول اضطراب او خپګان ، او همدارنګه د فزیکي روغتیا مسلې لکه د زړه ناروغۍ. د بدن د فشار په غبرګون کې د کورټیسول په څیر د هورمونونو خوشې کول شامل دي، کوم چې کله چې په دوامداره توګه لوړ شي، کولی شي په دماغ او بدن دواړو ناوړه اغیزې ولري.د رواني هوساینې ساتلو لپاره د فشار سره مبارزه اړینه ده. د صحي مقابلې میکانیزمونه د ستونزې حل کولو ستراتیژیو کې شامل دي، د ټولنیز مالتړ په لټه کې، د آرامۍ تخنیکونو تمرین کول لکه مراقبت یا ژوره تنفس، او په فزیکي تمرین کې ښکیلتیا. د یو چا د فشارونو پیژندنه او د اغیزمنې مبارزې ستراتیژیو رامینځته کول د اوږدمهاله فشار د منفي پایلو مخنیوي لپاره خورا مهم دي. ارواپوهان اکثرا د افرادو سره کار کوي ترڅو د دوی ځانګړي فشارونو او شرایطو سره سم د شخصي کاپي میکانیزمونه وپیژني ، د ذهني انعطاف او عمومي هوساینې وده کوي."},{"question":"Inona no hatao hoe famintinan-dahatsoratra?","answer":"Ny hatao hoe famintinan-dahatsoratra dia fanafohezana lahatsoratra lava iray amin'ny alalan'ny hevi-dehibe raketiny."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਸੋਈ ਸਾਸਤੁ ਸਉਣੁ ਸੋਇ ਜਿਤੁ ਜਪੀਐ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਉ ॥ਚਰਣ ਕਮਲ ਗੁਰਿ ਧਨੁ ਦੀਆ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਨਿਥਾਵੇ ਥਾਉ ॥ਸਾਚੀ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਸਚੁ ਸੰਜਮੋ ਆਠ ਪਹਰ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਉ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਭੇਟਿਆ ਮਰਣੁ ਨ ਆਵਣੁ ਜਾਉ ॥੧॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਹਰਿ ਭਜੁ ਸਦਾ ਇਕ ਰੰਗਿ ॥ਘਟ ਘਟ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਰਵਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਦਾ ਸਹਾਈ ਸੰਗਿ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸੁਖਾ ਕੀ ਮਿਤਿ ਕਿਆ ਗਣੀ ਜਾ ਸਿਮਰੀ ਗੋਵਿੰਦੁ ॥ਜਿਨ ਚਾਖਿਆ ਸੇ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਾਸਿਆ ਉਹ ਰਸੁ ਜਾਣੈ ਜਿੰਦੁ ॥ਸੰਤਾ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਮਨਿ ਵਸੈ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਮੁ ਬਖਸਿੰਦੁ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਸੇਵਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਆਪਣਾ ਸੋਈ ਰਾਜ ਨਰਿੰਦੁ ॥੨॥ਅਉਸਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਜਸੁ ਗੁਣ ਰਮਣ ਜਿਤੁ ਕੋਟਿ ਮਜਨ ਇਸਨਾਨੁ ॥ਰਸਨਾ ਉਚਰੈ ਗੁਣਵਤੀ ਕੋਇ ਨ ਪੁਜੈ ਦਾਨੁ ॥ਦ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਧਾਰਿ ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਵਸੈ ਦਇਆਲ ਪੁਰਖੁ ਮਿਹਰਵਾਨੁ ॥ਜੀਉ ਪਿੰਡੁ ਧਨੁ ਤਿਸ ਦਾ ਹਉ ਸਦਾ ਸਦਾ ਕੁਰਬਾਨੁ ॥੩॥ਮਿਲਿਆ ਕਦੇ ਨ ਵਿਛੁੜੈ ਜੋ ਮੇਲਿਆ ਕਰਤਾਰਿ ॥ਦਾਸਾ ਕੇ ਬੰਧਨ ਕਟਿਆ ਸਾਚੈ ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰਿ ॥ਭੂਲਾ ਮਾਰਗਿ ਪਾਇਓਨੁ ਗੁਣ ਅਵਗੁਣ ਨ ਬੀਚਾਰਿ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਤਿਸੁ ਸਰਣਾਗਤੀ ਜਿ ਸਗਲ ਘਟਾ ਆਧਾਰੁ ॥੪॥੧੮॥੮੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 48 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਪਰ ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ ਜੋਤਿਸ਼-ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਹੈ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਸ (ਗੁਰੂ) ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨਿਆਸਰੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਦਾ ਧਨ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਆਦਰ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ !) ਅੱਠੇ ਪਹਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹੁ, ਇਹ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸਰਮਾਇਆ ਹੈ, ਇਹੀ ਇੰਦ੍ਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਬੂ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਅਟੱਲ ਸਾਧਨ ਹੈ (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ (ਜੁੜ ਕੇ) ਸਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਭਜਨ ਕਰ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹਰੇਕ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਆਪਕ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਸਹੈਤਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਅੰਗ-ਸੰਗ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਧਰਤੀ ਦੇ ਪਾਲਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ (ਉਸ ਵੇਲੇ ਇਤਨੇ ਸੁਖ ਅਨੁਭਵ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ) ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਾ ਸਕਦਾ  ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਚੱਖਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰਜ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ; (ਪਰ ਜੇਹੜੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦੀ ਹੈ) ਉਹੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਉਸ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਦੀ ਹੈ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਮ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਣਹਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ  ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਰਾਜਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਰਾਜਾ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।੨।ਜਿਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਏ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਯਾਦ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ (ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ, ਮਾਨੋ) ਕੋ੍ਰੜਾਂ ਤੀਰਥਾਂ ਦੇ ਇਸ਼ਨਾਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਜੀਭ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਉਚਾਰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਤਾਂ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਦਾਨ (ਇਸ ਕੰਮ ਦੀ) ਬਰਾਬਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਹਰਬਾਨ ਦਇਆਲ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈਇਹ ਜਿੰਦ, ਇਹ ਸਰੀਰ, ਇਹ ਧਨ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।੩।ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਤਾਰ ਨੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਜੋੜ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਉਹ ਮਨੱੁਖ (ਕਦੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਬੰਧਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਫਸਦਾ, ਤੇ) ਕਦੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ) ਨਹੀਂ ਵਿੱਛੁੜਦਾ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਦਾਸਾਂ ਦੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ) ਬੰਧਨ (ਸਦਾ ਲਈ) ਕੱਟ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਜੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦਾਸ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ) ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਭੀ ਪੈ ਗਿਆ (ਸੀ ਤੇ ਫਿਰ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ) ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ (ਪਹਿਲੇ) ਗੁਣ ਔਗੁਣ ਨਾਹ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਹੀ ਰਸਤੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਪਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਉ ਜੋ ਸਾਰੇ ਸਰੀਰਾਂ ਦਾ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦਾ) ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੮।੮੮।\\""},{"question":"Maldives có đảo sinh quyển nào được UNESCO công nhận?","answer":"Tháng 7/2011, Baa Atoll bao gồm 75 hòn đảo đã được công nhận là Khu dự trữ sinh quyển bởi UNESCO. Chính phủ Maldives đang cố gắng nhân rộng mô hình này sang các khu vực khác.Đây là nơi lưu giữ những rạn san hô lớn nhất ở Ấn Độ Dương và nhiều loài có nguy cơ tuyệt chủng như rùa xanh, rùa diều hâu, cá mập y tá hung dữ.Maldives cũng là một trong những điểm lặn biển tốt nhất trên thế giới. Chỉ cần lặn cách bờ vài m, du khách có thể bơi cùng những loài sinh vật nhiều màu sắc và khám phá san hô qua kính."},{"question":"Para qual ex foi escrita a música “ All Too Well “ do álbum “ Red” da cantora Taylor Swift. ","answer":"Segundo alegações da mídia, foi escrita para o ator Jake Gyllenhaall."},{"question":"Tasavvufi düşüncede hakiki bilginin kaynağı nedir?","answer":"Tasavvuf ise, akıl, nass ve duyuların yanı sıra dinî yaşantıdan kaynaklanan zevk, ilham ve keşfi de kabul edip hakiki bilgiye (irfana) nihaî noktada keşf yoluyla ulaşılabileceğini savunur."},{"question":"متى قام سيدنا عثمان بن عفان -رضي الله عنه- بتجميع القرآن الكريم ؟\\t","answer":"العام 25 هجري"},{"question":"请回答这个问题：地球上最熱的地方是哪裡？","answer":"答案：死亡谷"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : « Ilay adala be ty ! Avereno haingana ny volako raha tsy te higadra ! »","answer":"Maneho hatezerana io fanambarana io. Milaza ny hanagadrako ilay olona tsy mamerina ny trosa hananako aminy ilay izy."},{"question":"Ngimkhumbule namuhla uMntungwa. Sasivame ukuhlala sobabiliphansi kwalesi sihlahla. Ngixakwa yilaba abangibelesele ngendabakaDumisani. Bayahlanya. Abazi ukuthi angiyingeni indaba yokungenwamina. Kodwa yena uMntungwa angathini lapho ekhona? Noma ngabeuDumisani usekhulile nje, ngeke ungibone ngimgana mina. Minaangisiye owokuganga. Naye ngizomgada manje uma efikile. Umaengeshela nje ngiyomkhombisa ikheli. Ngimbuze ukuthi ungithandamanini nje. Uma enganakile futhi siyodumelana kube kuncane indawo.Uyazi angimazi nalo muntu owasungula isiko lokungenwa wayehlushweyini. Abantu bayathanda ukusungula amasiko adala izinkinga.(Ezwe izigi) Nangu umama eza. Uma eqala le ndaba yesiko lakheuzongizwa kahle namuhla. Angihleki angithi nsi. Angifuni ndoda njeeduze kwami manje.Uyawuthanda lo msebenzi wokuthunga koti bo. (Ahlale phansi)Ngenzela ukuthi ngingakhohlwa mama. Nawo umshini awufuni ukuhlalaisikhathi eside ungasebenzi.Kuzofuneka ungifundise nami makoti ngizithungele.Awu mama uthi kungalunga ufundiswa imfundamakhwela?Akubonakali ukuthi usafunda koti. Ukwenza kwakho kukhombisaubumpetha. Impela ngicela ungifundise. Siningi kabi isikhathiesizosihlala nawe ngingagcina sengiwushaya njengawe nje.Usho ukuthini umama uma ethi sisazohlala isikhathi eside?Kanti uyahamba yini?Ngingeze ngasho ukuthi ngiyahamba mama. Uma sekukhunyulwe inzilobengizocela ukuba ngibuyele ekhaya. 1. Chaza ngesimo senhlalo kulo mdlalo. Bhala amaphuzu AMABILI. ","answer":"Sibi ngoba:Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo:• Akukho ukuthula selokhu kwaqala indaba yokungenwa kukaThenjiwe.• UThenjiwe akasahloniphi, usexabana noMaMbatha.• UMaMbatha akasamphathi kahle uNondumiso ngoba ethi ungenaizindaba zomuzi wakhe.• Akukho ukuthula emzini kaMondise ngoba uMondise akamesekeliuThenjiwe ezifisweni zakhe.• KwaMondise ubaba wakhona usexoshe uNondumiso ngoba ethi wonisaingane/udadewabo"},{"question":"\\"Nandraraka divay tamin'ny akanjoko ilay mpandroso sakafo nandritra ny sakafo hariva.\\" Inona ny fihetseham-po raketin'io fanambarana io?","answer":"Raha ny fanadihadiana an'io fanambarana io dia tsy mampiseho fihetseham-po ho an'ilay olona voararaka divay tamin'ny ankajony io fanambarana io fa milaza ny zava nitranga fotsiny."},{"question":"لدينا الجملة التالية: الطابق الأرضي ملئ بالبغايا طيلة أيام الأسبوع وعلى مدار الساعة، والحمامات قذرة، والضوضاء ليلاً مزعجة جداً، وأنا أعدكم بأنكم لن تغفو ولو لثوانى. ما مشاعر الجملة السابقة؟","answer":"مشاعر الجملة السابقة هي مشاعر سلبية."},{"question":" కంటి కటకం తన నాభ్యంతరాన్ని ……… సెం.మీ. నుండి ……… సెం.మీ. ల మధ్య ఉండేటట్లు సర్దుబాటు చేసుకుంటుంది.A) 22.7; 25B) 2.27; 2.42C) 2.26; 2.5D) 2.27; 2.5","answer":"D) 2.27; 2.5"},{"question":"Quel composant d’un atome pourrait-on s’attendre à orbiter autour de lui ?","answer":"Les électrons sont les composants d'un atome qui sont censés orbiter autour du noyau. Les électrons sont des particules subatomiques chargées négativement qui se déplacent autour du noyau selon des niveaux d'énergie ou des couches électroniques spécifiques. Ces coquilles sont souvent représentées comme des orbites circulaires ou elliptiques, bien que le comportement réel des électrons soit plus complexe et soit décrit par la mécanique quantique."},{"question":"Ai là Vua phá lưới nội duy nhất ở V-League 20 năm qua, không tính cầu thủ nhập tịch?","answer":"Vua phá lưới nội duy nhất ở V-League 20 năm qua là Nguyễn Anh Đức. Anh Đức là Vua phá lưới V-League 2017 với 17 bàn trong 26 trận cho Bình Dương. Anh nhỉnh hơn Nsi Amougou và Rod Dyachenko một bàn. Hoàng Vũ Samson cũng từng đoạt giải thưởng này năm 2013 và 2014 cùng Hà Nội nhưng anh có gốc Nigeria."},{"question":"Repita: O sol está brilhando hoje.","answer":"O sol está brilhando hoje."},{"question":"Berikan saya lirik lagu negeri Terengganu.","answer":"Lirik lagu negeri Terengganu adalah seperti berikut:Allah daulatkan Tuanku SultanTerengganu Darul ImanAllah peliharakan Tuanku SultanSejahtera sepanjang zamanAllah rahmatkan Tuanku SultanMemerintah rakyat aman"},{"question":"பிரிட்டிஷ் ஆட்சியின் பொழுது சென்னை மாகாணத்தில் கிராமப் பகுதிகளில் வசித்த மக்களை ஒன்று திரட்டும் நோக்கத்துடன் “சென்னை மாகான சங்கம்” என்ற அமைப்பு எப்பொழுது துவக்கப்பட்டது?A. 1887B. 1892C. 1916D. 1905","answer":"விடை : B. 1892"},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Punca-Punca Pengangguran dan Cara Mengatasinya.","answer":"Mutakhir ini, polemik tentang pengangguran dalam kalangan belia terutamanya semakin meningkat dari tahun ke tahun. Isu ini bukan sahaja berlaku di dalam negara kita tetapi juga melibatkan hampir kebanyakan negara membangun di segenap dunia. Revolusi industri yang bertujuan untuk mengautomasikan sektor pembinaan dan industri lain telah menjejaskan kebergantungan terhadap tenaga kerja daripada manusia. Oleh itu, isu pengangguran bukan sahaja merunsingkan golongan siswazah tetapi ia secara langsung melibatkan golongan pekerja yang terkesan daripada perkembangan teknologi hari ini. Bagi menyelesaikan isu yang menjadi tunjang ekonomi sesebuah negara ini, wajar untuk kita mengenal pasti punca dan cara-cara untuk mengatasinya.Punca utama bilangan pengangguran berlaku dalam kalangan siswazah khususnya adalah disebabkan tiada keseimbangan antara keperluan industri dan penghasilan graduan daripada institusi pengajian tinggi (IPT). Setiap tahun, lebih 100 000 graduan dihasilkan oleh IPT awam dan swasta dan menyebabkan lambakan graduan berlaku di dalam negara kita. Peluang pekerjaan yang dihasilkan hari ini pula terhad berbanding sedekad yang lalu dimana jumlah rakyat dalam negara telah bertambah berkali ganda tetapi struktur peluang kerja masih di tahap yang sama. Tambahan pula, kadar gaji yang tidak setara dengan kos kehidupan masa kini oleh industri telah menyebabkan graduan menganggur dan memilih dalam mencari pekerjaan.Selain itu, punca yang menyebabkan berlakunya pengangguran adalah disebabkan kursus di IPT tidak relevan dengan keperluan industri. IPT terutamanya IPT swasta menjalankan operasi mereka dalam bentuk perniagaan, maka kuantiti pelajar yang ramai akan mendatangkan keuntungan berbanding memastikan kursus yang dijalankan relevan dengan kehendak industri. Pelajar-pelajar pula mudah termakan dengan janji peluang pekerjaan yang akan ditawarkan setelah tamat pengajian kelak. Situasi ini juga berlaku diperingkat industri. Sebagai contoh, pihak kilang ingin menggunakan teknologi baru yang memerlukan kemahiran pekerja yang lebih tinggi. Maka, pekerja yang tiada kemahiran tersebut terpaksa dihentikan. Jelaslah bahawa, setiap pihak berperanan dalam memastikan masalah pengangguran dapat diselesaikan.Langkah yang pragmatik perlu dilaksanakan oleh semua pihak terutamanya kerajaan dalam memastikan kerjasama antara IPT dan keperluan industri. Inisiatif kerajaan dalam menambah bilangan IPT dari tahun ke tahun wajar dipuji tetapi permintaan yang sama dari segi peluang pekerjaan juga perlu dilaksanakan. Tamsilnya, syarikat petroleum terkemuka negara, Petronas telah membangunkan IPT mereka sendiri bagi menghasilkan graduan yang seiring dengan keperluan mereka. Justeru, kerajaan sewajarnya memberikan garis panduan kepada IPT dalam memastikan kursus yang ditawarkan dan kuantiti graduan seimbang dengan keperluan industri. Maka, kerajaan, IPT dan industri perlu menggembleng tenaga untuk memastikan aliran kehidupan rakyat daripada pengajian terus ke pekerjaan dan tidak tersangkut dengan isu pengangguran.Di samping itu, kerajaan juga memainkan peranan yang penting dalam memastikan peluang pekerjaan sentiasa ada bagi setiap golongan bukan sahaja graduan IPT. Antara cara yang boleh dilaksanakan adalah menrik pelabur asing untuk melabur dalam negara. Kemudahan infrastruktur yang lengkap di Kuala Lumpur tamsilnya dapat menjamin keyakinan pelabur untuk berdagang dalam negara. Kerajaan juga perlu sentiasa membantu usahawan tempatan untuk berkembang secara domestik dan global agar tidak menjadi seperti peribahasa Melayu, kera di hutan disusukan, anak di rumah kelaparan. Justeru kerajaan hari ini perlu melakukan anjakan paradigma dalam usaha menaikkan nama anak tempatan di samping menarik pelabur asing ke dalam negara. Dua inisiatif ini secara tidak langsung dapat memberikan peluang pekerjaan kepada setiap golongan pekerja dalam negara kita.Kesimpulannya, pelbagai faktor yang menyebabkan isu pengangguran berlaku dan banyak langkah yang boleh dilaksanakan bagi memastikan bilangan tersebut berkurangan. Pengenalan peluang pekerjaan seperti penghantar makanan dan e-hailing adalah bersifat sementara dan tidak sihat bagi perkembangan ekonomi dalam jangka masa panjang. Oleh itu, kerajaan dan rakyat perlu menjalankan tanggungjawab masing-masing dalam memastikan kedua-dua pihak bekerja demi membantu meningkatkan ekonomi diri dan negara. Pelbagai kerjasama secara domestik dan global diperlukan bagi membentuk model ekonomi terbaik agar Malaysia tidak ketinggalan dalam era revolusi industri yang kian mendatang."},{"question":"Морж адам деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Кышындасы лакылдап кар ❄️ жаап жатканда морж адамдар сууга түшүп чөмүлүшөт.🏊‍♀️🏊🤽🤽‍♀️🤽‍♂️ Жоок бассейндеги жылуу сууга эмес көчөдөгү муздак дарыянын суусуна чөмүлүшөт. Аткени морж адамдар денесин муздак сууга көндүрүшөт."},{"question":"What are some common metrics used for evaluating model performance in MLOps?","answer":"Common metrics include accuracy, precision, recall, F1 score, and area under the ROC curve, depending on the nature of the machine learning task."},{"question":"Фонетика (грек. phone — тыбыш деген сөзүнөн алынган) — тилдин тыбыштык түзүлүшүнизилдеп, аны үйрөтө турган тил илиминин бир бөлүгү.Тилдин тыбыштык түзүлүшүнүн татаал табияты аны ар кандай көз караштын негизиндеизилдөөнү талап кылат. Биринчиден, адамдын речи тыбыштардан түзүлгөндүктөн, башкабардык тыбыштык кубулуштар сыяктуу, физикалык жаратылышка ээ, ошондуктан алфизиканын бир бөлүгү акустикалык жактан изилденет. Экинчиден, речь адам тарабынанайтылып, адам тарабынан кабыл алынгандыктан, адамдын организминин белгилүү даражадагыфункциясы болуп эсептелет. Ошондуктан аны анатомо-физиологиялык жактан үйрөнүү талапкылынат. Коммуникация процессинде тилдин тыбыштык түзүлүшүнүн аткарган функциясынлингвистикалык максатта үйрөнүү маанилүү. Фонетика лингвистикалык илим болгондуктан,тыбыштын лингвистикалык аспектисин изилдейт.Адамдын речинин тыбыштык түзүлүшүнүн бардык өзгөчөлүктөрүн, кубулуштарын,жаратылышын толук жана кеңири ачуу максатында акустика менен физиология тарабынаналынган жыйынтыктарды пайдалануу лингвистикалык аспектинин негизин түзөт.Фонетика тилдин тыбыштык түзүлүшү менен катар сөздөгү басым, интонация, муун жанаанын типтерин да изилдейт.Суроо: Фонетика илими эмнени изилдейт?","answer":"Фонетика — тилдин тыбыштык түзүлүшүн изилдейт. Ага кошумча сөздөгү басым, интонация, муун жана анын типтерин да изилдейт."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 調査会社によると、1月から9月までに、介護の仕事をする100の会社が倒産しました。去年の同じときの2倍ぐらいに増えました。調べ始めてからいちばん速いスピードで増えています。いちばん多かったのは、お年寄りが通ったり、短い間泊まったりする施設の会社で、45の倒産がありました。調査会社は、次のようなことが原因だろうと考えています。介護の仕事をする人が足りないことや、新型コロナウイルスが広がったときに、利用するお年寄りが少なくなって、会社の収入が少なくなったことです。そして、食べ物やガソリンの値段、電気代が高くなったことです。調査会社の人は「介護の会社が料金を上げることは難しいです。小さな会社などで倒産がもっと増える心配があります」と言っています。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ ኤድስ ምህጻረ ቃል ምን ማለት ነው? መልስ፦ ","answer":"የተገኘ የበሽታ መከላከያ እጥረት ሲንድሮም"},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Nandeha ny fanamby sy ny olana izy hamoaka ny bokiny, ary taty aoriana dia lasa mahahomby izy.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Tamin'ny fandresena ireo sakana sy olana, dia namadika ny bokiny ho fahombiazana be indrindra izy.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"कोणत्या राज्यात प्रथम रक्तपेढीचे वॉलेट जारी केले गेले?(A) राजस्थान(B) महाराष्ट्र(C) मध्य प्रदेश(D) कर्नाटक=> ","answer":"(A) राजस्थान"},{"question":"Ата- эне жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Эне үй-бүлөнүн жүрөгү,Ата үй- бүлөнүн тиреги."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Nhưng vụ nổ do thủy lôi gần đây, nghi ngờ là của Nga trôi dạt vào vùng biển gần Constanta, cho thấy rủi ro mà các khu vực gần vùng chiến sự phải đối mặt.\\"Chúng tôi rất lo lắng. Nga tiếp tục tạo ra những rủi ro mới, nguy cơ dẫn tới leo thang và tính toán sai lầm\\", ông Tilvar nói.","answer":"Romania đã triển khai 11 tàu chiến, 2 trực thăng, 6 UVA giám sát hàng hải và 3 đội thợ lặn chuyên về chất nổ để đối phó với nguy cơ từ thủy lôi, UAV Nga. Máy bay trinh sát của NATO cũng tuần tra liên tục khu vực biên giới Romania.\\"Chúng tôi chuẩn bị cho bất kỳ tình huống bất ngờ nào có thể xảy ra\\", ông Tilvar nói, thêm rằng \\"không quốc gia nào giáp biên giới Ukraine có thể loại trừ khả năng bị bắn nhầm\\"."},{"question":"Khoảng cách giữa Trái Đất với Mặt Trời là bao nhiêu?","answer":"Vì Trái Đất di chuyển quỹ đạo hình elip quanh Mặt Trời, khoảng cách giữa hai thiên thể biến thiên 147-152 triệu km, theo sách Hệ Mặt Trời và các hành tinh lùn. Khoảng cách giữa Trái Đất và Mặt Trời gọi là Đơn vị thiên văn (AU)."},{"question":"No anime Dragon Ball Z, quem é Chi-Chi?","answer":"Chi-Chi é a esposa de Goku e mãe de Gohan e Goten, conhecida por sua personalidade enérgica e preocupação com o estudo e a educação de seus filhos."},{"question":"కింది వచనం చదివి, ప్రశ్నలకు జవాబులు రాయండి.స్వామి వివేకానంద అమెరికా, బ్రిటన్ వంటి సంపన్నదేశాలను దర్శించారు. భారతదేశానికి తిరిగి ప్రయాణమయినప్పుడు అక్కడి పత్రికా విలేఖరులు “మీ మాతృభూమి పట్ల మీ అభిప్రాయం ఏమిటి?” అని ప్రశ్నించారు. దానికి సమాధానంగా “భారతదేశాన్ని లోగడ ప్రేమించాను. కాని ఇప్పుడు భారతభూమిలోని ప్రతి ధూళికణం నాకు అత్యంత పవిత్రం. అది నాకొక తీర్థస్థానం” అని సగర్వంగా చెబుతారు. ఈ విధంగా కనిపించిన తల్లి మీద ఎలాంటి మాతృభావన ఉంటుందో మనకు జన్మభూమి అయిన భారతదేశం మీద కూడా అలాంటి మాతృభావన కలిగి ఉండాలనే ఉద్దేశాన్ని ప్రకటించారు.ప్రశ్నలు:1) వివేకానందుణ్ణి పరాయి దేశంలో పత్రికా విలేఖరులు ఏమని ప్రశ్నించారు?2) విలేఖరుల ప్రశ్నకు వివేకానందుడు ఏమని సమాధానం చెప్పారు?3) మాతృభావన ఎవరి యెడల కలిగి ఉండాలని ప్రకటించారు?4) వచనాన్ని చదివి ‘శీర్షిక’ను నిర్ణయించండి.","answer":"1) వివేకానందుణ్ణి పరాయి దేశంలో పత్రికా విలేఖరులు ఏమని ప్రశ్నించారు?జవాబు:వివేకానందుని మాతృభూమి పట్ల ఆయన అభిప్రాయాన్ని గూర్చి పత్రికా విలేఖరులు ప్రశ్నించారు.2) విలేఖరుల ప్రశ్నకు వివేకానందుడు ఏమని సమాధానం చెప్పారు?జవాబు:భారతదేశాన్ని గతంలో తాను ప్రేమించానన్నాడు. కాని ఇప్పుడు భారతభూమిలోని ప్రతి ధూళికణం తనకు అత్యంత పవిత్రమైనదని అన్నాడు. భారతదేశం తనకొక తీర్థ స్థానమని పత్రికా విలేఖరులకు వివేకానందుడు చెప్పాడు.3) మాతృభావన ఎవరి యెడల కలిగి ఉండాలని ప్రకటించారు?జవాబు:మన జన్మభూమి అయిన భారతదేశం ఎడల మనం మాతృభావన కలిగి ఉండాలని వివేకానందుడు ప్రకటించాడు.4) వచనాన్ని చదివి ‘శీర్షిక’ను నిర్ణయించండి.జవాబు:ఈ పేరాకు ‘వివేకానందుని వివేకం’ అనే శీర్షికను నిర్ణయించాను."},{"question":"Emishweni elandelayo kukhona amagama abhalwe ngezinhlamvuezinkulu. Nikeza isizathu sokwenza lokhu:Kukhona isifo esikhungethe abantu abaningi; UKUHLEBA. ","answer":" UKUHLEBA: indikimba esemqoka kakhulu empilweni/ukugcizelela. "},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 将棋の藤井聡太さんは19日、渡辺明さんに勝って「棋王」のタイトルを取りました。藤井さんが持っているタイトルは6つになりました。1994年に羽生善治さんが6つのタイトルを持ってから2人目です。藤井さんは20歳8か月で、羽生さんより3年6か月若い年齢で6つ取りました。","answer":"藤井さんは「まだ上手にできないことがあります。6つのタイトルを取ったので、もっといい将棋ができるように頑張らなければならないと思います」と話しました。 藤井さんは来月から、「名人」のタイトルを持っている渡辺明さんと将棋をします。藤井さんが「名人」を取ると、いちばん若い年齢で7つのタイトルを取ることになります。"},{"question":"¿Qué es un prisma dispersivo?","answer":"Un prisma dispersivo es un prisma óptico que dispersa las diferentes longitudes de onda de la luz en diferentes ángulos. Cuando la luz blanca se ilumina a través de un prisma dispersivo se separará en los diferentes colores del arco iris. "},{"question":"خشک میوہ کے فایدے بتایں؟","answer":"اللہ تعالیٰ نے انسان کے لیے قسم قسم کی نعمتیں اتاری ہیں جن میں ایک کشمش بھی ہے جس میں صحت کا پورا خزانہ چھپا ہوا ہے۔انسان کے لیے اللہ تعالیٰ نے کرہ ارض پر بے شمار نعمتیں اتاری ہیں جن سے وہ مستفید ہوتا ہے۔ ان ہی میں ایک خشک میوہ جات میں شامل کشمش ہے جو دیکھنے تو بہت چھوٹا سا میوہ ہے لیکن اس میں صحت کا انمول خزانہ چھپا ہوا ہے۔انگور کو خشک کرکے بنایا جانے والا یہ خشک میوہ ہر موسم میں انسان کو فائدہ پہنچاتا ہے جو دیگر میوہ جات کی نسبت کم قیمت اور ہر ایک کی دسترس میں ہے۔ ماہرین طب کہتے ہیں کہ روزانہ ایک کپ کشمش پانی میں بھگو کر پینے سے انسانی قوت مدافعت مضبوط اور کئی بیماریوں سے تحفظ ملتا ہے۔ماہرین صحت کے مطابق کشمش میں آئرن کے ذخائر پائے جاتے ہیں۔ یہ خشک میوہ وٹامن سی اور دیگر اینٹی آکسیڈنٹس سے بھرپور امرت کا درجہ رکھتا ہے۔ فائبر اور پولی فینول کی بھی اچھی مقدار ہوتی ہے۔ کئی معدنیات اور پروٹین بھی پائے جاتے ہیں جس کے باعث اس کو صحت کا چھپا ہوا خزانہ بھی کہا جاتا ہے۔اگر روزانہ ایک کپ کشمش کے پانی میں بھگو کر پی لیں تو قوت مدافعت مضبوط ہوتی ہے اور نزلہ و زکام جیسی بیماریاں دور ہوجاتی ہیں۔ماہرین صحت کے مطابق کشمش کو رات کو پانی میں بھگو کر اگلی صبح خالی پیٹ کھانے سے حیرت انگیز فوائد حاصل ہوتے ہیں۔ یہی نہیں بلکہ اس کا پانی بھی جسم کے لیے معجزانہ طور پر فائدہ مند ہے۔ جس سے نہ صرف قوت مدافعت بڑھتی ہے اور نزلہ زکام جیسی بیماریاں دور ہوتی ہیں بلکہ خون میں آئرن کی کمی دور ہوتی ہے اور اینیمیا (خون کی کمی) کا خطرہ ٹل جاتا ہے۔صبح نہار منہ کشمش کا پانی پینا جسم سے خراب چربی اور کولیسٹرول کو دور کرکے آپ کے دل کو فٹ اور زندگی کو چست رکھتا ہے۔کشمش کا پانی معدنیات اور پروٹین کے باعث بالوں کے لیے بہترین ٹانک سمجھا جاتا ہے جس سے بال مضبوط ہوتے ہیں اور جھڑنا ختم ہوجاتے ہیں۔ اس کے علاوہ خوبصورت اور چمکتی جلد کے لیے بھی کشمش اکسیر ہے کہ اس کا پانی پینے سے جلد کی خشکی دور، خارش اور داغ دھبوں کا خاتمہ ہوتا ہے۔صبح سویرے کشمش کا پانی پینے سے جسم کو امائنو ایسڈ ملتے ہیں۔ جس سے حمل کے امکانات بڑھ جاتے ہیں۔ یہی نہیں بلکہ یہ صحت مند حمل کے لیے بھی بہت فائدہ مند ہے۔ جب خواتین حاملہ ہوتی ہیں تو انہیں قبض اور ہاضمے کے مسائل ہوتے ہیں۔ ایسی صورتحال میں صبح سویرے کشمش کا پانی پینے سے نظام ہاضمہ درست رہتا ہے اور حاملہ خواتین کو خون کی کمی کے خطرے سے بچایا جا سکتا ہے۔"},{"question":"في أي سنة هجرية تمت حجة الوداع ؟","answer":"السنة العاشرة للهجرة"},{"question":"සඳුදා යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"සඳුදා යනු ඉරිදා සහ අඟහරුවාදා අතර දිනයයි."},{"question":"Qual é a resposta correta para essa pergunta? Abraham Lincoln foi o 2º presidente dos EUA?","answer":"A resposta correta para essa pergunta é Não"},{"question":"දේශීය විභාග ක්‍රමය ආරම්භ කරන ලද වර්ෂය?","answer":" 1862"},{"question":"அச்சு எழுத்துக்களில் வெளியான முதல் இந்திய மொழி?","answer":"விடை:  தமிழ்"},{"question":"Бул жомоктун уландысын жазып берчи: \\"—  Дүнүйөсү көп болбосо, малы жок болсо, эч кандай адам жоомарт боло албайт. Малдуу жоомарт болот. Колунда жок болсо, кандай мыкты адам болсо дагы, мен жоомарт боломун деп аракет кылганы менен боло албайт,- дешет.\\"","answer":"Бул жомоктун уландысы мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Андан көп күндөр өткөндөн кийин кан жаман кийим кийип кайырчы болуп, «вазирлерин сынап көрөйүн деп, бир күнү түндө бир вазиринин үйүнө барат.\\""},{"question":"Ano ang pinakanakakamatay na hayop sa buong mundo?","answer":"Ang lamok ang pinakanakakamatay na hayop sa buong mundo base sa mga estadistika ng mga taong namatay dahil dito. Sa mga lamok nagmumula ang ilang nakakamatay na sakit katulad ng malaria, dengue, yellow fever at iba pa. Milyun-milyong tao sa buong mundo ang namamatay kada taon, at mas marami pa ang nagkakasakit dahil sa mga lamok. "},{"question":"The intensity of the bulb will decrease when a resistance is connecteda. In seriesb. In parallelc. Series or paralleld. Intensity cannot be decreased.","answer":"Intensity of the bulb will decrease when resistance is high and resistance is high when they are connected in series combination."},{"question":"元は乗馬の時に着ていたもので、日本でその名が付けられたズボン式のスカートを何スカートと言う？","answer":"キュロットスカートです。"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన కథకి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి :ఒక చెరువులో దూరదర్శి, కుశాగ్రబుధ్ది, మందబుద్ధి అనే మూడు చేపలు ఉండేవి. ఒక సంవత్సరం వానలు పడక, చెరువు ఎండిపోతోంది. నీరు బాగా తగ్గింది. అది గ్రహించి, దూరదర్శి, మిగిలిన రెండు చేపలతో,”స్నేహితులారా! వానలు లేక,మన చెరువు రోజు రోజుకి ఎండిపోతోంది. జాలరులు వొచ్చి, మనని పట్టేసే ప్రమాదం కూడా ఉంది.","answer":"కనుక మనం మరో చెరువుకి ఈ సన్న నీటిమార్గం ద్వారా వెళ్ళిపోదాం రండి,” అని పిలిచింది.ఎప్పుడో ఆపద వొస్తుందని ఇప్పుడే పారిపోవటమెందుకు? అంతగా అపాయం వస్తే చూద్దాం లే” అంది కుశాగ్ర బుద్ది. మందబుద్ధి, “నేను ఈ చెరువు లోనే పుట్టాను. ఏది ఏమైనా ఇక్కడినించి కదిలేది లేదు,” అని మొండికేసింది.ఇంక వీళ్ళతో కుదరదనుకుని, దూరదర్శి గబా గబా ఈదుకుంటూ మరో చెరువు లోకి వెళ్ళిపోయింది. కొన్నాళ్ళకి జాలరులు వొచ్చి, వల వేసి చేపల్నిపెట్టే శారు. వలలో చిక్కిన చేపలలో బతికి ఉన్నవాటిని తన బుట్టలో వేస్తున్నాడు. కదలకుండా ఉన్నచనిపోయిన చేపల్ని ఒడ్డున పడేస్తున్నాడు. అది గమనించిన కుశాగ్రబుద్ధి, గుడ్లు తేలేసి,కదలక ఉండిపోయిన్నది. అది చూసి జాలరి చేప చచ్చిపోయిందనుకుని చెరువు గట్టున వొదిలేసాడు. నెమ్మదిగా అది ఎలాగో చెరువులో చేరి బతికి పోయింది. మందబుద్ధి మటుకు ఏమీ తోచక జాలరి చేతిలో చిక్కి చచ్చిపోయింది."},{"question":"\\"Ny 'Grande Muraille' dia rafitra malaza any Chine. Naorina tamin'ny vanim-potoana samy hafa sy tarana-mpanjaka maromaro izy io mba ho fiarovana ny fanjakana amin'ny fanafihana avy amin'ireo fanjakana hafa.\\"Amin'ny alalan'ilay lahatsoratra teo ambony: Inona no tena asan'ny 'Grande muraille' an'i Chine tamin'ny nanamboarana azy?","answer":"Ny 'Grande muraille' an'i Chine dia  mba ho fiarovana ny fanjakana amin'ny fanafihana avy amin'ireo fanjakana hafa."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca hay’addii ay hoos tegi jirtay Kooxdii Fanka ee Xusuus.?","answer":"Waxa ay hoos tegi jirtay Xiriirka Shaqaalaha Soomaaliyeed.."},{"question":"Okuta ni Oluwapelumi la mọ Jafaru lori tiyẹn fi ku, ladajọ ba ni ko maa lọ sẹwọn l’Ekiti","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ Majsitreeti kan to wa niluu Ado-Ekiti ti paṣẹ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, pe ki ọmọ ogun ọdun kan, Oluwapẹlumi Alọ, maa lọọ gbatẹgun lọgba ẹwọn titi di igba kan na.Ọmọkunrin to n kọ iṣẹ mẹkaniiki niluu Iyin-Ekiti lawọn ọlọpaa gbe wa si kootu lori ẹsun igbimọ-pọ lati paayan.Agbefọba, Insipẹkitọ Bamikọle Ọlasunkanmi, ṣalaye niwaju adajọ pe Oluwapẹlumi ṣẹ ẹṣẹ naa lọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu keje, ọdun yii, niluu Iyin-Ekiti, nijọba ibilẹ Irẹpọdun/Ifẹlodun, nipinlẹ Ekiti.Agbefọba yii sọ pe ọdaran naa atawọn kan ti ọlọpaa ṣi n wa bayii ni wọn gbimọ-po, ti wọn si pa ọkunrin kan to n ta awó tutu niluu naa ti orukọ rẹ n jẹ Jafaru Mohammed.O ṣalaye pe lọjọ ti iṣẹlẹ naa ṣẹlẹ, ija kekere kan lo waye laarin Oluwapẹlumi ati oloogbe naa, ti ọdaran yii si gbe okuta nla kan, to la a mọ oloogbe naa lori, eleyi to pada ja si iku fun un.Ẹsẹ yii ni agbefọba naa juwe gẹgẹ bii oun to lodi sofin 516 to jẹ ofin iwa ọdaran tipinle Ekiti n lo, ti wọn kọ ni ọdun 2012.Agbefọba naa waa tọrọ aaye ranpẹ lọwọ ile-ẹjọ naa pe ki oun le raaye fi iwe ẹsun naa ṣọwọ si ajọ to n gba ile-ẹjọ nimọran (DPP), fun imọran ati ki oun le ri aaye ko awọn ẹlẹrii oun jọ.O ṣeleri pe oun ṣetan lati ko awọn ẹlẹrii mẹta wa si ile-ẹjọ naa, ṣugbọn aaye ranpẹ yii ni oun yoo fi ṣa awọn ẹlẹrii oun jọ lati fara han ni kootu naa.Onidaajọ Abduhamid Lawal sọ pe ki ọdaran ọhun maa lọ si ọgba ẹwọn fun igba kan na, o si sun igbẹjọ si ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu kẹsan-an, odun 2021."},{"question":"ماهو العقرب الذي لايخاف منه الناس ولا يؤذيهم؟\\t","answer":"عقرب الساعة"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bak rasa kuda pula kukuran\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perihal orang miskin yang berlagak seperti orang kaya."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag  réewum Paraguay?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Paraguay mu ngi tudu Asunción."},{"question":"ප්‍රථම රාජ්‍ය මන්ත්‍රණ සභාවේ කෘෂිකර්ම සහ ඉඩම් සංවර්ධන ඇමැතිවරයා කවුද?","answer":"ප්‍රථම රාජ්‍ය මන්ත්‍රණ සභාවේ කෘෂිකර්ම සහ ඉඩම් සංවර්ධන ඇමැතිවරයා වූයේ ඩී. එස්. සේනානායක මහතාය."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Theo The South China Morning Post, một phụ nữ họ Li đã kiện một phụ nữ khác có biệt danh là Xiaoxia, yêu cầu cô này trả lại khoản tiền nói trên - do chồng cô Li đưa cho Xiaoxia trong suốt 14 năm, từ 2008 đến nay. Li và người chồng họ Wang kết hôn từ năm 1991. Cô Li bắt đầu nghi ngờ về mối tình ngoại hôn cách đây 2 năm khi phát hiện Wang gửi tiền cho Xiaoxia, theo tờ Morning Herald. Wang đã thừa nhận vụ ngoại tình và cho biết anh ta và bạn gái đã có với nhau một cậu con trai 10 tuổi. Ngoài tiền mặt, anh còn mua tài sản và xe hơi cho cô bạn gái. Xiaoxia khai trước tòa rằng cô cũng là nạn nhân vì anh Wang nói dối rằng mình đã ly hôn. Cô cũng đã thúc giục anh ta kết hôn chính thức nhưng người đàn ông nhiều lần thoái thác vì những lý do khác nhau. Trong phán quyết, tòa án nhấn mạnh rằng không bên nào có thể sử dụng tài sản chung với vợ chồng hợp pháp mà không có sự đồng ý của người kia. Như vậy, Wang đã xâm phạm quyền lợi của người vợ Li, cũng như mối quan hệ của anh ta với Xiaoxia là \\"trái thuần phong mỹ tục\\" và không được luật pháp bảo vệ. Xiaoxia lập luận rằng số tiền Wang đưa là để nuôi con trai của họ nhưng tòa án cho rằng vụ án liên quan đến quyền sở hữu tài sản chứ không phải về việc cấp dưỡng nuôi con. Cô có thể nộp đơn yêu cầu xử một vụ án riêng biệt để đòi tiền cấp dưỡng từ Wang. Tòa án yêu cầu cô Xiaoxia trả lại số tiền nói trên ngay lập tức cho cô Li. Đầu tháng này, tòa án nhân dân cấp cao tỉnh Tứ Xuyên đã xét xử vụ án do một phụ nữ đã ly hôn chống lại bạn gái của chồng cũ, yêu cầu cô này trả lại hơn 300.000 nhân dân tệ (44.000 USD) từ tài sản chung của 2 vợ chồng trong giai đoạn họ còn kết hôn. Người phụ nữ nói trên và chồng ly hôn năm 2017 nhưng 4 năm sau cô phát hiện chồng mình có bạn gái từ khi họ chưa ly hôn. Bạn gái của người chồng phủ nhận, cho rằng đó là tiền để hợp tác kinh doanh, tuy nhiên một số tin nhắn chat mà người vợ cũ nắm giữ đã tố cáo họ. Tòa án phán quyết người bạn gái phải trả lại 200.000 nhân dân tệ cho người vợ cũ.","answer":"Phát hiện chồng ngoại tình, vợ kiện tình địch 'đòi quà' 560.000 USD"},{"question":"Waa maxay xukunka qofka sooman ee indho-kuusha?","answer":"Waxba kuma jabna inuu qofka soomani indho kuusho iyo inuu indhihiisa ku dhibciyo dawo midna."},{"question":"Indro  misy fanehoan-kevitra:\\"Vehivavy izany any an-tokantrano no toerany mitaiza zaza fa tsy natao hiasa.\\"Maneho endrika fanavakavahana na ahitana teny mety hanafintohina ve io fanehoan-kevitra io?","answer":"Maneho endrika fanavakavahana ny vehivavy io fanehoan-kevitra io."},{"question":"Who was the first woman to win the Nobel Prize?","answer":"The first woman to win a Nobel Prize was Marie Curie, who was awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1903. She received the prize jointly with her husband Pierre Curie and Henri Becquerel for their work on radioactivity. Marie Curie's achievements didn't stop there; she won a second Nobel Prize in 1911, this time in Chemistry, for her discovery of the elements radium and polonium. She remains the only person to have won Nobel Prizes in two different scientific fields. Her groundbreaking work laid the foundation for much of our understanding of radioactivity and its applications."},{"question":"Riga mooy gëblag  man réew?","answer":"Riga mooy gëblag réewum Lettonie."},{"question":"வினா : தமிழ்நாட்டின் சிறிய மாவட்டம் எது?","answer":"விடை : கன்னியாகுமரி"},{"question":"Nkịta akpachala anya taa akpa nwa dibia ","answer":"Ma dibia akpachala anya bụọ nwa nkịta ọnụ"},{"question":"வினா : எரி பொட்டாஷ் எனப்படுவது ","answer":"விடை : பொட்டாசியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு"},{"question":"ਬਨਿਹਾਲ: ਜੰਮੂ-ਸ੍ਰੀਨਗਰ ਕੌਮੀ ਮਾਰਗ ਰਾਮਬਨ ਜ਼ਿਲੇ ਦੀ ਰਾਮਸੂ ਪੱਟੀ ਅੰਦਰ ਢਿੱਗਾਂ ਡਿੱਗਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਅੱਜ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਚੌਥੇ ਦਿਨ ਵੀ ਬੰਦ ਰਿਹਾ। ਵੱਖ ਵੱਖ ਥਾਵਾਂ ’ਤੇ 200 ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਵਾਹਨ ਫਸੇ ਹੋਏ ਸਨ। ਸੋਮਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਮੀਂਹ ਅਤੇ ਬਰਫ਼ਬਾਰੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਇਹ 270 ਕਿਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਲੰਮਾ ਕੌਮੀ ਮਾਰਗ ਬੰਦ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਥਾਵਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਵਾਹਨ ਫਸੇ?","answer":"ਵੱਖ ਵੱਖ ਥਾਵਾਂ ’ਤੇ 200 ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਵਾਹਨ ਫਸੇ ਹੋਏ ਸਨ।"},{"question":"Klausimas: kas yra 2018m. laidos \\"Amerikos kitas geriausias modelis\\" nugalėtojas Atsakymas:","answer":"Kyla Coleman"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഭാഗം വായിച്ച് ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക:ഭാഗം: ചൈനയുടെ ചരിത്രപരമായ വടക്കൻ അതിർത്തികളിൽ നിർമ്മിച്ച കോട്ടകളുടെ ഒരു പരമ്പരയാണ് ചൈനയിലെ വൻമതിൽ. 21,000 കിലോമീറ്ററിലധികം വ്യാപിച്ചുകിടക്കുന്ന ഇത് ചൈനീസ് രാജ്യങ്ങളെയും സാമ്രാജ്യങ്ങളെയും ആക്രമണങ്ങളിൽ നിന്ന് സംരക്ഷിക്കുന്നതിനാണ് ആദ്യം നിർമ്മിച്ചത്. ചോദ്യം: ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഈ ഭാഗം ചൈനയുടെ വൻമതിലിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്. മനുഷ്യനിർമ്മിതമായ മഹാത്ഭുതങ്ങളിലൊന്നാണ് ചൈനയിലെ വന്മതിൽ. ശാഖകളടക്കം 6325 കി.മീ. നീളമുള്ള വന്മതിൽ ലോകത്തെ ഏറ്റവും വലിയ മനുഷ്യനിർമ്മിത വസ്തുവാണ്. ചന്ദ്രനിൽ നിന്ന് നഗ്നനേത്രങ്ങളുപയോഗിച്ച് കാണാവുന്ന ഒരേയൊരു മനുഷ്യനിർമ്മിത വസ്തു ഇതാണ് എന്ന് വളരെക്കാലമായി ഒരു വിശ്വാസം ഉണ്ടായിരുന്നു. മനുഷ്യൻ ചന്ദ്രനിൽ പോയ ശേഷമാണ് ഈ ധാരണ മാറിയത്. പിന്നീട് ചൈനക്കാരായ ബഹിരാകാശ സഞ്ചാരികൾ ഇത് ശരിവയ്ക്കുകയും ചെയ്തു."},{"question":"كمل الفقرة:وإذا نظرنا إلى المعلومات المهمة التي جمعها المقريزي من المؤرخين السابقين الذين فُقدتْ تواريخهم؛ فسنرى أن صناعة الأساطيل البحرية بمصر بلغت أوْجها زمن الفاطميين، فهو","answer":"يقول إن خليفتهم المعزّ لدين الله (ت 365هـ/976م) \\"أنشأ دار الصناعة التي بالمقس (= قرب ميدان رمسيس بالقاهرة)، وأنشأ بها ستمئة مركب لم يُرَ مثلها في البحر على ميناء.. فيما تقدَّم كبرا ووثاقة وحُسنا\\"!!"},{"question":"Furze Hill 19 වන සියවසේ ස්ථාපිත ප්‍රජාවක් ද?","answer":"නැත, Furze Hill 20 වන සියවස දක්වා ස්ථාපිත ප්රජාවක් නොවීය. Furze Hill (හෝ Furzehill) යනු එංගලන්තයේ හැම්ප්ෂයර් හි නව වනාන්තර ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානයේ පිහිටි කුඩා ගම්මානයකි. එය Ellingham, Harbridge සහ Ibsley හි සිවිල් පල්ලියේ ය. එහි ආසන්නතම නගරය වන්නේ ෆෝඩින්බ්‍රිජ් වන අතර එය ගම්මානයේ සිට වයඹ දෙසින් දළ වශයෙන් 3.1 සැතපුම් (5.2 km) පිහිටා ඇත. ෆර්ස් හිල් යනු හයිඩ් හි සිවිල් පල්ලියේ කුඩා ගම්මානයකි. එය දකුණු ගොර්ලි සිට ඔග්ඩෙන්ස් මාර්ගයේ හක්ල්ස් බෲක් දෙපස පහත් බිමක පිහිටා ඇත. ගෙවල් කුඹුරුවලින් වට වී ඇත. උතුරු ගෝර්ලි වෙත පටු මාර්ගයක් ඔස්සේ Gorley Common හි දකුණු කෙළවරේ අමතර නිවාස සොයාගත හැකිය. ෆර්ස් හිල් යනු හයිඩ් පල්ලියේ නවතම ජනාවාසය වන අතර එය ස්ථාපිත ප්‍රජාවක් බවට පත්වන්නේ 20 වන සියවසේදී පමණි."},{"question":"Babatunde ati Akinpẹlu lu oyinbo ni jibiti, wọn ti mu wọn o","answer":"Ẹka ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to n gbogun ti jibiti ori intanẹẹti, labẹ agbarijọpọ ikọ ọlọpaa agbaye (INTERPOL),  ti mu awọn meji kan, Babatunde Adesanya ati Akinpẹlu Hassan Abass, lori ẹsun pe wọn lu ileeṣẹ kan to jẹ tilẹ Germany ni jibiti.Aṣọ tawọn to n ṣetọju ẹni to ba ni arun Koronafairọọsi n lo, eyi ti wọn n pe ni Personal Protective Equipment (PPE), lawọn ọlọpaa sọ pe awọn afurasi ọhun  ni awọn yoo ta fun ẹnikan, ẹni naa si ro pe ileeṣẹ to n ta a lo n ba oun sọrọ lai mọ pe o ti ko sọwọ onijibiti.Gẹgẹ bi atẹjade ti Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa lorilẹ-ede yii, Frank Mba, fi sita, Adesanya to jẹ ẹni aadọta ọdun ati Akinpẹlu, ẹni ọdun mọkanleogoji to jẹ alaṣẹ the M.D of Musterpoint Investment Nig. Ltd, ni wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ pẹlu awọn onijibiti agbaye mi-in.Mba ni aṣọ PPE towo ẹ sun mọ miliọnu mẹẹẹdogun yuro lawọn afurasi yii sọ pe awọn fẹẹ ta fun ọkunrin kan to n jẹ Freiherr Fredrick Von Hahn nilẹ Holland, ẹka intanẹẹti ileeṣẹ ILBN Holdings BV to wa niluu naa ni wọn si fi ba ọkunrin naa sọrọ, eyi to jẹ ko ro pe awọn alaṣẹ ileeṣẹ naa ni wọn ba oun dunaa-dura.Lẹyin naa ni wọn gba miliọnu kan aabọ yuro lọwọ ẹ, wọn tun gba owo to sun mọ ẹgbẹrun lọna ọrinlelẹẹẹdẹgbẹrin (880,000) yuro, nigba ti ọkunrin naa ko si ri ọja to fẹẹ ra gba lo lọ si ẹka ileeṣẹ ọhun to wa niluu Holland, nibi to ti han pe awọn mi-in lo ba sọrọ.Alukoro ọlọpaa ọhun sọ siwaju pe nigba ti iwadii awọn ọlọpaa agbaye ti wọn n pe ni INTERPOL bẹrẹ iwadii ni wọn mu awọn meji kan, Eduardus Boomstra ati Geradius Maulder, nilẹ Holland, o si pada han pe ṣe ni wọn n ṣiṣẹ pẹlu Babatunde ati Akinpẹlu.Itẹsiwaju iwadii naa lo ni ijọba ilẹ Germany rọ ilẹ Naijiria lati ṣe, eyi lo si pada yọri si bi ọwọ ṣe tẹ awọn afurasi meji wọnyi, akọsilẹ si wa pe wọn fi ileeṣẹ Akinpẹlu gba owo lọwọ awọn tọwọ tẹ ni Holland.Mba waa ni awọn afurasi naa yoo foju bale-ẹjọ laipẹ lati sọ nnkan ti wọn mọ nipa ẹsun nla naa."},{"question":"Q: What do you call an old snowman? A: Water!What do you think is the punchline of the joke?","answer":"Snowmen do not last very long because eventually they melt as time passes by or as temperature rises. When a snowman melts he becomes water thus the funny part of saying a snowman being \\"old\\"."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:వ. ‘పున్నామ్నో నరకా త్రాయత ఇతిపుత్ర’ యను వేద వచనంబు గలదుఁ గావునఁబుణ్యాచారుండయిన పుత్రుండుభయపక్షంబులవారి నుద్ధరించుఁ; గావున.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :పుత్ + నామ్న . = ‘పుత్’ అనే పేరు కలనరకాత్ = నరకం నుంచిత్రాయతే + ఇతి = కాపాడతాడు కాబట్టిపుత్రః = పుత్రుడు అంటారుఅను = అనేవేదవచనంబు = వేదవచనంకలదు = ఉన్నదికావునన్ = కనుకపుణ్య + ఆచారుండు + అయిన = చక్కని నడవడిక కలవాడైనపుత్రుండు = పుత్రుడుఉభయపక్షంబుల వారినిన్ = ఇటు తండ్రివైపు వారికీ అటు తల్లివైపు వారికీఉద్దరించున్ = ఉత్తమలోకాలను కలిగిస్తాడుకావున = కాబట్టితాత్పర్యం :ఓ రాజా ! ‘పుత్’ అనే పేరు గల నరకం నుంచి తల్లిదండ్రులను కాపాడతాడు కాబట్టి పుత్రుడు అనే పేరు ఏర్పడింది అని వేదం చెప్పింది. కాబట్టి ఉత్తమశీలుడైన పుత్రుడు అటు తల్లివైపు వంశాన్నీ ఇటు తండ్రివైపు వంశాన్ని ఉద్దరిస్తాడు కాబట్టి."},{"question":"أجب على السؤال التالي : كم كلية توجد في جسم الإنسان السليم ؟","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة هي كليتان."},{"question":"Voltooi de paragraaf: De volhardingspolitiek was de politiek die volgde uit de weigering van koning Willem I van Nederland tussen 1830 en 1839 om de Belgische omwenteling","answer":"te accepteren. Pas met het Verdrag van Londen van 1839 erkende Nederland de Belgische onafhankelijkheid. Het leger bleef in deze periode gemobiliseerd op oorlogssterkte, wat de al grote staatsschuld enorm deed toenemen. De volhardingspolitiek heeft in zowel Nederland als België het nationale bewustzijn versterkt."},{"question":"Impiry isan'andro ny olona no tokony misakafo?","answer":"In-telo isan'andro ny olona no tokony misakafo."},{"question":"汉字“廿”表示","answer":"二十"},{"question":"অনুচ্ছেদ লিখুন: গণিত অলিম্পিয়াড।","answer":"আন্তর্জাতিক গণিত অলিম্পিয়াড হচ্ছে এমন একটি গণিত অলিম্পিয়াড যা মূলত প্রতিযোগীদের বুদ্ধিমত্তা ও গণিতের ওপর পারদর্শিতা নির্ণয়ের প্রতিযোগিতা। এটি আন্তর্জাতিক বিজ্ঞান অলিম্পিয়াডগুলোর মধ্যে সবচেয়ে পুরাতন প্রতিযোগিতা, যেটি মাধ্যমিক স্কুলের ছাত্রছাত্রীদের জন্যে প্রতিবছর অনুষ্ঠিত হয়। সর্বপ্রথম রোমানিয়ায় ১৯৫৯ সালে এটি অনুষ্ঠিত হয়। এরপর থেকে প্রতিবছর হয়ে আসছে এই অনুষ্ঠান। একমাত্র ১৯৮০ সালে মঙ্গোলিয়ায় অভ্যন্তরীণ গণ্ডগোলের কারণে গণিত অলিম্পিয়াড অনুষ্ঠিত হয়নি। এ প্রতিযোগিতায় মাধ্যমিক স্তরে পড়ুয়া শিক্ষার্থীরা অংশগ্রহণ করতে পারে এবং বয়স হতে হবে অনধিক ২০ বছর। প্রায় ৯০টি দেশ গণিত অলিম্পিয়াডে অংশগ্রহণ করে থাকে। প্রতিটি দলের সদস্য সংখ্যা থাকে ছয়জন করে। এই সকল শর্তসাপেক্ষে যে কোনো ছাত্র একাধিকবার গণিত অলিম্পিয়াডে অংশগ্রহণ করতে পারে। এই পরীক্ষাটি হয়ে থাকে দুই দিনব্যাপী। প্রশ্নপত্রে থাকে ছয়টি সমস্যা। প্রতিটি সমস্যার জন্যে বরাদ্দ থাকে ৭ নম্বর। তাই এ পরীক্ষার পূর্ণমান হচ্ছে ৪২। প্রতিযোগীরা একেক দিনে তিনটি সমস্যা সমাধান করার জন্যে সাড়ে চার ঘণ্টা সময় পায়। সমস্যা সমাধান করার ক্ষেত্রে প্রতিযোগীদের ক্যালকুলেটর ব্যবহার করা সম্পূর্ণ নিষিদ্ধ। মাধ্যমিক স্তরের গণিত থেকেই নির্ধারণ করা হয়ে থাকে এই সমস্যাগুলো। কিন্তু সমস্যাগুলো থাকে ছোটো ও বিচিত্র। ফলে মাধ্যমিক স্তরের গণিত ভালোভাবে আয়ত্ত করতে পারলেই এ প্রতিযোগিতায় জয়লাভ করা সম্ভব। মাধ্যমিক স্কুল গণিতের নানা বিভাগ যেমন জ্যামিতি, বীজগণিত, সংখ্যাতত্ত্ব এবং কম্বিনেটরিক্স ইত্যাদি বিভাগ থেকে প্রশ্ন করা হয়। এই সমস্যাগুলোর সমাধান প্রাক-বিশ্ববিদ্যালয় পর্যায়ের জ্ঞান দিয়ে করা গেলেও প্রয়োজন হয় প্রচুর অভিজ্ঞতা এবং দক্ষতার। উল্লেখ্য, প্রতিযোগিতায় কোনো দলকে নম্বর না দিয়ে নম্বর দেওয়া হয় প্রতিযোগীকে। প্রতিযোগীদের ব্যক্তিগত নম্বরের ওপর ভিত্তি করে নির্ধারণ করা হয় র‍্যাংকিং। পদক প্রাপ্তির জন্যে ন্যূনতম নম্বর এমনভাবে নির্ধারণ করা হয় যেন সোনা, রুপা ও ব্রোঞ্জপ্রাপ্ত ছাত্রছাত্রীর অনুপাত প্রায় ১ : ২ : ৩ হয়। এছাড়া অসাধারণ নৈপুণ্য বা চমৎকার সাধারণীকরণের জন্যে দেওয়া হয় বিশেষ পুরস্কার। আন্তর্জাতিক গণিত অলিম্পিয়াডে দল প্রেরণ করার জন্যে প্রতিটি দেশই দেশের অভ্যন্তরে সাধারণত স্থানীয়, বিভাগীয় ও জাতীয় প্রতিযোগিতার আয়োজন করার মাধ্যমে দল নির্বাচন করে। বিশ্বের বিভিন্ন দেশের শিক্ষার্থীদের গণিত উন্নয়নে গণিত অলিম্পিয়াডের ভূমিকা অনস্বীকার্য।"},{"question":"Paris no renivohitr'i Alemaina. Marina sa diso?","answer":"Diso, renivohitr'i Frantsa i Paris fa tsy an'i Alemaina."},{"question":"Wangsulana pitakonan ing ngisor iki nganggo pilihan sing disedhiyakake.Iman marang kuwasa sing luwih dhuwur kuwi isa nglipur wektu apa? Pilihan: A. pindhah gunung B. putus asa C. ora duwe pendidikan D. ora percaya kawruh","answer":"Iman marang Gusti Allah menehi kita dhukungan mental nalika wektu seneng lan susah (sedih). Dadi, wangsulanipun pitakonan ing ndhuwur yaiku: B. putus asa, sebab termasuk jenis ekspresine wektu susah."},{"question":"Apakah soalan untuk: \\"\\"Stand by Me\\" adalah lagu yang asalnya dari Ben E. King dan ditulis oleh King, Jerry Leiber, dan Mike Stoller, yang diilhamkan oleh rohani \\"Lord Stand by Me\\", ditambah dua baris yang berakar pada Mazmur 46:2? Topiknya ialah Stand by Me (lagu).","answer":"Apakah itu lagu \\"Stand by Me\\"?"},{"question":"Est-ce que tu peux me raconter une blague ?","answer":"D'accord, voici une blague :Question : Pourquoi les plongeurs plongent-ils toujours en arrière et jamais en avant ?Réponse : Parce que sinon ils tombent toujours dans le bateau !"},{"question":"ما هو البرج الذي يُعتبر رمز مدينة باريس؟","answer":"برج إيفل."},{"question":"Ijọba apapọ fẹẹ pese iṣẹ fun miliọnu marun-un eeyan","answer":"Ijọba apapọ ilẹ yii ti kede pe awọn yoo pese iṣẹ fun miliọnu marun-un eeyan gẹgẹ bii ileri tawọn ṣe tẹlẹ.Igbakeji Aarẹ, Ọjọgbọn Yẹmi Ọṣinbajo, lo kede ọrọ naa lasiko to n ṣepade pẹlu ileeṣẹ okoowo ipinlẹ Eko lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọsẹ to kọja.Ọṣinbajo ni eto iṣẹ agbẹ, ilegbee atawọn iṣẹ akanṣe mi-in yoo ran awọn ọdọ lọwọ lati ri iṣẹ nitori awọn nnkan ilẹ wa ti wọn yoo maa lo, eyi ti yoo din owo ti wọn yoo na lati pese awọn nnkan ti wọn fẹẹ ta ku, ki wọn le jere daadaa.Bakan naa lo ni ile miliọnu marun-un nijọba n gbero lati fa ina to n lo oorun (Solar) si, eyi ti yoo ran awọn oniṣẹ-ọwọ lọwọ, paapaa awọn ileeṣẹ to n pese aṣọ to n ṣeto aabo lasiko arun Korona yii."},{"question":"గిఫెన్ వైపరీత్యం లేదా గిఫెన్ వస్తువులు గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"ధర పెరిగినప్పటికి డిమాండ్ తగ్గకపోగా, పెరగటం లేదా అదే విధంగా డిమాండ్ను కలిగి ఉండే వస్తువులను గిఫెన్ వస్తువులంటారు. నాసిరకపు వస్తువులను గిఫెన్ వస్తువులంటారు. వాటి ధర పెరిగితే ఇతర వస్తువులపై ఖర్చు తగ్గించి ఈ వస్తువులను కొనుగోలు చేస్తారు. దీనిని సర్ రాబర్ట్ గిఫెన్ అనే ఆర్థికవేత్త పరిశీలించడం వల్ల దీనిని “గిఫెన్ వైపరీత్యం” అంటారు."},{"question":"كم خطوط المجالات السامحة للسباحة في السباحة الأولمبية","answer":"ترقم المجالات باألرقام 0– 9 ويسمح باستخدام المجاالت من 1– 8 في المسابقات الرسمية وتترك بقية المجالات فارغة."},{"question":"ما هي عاصمه استراليا؟","answer":"كانبيرا"},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Jawa yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.Bareng wis suwe, Razia weruh luwih akeh kewan nglangi. Dheweke sinau solahe kewan kang anyar. Razia nendhang. Dheweke ngambang. Dheweke lumenggang. Dheweke nyilem. Dheweke ngampet ambegan suwe lan saya suwe. Dheweke nglangi cepet.Terjemahan:","answer":"Hari-hari berlalu. Rasya mengamati cara berenang beraneka ragam hewan. Ia mempelajari banyak gerakan baru. Rasya menendang. Ia mengapung. Ia bergoyang- goyang. Ia menyelam. Ia menahan napasnya makin lama. Ia berenang makin cepat."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Cùng đi với Thủ tướng có Phó thủ tướng Chính phủ Lê Minh Khái, Trưởng Ban Chỉ đạo xử lý các tồn tại, yếu kém của một số dự án và doanh nghiệp chậm tiến độ, kém hiệu quả thuộc ngành công thương; lãnh đạo một số bộ, ngành, cơ quan Trung ương và địa phương. Dự án giai đoạn 2 mở rộng Nhà máy Gang thép Thái Nguyên được khởi công từ năm 2007 nhưng kéo dài tới nay, tồn tại nhiều vướng mắc chưa được giải quyết nên dự án chưa thể hoàn thành, đi vào hoạt động.   Tiếp đó, Thủ tướng và đoàn công tác tham quan Nhà máy Cán thép Thái Trung (nhà máy đang hoạt động của Tisco) và làm việc tại Công ty cổ phần Gang thép Thái Nguyên.  * Sáng cùng ngày, tại thành phố Thái Nguyên, Thủ tướng Phạm Minh Chính và đoàn công tác đến dâng hương, hoa tưởng niệm 60 liệt sĩ Thanh niên xung phong Đại đội 915, Đội 91 Bắc Thái hy sinh đêm 24-12-1972 tại khu vực Ga Lưu Xá khi đang làm nhiệm vụ giải tỏa hàng hóa chi viện cho chiến trường miền Nam. HUY LÊ","answer":"Thủ tướng Chính phủ Phạm Minh Chính khảo sát dự án mở rộng Nhà máy Gang thép Thái Nguyên"},{"question":"Contoh ejaan yang betul dalam bahasa melayu:","answer":"menggalakkan meyakinkan mengetengahkan kebaikan kenaikan resipi tanggungjawab mestika kebanyakan kerosakan diayah zuhur taasub legenda catat karisma kolesterolefisien masyhur rambut keriting Tuhan automotif audiens agregat aritmetik ejen (wakil) empangan"},{"question":"Lehenengo esaldia: Brasilgo musikan, Doriano doinua Mixoldiano doinuaz eratzen da, lehenengoa beheratzearen bidez, beraz hirugarrenaren bertsio bat txikiagoa da. Bigarren esaldia: Brasilgo musikan, Doriano doinua, Mixoldiano doinua, lehenengoa beheratzean sortzen da, eta beraz, hirugarrena bertsio txikiagoa da. Lehenengo esaldia eta bigarren esaldia zentzu berean daude? Bai edo ez?","answer":"Bai, badaude."},{"question":"Írj át minden nevet <anonim>-ra a következő bekezdésben:Nagy Róbert felkelt, megitta reggeli kávéját, elköszönt feleségétől, Évától és beült autójába. Késésben volt, ezért gyorsabban vezzetett a megengedettnél, aminek következményeképp Pesti Károly ezredes megállította. Végül egy bírsággal megúszta, de a munkából már bőven elkésett.","answer":"Tessék, az anonimizált mondat:<anonim> felkelt, megitta reggeli kávéját, elköszönt feleségétől, <anonim>-tól és beült autójába. Késésben volt, ezért gyorsabban vezzetett a megengedettnél, aminek következményeképp <anonim> ezredes megállította. Végül egy bírsággal megúszta, de a munkából már bőven elkésett."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la pregunta correspondiente a la siguiente respuesta? \\"LR44 es la designación de la CEI para una célula de botón alcalina de 1,5 voltios, comúnmente utilizada en pequeñas linternas LED, termómetros digitales, calculadoras, pinzas, relojes, relojes, juguetes y punteros láser.\\"? El tema es la batería LR44.","answer":"\\"¿Qué tipo de baterías son las LR44?\\""},{"question":"纽约有什么好玩的？","answer":"纽约是一个充满活力和多样性的城市，拥有众多景点和活动，包括时代广场、中央公园、第五大道、自由女神像等。"},{"question":"Văn bản này nói về sự kiện quan trọng nào? - Trong thập niên 1960, Timerman là một nhà báo được ưa thích. Cuối thập niên 1960, ông sáng lập 2 tuần báo tin tức khác nhau. Từ năm 1971 tới 1977, Timerman biên tập và xuất bản tờ nhật báo khuynh tả La Opinión(\\"Dư luận\\"). Dưới sự lãnh đạo của ông, tờ báo này đăng các tin và các bài chỉ trích những vụ vi phạm nhân quyền của chính phủ Argentina trong những năm đầu của cuộc \\"Chiến tranh bẩn thỉu\\" (\\"Dirty War\\").","answer":"Sự kiện quan trọng được nói tới trong văn bản này là vai trò của Timerman trong việc xuất bản và chỉ trích vụ vi phạm nhân quyền của chính phủ Argentina trong thời kỳ \\"Chiến tranh bẩn thỉu\\" (\\"Dirty War\\") trong những năm đầu thập niên 1970. "},{"question":"*من هي الزوجة التي أنجبت القاسم للرسول صلي الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"السيدة خديجة"},{"question":"Cad iad na hábhair chun pizza a dhéanamh?","answer":"Go traidisiúnta, na comhábhair chun pizza a dhéanamh, mar shampla pláta pizza. Ullmhaítear é ó bhraith, uisce, córas, salann, agus uaireanta ola ólann. Agus sóis pizza. Salann trátaí atá seachas le hórtaí agus spíosraí cosúil le horeagáin, basil, gairleog, agus píosa beag salainn agus siúcra. Chomh maith leis sin tá Cáis an-thahbachtach. Is minic a úsáidtear cáis mozzarella mar gheall ar a éilimh le topadh, ach is féidir comhoiriúnacht a dhéanamh le cineálacha eile cosúil le cheddar. Ar deireadh tagann na buntáscanna. Is féidir leat réimse leathan de buntáscanna a úsáid chun an pizza a chuspóireachtú"},{"question":"Miigan micnihiisu maxuu yahay.","answer":"lamid tahay maqiiqan."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட் செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:2 பீட்ரூட்5 உருளைக்கிழங்கு½ கப் பச்சை பட்டாணி1 பெரிய வெங்காயம்1 பச்சை மிளகாய்3 பல் பூண்டு1 துண்டு இஞ்சி2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி மைதா மாவு4 பிரெட்½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி சீரக தூள்½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி கரம் மசாலா1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சாட் மசாலா4 அல்லது 5 முந்திரிதேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்தேவையான அளவு உப்புசிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லி","answer":"வெளியில் மிருதுவாகவும் உள்ளே மென்மையாகவும் இருக்கும் பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட் ஒரு சூடான கப் டீ அல்லது காபியை சாப்பிட சிறந்த சிற்றுண்டியாகும். இந்த கட்லெட் தயாரிப்பதில் பீட்ரூட் மற்றும் உருளைக்கிழங்கு முக்கிய பொருட்கள். இந்த கட்லெட்டின் நல்ல விஷயம் என்னவென்றால், நீங்கள் ஷாலோ ஃப்ரை அல்லது ஏர்-ஃப்ரை அல்லது பேக் செய்யலாம். ஆரோக்கியமான பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட்டுகள்முயற்சி செய்ய இன்னும் பல கட்லெட் ரெசிபிகள் – சோயா சங்க்ஸ் கட்லெட் , மிக்ஸ்டு வெஜிடபிள் கட்லெட் , சிக்கன் கட்லட் , ராஜ்மா ஆலு கட்லெட் , பான் ஃப்ரைடு சிக்கன் கேரட் கட்லெட்இந்த செய்முறையைப் பற்றிஒவ்வொரு பேக்கரிக்கும் அதன் சொந்த கையெழுத்து செய்முறை உள்ளது. அது கர்நாடகாவில் உள்ள ஐயங்கார் பேக்கரியின் வெஜிடபிள் சாண்ட்விச் அல்லது ஆந்திர பேக்கரிகளில் மேடு போண்டா மற்றும் கேரளா பேக்கரிகளில் தில்குஷ். அதேபோல, பீட்ரூட் கட்லட் என்பது தமிழ்நாட்டில் நான் கண்ட பிரபலமான பேக்கரி சிற்றுண்டிகளில் ஒன்றாகும்.முதலில் ஒரு ரகசியம் சொல்கிறேன். நான் பீட்ரூட் ரசிகன் அல்ல. வண்ணம் துடிப்பாகவும் அழகாகவும் இருந்தாலும், அது என்னை பயமுறுத்துகிறது. உள்ளூர் உணவுகளை ருசிப்பதும், அதைப் பற்றி அதிகம் தெரிந்துகொள்வதும் எனக்கு எப்போதும் பிடித்தமான விஷயம். நண்பர் ஒருவர் மூலம் இந்த பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட் அறிமுகமானது.ரம்ஜான் சமயத்தில், நான் இப்தார் பாட்லக் நடத்தினேன், நண்பர் ஒருவர் இந்த கட்லெட்டுகளை கொண்டு வந்தார். அவை மிகவும் மிருதுவாகவும் சுவையாகவும் இருக்கும். நான் கட்லெட்டை சுவைத்தபோது, ​​​​அது மிகவும் மென்மையாகவும், வாயில் உருகவும் இருந்தது. நான் செய்முறையைக் கேட்டபோது, ​​அருகில் உள்ள பேக்கரியில் இருந்து கொண்டு வந்தேன் என்றாள்.அப்போதிருந்து, இந்த கட்லெட்டுகளை நான் மட்டுமே விரும்பி சாப்பிடுவதால், பேக்கரியில் இருந்து வாங்குவேன். லாக்டவுன் காலத்தில், நாங்கள் வீட்டில் இருந்தபோதும், வெளியே சாப்பிடுவது தடைசெய்யப்பட்டிருந்தபோதும், நான் இந்த கட்லெட்டுக்காக ஏங்கிக்கொண்டிருந்தேன். எனவே, இதை முயற்சிக்க நினைத்தேன்!இந்த பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட்டுகளை நான் வீட்டில் செய்த போது, ​​அனைவருக்கும் பிடித்திருந்தது, விரைவில் இவை என் வீட்டில் வழக்கமான டீ டைம் ஸ்நாக் ஆகிவிட்டது.பல முயற்சிகள் மற்றும் சோதனைகளுக்குப் பிறகு, இங்கே மிகவும் எளிமையான மற்றும் எளிதான பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட் செய்முறை உள்ளது . பொருட்கள் சரக்கறைக்கு ஏற்றவை மற்றும் குறிப்புகள் மற்றும் மாறுபாடுகளுக்கு இடுகையை கடைசி வரை படிக்கவும்.பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட் எளிதான செய்முறைபீட்ரூட் கட்லெட்'கட்லெட்' என்ற வார்த்தையின் தோற்றம் பிரெஞ்சு மொழியிலிருந்து வந்தது. Tiiki, patty, croquette, pattie, chop, போன்றவை கட்லெட்டின் பிற பெயர்கள். கட்லெட் பொதுவாக, தடிமனாகவும் வட்டமாகவும் இருக்கும், பொதுவாக நமது உள்ளங்கையின் மையத்தின் அளவு. இடத்தைப் பொறுத்து, இந்த பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட்டை பீட்ரூட் டிக்கி அல்லது பீட்ரூட் பாட்டி அல்லது பீட்ரூட் சாப் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது .இது தவிர, அவை பொருட்கள் மற்றும் இடத்தைப் பொறுத்து வடிவத்தில் சில வேறுபாடுகள். வங்காளத்தில், மக்கள் இந்த கட்லெட்டை பீட்ரூட் சாப் என்று அழைக்கிறார்கள் மற்றும் பெரும்பாலும் பஃப்டு ரைஸுடன் பரிமாறப்படுகிறார்கள்.கிழங்கு, உருளைக்கிழங்கு, பச்சை மிளகாய், வெங்காயம், நறுக்கிய வேர்க்கடலை (அல்லது முந்திரி பருப்புகள்), கரம் மசாலா, மிளகு தூள் மற்றும் உப்பு ஆகியவை பீட் கட்லெட்டின் முக்கிய பொருட்கள்.அனைத்து பொருட்களையும் கலந்து, தடிமனான மற்றும் வட்டமான பஜ்ஜிகளாக வடிவமைத்து, இருபுறமும் மிருதுவாக மாறும் வரை ஆழமாக வறுக்கவும். பீட்லெட் தயார்! கெட்ச்அப் அல்லது சாஸுடன் சூடாகப் பரிமாறவும்.உருளைக்கிழங்கு கொண்ட பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட்பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட் தேவையான பொருட்கள்பீட்ரூட் | சுகந்தர் - ஒரு பல்துறை வேர் காய்கறி. இந்தியாவில், சாலட், கறி, டிப்ஸ் (ஹம்முஸ்), வறுவல் (பொரியல்), சூப் போன்றவற்றில் பீட்ஸைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறோம். பீட்ஸில் மண் வாசனையும் வாசனையும் உள்ளது. இவை சத்தானவை மற்றும் அத்தியாவசிய வைட்டமின்கள், தாதுக்கள் மற்றும் மருத்துவ குணங்களைக் கொண்ட தாவர கலவைகளால் நிரம்பியுள்ளன.பீட்ஸில் குறிப்பாக ஃபோலேட் நிறைந்துள்ளது, இது ஒரு வைட்டமின் வளர்ச்சி, வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் இதய ஆரோக்கியத்தில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது. நைட்ரேட்டுகள் இருப்பதால், பீட்ரூட் இரத்த அழுத்த அளவைக் குறைக்க உதவுகிறது. பீட்ஸின் ஊட்டச்சத்து நன்மைகள் பல. இந்த சூப்பர்ஃபுட்டை உங்கள் உணவில் சேர்க்க மறக்காதீர்கள்.உருளைக்கிழங்கு | ஆலு - கட்லெட்டை பிணைக்க உதவுகிறது மற்றும் ஊட்டச்சத்து, சுவையையும் வழங்குகிறது. மற்றும் அமைப்பு. நான் உருளைக்கிழங்கை வேகவைத்து, அதை தட்டி பிறகு கட்லெட் கலவையில் சேர்க்கிறேன். உருளைக்கிழங்கை மசித்துச் சேர்க்கலாம். உருளைக்கிழங்கை அரைப்பதன் மூலம், கட்லெட்டில் நல்ல முறுக்கு கிடைக்கும்.வெங்காயம் - வெங்காயம் சேர்ப்பது முற்றிலும் விருப்பமானது. வெங்காயம் சுவையையும், அமைப்பையும் தரும்.கரம் மசாலா - சுவை, வாசனை மற்றும் சுவை சேர்க்கிறது.பச்சை மிளகாய் - வெப்பம் மற்றும் மசாலா சேர்க்கிறது.சாட் மசாலா - சாட் மசாலாவைச் சேர்ப்பது விருப்பமானது. சாட் மசாலா சுவை, சுவை மற்றும் வாசனை சேர்க்கிறது.ரவை | ரவா | சூஜி - நன்றாக சூஜி பயன்படுத்தவும். நாங்கள் சூஜியுடன் கட்லெட்டை பூசுகிறோம். இது கட்லெட்டுக்கு மிருதுவான வெளிப்புற உறையைக் கொடுக்க உதவும்.சோள மாவு - சோள மாவையும் தண்ணீரையும் சேர்த்து ஒரு மெல்லிய குழம்பு தயார் செய்கிறோம். இதில் நாம் கட்லெட்டுகளை நனைத்து, வறுப்பதற்கு முன் சூஜியில் உருட்டுவோம். சோள மாவு குழம்பு வறுக்கும்போது கட்லெட்டின் வடிவத்தை அப்படியே வைத்திருக்க உதவுகிறது.கொட்டைகள் - கொட்டைகள் சேர்ப்பது முற்றிலும் விருப்பமானது. ஆனால் வேர்க்கடலை அல்லது முந்திரி பருப்புகள் மென்மையான கட்லெட்டுக்கு நல்ல முறுக்கு சேர்க்கின்றன.மற்ற பொருட்கள் - மிளகு தூள், மஞ்சள் தூள், வறுத்த கொத்தமல்லி தூள், வறுத்த சீரக தூள், உப்பு மற்றும் எண்ணெய்.பீட் சாப் - பீட்ரூட் பாட்டிகுறிப்புகள் & மாறுபாடுகள்கட்லெட் தயாரிப்பதற்கு பீட்ரூட் தயாரிப்பதற்கான இரண்டு வழிகள் அவை.–> ஒன்று பீட்ரூட்டை அரைத்து, அதிகப்படியான தண்ணீரைப் பிழிந்து, வெங்காயம் மற்றும் பச்சை மிளகாயுடன் சேர்த்து வதக்கவும். வதக்குவதன் மூலம், கட்லெட்டில் உள்ள ஈரப்பதத்தை எளிதாகக் குறைக்கலாம், மேலும் ஃப்ரீசரில் ஒரு வாரம் உறைய வைக்கலாம்.–> மாற்றாக பீட்ரூட்டை உரித்து உருளைக்கிழங்குடன் சேர்த்து வேகவைக்கலாம். இந்த முறையில், உருளைக்கிழங்கு கூட நிறமடையும் மற்றும் கொதிக்கும் போது முள் இருக்கும்.பீட்ஸை வேகவைத்த பிறகு, அவற்றை மாஷரைப் பயன்படுத்தி மசிக்கலாம் அல்லது உருளைக்கிழங்குடன் சேர்த்து அரைக்கலாம்.இரண்டு முறையும், கட்லெட்டின் சுவையில் எந்த மாற்றமும் இருக்காது.சூஜி அல்லது ரொட்டி துண்டுகளுக்கு வருகிறது. நான் சூஜியைப் பயன்படுத்த விரும்புகிறேன், ஏனெனில் இது வறுக்கும்போது சுவையாகவும், சுவையாகவும் இருக்கும்.மாற்றாக, நீங்கள் ரொட்டி துண்டுகளை பயன்படுத்தலாம். ரொட்டித் துண்டுகளைப் பயன்படுத்தினால் ஒரு சிட்டிகை மிளகுத் தூள் சேர்த்து நன்கு கலக்கவும். இல்லையெனில், கட்லெட் வறுக்கும்போது சிறிது இனிப்பாக மாறும்.பீட் பஜ்ஜிஇந்த பீட்ரூட் கட்லெட் செய்முறையை நான் ஏன் முயற்சிக்க வேண்டும்?எளிமையானதுசரக்கறைக்கு உகந்த பொருட்கள்சைவம்பசையம் இல்லாததுஆரோக்கியமான  டீடைம் ஸ்நாக் , இந்தியன்பார்ட்டிக்கு எளிதான  சிற்றுண்டிகள் குழந்தை நட்புரமலான் காலத்தில் இப்தாருக்கு சிறந்தது"},{"question":"ක්ලෝරොප්ලාස්ටික් පටල හැදුනොත් මොකද වෙන්නේ? පෙර ප්‍රශ්නයට අනුව, පිළිතුර ඇතුළත් සන්දර්භය ලියන්න. ඒක වාක් ය 1 - 20 ක් වෙන්න පුළුවන්. පසුබිම:","answer":"ක්ලෝරොප්ලාස්ටික් පටල සමහර විට සයිටොප්ලාස්මයට පිටතට විහිදී ස්ට් රෝමියුලයක් හෝ ස්ට් රෝමිය අඩංගු නලයක් සාදයි. ක්ලෝරොප්ලාස්ට් වල ස්ට්රෝ  මුල් ඉතා දුර්ලභ වන අතර ක් රෝමොප්ලාස්ට් සහ ඇමයිලොප්ලාස්ට් වැනි වෙනත් ප්ලාස්ටිඩ් වල පිළිවෙලින් පෙති සහ මුල් වල බෙහෙවින් බහුල වේ. ඒවා  ක්ලෝරොප්ලාස්ට් මතුපිට ප් රදේශය වැඩි කිරීම සඳහා පවතී. 1962 දී ප් රථම වරට ඒවා නිරීක්ෂණය කළ විට ඇතැම් ශාක ජීව විද් යාඥයින් මෙම ව් යුහයන් කෘතිම ලෙස බැහැර කළ අතර, ස්ට් රෝමූල් යනු සංකෝචිත ප් රදේශ සහිත අමුතු හැඩැති ක්ලෝරොප්ලාස්ට් හෝ බෙදී යන ක්ලෝරොප්ලාස්ට් පමණක් බව ප් රකාශ කළහ. කෙසේ වෙතත්, ස්ට් රෝමුල්ස් යනු ශාක සෛල ප්ලාස්ටිඩවල ක් රියාකාරී, ඒකාබද්ධ ලක්ෂණ වන අතර ඒවා හුදෙක් කෘතිම නිෂ්පාදන නොවන බවට වැඩි වැඩියෙන් සාක්ෂි තිබේ."},{"question":"Mutsara wokutanga: Basa racho raiva rokusimbisa dzimwe nzvimbo dzomumvura nechokumabvazuva kwechivako chacho uye kubvisa tsvina netsvina zvishoma. Mutsara wechipiri: Basa racho raiva rokusimbisa dzimwe nzvimbo dzechivanze chiri nechokumabvazuva kwechivako chacho uye kubvisa tsvina netsvina zvishoma. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hongu kana kuti Kwete?","answer":"Kwete, mutsara wekutanga nemutsara wechipiri hazvireve chinhu chimwe chete. Pane misiyano mune zvese zvirimo uye mazwi zvinotungamira mukududzirwa kwakasiyana:1. Mutsetse Wekutanga:    - \\"Basa racho raiva rekusimbisa dzimwe nzvimbo dzemvura dziri kumabvazuva kwechivako uye kubvisa imwe tsvina nemarara.\\"Mumutsara uyu, zvinotariswa pane \\"nzvimbo dzemvura\\" kumabvazuva kwechivako. Chinangwa chikuru chebasa ndechekusimbisa izvi zvine chekuita nemvura, izvo zvinogona kusanganisira zvinhu zvakaita semadziva, zvitubu, kana masisitimu emvura. Pamusoro pezvo, basa rinosanganisira kubvisa \\"imwe tsvina nemarara,\\" zvichiratidza maitiro ekuchenesa.2. Mutsetse Wechipiri:    - \\"Basa racho raive rekusimbisa dzimwe nzvimbo dzechivanze kumabvazuva kwechivako uye kubvisa tsvina uye tsvina shoma.\\"Mumutsara uyu, kutarisa kunoshandura kune \\"nzvimbo dzechivanze\\" kumabvazuva kwechivako, kwete kunyanya \\"nzvimbo dzemvura.\\" Basa racho rine chinangwa chekusimbisa nzvimbo dzechivanze idzi, dzinogona kusanganisira nzira dzekufamba, kugadzirwa kwevhu, kana zvimwewo. Inotaurawo nezve \\"bvisa tsvina netsvina,\\" inoita senge isina basa uye inogona kunge iri chikanganiso chekunyora, asi inoratidza maitiro ekuchenesa zvakare.Saka, mitsetse miviri inosiyana maererano nenzvimbo dzakananga dziri kutariswa (nzvimbo dzemvura vs. nzvimbo dzechivanze) uye mutsauko muduku wemashoko ane chokuita nokubviswa kwetsvina."},{"question":"*Балалык* ырын жазып берчи?","answer":"Ай чыкты карачы,Айдан биз жаралдык,Ай нуру төгүлгөн,Алтындай балалык.Күн чыкты карачы,Күндөн биз жаралдык,Күн нуру төгүлгөн,Күмүштөй балалык."},{"question":"Ọmọ ọdun mẹsan-an ni James pa to fẹẹ fi ṣoogun owo tọwọ fi tẹ ẹ l’Ọffa","answer":"Ba a ṣe n jekuru ko tan lawọn agbenipa sowo n gbọn ọwọ ẹ sawo ni Kwara bayii pẹlu bi ọrọ awọn apaniṣowo ṣe n legba kan si i nipinlẹ Kwara.Ọwọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti tun tẹ ọkunrin kan, Alade James, lagboole Alawe, niluu Ọffa, lakooko to n bo ọmọdebinrin ẹni ọdun mẹsan-an, Faith Samuel, to pa mọlẹ pẹlu ẹgbẹrun kan naira ni agbegbe Ikọtun, nijọba ibilẹ Ọffa, ipinlẹ Kwara, to si jẹwọ pe oogun owo loun fẹẹ fi i ṣe.Ọjọ Aiku, Sunnde, ọṣẹ yii, ni agbẹnusọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, ẹka ti ipinlẹ Kwara, Ọgbẹni Okasanmi Ajayi, fi iroyin naa lede niluu Ilọrin pe ọwọ ti tẹ arakunrin kan torukọ rẹ n jẹ Alade James, fẹsun pe o ṣeku pa ọmọde ọdun mẹsan-an, Faith Samuel, ti agboole Onireke, niluu Ọffa, to si n bo o mọlẹ pẹlu ẹgbẹrun kan naira.Nigba ti wọn gbe ọmọ naa jade ninu koto to n bo o mọ ni wọn gbe e lọ si ileewosan, nibi ti wọn ti ṣe ayẹwo fun un. Dokita fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ọmọdebinrin ọhun ti dagbere faye, wọn si ti gbe oku ẹ si yara igbokuu-si nileewosan naa to wa niluu Ọffa. James si jẹwọ pe oogun owo loun fẹẹ fi ọmọdebinrin ọhun ṣe.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Kwara, Tuesday Assayomo, ti waa paṣẹ pe ki wọn ṣe ẹkunrẹrẹ iwadii lori iṣẹlẹ naa lati mọ igbeṣẹ to kan."},{"question":"MüzeKart Topkapı sarayından alınır mı?","answer":"NOT: MüzeKart, Topkapı Sarayı içerisinde bulunan Harem Dairesi, Aya İrini Anıtı, Efes Örenyeri içerisinde bulunan Yamaçevler , Göreme Açıkhava Müzesi içerisinde bulunan Karanlık Kilise, Sedir Adası ve İstanbul Sinema Müzesi geçerli değildir. Belirtilen bu yerler için ayrıca bilet almanız gerekmektedir."},{"question":" Como são o deserto e o oásis representados na narrativa de \\"O Alquimista\\"?","answer":"O deserto é um lugar de testes e purificação, onde Santiago enfrenta desafios. O oásis, com a sua fonte de vida, simboliza a recompensa do esforço e a conexão espiritual. Ambos os cenários são utilizados para refletir etapas da jornada pessoal."},{"question":"متى ولد الملك السادس الذي كان يحكم المغرب؟","answer":"ولد عام 1963 ميلاديًا."},{"question":"Moa ve ny lehilahy mirona kokoa amin’ny famahana olana amin’ny fomba famakafakana?","answer":"Misy fahasamihafana eo amin'ny safidy, fa ny fahaiza-manadihady dia tsy voafetra amin'ny mahalahy na mahavavy."},{"question":"ලෝකයේ රටවල් අතරින් චතුරශ්‍රාකාර හැඩයක් නොගන්නා  ජාතික කොඩියක් ඇති රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"නේපාලයේ ජාතික ධජය රටවල් අතර සුවිශේෂී වන්නේ එයට සෘජුකෝණාස්‍රාකාර හෝ  හතරැස් හැඩයක් නොමැති බැවිනි. ඒ වෙනුවට, එය එක මත එක තබන ලද  ත්රිකෝණ දෙකකින් සමන්විත වේ. මෙම සුවිශේෂී සැලසුම නේපාලයේ ධජය ලෝකයේ එකම චතුරස්‍ර නොවන ජාතික ධජය බවට පත් කරයි. ධජය රටේ ප්‍රාථමික ආගම් දෙක වන හින්දු ආගමේ සහ බුද්ධාගමේ සංකේත ඒකාබද්ධ කරයි, එහි තද රතු පැහැයෙන් නිර්භීතකම නියෝජනය කරන අතර නිල් මායිම සාමය සංකේතවත් කරයි. ධජයේ නිරූපිත හිරු සහ සඳ ද ගැඹුරු සංකේතාත්මක වන අතර, නේපාලය මෙම ආකාශ වස්තූන් පවතින තාක් කල් පවතිනු ඇතැයි යන බලාපොරොත්තුව නියෝජනය කරයි."},{"question":"Atsakykite į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kuriame Gilmoro mergaičių serialo sezone buvo aktorė, kuri taip pat vaidino Vini Foster?","answer":"Trečiame sezone"},{"question":"பின்வரும் பாடலில் அமைந்துள்ள தொடைநயங்களை எழுதுக:கிளிக்கு றெக்கை இருக்கும் வரைக்கும்கிழக்கு வானம் தூரமில்லைமுளைக்கும் விதைகள் முளைக்கத் துடித்தால்பூமி ஒன்றும் பாரமில்லை .","answer":"தொடைநயங்கள் :1. கிளிக்கு - கிழக்குஇதில், முதல் எழுத்து ஒன்றிவந்து \\"மோனை நயம்\\" உள்ளது.2. முளைக்கும் – முளைக்கத்இதில், முதல் எழுத்து ஒன்றிவந்து \\"சீர் மோனை\\" நயமும், இரண்டாம் எழுத்து ஒன்றி வந்து \\"சீர் எதுகை\\" நயமும் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளது.3. தூரமில்லை – பாரமில்லைஇதில் \\"மில்லை\\" என்னும் இறுதி சீர் ஒன்றி வந்து \\"இயைபுத் தொடை\\" நயம் அமைந்துள்ளது."},{"question":"What is the capital of Armenia?","answer":"Yerevan, Armenia's capital, is marked by grand Soviet-era architecture. The Matenadaran library, housing thousands of ancient Greek and Armenian manuscripts, dominates its main avenue. Republic Square is the city's core, with musical water fountains and colonnaded government buildings. The 1920s History Museum of Armenia on the square's eastern side contains archaeological objects like a circa-3500-B.C. leather shoe."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Thành phố hiện nằm dưới sự kiểm soát của tướng Khalifa Hifter, lãnh đạo liên minh Quân đội Quốc gia Libya (LNA), sau cuộc giao tranh năm 2018-2019. Hạ tầng ở Libya nhìn chung đã suy yếu do xung đột kéo dài, các công trình ở Derna cũng chưa được sửa chữa hay tái thiết hoàn toàn do xung đột. \\"Các con đập, cơ sở khử muối, lưới điện và đường sá ở Libya đều ","answer":"trong tình trạng hư hỏng\\", Stephanie T. Williams, cố vấn đặc biệt về Libya của tổng thư ký Liên Hợp Quốc giai đoạn 2021-2022, nói.Derna có hai con sông chảy qua, và được bảo vệ bởi hai con đập được xây dựng từ những năm 1970 để ngăn lũ. Tuy nhiên, do vùng này ít khi bị lũ lụt, hai con đập được xây dựng khá thô sơ, với phần lõi được đắp bằng đất sét, hai bên thân được gia cố bằng đá hộc và đá dăm."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Giá gạo tăng nhanh có thể khiến lạm phát tại đây tăng tốc trở lại, sau khi đã xuống thấp nhất 16 tháng trong tháng 7. Gạo hiện chiếm 9% rổ hàng hóa để tính lạm phát tại nước này. Ngân hàng Trung ương Philippines ","answer":"ước tính lạm phát tháng trước tăng tốc lần đầu tiên trong 7 tháng, do giá nhiên liệu và gạo lên cao.Năm 2018, giá gạo tăng cao do thiếu cung đã thổi bùng lạm phát tại Philippines, khiến nước này phải nâng lãi suất. Tháng trước, giá gạo tại châu Á lên cao nhất 15 năm, do Ấn Độ - nước xuất khẩu gạo lớn nhất thế giới – cấm xuất khẩu nhiều loại gạo ra nước ngoài."},{"question":"Dàpọ̀ Abíọ́dún","answer":"Dàpọ̀ Abíọ́dún (tí wọ́n bí ní ọjọ́ kọkándínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù Kàrún-ún ọdún 1960) jẹ́ oníṣòwò àti olóṣèlú ọmọ ilẹ̀ Yorùbá láti ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ Gómìnà Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn nígbàtí O borí ìdìbò ti Gómìnà ni ọdún 2019 lábẹ́ àsíyá ẹgbẹ́-òṣèlú (APC). Dàpọ̀ Abíọ́dún ni olórí ìgbìmọ̀ ti Corporate Affairs Commission. Ó tún jẹ́ alakoso àti olùdarí ti ilé epo Heyden àti olùdásílẹ̀ First Power Limited. Ní ọjọ́ kewa oṣù kẹta ọdún 2019, ìgbìnmọ̀ ti o n darí ìdìbò ni ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà èyí tí ó jẹ́ Independent Electoral Commission kede Dapo Abiodun gẹ́gẹ́ bí Gómìnà ti a dìbò yàn ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn. Wọ́n ṣe ìbúra fún un gẹ́gẹ́ bi Gomina Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn ní ọjọ́ kọnkàndínlọ́gbọ̀n, oṣù karùn-ún, ọdún 2019 (29 may 2019)Dapọ Abiọdun wa láti Ìpèrù Remọ ni Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn. Ó wá láti ìdílé Ọba. A bi sínú ẹbí dọ́kítà Emmanuel àti Arábìnrin Victoria Abiodun tí wọ́n wá láti Ìpèrù Remọ ní ìla-òrùn Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn ni ọjọ́ kọkàndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù karun ọdún 1960 (29 May 1960).Dapọ Abiọdun kọ́ ẹ̀kọ́ nípa ìmọ̀ ẹ̀rọ ní ilé ẹ̀kọ́ gíga Fásìtì Obafẹ́mi Awólọ̀wọ̀ tí ó wà níDapọ Abiọdun ni alakoso àti olùdarí ilé iṣẹ́ Heyden Petroleum Limited (UPL), ilé iṣẹ́ ti epo ati gaasi ni ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà. Ó tún jẹ́ olùdásílẹ̀ ilé iṣẹ́ First Power Limited.Dapọ Abiọdun jẹ́ ọ̀kan lara ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ tí Ó dá ẹgbẹ́ Alábùradà (Peoples Democratic Party) sílẹ̀ ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn, bíòtilẹ̀jẹ́pé Ó jẹ́ ọ̀kan lara ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ onigbalẹ (All Progressive Congress) lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́ bayi nígbàtí O fi ẹgbẹ́ ti Ó wà tẹ́lẹ̀ sílẹ̀ lẹhin ìdìbò gbogboogbo ti ọdún 2015. Ó díje du ipò láti lọ si ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin àgbà lati lọ ṣojú ilà oorun ti Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ onigbale (All Progressive Congress) nínú ìdìbò gbogboogbo tí ó waye ni Nàìjíríà ni ọdún 2015 èyí tí Ó pàdánù rẹ fún ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ Alábùradà (Peoples Democratic Party). Wọ́n yan Dapọ Abiọdun gẹ́gẹ́ bi ọ̀kan lára àwọn aṣòfin àgbà tí ìjọba àpapọ̀ ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà ní ọdún 1988 lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ United Nigeria Congress Party (UNCP) èyí tí o ti kógbá sí ilé. Ó ti ṣiṣẹ́ sìn lábẹ́ ìgbìmọ̀ aarẹ àti ilé iṣẹ́ lórísirísi.Ní ọdún 2019, Ó díje nínú ìdìbò ti Gómìnà ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn labẹ ẹgbẹ́ onigbale (All Progressive Congress). Ó sì borí ìbò na. Ó jẹ́ ọmọ lẹ́hìn kristi tooto ti O si njọsin pẹ̀lú ilé ìjọsìn (Mountain Of Fire And Miracles Ministry). Ó ti jẹri pe pẹ̀lú gbogbo bí àtakò láti má lè dé ófìsì ti Gómìnà Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn ṣe pọ̀ tó, Olórun sì tún mú Ò un dé ibẹ̀.Abiodun ṣe ìgbéyàwó sí Bamidele Abiodun lọ́dún 1990, ó sì bí ọmọ márùn-ún, lára rẹ̀ ni olóògbé Olugbenga Abiodun, DJ Nàìjíríà kan tí a tún mọ̀ sí DJ Olu."},{"question":", wabonakala uNokulindela ekhala, kephakungezona ezosizi kungezenjabulo. Kwaba sengathi bobabili babengasenaloithemba lokuthi uNokulindela uyobuye aphindele esimeni sakhe. Baxoxa eziningiuNokulindela efuna ukwazi ukuthi ngabe banjani ekhaya. Uyise-ke wagcina esezewabazisa ukuthi bona njengomndeni banqume ukuthi uNokulindela ake angasheshiukubuyela ngasekhaya. Into ababenovalo ngayo ukuthi babengazi ukuthi njengobaizinhliziyo zazisebomvu nje koZabalaza kwakungahle kwenzekeni. Into ayeyesabauMchunu ukuthi funa athi ubuyisa ingane yakhe kanti useyimbela ithuna. Babonakungcono intombazane ike ihlale, indaba ize ithi sengathi iyalotha.1. Lichazani leli gama elibhalwe ngokugqamile kulo musho olandelayo njengobalisetshenzisiwe kulesi siqeshana? Nikeza isibonelo esisendabeni.'Sona saba sihle impela isigwebo sabo' ","answer":"Leli gama lichaza isijeziso esisemthethweni esinikezwa umuntu owenzeicala√ njengoba kwenzeka kuZabalaza, uNomgedla kanye noJiyane ngecalalokuthakatha uNokulindela. "},{"question":"Wat is de Liparis mucosus?","answer":"Liparis mucosus is een straalvinnige vissensoort uit de familie van snotolven (Cyclopteridae). De wetenschappelijke naam van de soort is voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 1855 door Ayres. "},{"question":"வினா:அதிக மக்கள் அடர்த்தியை கொண்ட கண்டம் எது?","answer":"விடை: ஐரோப்பா"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bulat fikiran'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud mengambil keputusan yang tetap. Contoh ayat: Dia telah bulat fikiran untuk meneruskan pelajarannya ke luar negeri."},{"question":"নোংরা কিছু দেখলে মুখে থুথু আসে কেন? এক বাক্যে উত্তর দাও।","answer":"নোংরা কিছু দেখলে শরীরের বিশেষ বিশেষ ইন্দ্রিয় থেকে উত্তেজনা মস্তিষ্কের কোষে পৌঁছে এবং এখান থেকে সংকেত সংশ্লিষ্ট গ্রন্থিতে পৌঁছানোর কারণে মুখে থুথু আসে।"},{"question":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa bẹrẹ iwadii lori oku Kabiru ti wọn ba lorita Ọkinni, nipinlẹ Ọṣun","answer":"Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọṣun, SP Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, ti sọ pe iwadii ti bẹrẹ lori iku ọmọkunrin kan ti awọn eeyan ilu Ọkinni, nijọba ibilẹ Ẹgbẹdọrẹ, ba lorita ilu naa nidaaji ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii.Ṣe lawọn araalu deede ba oku ọkunrin ti wọn pe ni Kabiru naa ninu agbara ẹjẹ, ti ko si sẹni to mọ bo ṣe debẹ tabi ibi to ti n bọ.ALAROYE gbọ pe oju ibọn wa lara ọmọ bibi ilu Ilobu, nitosi ilu Ọkinni, ọhun, eleyii to fi han pe o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ pe ibọn ni wọn fi pa a.Kia ni wọn lọọ fi ọrọ naa to ọlọpaa agbegbe naa leti, ṣugbọn nigba ti awọn ọlọpaa fẹẹ gbe oku rẹ lawọn mọlẹbi rẹ sọ pe awọn ko le yọnda rẹ fun wọn, nitori awọn gbọdọ sin in nilana ẹsin Musulumi.Ọpalọla ṣalaye pe gbogbo atotonu awọn ọlọpaa pe ki wọn gbe oku Kabiru lọ fun ayẹwo nileewosan lati le mọ nnkan to ṣeku pa a ni awọn mọlẹbi rẹ ko gba.Alukoro sọ siwaju pe awọn ọlọpaa ti duro wamuwamu lagbegbe naa lati le dena wahala ti ẹnikẹni ba fẹẹ da silẹ latari iku Kabiru, ati lati tuṣu desalẹ ikoko ohun to ṣokunfa iku rẹ."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Vanuatu?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Vanuatu mu ngi tudd Port-Vila."},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي بدأت وانتهت بالتسبيح؟.","answer":"\\tسورة الحشر."},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন - উহুদ যুদ্ধের","answer":"পর চতুর্থ মাসে নাজদের বনী কিলাব গোত্রের সরদার আবু বারা আমের ইবন মালেক মদীনায় হযরত রাসূলে কারীমের সা: খিদমতে হাজির হয় । এবং তার নিজের গোত্রের ইসলাম গ্রহণের জন্য একটি দলের আরজ করেন । রাসুল নাজদ গোত্রের ব্যপারে সংশয় প্রকাশ করলেও আবু বারা আমের এই দলের দায়িত্ব নিলে রাসুল রাজি হন এবং মুনজির ইবন আমেরের নেতৃত্বে ৪০ জন মতান্তরে ৭০ জনের একটি দল পাঠান ।"},{"question":"次の段落の内容を書き続けてください： 三重県桑名市は来年4月から、市の消防士が60歳になって仕事をやめたあと、バスの運転手になることができるようにしました。バスの会社の三重交通と一緒に決めました。","answer":"県や市などの役所で働く人は、仕事をやめる年齢が少しずつ高くなって、将来は65歳になります。しかし、火事を消したり病気の人を運んだりする消防士の仕事は、年齢が高くなると、続けることが難しい場合があります。 バスの会社は運転手が足りなくて困っています。消防士だった人が運転手になると、道をよく知っている人に働いてもらうことができます。 バスの運転手の免許は、消防署で働いている間に取ることができます。お金は三重交通が出します。運転手になったら72歳まで働くことができます。"},{"question":"Murat Kurşun MS hastası mı?","answer":"- YouTube. Ünlü türkücü Murat Kurşun'a MS teşhisi konuldu."},{"question":"قوڵترین ناوچەی ئاو دەکەوێتە کوێ؟ ","answer":"ماریانا "},{"question":"කදම්භ නදී නමින්‌ හැඳින්වු ගංගාව දැන්‌ හඳුන්වන නම කුමක්ද?","answer":"කදම්භ නදී නමින්‌ හැඳින්වු ගංගාව දැන්‌ හඳුන්වන නම මල්වතු ඔය වේ. මල් වතු ඔය (Malvathu River) දිගින් කි.මි.164 (සැතපුම් 102) වන අතර මෙය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගංගා අතරින් දිගින් දෙවන ස්ථානය ගනි. ඓතිහාසික වටපිටාවකට උරුමකම් කියන මෙම නදිය අනුරාධපුර නගරයට සම්බන්ධව ආරම්භවී මන්නාරම් මුහුදු සිමාවෙන් අවසානවේ."},{"question":"\\"Losing my religion\\" foi um sucesso para qual banda alternativa de rock em 1991?","answer":"\\"Losing My Religion\\" é uma canção da banda americana de rock alternativo R.E.M. Foi lançada nos Estados Unidos em 19 de fevereiro de 1991, através da Warner Bros. Records, como o primeiro single do sétimo álbum de estúdio da banda, Out of Time."},{"question":"Iza no mpahay siansa malaza namorona ny teoria momba ny \\"relativité\\"?","answer":"Albert Einstein no namorona ny teoria momba ny \\"relativité\\"."},{"question":"ਆਮ ਲੋਕ ਤਕਰੀਬਨ ਏਨਾ ਕੁ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਸਾਹਨੀ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਵਧੀਆ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ 135 ਦੇ ਲਗਪਗ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਿਵੇਕਲੀ ਛਾਪ ਛੱਡਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਏ। ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਹੁਤੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਮਕਬੂਲ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਏਨਾ ਟੇਢਾ ਮੇਢਾ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਕਿਆਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀਅਤ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਇੱਕ ਮਈ 1913 ਨੂੰ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਵਿਖੇ ਹੋਇਆ। ਪੁਰਖਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਪਿੰਡ ਭੇਰਾ ਸੀ। ਬਲਰਾਜ, ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਦੇ ਬੜੇ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਕਾਰੋਬਾਰੀ ਹਰਬੰਸ ਲਾਲ ਸਾਹਨੀ ਅਤੇ ਸ੍ਰੀਮਤੀ ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਦੇਵੀ ਦਾ ਪੰਜਾਂ ਧੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਜੰਮਿਆ ਪੁੱਤਰ ਸੀ। ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਨਾਂ ਯੁਧਿਸ਼ਟਰ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਨਾਂ ਲੈਣਾ ਔਖਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਘਰ ਦਾ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਵੀ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਮਨ੍ਹਾ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ 'ਗੁਰੂਕਲ ਪੋਠੋਹਾਰ' ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਨੇ ਪਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਫਿਰ ਚੌਥੀ ਜਮਾਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਡੀ.ਏ.ਵੀ. ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਾਲ1930 ਵਿੱਚ ਡੀ.ਏ.ਵੀ. ਕਾਲਜ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਤੋਂ ਇੰਟਰਮੀਡੀਏਟ ਪਾਸ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਫੈਸਰ ਜਸਵੰਤ ਰਾਏ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਭੈਣ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ 1936 ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋਇਆ।ਸਾਲ 1930 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਕਾਲਜ ਲਹੌਰ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਿੱਥੋਂ ਉਸ ਨੇ 1934 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਲਜ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ ਲਿਖੀਆਂ।  ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਯਥਾਰਥਵਾਦੀ ਰੰਗਮੰਚ ਬਾਰੇ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਾ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਤਰ ਸੁਭਾਵਕ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਲਹਿਜ਼ੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੋਲਦੇ ਸਨ। ਪਾਰਸੀ ਰੰਗਮੰਚ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਚੱਲਤ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ ਦੀ ਨਕਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਨ ਕਰਦੇ। ਸੰਨ 1934 ਵਿੱਚ ਲਾਹੌਰ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੀ ਐਮ.ਏ. ਕਰਨ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਵਾਪਸ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਤੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਵਪਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ। ਇਨ੍ਹੀਂ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਹੀ ਦਵਿੰਦਰ ਸਤਿਆਰਥੀ ਇੱਕ ਮਹੀਨਾ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਘਰ ਰਿਹਾ। ਛੇਤੀ ਹੀ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਵਪਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਉਕਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਨਵੀਂ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਅੰਗੜਾਈਆਂ ਲੈ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ।  ਫਿਰ ਓਧਰੋਂ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਦੀ ਕੁੱਖੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਬੇਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਕਸ਼ਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮੀਆਂ ਬੀਵੀ ਨਾਟਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ  ਦਿਲਚਸਪੀਆਂ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਰਹੇ। ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਆਪਣਾ ਬੋਰੀਆ ਬਿਸਤਰਾ ਵਲ੍ਹੇਟ ਕੇ ਕਲਕੱਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਤੁਰ ਪਏ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਰਵਿੰਦਰ ਨਾਥ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਨਿਕੇਤਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕਰ ਲਈ। ਉੱਥੇ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹਾ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਣ ਸੀ, ਸੋਹਣਾ ਤੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਨ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਵਰਗੀ ਰੂਹ ਦੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ। ਉੱਥੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਹੋਰਾਂ ਬਰਨਾਰਡ ਸ਼ਾਹ ਦਾ ਨਾਟਕ 'ਆਰਮਜ਼ ਐਂਡ ਦੀ ਮੈਨ' ਖੇਡਿਆ। ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਨਿਕੇਤਨ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖਾਸ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਰਹੀ ਕਿ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਨੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਾਂ ਬੋਲੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਖਣ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 1940 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਅਤੇ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਲਈ ਰਵਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਗਏ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਚਾਰ ਸਾਲ ਬੀ.ਬੀ.ਸੀ. ਲੰਡਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਹ ਉਹ ਸਮਾਂ ਸੀ ਜਦ ਰੋਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਜਰਮਨ ਜੰਗੀ ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਲੰਡਨ ਉਤੇ ਬੰਬਾਰੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਬੇਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਕਸ਼ਤ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਦਾਦਾ-ਦਾਦੀ ਕੋਲ ਰਿਹਾ। ਜਦ ਬਲਰਾਜ 1944 ਵਿੱਚ ਲੰਡਨ ਤੋਂ ਮੁੜਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਜੰਗ ਦੀ ਭਿਆਨਕਤਾ ਵੇਖ ਆਇਆ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਕਲਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਨਾਲ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਬੰਬੇ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ ਚੇਤਨ ਆਨੰਦ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੋਲ ਕਰਨ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਉਹ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਪੀਪਲਜ਼ ਥੀਏਟਰ ਐਸੋਸੀਏਸ਼ਨ (ਇਪਟਾ) ਦਾ ਸਰਗਰਮ ਆਗੂ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ, ਜੋ ਨਾਟਕ ਨੂੰ ਇਨਕਲਾਬੀ ਲਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਦਾ ਹਥਿਆਰ ਸਮਝਦੀ ਸੀ।ੇ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਫਿਟਕਾਰਾਂ ਪਾਈਆਂ, ਜਿਹੜਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਸਕਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 1949 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਭੂਆ ਦੀ ਕੁੜੀ ਸੰਤੋਸ਼ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਇਆ। ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਗ੍ਰਿਫਤਾਰ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ। ਇਨਕਲਾਬੀ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਸਰਗਰਮੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਛੇ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਜੇਲ੍ਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਗੁਜ਼ਾਰੇ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਜੀ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦਸੋ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ  ਸ੍ਰੀਮਤੀ ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਦੇਵੀ "},{"question":" வினா:  நள்ளிரவில்  சூரியன் உதிக்கும் நாடு எது? காரணம்  கூறுக .","answer":"விடை:நள்ளிரவில்  சூரியன் உதிக்கும் நாடு நார்வே.நோர்வே அல்லது நார்வே ஐரோப்பாவில் எசுக்காண்டினாவியா தீபகற்பத்தின் மேற்குப்பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ள நாடாகும். இது அதிகாரபூர்வமாக நோர்வே இராச்சியம் என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. இந்நாடு வடக்கே ஆர்க்டிக் பெருங்கடல், மேற்கே நோர்வே கடல், தெற்கே வட கடல் என்பவற்றையும், சுவீடன், பின்லாந்து, இரசியா என்பவற்றுடன் நில எல்லைகளையும் கொண்டுள்ளது.       நோர்வே நள்ளிரவுச் சூரியன் உதிக்கும் நாடு எனப் பெயர்பெற்றது.சிறப்புக்கள்:    கடல்நீரேரிகள் அதிகம் உள்ள நாடு.    வடமுனை ஒளியின் அழகை காணக்கூடிய நாடுகளில் ஒன்றாக இருக்கிறது.    மனித வளர்ச்சிச் சுட்டெண் கொண்டு நோக்கும்போது, பல வருடங்களாக முன்னணியில் இருக்கும் நாடாகும்.    காரணம்:               நள்ளிரவுச் சூரியன் அல்லது துருவப் பகல் என்பது, ஆர்க்டிக் வட்டத்தின் வடக்கிலும், அதற்கு அண்மையில் ஓரளவு தெற்கிலும், அண்டார்டிக் வட்டத்துக்குத் தெற்கிலும் அதற்கு ஓரளவு வடக்கிலும் காணப்படும் ஒரு தோற்றப்பாடு ஆகும். இது அப்பகுதிகளில் உள்நாட்டு நேரம் நள்ளிரவு 12 மணிக்கும் சூரியன் தெரிவதைக் குறிக்கும். காலநிலை தெளிவாக இருப்பின் 24 மணி நேரமும் சூரியன் தெரியக்கூடியதாக இருக்கும். ஓராண்டில் நள்ளிரவுச் சூரியன் தெரியும் நாட்களின் எண்ணிக்கை துருவங்களை நோக்கிச் செல்லும்போது அதிகரிக்கும்.அண்டார்க்டிக் வட்டத்துக்குத் தெற்கே நிரந்தர மனிதக் குடியிருப்புகள் எதுவும் இல்லை. எனவே இத் தோற்றப்பாட்டைக் காணும் வாய்ப்புப் பெற்றவர்கள் ஆர்க்டிக் வட்டப் பகுதியில் வாழும் மக்கள் மட்டுமே. இப் பகுதிகள், ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்கா, கனடா, கிறீன்லாந்து, நார்வே, சுவீடன், பின்லாந்து, ரஷ்யா, ஐஸ்லாந்தின் வடபகுதி ஆகியவற்றில் உள்ளன. பின்லாந்தின் கால்பங்கு பகுதி ஆர்க்டிக் வட்டத்துள் அடங்கியுள்ளதுடன், அதன் வடக்குக் கோடியில், கோடை காலத்தில் சூரியன் 73 நாட்களுக்கு மறைவதே இல்லை. ஐரோப்பாவில் கூடிய தொலைவு வடக்கில் அமைந்த குடியிருப்பான நார்வேயின் சுவல்பார்ட்டில் ஏறத்தாழ ஏப்ரல் 19 ஆம் தேதி தொடக்கம் ஆகஸ்ட் 23 வரை சூரியன் மறைவதில்லை. துருவங்களில் தொடர்ந்து ஆறு மாதங்கள் சூரியன் மறைவதில்லை.இதன் எதிர்த் தோற்றப்பாடான துருவ இரவுத் தோற்றப்பாடு மாரி காலத்தில் ஏற்படும். இக் காலத்தில் சூரியன் நாள் முழுதும் அடிவானத்துக்குக் கீழேயே இருக்கும்.சூரிய வீதிக்குச் சார்பாகப் புவியின் அச்சு 23 பாகை 27 கலை அளவு சரிந்து இருப்பதால், உயர் நிலநேர்க்கோட்டுப் பகுதிகளில், உள்ளூர் கோடை காலத்தில் சூரியன் மறைவதில்லை. நள்ளிரவுச் சூரியனின் கால அளவு துருவ வட்டத்தில் ஒரு நாள் தொடக்கம் துருவத்தில் ஏறத்தாழ ஆறு மாதங்கள் வரை மாறுகிறது. துருவத்துக்கு அண்மையிலான நிலநேர்க்கோட்டுப் பகுதிகளில் சூரியன் அடிவானத்துக்கு மேலிருக்கும் காலம் ஆர்க்டிக் வட்டத்திலும், அண்டார்க்டிக் வட்டத்திலும் 20 மணி நேரத்தில் தொடங்கி வட, தென் துருவங்களில் 186 நாட்களாக உள்ளது. துருவங்களில் ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் சூரியன் ஒரேயொரு முறை எழுந்து ஒரேயொரு முறை மட்டுமே மறைகிறது.                     "},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Чыйырдыга каңгайдын Кара мергени аткан жолборстун жүрөгүн алып келип берген жылкычыа) Бадалбай б) Болотбайв) Акбалта г) Байжигит","answer":"а) Бадалбай "},{"question":"په ارواپوهنه کې د طبیعت - تغذیه فشارونه چیرته دي، او دا څنګه د انسان په پرمختګ اغیزه کوي؟","answer":"د طبیعت - تغذیه بحث په ارواپوهنه کې یوه مرکزي مسله ده چې د انسان پرمختګ او چلند کې د جینیات (طبیعت) او چاپیریال (تغذیه) نسبي ونډې معاینه کوي. دا بحث تر هغه حده پورې اړه لري چې جینیاتي عوامل او بیولوژیکي وړاندیزونه د چاپیریال اغیزې په مقابل کې د یو فرد د شخصیت، هوښیارتیا او چلند مختلف اړخونه جوړوي. پوهان عموما موافق دي چې طبیعت او پالنه دواړه د انسان په پرمختګ کې مهم رول لوبوي. جینیات د اشخاصو په میراث کې د وړاندیزونو او امکاناتو سره مرسته کوي، په اړخونو اغیزه کوي لکه مزاج او ځینې ادراکي وړتیاوې. له بلې خوا، د چاپیریال عوامل، په شمول د پالنې، کلتور، او د ژوند تجربې، د دې میراثي ځانګړتیاوو بڼه او تعدیل.د طبیعت - پالنې بحث اغیزه د رواني اختلالاتو، تعلیمي ستراتیژیو، او حتی عامه پالیسۍ په اړه زموږ پوهه ته پراختیا ورکوي. د جینیات او چاپیریال تر مینځ د تعامل پیژندل د ارواپوهانو سره مرسته کوي د ځانګړو اړتیاو سره د اشخاصو لپاره مداخلې تنظیم کړي ، که د رواني روغتیا ، تعلیم یا ټولنیز ملاتړ شرایطو کې وي."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Gdzie znajduje się Małopolska?","answer":"Odpowiedź: Małopolska to województwo oraz kraina historyczna Polski, obejmująca obecnie południowo-wschodnią część kraju, w górnym i częściowo środkowym dorzeczu Wisły oraz w dorzeczu górnej Warty. Stolicą Małopolski jest Kraków."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'keras hati'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud 1. Terus berusaha dan tidak mudah putus asa. 2. Degil dan tidak mahu mendengar nasihat orang."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'buang sial'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berbuat sesuatu untuk menghilangkan malang. Contoh ayat: Kebiasaan penduduk di situ akan mengadakan adat mandi bunga sebagai usaha buang sial."},{"question":"من هو أول شهيد في غزوة بدر الكبرى ؟","answer":" عمير بن الوقاص"},{"question":"Quem é o deus dos mares?","answer":"Poseidon."},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਵਾਕਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਨਾਂਵ ਚੁਣੋ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਵੀ ਦੱਸੋ(ਉ) ਜਮਾਤ ਵਿਚ ਤੀਹ ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਬੈਠੇ ਹਨ ।(ਅ) ਬਜ਼ਾਰ ਜਾਓ ਤੇ ਸਰੋਂ ਦਾ ਤੇਲ ਲਿਆਓ ।","answer":"ਉੱਤਰ(ਉ) ਜਮਾਤ - ਇਕੱਠਵਾਚਕ ਨਾਂਵ      ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ - ਆਮ ਨਾਂਵ (ਅ) ਬਜ਼ਾਰ - ਇਕੱਠਵਾਚਕ  ਨਾਂਵ        ਸਰੋਂ - ਖਾਸ ਨਾਂਵ       ਤੇਲ - ਆਮ ਨਾਂਵ "},{"question":"السؤال: من من أمهات المؤمنين كانت تلقب بأم المساكين؟","answer":"الإجابة: زينب بنت خزيمة"},{"question":"أكمل هذه الجملة: عرفان باتان ؛ من مواليد في فادودارا، هو شقيق اللاعب يوسف باتان، هو مُدرب ولاعب كريكت هندي سابق شارك في","answer":"كأس العالم للكريكيت 2007. وكان عضوا في فريق الهند الذي فاز في موسم كريكت توينتي 20 عام 2007م."},{"question":"Эл мунун себебин түшүнө албай, бир күнү: «Каным, эмне үчүн казынага кирип ыйлап чыгасыз?» — деп сурап калышты.Ошондо кан: «Казынада көп дүнүйө бар, суйсалган түлкү ичиктер бар, жыйылган атилес, шайы бар, алтын, күмүш баары бар, ошонун ичинде менин койчу убагымда кийген, колго алгысыз жыртык жамаачылуу эски кийимим да бар, мен ошону көрүп ыйлап жүрөмүн»,- деди.Суроо: Койчу казынага киргенинде эмне себептен ыйлап жүргөн экен?","answer":"Жооп: Себеби, казынада толгон дүйнө-мүлктүн арасында, ал койчуман кезинде, жакыр кезинде кийип жүргөн, эски, жамаачылуу кийими дагы бар экен, ошону көргөнүндө ыйлап жүргөн экен"},{"question":"ประเทศไทยช่วงเช้าเคารพธงชาติเมื่อไร","answer":"เวลา 8:00 นาฬิกา เป็นเวลาเคารพธงชาติช่วงเช้าของประเทศไทย"},{"question":"මහා පන්ථක මහ රහතන්වහන්සේ , ගෞතම බුදුසසුනේ ලබා සිටි \\" අග්‍ර තනතුර \\" කුමක්ද ?","answer":"මහා පන්ථක මහ රහතන්වහන්සේ , ගෞතම බුදුසසුනේ ලබා  සිටි \\" අග්‍ර තනතුර \\"  අරූපධ්‍යාන ලාභී භික්ෂූන් අතරින් අග්‍ර තනතුර"},{"question":"வினா : உலகிலேயே அதிக அளவிலான படங்கள் தயாரிக்கும் நாடு எது?","answer":"விடை : இந்தியா"},{"question":" Inona no hitan'i Rosalind Franklin momba ny firafitry ny ADN?","answer":"Nanao asa lehibe i Rosalind Franklin tamin'ny fampiasana diffraction X-ray mba handinihana ny firafitry ny ADN, manome fampahalalana fototra momba ny fahitana ny helice roa sosona nataon'i Watson sy Crick."},{"question":"Gönül kelimesi nasıl yazılır?","answer":"Hem sosyal medyada hem de gündelik yaşantıda kullanılan gönül kelimesi, uzun yıllardan beri dilimizdedir. Türk Dil Kurumu'na (TDK) göre farklı anlamları olan gönül kelimesi, Türkçe'de tek başına ya da çeşitli cümleler eşliğinde kullanılabilir."},{"question":"En çok Alevi köyü nerede?","answer":"Örneğin Türkiye'de en çok alevi köyü bulunan Sivas'ta 489′u Alevi, 45′i karışık olmak üzere 534 adet alevi yerleşim yeri bulunduğu belirtilmektedir.[3] Ayrıca alevi forum sitesinde bilgi bulunmayan bazı iller için ise diğer (http://www.piryolu.com/, www.zohreanaforum.com gibi) internet siteleri taranmıştır."},{"question":"  ராக்கெட்டுகளில் எரிபொருளாகப் பயன்படும் சேர்மம்?","answer":" ஹைட்ரஜன் ராக்கெட்டுகளில் எரிபொருளாகப் பயன்படுத்த படுகிறது."},{"question":"\\" හමාර බණවර \\"පදය පහදන්න.","answer":"පරිත්‍රාණ ධර්ම දේශනයක්(පිරිත් සජ්ඣායනය) බණ වර හතරකින් යුක්ත වෙයි. මේ එක් බණවරකට අක්ෂර 8000ක් ඇතැයිද සතර බණවර අක්ෂර 32000 කින් සමන්විත බව ද කියැවෙයි.*දසදම්ම සූත්‍රයේ සිට ධජග්ග සූත්‍රය දක්වා පළමු බණවරයි.*මහාකස්සප ථේර බොජ්ඣංගයේ සිට ඉසිගිලි සූත්‍රය දක්වා දෙවන බණවරයි.*ආටානාටිය 1 හා 2 සමග තවත් සූත්‍ර දේශනා කිහිපයකින් හමාර බණ වර සමන්විත වෙයි.ඉන්පසු සෙත් පිරිත් සජ්ඣායනයෙන් හා පළාත් බඳව සෙත් පතන ගාථා සජ්ඣායනා හා ආශිර්වාද වත් පිළිවෙත් පවත්වා පිරිත් දේශනාව නිමා වෙයි."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la teoría de la evolución de Charles Darwin?","answer":"La teoría de la evolución de Charles Darwin, publicada en su libro \\"El origen de las especies\\" en 1859, propone que las especies cambian a lo largo del tiempo a través de un proceso llamado selección natural. Darwin argumentó que las poblaciones de organismos producen más descendientes de los que pueden sobrevivir debido a la competencia por recursos limitados. Los individuos con características favorables para su entorno tienen más probabilidades de sobrevivir y reproducirse, transmitiendo esas características a la siguiente generación. Con el tiempo, esto conduce a la adaptación y diversificación de las especies."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన తాత్పర్యం వచ్చేలాగా ఒక పద్యాన్ని రాయండి:అపుడు మారీచుడు ఓ ప్రభువైన రావణా ! ఈ పుష్పకము కుబేరుని ఎక్కించుకొని తప్ప కైలాసమున ప్రవేశింపదేమో ! అతడే కోపముతో దీనిని ఆపేశాడేమో ! అన్నాడు. ఆ సమయమున వికట రూపమున ఉన్న, తేజోవంతమైన ముఖము కలిగిన, పొట్టివాడుగా యున్న, బలవంతుడైన నందీశ్వరుడు ఆ రావణునితో ఇలా అన్నాడు.","answer":"అల మారీచుఁడు దేవ వింటె యిది యక్షాధ్యక్షునిన్ గాని యన్యులం జైనూని చరింపదో యతఁడు క్రోధోద్రేకి యై నిల్వెనోతెలియుండం చనునంతలో వికటుండే దీప్తాస్యుండైకుజ్జుఁడై బల ధుర్యుండగు నంది యందుఁగని యబ్పేలస్త్యుతో నిట్లనున్."},{"question":"Кыргызстан мамлекетинин президенти Садыр Жапаровдун туулган күнү качан?","answer":"Бүгүн 6-декабрь 2023-жыл КР президенти Садыр Жапаров 55 жашка чыгып жатат.Садыр Жапаров кол алдындагыларга туулган күнүнө белек берүүгө тыюу салды. Бул тууралуу Эдил Байсалов  маалымат борбордо сүйлөп жатып айтты.“Президент баарыбызга белек берүүгө, мактап-жактоого тыюу салды. Абдан жөнөкөй адам. Үч жыл аралыгында Жапаров элибиз аны президент кылып шайлап жаңылбаганын далилдеди. Садыр Жапаров кимдир бирөөгө жагышы мүмкүн, айрымдарга жакпашы ыктымал, бирок баарыбыз ага ийгилик каалашыбыз керек. Анткени анын ийгилиги — бул жалпы элдин жана мамлекеттин ийгилиги”, — деп айтты Эдил Байсалов."},{"question":"Me dê uma questão de trivia sobre o seguinte tema: história. ","answer":"O sismógrafo foi inventado por qual Dinastia chinesa? Han"},{"question":"Iza no sangany amin' ny sekoly katolika Zezoita eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny kolejy Masina Misely Amparibe na hoe \\"Collège Saint Michel Amparibe\\" no sangany amin' ny sekoly katolika Zezoita eto Madagasikara."},{"question":"问题：铅笔刀是否有特殊的安全设计？","answer":"答案：一些铅笔刀可能具有防护盖或其他安全设计，以防止意外划伤或割伤。"},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் மிகப்பெரிய மாநிலம் எது?","answer":"ராஜஸ்தான்."},{"question":"रानी लक्ष्मी बाई","answer":"रानी लक्ष्मीबाई एक महान वीरांगना थी उन्होंने अपने देश के लिए बहुत से महान कार्य किए हैं, इनका जन्म वाराणसी में 19 नवंबर 1828 को हुआ था। रानी लक्ष्मी बाई के बचपन का नाम मणिकर्णिका था लेकिन उन्हें प्यार से मनु कहा जाता था।उनके पिता का नाम मोरोपंत तांबे और माता का नाम भागीरथी तांबे था। रानी लक्ष्मीबाई बचपन से युद्ध कला में निपुण थी, ये नाना जी पेशवा राव की मुहबोली बहन थी, इनका बचपन इन्हीं के साथ खेलते कूदते हुए बीता है और इनका पालन-पोषण बिठूर में हुआ था।बचपन में ही रानी लक्ष्मी बाई के माता का देहांत हो गया जिसकी वजह से उनका जीवन वीर योद्धा पुरुषों के बीच बीता और उन्होंने घुड़सवारी और युद्ध कला की शिक्षा प्राप्त की और बचपन में ही रानी लक्ष्मीबाई बहुत ही ज्यादा अच्छे घुड़सवारी और युद्ध कर लेती थी।रानी लक्ष्मीबाई का विवाह राजा गंगाधर राव के साथ उन 1842 ईसवी में हुआ था, विवाह के बाद ही इनका नाम रानी लक्ष्मीबाई पड़ा और 9 वर्ष बाद रानी लक्ष्मीबाई को एक लड़का हुआ जो कि 3 महीने में उसकी मृत्यु हो गई, इसके बाद गंगाधर राव ने 5 वर्षीय दामोदर राव को गोद लिया और पुत्र वियोग में उनकी दशा खराब होती गई और अगले ही दिन उनकी भी मृत्यु हो गई।जब दामोदर राव को गोद लिया जा रहा था तब अंग्रेज का एक अधिकारी वहां पर उपस्थित था लेकिन राजा की मृत्यु होने के बाद अंग्रेजी सरकार कहती है कि जिस राज्य का कोई उत्तराधिकारी और राजा नहीं होता है तो वह राज्य हमारी अधिकार में आता है।जब अंग्रेजों ने रानी लक्ष्मीबाई को झांसी छोड़कर जाने के लिए कहा तो रानी लक्ष्मीबाई ने साफ शब्दों में उन्हें कह दिया कि ” झांसी मेरी है और मैं इसे अपने प्राण रहते कभी नहीं छोड़ सकती “इसके बाद अंग्रेजों ने झासी को मिलाने की बहुत कोशिश की लेकिन रानी लक्ष्मी बाई उनके हर वार को ना काम करती रही इसके बाद जब अंग्रेजों ने अपनी सेना से बहुत बड़ा हमला किया तब भी रानी लक्ष्मीबाई अपनी जमीन को छोड़कर नहीं हटी वह डट कर अंग्रेजों का सामना किया और अंग्रेजों ने रानी लक्ष्मीबाई को कमजोर समझा लेकिन रानी लक्ष्मीबाई ने अंग्रेजों के दांत खट्टे कर दिए।रानी लक्ष्मी बाई युद्ध के मैदान में अपने घोड़े की लगाम को अपने दातों में दबा कर दोनों हाथों में तलवार लेकर अंग्रेजों के सर धड़ से अलग कर रही थी, और एक समय बाद उनका घोड़ा भी घायल हो गया और उसने युद्ध में वीरगति को प्राप्त की, लक्ष्मीबाई के पास तीन घोड़े भी थे, जिनका नाम सारंगी, बादल और पवन था।रानी लक्ष्मी बाई के कमर पर एक राइफल की गोली लगी थी जिसमें से लगातार खून बह रहा था और उसके बाद उनके सर पर भी बहुत गहरा चोट लगा था जिससे उनके सर से लगातार खून बह रहा था इसके कारण वे अपनी आंखें नहीं खोल पा रही थी।इसके बाद उनके सेना के कुछ जवानों ने उन्हें पास के एक मंदिर में ले गए जहां पर एक पुजारी जी लक्ष्मी बाई के सूखे होठों पर गंगाजल का पानी रखा और उधर दूसरी तरफ अंग्रेज झांसी के सभी सेनाओं को खत्म करते हुए आगे बढ़ रहे थे।उन्हें इतनी ज्यादा चोट लगी थी कि वह सही से बोल भी नहीं पा रही थी उन्होंने अपने दामोदर को सैनिकों को सबसे बड़ा दिन में इसे आपको शक्ति हुए हैं आप छावनी ले जाओ, दामोदर के साथ उन्होंने अपने गले का एक बार उतार कर उन्हे दे दिया।इसके बाद उन्होंने सैनिकों से कहा कि अंग्रेजों को मेरा शरीर नहीं मिलना चाहिए यह उनके आखिरी शब्द थे इसके बाद रानी लक्ष्मीबाई वीरगति को प्राप्त हुए और सैनिकों ने पास में रखे सभी लकड़ियों को इकट्ठा किया और रानी लक्ष्मीबाई के शव को अग्नि को समर्पित कर दिया।रानी लक्ष्मीबाई सभी स्त्री जाति के लिए एक प्रेरणा है उन्होंने अपने देश के लिए बहुत बड़ी कुर्बानी दी, और हमें इनकी वीरता से कुछ सीखना चाहिए।"},{"question":"ലോകത്ത് എത്ര ഭൂഖണ്ഡങ്ങളുണ്ട്?","answer":"ലോകത്ത് ഏഴ് ഭൂഖണ്ഡങ്ങളുണ്ട്: ആഫ്രിക്ക, അന്റാർട്ടിക്ക, ഏഷ്യ, യൂറോപ്പ്, വടക്കേ അമേരിക്ക, ഓസ്ട്രേലിയ (അല്ലെങ്കിൽ ഓഷ്യാനിയ), തെക്കേ അമേരിക്ക."},{"question":"Có 315 viên sỏi được chia thành ba phần, số viên sỏi ở các phần lần lượt là 81, 115 và 119.Mỗi bước, ta có thể gom một số phần lại thành một phần hoặc chia một phần có số chẵn viên sỏi thành hai phần có số viên sỏi bằng nhau.Hỏi, sau một số hữu hạn bước thì có thể thu được 315 phần, mỗi phần một viên sỏi hay không? Vì sao?","answer":"Ban đầu, mỗi phần có số lẻ các viên sỏi nên chắc chắn ở bước đầu tiên, phải gom một số phần lại làm một. Nếu gom cả ba phần lại làm một thì sẽ không thể thực hiện được thêm bước nào, do đó chỉ có thể gom hai phần lại.Nếu ở bước đầu tiên, hai phần gom lại là 81 và 115 thì sau bước này, ta có hai phần với số sỏi ở mỗi phần lần lượt là 196 và 119. Do 196 và 119 cùng chia hết cho 7 nên kể từ đây, dù ta có thực hiện gom lại hay chia ra thì số sỏi ở mỗi phần luôn chia hết cho 7. Và vì vậy, chắc chắn không thể thu được 315 phần, mỗi phần một viên sỏi.Tương tự, nếu hai phần gom lại là 81 và 119 thì sau đó, số sỏi ở mỗi phần luôn chia hết cho 5; còn nếu hai phần gom lại là 115 và 119 thì sau đó, số sỏi ở mỗi phần luôn chia hết cho 9. Do đó, chắc chắn không thể thu được 315 phần, mỗi phần một viên sỏi.Tóm lại, dù thực hiện thế nào đi chăng nữa, ta cũng không thể thu được 315 phần, mỗi phần một viên sỏi."},{"question":"Magbigay ng Python code kung saan inaalam kung ang isang numero ay positibo o negatibo.","answer":"Ang sumusunod na Python code ay inaalam kung ang isang numero ay positibo o negatibo:num = float(input(\\"Magbigay ng numero: \\"))if num > 0:   print(\\"Ang numero ay positibo.\\")elif num == 0:   print(\\"Zero\\")else:   print(\\"Ang numero ay negatibo.\\")"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గేయ పంక్తులకి భావం రాయండి:ఏది తక్కువయిననూ ఓచెల్లి నిన్నేడిపిస్తరమ్మానీ మొఖం పాడుగాను నువ్వేమి తెచ్చినావంటరమ్మానిను చంపి వంటింట్లో కాలి చచ్చినవంటు పేపర్లకిస్తరమ్మ ఆడ ”","answer":" ఓ చెల్లెమ్మా! నీవు తెచ్చిన కట్నంలో ఏ కొద్దిగా తగ్గినా నీ మొఖం పాడుగాను, నువ్వేం తెచ్చావని అంటారు. నిన్ను వాళ్ళే చంపేసి వంటింట్లో చచ్చిందని వార్తాపత్రికలకు ఇస్తారని నిసార్ హెచ్చరించాడు."},{"question":"கேள்வி :  பின்வரும் தொடர்களில் பிழை நீக்கி எழுதுக :அ) மதீனா சிறந்த இசைவல்லுநர் வேண்டும்.ஆ) நல்ல தமிழுக்கு எழுதுவோம்.இ) பவள விழிதான் பரிசு உரியவள்.ஈ) துன்பத்தால் பொறுத்துக் கொள்பவனே வெற்றி பெறுவான்.உ) குழலியும் பாடத் தெரியும்.","answer":"பதில் :  பிழை நீக்கிய தொடர்கள்:அ) மதீனா சிறந்த இசைவல்லுநராக வேண்டும்.ஆ) நல்ல தமிழில் எழுதுவோம்.இ) பவளவிழிதான் பரிசுக்கு உரியவள்.ஈ) துன்பத்தைப் பொறுத்துக் கொள்பவன் தான் வெற்றியைப் பெறுவான்.உ) குழலிக்கும் பாடத் தெரியும்"},{"question":"Inona ny hatao hoe vintana ara-kevitra?","answer":"Ara-kevitra, ny hatao hoe vintana dia hery tsy hita maso sy tsy azo tsapain-tanana, mifehy sy mamolavola ny fiainan'olombelona. Araky ny finoan'ny Ntaolo dia misy ny efa voapetraka hifanambina ny zav-boaary eto ambonin'ny tany. Hery mandahatra ny zavatra rehetra ny vintana ary tsy azo hiolahana. "},{"question":"Pedal mana yang anda guna apabila menghentikan kenderaan?A. Pedal brek diikuti dengan klacB. Pedal klac diikuti dengan brekC. Pedal pemecut diikuti dengan klac","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A. Pedal brek diikuti dengan klac"},{"question":"Isivakalisi 1: IBorbon County, eKansas, eUSA yidolophu yaseTimberhill Township. Isivakalisi 2: IBorbon County, eKansas, eUSA yidolophu yaseTimberhill Township. Umbuzo: Ingaba isivakalisi 1 nesivakalisi 2 zithetha into enye? Ewe okanye Hayi?","answer":"Ewe"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: \\"Từ năm 2015 đến nay, XSKT Sóc Trăng đã cùng Báo Thanh Niên chuyển trao hơn 40.000 quyển tập giúp đỡ kịp thời những học sinh có hoàn cảnh khó khăn ở nhiều tỉnh, thành. Ông Trần Hữu Nghị, Chủ tịch UBND P.An Phú (Q.Ninh Kiều, TP.Cần Thơ), cho rằng sự hỗ trợ thiết thực nêu trên đã góp phần giảm bớt khó khăn cho nhiều hộ dân, đảm bảo mọi trẻ em trong độ tuổi đều được đến trường.\\"","answer":"Nghĩa cử cao đẹp và sự tận tâm dành cho công tác an sinh xã hội của quý cơ quan (Báo Thanh Niên, XSKT Sóc Trăng) rất đáng trân trọng. Ông Lê Văn Khanh, Chủ tịch Công ty XSKT Sóc Trăng, cho biết năm 2021 dù phải đối mặt với khó khăn của đại dịch Covid-19 nhưng XSKT Sóc Trăng vẫn tích cực đóng góp kinh phí cho quỹ vắc xin phòng chống Covid-19, hỗ trợ người bán vé số lẻ trên địa bàn tỉnh Sóc Trăng, xây nhà đại đoàn kết, nhà tình thương, tài trợ học bổng, tặng tập giúp học sinh nghèo với tổng số tiền trên 30 tỉ đồng."},{"question":"Me kalmar: \\"woman\\" ke nufi a harshen Hausa?","answer":" Kalmar \\"woman\\" na nufin \\"mace\\" a harshen Hausa"},{"question":"\\"සාර්ථක\\" වචනේ තේරුමට අර්ථ සහගත කියන දේත ඇතුලත් ද?","answer":"හින්දිවලින් (තත්සම) සාර්ථක් කියන්නේ අර්ථ සහිත කියන එක. සංස්කෘතවලත් එහෙම ද දන්නේ නෑ.අපි වෙනත් තේරුම්වලින් භාවිත කරන තව වචන තියෙනවා.සාදර = ආදරය සහිතමෙතන ආදරය කියන්නේ love නෙවෙයි, ගෞරවය. අපිත් සාදර ආරාධනා කරනවා තේරුම නොදැන."},{"question":"Η Κιμ Νιούμαν το αποκάλεσε \\" ψυχρό αλλά έξυπνο, ανατρεπτικό ντεμπούτο \\" για την \\" Αυτοκρατορία \\". Η Κιμ Νιούμαν το αποκάλεσε \\" έξυπνο, ανατρεπτικό αλλά μάλλον ψυχρό ντεμπούτο \\" για την \\" Αυτοκρατορία \\". Ερώτηση: Η πρόταση 1 και η πρόταση 2 εκφράζουν το ίδιο νόημα; - Ναι ή όχι;","answer":"Όχι."},{"question":"கீதாஞ்சலி என்னும் நூலை எழுதியவர் யார்?","answer":"விடை: இரவீந்தரநாத் தாகூர்"},{"question":"\\"ابتسم لحياتك وابتسم لكل ما هو حولك... وفكر في كُل ما يسعدك، ولا تفكر في أمر يقلقك؛ فالأمل دواء والقلق عناء والتفاؤل رجاء\\" ماهي مشاعر هذه التغريدة؟","answer":"مشاعر التغريدة السابقة تعكس روحًا إيجابية وتحفيزية. النص يحث على الابتسام والتفاؤل في مواجهة الحياة، ويشير إلى أهمية التفكير في الأشياء الإيجابية وتجنب التفكير في الأمور التي قد تسبب القلق. يظهر التركيز على الأمل كدواء للصعوبات والتحفيز للاستمتاع بالحياة بإيجابية."},{"question":"Budapest moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Budapest moy péeyu réwum Hongrie"},{"question":"السؤال: فازت ألمانيا بكأس العالم أربع مرات، ولكن كم مرة فعلت ذلك كدولة موحدة؟","answer":"الإجابة: مرة واحدة (2014)"},{"question":"Soalan: Bilakah Cat and Mouse Act diperkenalkan? Jawapan:","answer":"Tahun 1913"},{"question":"Cuál es la pregunta correcta a la siguiente pregunta: ¿Para cuántos equipos ha jugado Travis Kelce?","answer":"La respuesta correcta a la pregunta es 1"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Phó giám đốc Công an kể phút đấu trí với nghi phạm cướp tiệm vàng","answer":"Chiều 31/7, Công an tỉnh TT-Huế đã có thông tin ban đầu vụ nghi phạm dùng súng AK, nổ súng cướp tiệm vàng trước cổng chợ Đông Ba (TP Huế). Theo đó, vào khoảng 12h45 chiều nay, một đối tượng sử dụng súng AK bất ngờ xông vào tiệm vàng Hoàng Đức và Thái Lợi tại chợ Đông Ba nổ súng chỉ thiên, uy hiếp chủ tiệm để cướp vàng. Nhận tin báo, lãnh đạo Công an tỉnh TT-Huế đã trực tiếp chỉ đạo các lực lượng chức năng triển khai truy bắt đối tượng. Xác định đối tượng mang theo vũ khí, có thể gây nguy hiểm trong quá trình truy bắt, Công an tỉnh TT-Huế đã điều lính bắn tỉa và xe bọc thép tới hiện trường. Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn – Phó giám đốc Công an tỉnh TT-Huế cho biết, hiện trường xảy ra vụ án là khu vực trung tâm thành phố, đông dân; do vậy, để đảm bảo an toàn, lực lượng công an đã tìm cách hướng đối tượng di chuyển đến nhà Lục Giác - Công viên Trịnh Công Sơn. Lúc này, thông qua nhận diện, lực lượng chức năng xác định nghi phạm là Ngô Văn Quốc (SN 1984, trú thị xã Hương Thuỷ, TT-Huế). Ngoài lực lượng nghiệp vụ tại hiện trường, Công an tỉnh TT-Huế cũng cử tổ công tác tiếp cận, tìm hiểu thân nhân của nghi phạm. Theo cơ quan công an, khi bị vây bắt, đối tượng có biểu hiện kích động, muốn... tự sát. Đại tá Phạm Văn Toàn - Trưởng phòng Cảnh sát hình sự và một số cán bộ công an trực tiếp trò chuyện, thuyết phục Quốc buông vũ khí đầu hàng. Tuy nhiên, đối tượng đã yêu cầu được nói chuyện với Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn - Phó GĐ Công an tỉnh TT-Huế. Chia sẻ với P.V VietNamNet, Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn cho biết, xác định đối tượng mang vũ khí nóng và có thể chống trả hoạt động vây bắt, lãnh đạo công an tỉnh chỉ đạo các đơn vị nghiệp vụ cẩn trọng, an toàn và không gây kích động cho đối tượng. \\"Khi tiếp cận, tôi phân tích cho Quốc biết hành vi vi phạm pháp luật của mình, không nên lún sâu vào vi phạm mà phải nghĩ đến bản thân, người nhà. Mất khoảng 20 phút để tôi trò chuyện, thuyết phục nghi phạm buông vũ khí. Quốc chỉ đồng ý hạ vũ khí và để lực lượng công an bắt giữ khi đích thân tôi trực tiếp dẫn giải, bảo vệ y rời khỏi hiện trường\\", Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn chia sẻ. Cũng theo Phó giám đốc Công an tỉnh TT-Huế, ngay khi đạt được thoả thuận về việc đảm bảo an toàn cho nghi phạm, đối tượng Quốc buông vũ khí và bị lực lượng chức năng ập đến bắt giữ. Tại hiện trường, Công an tỉnh TT-Huế thu giữ một khẩu súng AK47, một hộp tiếp đạn và nhiều trang sức bằng vàng."},{"question":"Ahoana no azo antoka fa hahafahanao mamorona loharano mifandraika amin'ny fampiasana ny teknolojia?","answer":"Mifandray amin'ny teknolojia vaovao, mitondra fampahalalana, ary manomezana toe-tsaina momba ny fampiasana dia hafatra mahavariana amin'ny mamorona loharano."},{"question":"أريد أن أعلِّم صفي عن موضوع اتفاقية سايكس بيكو. هل يمكنك أن تكتب لي مقالاً يمكنني أن أعطيهم لقراءته كواجب منزلي؟ يجب أن تجيب متى تم وضع اتفاقية سايكس بيكو؟ ، وتكون باللغة العربية الفصحى لو سمحت.","answer":"اتفاقية سايكس بيكو  عام 1916، كانت اتفاقا وتفاهمًا سريًا بين فرنسا والمملكة المتحدة بمصادقة من الإمبراطورية الروسية على اقتسام منطقة الهلال الخصيب بين فرنسا وبريطانيا لتحديد مناطق النفوذ في غرب آسيا بعد تهاوي الدولة العثمانية، المسيطرة على هذه المنطقة، في الحرب العالمية الأولى."},{"question":"¿Cuál es el tipo de cáncer de pulmón más común en los Estados Unidos de América?","answer":"Si bien hay tipos de cáncer que son más comunes en hombres o mujeres, el tipo de cáncer más común en general es el cáncer de pulmón, que representa alrededor del 30% de los casos reportados en dicho país."},{"question":"O que são outliers em estatística?","answer":"Outliers são valores atípicos ou extremos em um conjunto de dados que se afastam significativamente da maioria dos outros valores. Eles podem distorcer as análises estatísticas e, por isso, geralmente são identificados e tratados separadamente."},{"question":"Which was the first radio service in Asia?","answer":"The first radio service in Asia was established in India. It began as a private venture known as the \\"Indian Broadcasting Company (IBC)\\" and was initiated in Bombay (now Mumbai) on July 23, 1927. This was followed by a station in Calcutta (now Kolkata), which started broadcasting later that year. However, the IBC was not financially successful and was dissolved in 1930.Subsequently, the government of British India took over the broadcasting facilities and started the \\"Indian State Broadcasting Service\\" on April 1, 1930, which was later renamed \\"All India Radio (AIR)\\" in 1936. AIR played a significant role in developing radio broadcasting in India and across Asia."},{"question":"මූල්‍යමය වශයෙන් දුෂ්කරතා ඇති අයගෙන් මූල්‍ය උපදෙස් ගැනීමෙන් වැළකී සිටීම නුවණට හුරුද?","answer":"හොද ආර්ථික ශක්තියක් හෝ විශේෂඥ දැනුමක් ඇති පුද්ගලයන්ගෙන් උපදෙස් ලබාගැනීම අතිශයින්ම ප්‍රයෝජනවත් විය හැකි බව සත්‍යයක් වුවද, මූල්‍යමය වශයෙන් දුෂ්කරතා ඇති අයෙකුගෙන් ලද උපදෙස් සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කිරීම සැමවිටම හොඳම ප්‍රවේශය නොවිය හැකිය. මූල්‍ය දුෂ්කරතාවලට මුහුණ දෙන පුද්ගලයින්ට ඔවුන්ගේ අත්දැකීම් සහ වැරදි මත පදනම්ව වටිනා අවබෝධයක් ලබා දිය හැකි අතර, නොකළ යුතු දේ මොනවාදැයි ඉස්මතු කල හැක. විවිධ ප්‍රභවයන්ගෙන් උපදෙස් සලකා බැලීම සහ ඔබේ මූල්‍ය තත්ත්වයට එහි අදාළත්වය මත පදනම්ව එය ඇගයීම ඉතා වැදගත් වේ."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'malu bertanya sesat jalan, malu mengayuh perahu hanyut'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kalau tidak berusaha, tentulah susah dan kalau segan bertanya, akan membuat kesilapan"},{"question":" Sheeg Labada Degmo Uu Ka Bilowdo Xarafka (J) Uu Maro Wabiga Juba?","answer":"Waa Degmooyinka Jilib Iyo Jamaame, Labadaba Waa Uu Maraa Wabiga Juba MahadCelin Balaaran"},{"question":"Sử dụng tiêu đề và tóm tắt sau để viết một bài báo tối đa 500 chữ.Tiêu đề: Nga, Arab Saudi tiếp tục siết cung dầuTóm tắt: Hôm 5/11, hai nước xuất khẩu dầu hàng đầu thế giới là Nga và Arab Saudi thông báo vẫn tự nguyện giảm sản lượng đến cuối năm nay.","answer":"Reuters trích nguồn tin từ Bộ năng lượng Arab Saudi cho biết nước này vẫn sẽ giảm sản xuất thêm 1 triệu thùng một ngày, duy trì sản lượng quanh 9 triệu thùng mỗi ngày trong tháng 12. Họ lo ngại nhu cầu và tăng trưởng kinh tế sẽ gây sức ép lên thị trường dầu thô.\\"Việc giảm sản xuất tự nguyện sẽ củng cố nỗ lực của OPEC+ (Tổ chức Các nước Xuất khẩu dầu mỏ và đồng minh), nhằm hỗ trợ sự bình ổn và cân bằng của thị trường dầu\\", nguồn tin này cho biết.Cùng ngày, Phó thủ tướng Nga Alexander Novak cũng thông báo tiếp tục giảm xuất khẩu 300.000 thùng một ngày với dầu thô và các sản phẩm từ dầu. Nga đã duy trì chính sách này từ tháng 8.Một năm qua, OPEC+ duy trì giảm sản xuất để hỗ trợ thị trường. Tháng 10/2022, OPEC+ tuyên bố giảm sản xuất 2 triệu thùng một ngày - lớn nhất từ khi đại dịch xuất hiện.Tháng 5, Arab Saudi dẫn đầu một nhóm nhỏ thông báo tự nguyện cắt giảm thêm 1 triệu thùng một ngày. Đến tháng 7, họ giảm thêm 1 triệu thùng nữa. Từ tháng 4, Nga cũng giảm sản xuất 500.000 thùng một ngày.Theo tính toán của hãng tư vấn Energy Aspects, chính sách siết cung đã giúp Nga và Arab Saudi có thêm hàng tỷ USD từ bán dầu trong vài tháng qua. Nguyên nhân là giá dầu tăng đủ bù cho lượng xuất khẩu giảm."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన శాస్త్రవేత్త గురించి మీకు తెలిసింది రాయండి:లియోనార్డో డావిన్సీ & స్టీఫెన్ హేల్స్","answer":"కొన్ని జంతువులలో మెదడును తొలగించినప్పటికీ ఉద్దీపనలకు ప్రతిస్పందనలను చూపించడాన్ని వీరు ఇరువురు గుర్తించారు."},{"question":"آیا واکسن آنفولانزا عوارض جانبی دارد؟","answer":"واکسن آنفولانزا هم گاهی ممکن است عوارض خفیف مانند درد و تورم موضعی یا تب های خفیف ایجاد کند. عوارض جدی‌تر عصبی و عضلانی هم بسیارنادر بوده و برگشت‌پذیر بوده و ارزش نگرانی و حتی فکر کردن ندارد. با توجه به فواید بسیار واکسن حتما تزریق واکسن را در برنامه هرساله خود قرار دهید."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:श्रोते पुसती कोण ग्रंथ । काय बोलिलें जी येथ ।श्रवण केलियानें प्राप्त । काय आहे ॥ १॥अर्थ:","answer":"ग्रंथाच्या सुरुवातीलाच श्रोते श्री सद्‌गुरू समर्थ रामदास स्वामींना विचारत आहेत की, आपण जो ग्रंथ सांगणार आहात त्याचे नाव काय आहे, यात काय सांगितले आहे आणि हा ग्रंथ श्रवण केल्याने काय लाभ होणार आहे? (१)"},{"question":"හිවලා සහ සිවලා සමාන වචනද?","answer":"ස' කරට වණ අදෙස් 'හ' කර සිංහලයේ ප්‍රසිද්ධ ය යනු කියමනකි.මෙයින් කියවෙන්නේ 'ස' යන්න වෙනුවට බොහෝ විට ' හ' අකුර භාවිත වන බව යි.උදා:- සඳ > හඳසාවා > හාවාසැක > හැක ( හැකි නො වේ)සොඳ > හොඳසොටු > හොටුසොඬ > හොඬ*සිවලා > හිවලා"},{"question":"Apakah maksud aur dengan tebing?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah memberikan pertolongan antara satu sama lain"},{"question":"Our solar system is located in which galaxy?","answer":"Our solar system is located in the Milky Way Galaxy. It orbits the galactic center at a distance of about 26,000 light-years, residing within the Orion Spur, one of the galaxy's spiral arms.The Milky Way is a majestic spiral galaxy with an estimated 100-400 billion stars, including our sun. It's truly our cosmic home! "},{"question":"Saako rauhoitettuja eläimiä pitää eläintarhassa?","answer":"Rauhoitettujen eläinten pitäminen edellyttää poikkeuslupaa luonnonsuojelulain rauhoitusmääräyksistä. Elävien rauhoitettujen lintujen ja luontodirektiivin IV (a) liitteen eläinlajien (pl. riista ja rauhoittamattomat eläimet) hallussapitoon eläintarhassa myöntää poikkeusluvan Varsinais-Suomen ELY-keskus. Muiden eläinlajien osalta poikkeusluvan myöntää se ELY-keskus, jonka alueella ko. eläintarha sijaitsee. Poikkeuslupa voidaan myöntää opetus- ja tutkimustarkoituksessa, jollei muuta tyydyttävää ratkaisua ole.Poikkeuslupia eläinten pitoon myönnetään vain sellaisille eläintarhoille, joilla on aluehallintoviraston myöntämä eläintarhalupa."},{"question":" Maxay kala yihiin tiirarka islaamku","answer":" Tiirarka islaamku waxay ka koobanyihiin;"},{"question":"أكمل النص التالي: احتلت إسرائيل جزيرة تيران عام 1956 ضمن الأحداث المرتبطة بالعدوان الثلاثي","answer":"ومرة أخرى في الأحداث المرتبطة بحرب 1967 وانسحبت منها عام 1982 ضمن اتفاقية كامب ديفيد. بعد الانسحاب الإسرائيلي عادت الجزيرة إلى الحماية والإدارة المصرية ويتواجد بها حالياً قوات دولية متعددة الجنسيات بحسب إتفاقية كامب ديفيد ومعاهدة السلام المصرية الإسرائيلية."},{"question":"Qual è la categoria a cui appartiene la seguente domanda?\\"Qual è il terzo libro della serie Twilight?\\"","answer":"La domanda appartiene alla categoria \\"Libri\\"."},{"question":"Numune Hastanesinin Başhekimi kimdir?","answer":"HAYDARPAŞA NUMUNE EĞİTİM VE ARAŞTIRMA HASTANESİProf.Dr. Aytekin KAYMAKCI 1966 tarihinde Konya'da doğdu. 2019 yılının 22 Mayıs tarihinden itibaren SBÜ İstanbul Haydarpaşa Numune Eğitim ve Araştırma Hastanesi Başhekimi olarak devam etmektedir."},{"question":"Nitori owo Tinubu, ẹgbẹ APC ati PDP Ọṣun sọko ọrọ sira wọn ","answer":"Ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC nipinlẹ Ọṣun, ti sọ pe ti Gomina Ademọla Adeleke ko ba le kede eto to ni gẹgẹ bii palietiifu fawọn araalu, ko bojumu kijọba rẹ tun pa ika mọ bìliọnu meji Naira tijọba apapọ fi ranṣẹ.Alaga ẹgbẹ naa, Sooko Tajudeen Lawal, sọ nipasẹ alakooso iroyin wọn, Oloye Kọla Ọlabisi, pe o jẹ ohun to buru ki ijọba ipinlẹ kankan lorileede yii maa huwa to le mu ki awọn araalu korira ijọba apapọ.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, ohun ti ko ṣee gbọ ni pe ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun ko biliọnu meji Naira tijọba apapọ fi ranṣẹ gẹgẹ bii palietiifu fawọn araalu pamọ lati oṣu meji sẹyin ti wọn ti gba a.O ni ko si awijare kankan tijọba Adeleke ni lori ohun ti wọn ṣe yii nitori ṣe ni wọn mọ-ọn-mọ n fara ni awọn araalu, ko si sẹni to mọ boya wọn n reti ki awọn eeyan bẹrẹ si i ku ki wọn too pin owo naa.Ṣugbọn nigba to n fesi, alaga ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Ọnarebu Sunday Bisi, sọ pe alainitiju lẹgbẹ APC, nitori ko yẹ ki wọn lẹnu ọrọ mọ pẹlu ọgbun gbese ti wọn ti ipinlẹ Ọṣun si ki wọn too kogba wọle.Sunday Bisi ṣalaye pe ẹgbẹ PDP ki i ṣe ẹgbẹ alajẹbanu bii tiwọn. O ni adari to bọwọ fun akoyawọ ni Gomina Adeleke, o si ti ranṣẹ ọpọlọpọ nnkan to wa fun iranwọ fun awọn araalu, laipẹ ni gbogbo aye yoo si ri i.O ni awọn nnkan palietiifu naa pọ debii pe yoo lọ kaakiri tibu-tooro ipinlẹ Ọṣun, awọn ti awọn araalu si fi ibo wọn le danu nitori iwa ole wọn nikan ni wọn le maa ro pe gomina to wa lati idile olowo yoo dẹbiti aya de owo palietiifu.O kilọ fun ẹgbẹ APC Ọṣun lati dẹkun sisọ ọrọ alufansa kaakiri nipa iṣẹjọba to wa lode, nitori awọn ko ni i kuna lati gbe igbesẹ to tọ lori wọn ni ibamu pẹlu ofin lọjọ ti wọn ba tun hu iru iwa bẹẹ."},{"question":"Gần đây khi tìm hiểu về thị trường đầu tư cổ phiếu ở Việt Nam, tôi thấy có hai cách sinh lời: nhận cổ tức và bán để kiếm lời từ chênh lệch giá. Tôi thấy nhiều người khi nhắc đến đầu tư cổ phiếu đều nghĩ về việc bán lấy chênh lệch, gần như ít ai theo cách nhận cổ tức. Vì sao lại thế? Làm sao để biết bản thân phù hợp với cách đầu tư nào kể trên?","answer":"Cổ tức thường được chia dưới dạng tiền mặt, cổ phiếu tái đầu tư hoặc tài sản khác. Ở đây tôi tạm hiểu thắc mắc của bạn về nhận cổ tức dưới dạng tiền mặt, vì bạn vừa tìm hiểu về đầu tư cổ phiếu và có thể chưa có hiểu biết về những dạng cổ tức khác.Đúng là hầu hết nhà đầu tư trên thị trường thường quan tâm đến việc nhận lợi nhuận qua mua bán cổ phiếu lấy chênh lệch hơn là nhận cổ tức. Nguyên nhân chủ yếu là do bán chênh lệch cho mức sinh lợi hấp dẫn hơn.Việt Nam thường được ví là \\"con hổ mới\\" của châu Á nhờ tốc độ tăng trưởng kinh tế thần tốc. Do đó, các doanh nghiệp trong nước thường có tốc độ mở rộng quy mô lẫn kết quả kinh doanh rất ấn tượng trong những năm gần đây, một số có tốc độ tăng trưởng 30-40% mỗi năm. Kết quả kinh doanh phản ánh phần lớn vào giá cổ phiếu, khiến thị giá có thể tăng đến hơn 30% mỗi năm.Ngược lại, lượng cổ tức ở hầu hết doanh nghiệp niêm yết trên sàn đều không quá hấp dẫn so với lãi suất tiết kiệm. Khi phải đối mặt với những rủi ro hiện hữu trên thị trường, nhà đầu tư thường có kỳ vọng tỷ suất sinh lợi cao hơn.Tuy nhiên, như vậy không có nghĩa việc đầu tư nhận cổ tức lép vế hoàn toàn so với đầu tư \\"ăn\\" chênh lệch giá. Trong thời kỳ suy thoái, những cổ phiếu chia cổ tức đều đặn bằng tiền mặt sẽ được chú ý nhiều hơn. Nguyên nhân là áp lực chung của thị trường có thể đẩy thị giá cổ phiếu về mức thấp, tỷ lệ cổ tức cao hơn lãi suất tiết kiệm, thường được tham chiếu với mốc tiền gửi một năm. Ngoài ra, các doanh nghiệp chia cổ tức đều bằng tiền mặt thường thuộc những ngành nghề phòng thủ khá an toàn, chủ yếu là điện, nước, dược phẩm, xăng dầu, khí đốt. Điều này giúp các cổ phiếu ít có khả năng bị giảm giá quá sâu.Như vậy, làm sao để biết bản thân phù hợp với cách đầu tư nào? Tôi cho rằng, xác định khẩu vị rủi ro và kỳ vọng sinh lợi sẽ quyết định phong cách đầu tư nào phù hợp với bản thân.Khẩu vị rủi ro là quan điểm, mức độ chấp nhận của mỗi người về sự rủi ro. Cái này thường được xác định qua các yếu tố như lứa tuổi, khả năng tài chính, gia đình... Khẩu vị rủi ro ở mức nào sẽ quyết định sự an toàn cho nguồn vốn của bản thân và kỳ vọng sinh lợi.Ví dụ, nếu đầu tư 100 triệu đồng, bạn sẽ chấp nhận mất bao nhiêu khi khoản đầu tư đó bị thua lỗ? Với độ rủi ro ở mức đã xác định, bạn kỳ vọng sẽ thu về tỷ suất lợi nhuận bao nhiêu để bù đắp cho những rủi ro có thể gặp phải?Nếu như bạn có khẩu vị rủi ro thấp, ít có thời gian theo dõi thị trường, cách đầu tư nhận cổ tức sẽ là lựa chọn phù hợp với bạn.Ngược lại, cách đầu tư theo kiểu thu được lợi nhuận qua việc mua - bán chênh lệch, bạn cần có khẩu vị rủi ro cao hơn và thời gian theo dõi thị trường sẽ lớn hơn nếu muốn đầu tư hiệu quả. Phong cách này cũng đòi hỏi sự hiểu biết rộng về kinh tế vĩ mô lẫn tài chính doanh nghiệp nhằm đưa ra quyết định đầu tư chính xác. Cổ phiếu tăng trưởng là lựa chọn số một cho phong cách đầu tư này.Cần lưu ý rằng trong thời gian ngắn hơn, hiệu suất tăng trưởng hoặc giá trị các cổ phiếu sẽ phụ thuộc phần lớn vào thời điểm trong chu kỳ của thị trường. Nhìn chung, cách đầu tư sẽ phù hợp nhất khi phục vụ hiệu quả cho việc sinh lợi mà vẫn kiểm soát được rủi ro."},{"question":"Ta lo n purọ: Owo dija silẹ laarin Gomina Makinde ati ileewosan UCH","answer":"Gbogbo aye lo n fi ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ atawọn alaṣẹ UCH, iyẹn ileewosan ijọba apapọ to wa niluu Ibadan ṣe yẹyẹ nigba ti owo nla kan dija silẹ laarin wọn.Lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu kẹfa, ọdun 2020 yii, ni Kọmiṣanna feto iṣuna nipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ọgbẹni Akinọla Ojo, sọ fawọn oniroyin pe owo to le ni biliọnu meji Naira (N2.77b) nijọba oun ti na lori igbogun ti itankalẹ arun Korona ati itọju awọn to lugbadi arun naa bayii.Kọmiṣanna Gomina Makinde yii sọ pe ninu owo yii, miliọnu mejidinlọgọfa Naira (N118m) nijọba awọn pin kan ileewosan UCH lati fi gbọ bukaata ti wọn n gbọ lori ayẹwo ati itọju awọn eeyan lori ajakalẹ arun ọhun.Ṣugbọn awọn alakooso UCH ko ti i jẹ ki iroyin yii tutu ti wọn fi pariwo sita, wọn ni ijọba ko fawọn lowo kankan, ati pe gbogbo akitiyan awọn lori ayẹwo ati itọju awọn alarun Korona, awọn kan n ṣe e gẹgẹ bii ojuṣe awọn si igbe aye alaafia awọn araalu ni, ki i ṣe pe ẹnikẹni n fun awọn lowo iṣẹ naa lọtọ.Ninu atẹjade ti Alukoro ileewosan ijọba apapọ yii, Ọgbẹni Toye Akinrinọla, fi sita, lo ti ni “A gbọ ọ ninu iroyin pe ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ fun ileewosan UCH ni miliọnu mejidinlọgọfa Naira gẹgẹ bi Ọgbẹni Akinọla Ojo ti i ṣe kọmiṣanna feto iṣuna ṣe sọ.“Ọrọ naa ru wa loju diẹ, iyẹn la ṣe kan si awọn to yẹ ka kan si ninu awọn to n ṣejọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ lati beere alaye lori ẹ. Ṣugbọn wọn n sọ ọ bii ẹni pe ẹka imọ iṣegun oyinbo (College of Medicine) ti Yunifasiti Ibadan ni wọn fun lowo naa, ohun to si fẹẹ da aigbọra-ẹni-ye silẹ niyẹn nitori ẹka imọ iṣegun oyinbo ti Yunifasiti Ibadan yatọ sileewosan UCH.“Gbogbo iranlọwọ ta a (UCH) ri gba latọwọ ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ ko ju ọtalerugba-odin-mẹwaa (250) ohun eelo idaabobo lori ajakalẹ arun Korona ti wọn fun wa laipẹ yii lọ. Ṣugbọn pe ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ fun wa lowo iranwọ kan lori ọrọ Korona, irọ, ko si ohun to jọ ọ.“Oludari agba ileewosan UCH, (CMD, Ọjọgbọn Jesse Ọtẹgbayọ) jẹ ọkan ninu awọn adari igbimọ to n gbogun ti ajakalẹ arun Korona, nipa bẹẹ, ko si bi ijọba ṣe maa fun UCH niru owo bẹẹ ti wọn ko ni i mọ nipa ẹ.”Bi iroyin ọrọ yii ṣe jade sita fun gbogbo aye gbọ lawọn eeyan ti bẹrẹ si i bu ẹnu atẹ lu ijọba Gomina Makinde, wọn ni ki lo de ti wọn n pa iru irọ nla bẹẹ, irọ ti ko le bo wọn lẹyin ẹsẹ. Wọn si n reti ọrọ ti aṣoju ijọba tabi Gomina Makinde funra rẹ yoo sọ lati ko ọrọ wọn nipa ileewosan UCH jẹ.Ṣugbọn niṣe nijọba tun sọrọ pẹlu igboya pe loootọ lawọn na owo nla naa fun awọn oṣiṣẹ ẹka kan nileewosan UCH lati gbọ bukaata wọn lẹnu iṣẹ.Akọweeroyin Gomina Makinde, Ọgbẹni Taiwo Adisa sọ ninu atẹjade to tun fi sita l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, to kọja pe ijọba ti ṣetan lati gbe ẹri jade sita fun gbogbo aye ri lati mọ pe loootọ lawọn fi miliọnu mejidinlọgọfa Naira ran ileewosan ijọba apapọ naa lọwọ.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Ẹka to n ri si itọju awọn arun to ni i ṣe pẹlu kokoro aifojuri nileeewosan UCH la nawo yẹn fun lati maa fi tọju awọn to lugbadi arun Korona nipinlẹ yii.“Oludari agba ileewosan UCH, Ọjọgbọn Jesse Ọtẹgbayọ, funra rẹ lo fi akọsilẹ awọn ohun eelo ti ẹka yii nilo ṣọwọ si ijọba nigba kan, ohun eelo fun eto ilera to jẹ miliọnu mẹẹẹdọgbọn Naira nijọba wa si ra lẹẹkan naa nigba naa.“Diẹ ninu awọn ohun eelo ta a tun ra fun awọn olutọju alarun Korona nigba naa lọhun-un ni bata amunidórúnkún, awò ojú, aṣọ gbagẹrẹ to maa n bo awọn olutọju alarun Korona ni gbogbo ara. Iru awọn inawo bayii atawọn inawo min-in bẹẹ si ti na ijọba wa to miliọnu lọna ọgbọn (N30m) Naira.“Lara awọn nnkan ta a na owo yooku le lori ni ipese awọn ohun eelo fun ayẹwo ẹjẹ lati mọ awọn to ti ni kokoro arun Korona lara. Bẹẹ nijọba wa n fun awọn oṣiṣẹ ẹka itọju arun kokoro aifojuri to jẹ ẹka kan nileewosan UCH lowo ajẹmọnu lori iṣẹ ti wọn n ṣe lasiko ajakalẹ arun yii.”Ṣugbọn awọn alaṣẹ ileewosan yii ti sẹ kanlẹ, wọn lawọn ko jẹ iru anfaani owo nla bẹẹ lọdọ ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ibi ti wọn ba nawo si gan-an ni ki wọn sọ.Nigba to n ba akọroyin wa sọrọ, agbẹnusọ ileewosan UCH, Ọgbẹni Toye Akinrinọla tun sọ ọ pẹlu igboya pe “bẹẹ ni, UCH ko gbowo kankan lọwọ ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ. A ti sọ bẹẹ tẹlẹ ninu atẹjade kan ta a fi sita. Ohun ta a si sọ naa ko yipada.”Ni bayii ti agbọn n sẹ, ti oyin paapaa si n sẹ, to si jẹ oju oloko lo wu gbandu mọ ọn lagbari yii, ẹni to n purọ ninu ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ atawọn alaṣẹ ileewosan UCH, Ibadan lẹnikan ko ti i mọ bayii."},{"question":"第1句: 在宇宙学宇宙学中, 物理真空的能量表现为宇宙学常数. 第二句话:宇宙真空的能量在物理宇宙学中表现为宇宙常数. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"  பூச்சி இனங்களில் அதிக அறிவு உடையது?","answer":"எறும்பு."},{"question":"ကျွန်ုပ်၏အင်္ဂလိပ်စာကို မည်သို့တိုးတက်နိုင်မည်နည်း။","answer":"ဤအရာများသည် သင်၏စကားပြောအင်္ဂလိပ်စာကို တိုးတက်စေရန် သင်အသုံးပြုနိုင်သော နည်းပညာများဖြစ်သည်။စကားပြောပါ။ : အခြေခံအားဖြင့် အင်္ဂလိပ်စကား ပိုကောင်းအောင်ပြောရန် အကောင်းဆုံးနည်းလမ်းမှာ စကားများများပြောခြင်းဖြစ်သည်။ တတ်နိုင်သမျှ မတူညီသောလူများနှင့် မကြာခဏလေ့ကျင့်ပါ။ သင်၏မိတ်ဆွေများ၊ ၎င်းတို့၏မိသားစုများ၊ လုပ်ဖော်ကိုင်ဖက်များ၊ အတန်းဖော်များ၊ ရုံးစာတိုက်နှင့် သင်သွားရောက်လည်ပတ်သည့် အခြားနေရာများရှိ အင်္ဂလိပ်စကားပြောဆိုသူများနှင့် စကားများများပြောပါ။ အကယ်၍ သင်သည် သင့်နိုင်ငံ၌ သင်ယူနေပါက၊ အတန်းပြီးနောက် သင့်အတန်းဖော်များနှင့် တွေ့ဆုံခြင်း၊ ဘာသာစကားဖလှယ်သည့် လုပ်ဖော်ကိုင်ဖက်တစ်ဦးကို ရှာဖွေခြင်း သို့မဟုတ် သင်ယူသူများ၏ အွန်လိုင်းအသိုင်းအဝိုင်းတွင် ပါဝင်ခြင်းဖြင့် သင်၏လေ့ကျင့်ချိန်ကို တိုးမြှင့်လိုက်ပါ။သင်၏ပြောဆိုမှုများကို ပြန်လည်သုံးသပ်ပါ။ : သင့်စကားဝိုင်းပြီးသွားသောအခါတွင် ပြန်လည်သုံးသပ်ရန် အချိန်ယူပါ။ ဘယ်လိုသွားတာလဲ။ ဘယ်လောက်နားလည်မယ်ထင်လဲ။ အဲဒီအကြောင်းအရာနဲ့ ပတ်သက်ပြီး သင်ဘယ်လောက်အဆင်ပြေခဲ့လဲ။ မသိတဲ့ စကားလုံးတွေ တွေ့ဖူးလား။ ဤနည်းဖြင့် ၎င်းကို တွေးတောခြင်းက နောက်တစ်ကြိမ်ပြောဆိုမှုအတွက် သင်၏ယုံကြည်မှုကို တိုးစေသည်။နားထောင်ပြီး ဖတ်ပါ။ : စကားပြောဖို့အတွက် စကားလုံးတွေလိုပါတယ်။ စာသင်ချိန်သည် ဝေါဟာရလေ့လာရန်အတွက် ကောင်းမွန်သော်လည်း သင့်အား သင်တိုးပေးနိုင်သည့် အခြားနည်းလမ်းများ ရှိပါသည်။ ရုပ်ရှင်ကြည့်ခြင်း၊ တေးဂီတနားထောင်ခြင်း၊ ရေဒီယိုနှင့် ပေါ့တ်ကာစ်များနားထောင်ခြင်း။ စာအုပ်များ၊ မဂ္ဂဇင်းများနှင့် ဘလော့ဂ်များကို ဖတ်ပါ။ နားထောင်ခြင်းနှင့် စာဖတ်သည့်အခါ၊ စိတ်ဝင်စားဖွယ်ကောင်းသော အသုံးအနှုန်းများ၊ ဘန်းစကားအသုံးအနှုန်းများနှင့် တူညီသောအသုံးအနှုန်းများကို ရှာဖွေပါ၊ ဤအကြောင်းအရာအသစ်ကို ချရေးပြီး သင်နှင့်မရင်းနှီးသည့်အရာများကို ရှာဖွေပါ။ မှတ်စုများပြင်ဆင်ပါ။ : စကားပြောရာတွင် ကြောက်ရွံ့မှု၏ တစ်စိတ်တစ်ပိုင်းမှာ ဘာပြောရမှန်းမသိသည့် ခံစားချက်ဖြစ်သည်။ ဒါကို တိုက်ဖျက်ဖို့အတွက် မှတ်စုများကို ပြင်ဆင်ပါ။ မင်းဆရာဝန်ဆီသွားနေတာလား။ သင်ချိန်းဆိုခြင်းမပြုမီ သင့်အခြေအနေနှင့်ပတ်သက်သော ဝေါဟာရနှင့် သင်လိုအပ်မည့် အသုံးများသော အသုံးအနှုန်းအချို့ကို သုတေသနပြုပါ။ ဘေလ်မပေးမီ၊ စားသောက်ဆိုင်တွင် စားသောက်ခြင်း၊ အလုပ်အင်တာဗျူးများ၊ တိုင်ကြားချက်တစ်ခု ပြုလုပ်ခြင်း သို့မဟုတ် သင်စိတ်ပူပန်စေမည့် အခြားအခြေအနေများအတွက် အသုံးပြုပါ။သင့်အသံကို မှတ်တမ်းတင်ပါ။ : လူအများစုသည် ၎င်းတို့၏အသံကို မှတ်တမ်းတင်ထားသည်ကို မကြားချင်ကြသော်လည်း၊ ၎င်းသည် သင်၏စကားပြောခြင်းကို မြှင့်တင်ရန်အတွက် အလွန်အကျိုးရှိသောနည်းလမ်းဖြစ်သည်။ တိပ်ခွေပေါ်တွင် သင့်ကိုယ်သင် ကြားနေရခြင်းသည် သင်သဘောမပေါက်နိုင်သောအရာများကို ပြသသည်။ အခြားတစ်ဖက်တွင်၊ သင်၏စကားသည် သင်ထင်သည်ထက် များစွာသာလွန်ကြောင်း ကြားသိရသည့်အတွက် အံ့ဩသွားနိုင်သည်။ ဘောနပ်စ်အမှတ်များအတွက်၊ သင်၏အသံသွင်းချက်ကို သင့်ဆရာ သို့မဟုတ် မူရင်းစကားပြောသူမိတ်ဆွေထံ ယူဆောင်ပြီး သင့်အား တုံ့ပြန်ချက်ပေးခိုင်းပါ။စကားလုံးတစ်လုံးတည်းမဟုတ်ဘဲ စကားစုများကို လေ့လာပါ။ : သင်၏ သွက်လက်မှုကို တိုးမြှင့်ရန် နောက်ထပ် အကြံပြုချက်မှာ စကားလုံးများထက် စကားစု အမျိုးမျိုးကို အသုံးပြု၍ ပြောဆိုရန် ဖြစ်သည်။ (မင်းရဲ့ မိခင်ဘာသာစကားနဲ့ တစ်ချိန်လုံး ဒီလိုလုပ်နေတာ ဖြစ်နိုင်တယ်။) \\"ဟဲလို၊ ဒီနေ့ နေကောင်းလား\\" လို့ အလိုအလျောက် မေးမယ့်အစား \\"What's up, man?\\" ကဲ့သို့သော အခြားအသုံးအနှုန်းများကို ရွေးချယ်ခြင်းဖြင့် ၎င်းကို ရောနှောလိုက်ပါ။ \\"ဟေ့ကောင်!\\" ဒါမှမဟုတ် \\"ဘယ်လိုနေလဲ သူငယ်ချင်း\\" (သတိထားပါ- အချို့သောအသုံးအနှုန်းများသည် အလွန်အလွတ်သဘောဖြစ်ပြီး အချို့သောအခြေအနေများအတွက် မသင့်တော်ပါ။)ပျော်စရာကောင်းအောင်လေ့လာပါ : သင်ပျော်နေတဲ့အခါ အသစ်တစ်ခုကို သင်ယူရတာ ပိုလွယ်ပါတယ်။ အထီးကျန်နေချိန်၊ အင်္ဂလိပ်လို နာမည်ကြီးသီချင်းတွေနဲ့အတူ သီဆိုခြင်း သို့မဟုတ် ကျပန်းရွေးချယ်ထားသော အကြောင်းအရာများအတွက် တစ်မိနစ်ကြာ \\"လက်ငင်းပြောဆိုမှုများ\\" ပြုလုပ်ခြင်းဖြင့် သင်၏ စကားပြောလေ့ကျင့်မှုထဲသို့ ပျော်စရာများကို ထည့်သွင်းပါ။"},{"question":"ਨਾਈਜੀਰੀਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਲ 2014 ਵਿੱਚ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਨੂੰ ਗੈਰ-ਕਾਨੂੰਨੀ ਕਰਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ।ਇਹ ਮੁਲਜ਼ਮ ਸਾਲ 2018 ਵਿੱਚ ਲਾਗੋਸ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਹੋਟਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਛਾਪੇਮਾਰੀ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਗ੍ਰਿਫ਼ਤਾਰ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ 57 ਵਿਅਕਤੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਮੂਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਸੀ। ਪਰ ਉਹ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਖਾਰਿਜ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।ਹਾਲ ਹੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਾਸ਼ੀਏ 'ਤੇ ਲਿਆਉਣ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਨਵੀਂ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਹੈ। 7 ਜਨਵਰੀ, 2014 ਨੂੰ ਨਾਈਜੀਰੀਆ ਦੇ ਤਤਕਾਲੀ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਗੁੱਡਲਕ ਜੋਨਾਥਨ ਨੇ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀ ਵਿਆਹ (ਰੋਕੂ) ਬਿੱਲ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਹਸਤਾਖਰ ਕੀਤੇ ਸਨ।ਕਾਰਕੁਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਬੇਹੱਦ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਦੇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਨੇ ਜਿਨਸੀ ਘੱਟ ਗਿਣਤੀਆਂ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਵਿਤਕਰੇ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਬਦਤਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ।ਉਹ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਕਰਮੀਆਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਐਲਜੀਬੀਟੀਕਿਊ ਭਾਈਚਾਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਜ਼ਬਰਦਸਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਬਲੈਕਮੇਲ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਮਾਮਲਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਧਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ।ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨਾਈਜੀਰੀਆ ਦੀ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰ ਮੇਏਨੀ ਜੋਨਸ ਨੇ ਕੁਝ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਹ ਜਾਣਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਕਿ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਮਤਲਬ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਾਹਮਣਾ ਕਰਨਾ ਪੈ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਦੇ ਮੱਦੇਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਮ ਬਦਲੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ।'ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਥੈਰੇਪੀ'ਅਪੁਨਨਵੂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਰਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ \\"ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਥੈਰੇਪੀ\\" ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਲੰਘੀ।ਉਸ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ 'ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਥੈਰੇਪੀ' ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। \\"ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਲੱਤਾਂ ਚੁੱਕੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਵਜਾਇਨਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੇਲ ਪਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।\\" ਇਸ ਕੁੜੀ ਨੇ ਸਮਲਿੰਗਤਾ ਤੋਂ ਛੁਟਕਾਰਾ ਪਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਖੁਦ 'ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਥੈਰੇਪੀ' ਕਰਵਾਈ।\\"ਹੁਣ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਤਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੇਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀ ਸੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਹ ਮਿਰਚ ਵਰਗਾ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਤੰਗ ਕੀਤਾ।\\"ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਕੀ ਹਾਸਲ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ, ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਯਕੀਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ।\\"ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਗੜਬੜ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਮੇਰੀ ਯੋਨੀ ਦਾ ਮੁਕਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਕੀ ਲੈਣਾ-ਦੇਣਾ ਹੈ?\\"\\"ਪਰ ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਤਾ ਸੀ। ਮੈਂ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀ ਖਿੱਚ ਦੀ ਭਾਵਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੂਰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕੁਝ ਵੀ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ।\\"ਜਦੋਂ ਸੈਮੂਅਲ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੂਜੇ ਮਰਦ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ਹਨ ਤਾਂ ਉਸਦੀ ਭੈਣ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਬੁਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਕ੍ਰਿਆ ਦਿੱਤੀ।\\"ਹਰ ਕੋਈ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਘ੍ਰਿਣਾ ਨਾਲ ਦੇਖਦਾ ਹੈ।\\"ਇਸ ਨੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀ ਹੋਣ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੇ ਟੋਟਕੇ ਕਰਵਾਉਣੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ।\\"ਮੇਰਾ ਜਨਮ ਇੱਕ ਕ੍ਰਿਸਚਨ ਪਰਵਿਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ, ਇੱਕ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਜੋ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀ ਵਿਆਹ ਨੂੰ ਪਿਸ਼ਾਚਗ੍ਰਸਤ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ।\\"ਸੈਮੁਅਲ ਦੀ ਭੈਣ ਇੱਕ 'ਬਾਬੇ' ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਆਈ ਜਿਸਨੇ ਉਸਨੂੰ 'ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਥੈਰੇਪੀ' ਲਈ ਮਜਬੂਰ ਕੀਤਾ।","answer":"ਨਾਈਜੀਰੀਆ ਵਿਚ ਸਮਲਿੰਗੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਦਿਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ 'ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਥੈਰੇਪੀ' ਤਹਿਤ ਕਈ ਤਰੀਕਿਆਂ ਬਾਰੇ।"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Isha Ugu Muhiimsan Ileyska (Iftiinka)?","answer":"Jawaab: Isha Ugu Muhiimsan Ileyska (Iftiinka) Waa Qoraxda."},{"question":"1842 இல் நடந்த முதலாம் அபினிப் போரின் முடிவில் பிரித்தானியரால் கைப்பற்றப்பட்ட முதல் நிலப்பரப்பு இந்த ஒங்கொங் தீவாகும். பிரித்தானியர் இத்தீவை தம்வசப்படுத்தும் போது, இத்தீவில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 7,000 வரையிலான பூர்வக் குடிகள் மட்டுமே இருந்துள்ளனர். ஆங்காங்கே சில மீனவக் குடிகள் மட்டுமே தென்பட்டுள்ளன.","answer":"முதலாம் அபினிப் போரின்"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fanatontoloana?","answer":"Ny fanatontoloana  dia diharian-karena misandrahaka amin’izao tontolo izao indrindra fa eo amin’ny lafiny varotra. Misy ny fifandraisana ara-barotra maneran-tany. Tsy misy intsony ny fifanarahana eo amin’ny firenena roa fotsiny amin’ny fifampivarotana satria misokatra amin’ny firenena rehetra ny fifanakalozana. Foana ny antsojay eo amin’ny firenena mpamokatra sy mpanjifa."},{"question":"ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ (Ecosystem) ਕਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ? ਇਸਦਾ ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਨਾਲ ਕੀ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ – ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਵਿਚ ਊਰਜਾ ਅਤੇ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਦਾ ਆਦਾਨ-ਪ੍ਰਦਾਨ ਜੈਵ ਅਤੇ ਅਜੈਵ ਘਟਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਤਾਲਾਬ, ਝੀਲ, ਜੰਗਲ, ਖੇਤ ਅਤੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਬਣਾਏ ਜੀਵ ਸ਼ਾਲਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੈਵ ਅਤੇ ਅਜੈਵ ਘਟਕ ਆਪਸ ਵਿਚ ਕਿਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ । ਇਕ ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਗਟ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਜੈਵ ਸੰਖਿਆ, ਜੈਵ ਅਤੇ ਅਜੈਵ ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਦੇ ਘਟਕ ਹਨ, ਜੋ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਅਤੇ ਗਤੀਸ਼ੀਲਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਦਾਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਕੋਈ ਤਾਲਾਬ, ਜੰਗਲ ਜਾਂ ਘਾਹ ਦਾ ਮੈਦਾਨ ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਦੇ ਉਦਾਹਰਨ ਹਨ ।ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਦਾ ਹਰ ਘਟਕ ਆਪਣਾ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੁੱਝ ਕਾਰਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਾਰਾ ਯੋਗ ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਨੂੰ ਸਥਿਰਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਦਾਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਸੇ ਭੂਗੋਲਿਕ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਬਾਇਓਮ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਬਾਇਓਮ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਘਟਕ ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਜੀਵ-ਮੰਡਲ ਨੂੰ ਗਤੀਸ਼ੀਲਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਦਾਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"barang siapa yang ketuk dialah yang bertelur\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang berasa tersinggung oleh sesuatu sindiran itulah yang telah melakukan perkara yang disindirkan itu."},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Izaho miantoka ny fiainany rehetra indray no hiavonany.\\"","answer":"Ity fanambarana ity dia maneho hatezerana. Tezitra ianao satria miavona aminao ilay olona iantohanao."},{"question":"Zou plietsneep een Nederlands woord kunnen zijn?","answer":"Plietsneep is geen Nederlands wordt, maar voldoet wel aan de regels voor Nederlandse morfologie en fonologie. Het zou in theorie een Nederlands woord kunnen zijn. "},{"question":"राष्ट्रिय लिग फूटबल को पुरुस्कार राशी कति छ ?","answer":"राष्ट्रिय लिग फूटबल को पुरुस्कार राशी ७५ लाख छ ।"},{"question":"టెలిస్కోప్ అంశం మీద వ్యాసం రాయండి ","answer":"నాపేరు అర్జున్.  నేను 10 వ తరగతి చదువుతున్నాను.  మాకు గత వారం మా సైన్సు టీచరు టెలిస్కోప్ పాఠం చెప్పేరు.  ఈరోజు ఆపాఠంపై మాకు ఏమి అర్ధమైంది, ఎంతవరకు అర్ధమైంది ఒక వ్యాసంగా వ్రాసుకుని రమ్మన్నారు.  అంటే నేను రేపు స్కూలుకి వెళ్ళినప్పుడు వ్యాసం మాటీచరు గారికి చూపించాలి.  అందుకని ఇప్పుడు నాకు టెలిస్కోప్ గురించి తెలిసిన విషయాలు  మీతో పంచుకుంటున్నాను. ఇటలీ దేశానికి చెందిన ఖగోళ శాస్త్రవేత్త గెలీలియో తొలి దూరదర్శినిని 1609 సంవత్సరం లో కనిపెట్టెను. పిమ్మట టెలిస్కోపుతో అంతరిక్షాన్ని విశేషంగా పరిశీలించి చంద్రుని ఉపరితల భాగం పర్వతములను, లోయలను కలిగి ఉన్నదని నునుపుగా లేదని తెలియచేసెను. అంతేకాకుండా పాలపుంత (milky way) అనేక నక్షత్రాల సముదాయమని, గురు గ్రహమునకు నాలుగు ఉప గ్రహములు కలవను సిద్ధాంతమును మానవాళికి తెలియచేసెను. కానీ ఈ సిద్ధాంతమును అప్పటి అధికారులెవరూ అంగీకరించలేదు.  అతనిపై మతపరమైన ఆరోపణలను మోపి అతని చేతనే అతని సిద్ధాంతము తప్పు కావొచ్చునని చెప్పించి, జీవితకాలం తన సిద్ధాంతం గురించి మాట్లాడకుండా ఉండే  విధంగా శిక్ష విధించారు. ఇంచుమించుగా గెలీలియో టెలిస్కోప్ కనుగొన్న సమయానికే కెప్లర్ అను శాస్త్రవేత్త కూడా టెలిస్కోప్ ను కనుగొనెను. ఇప్పుడు మనం వాడుతున్న బైనాక్యులర్సు వీటి నమూనాగా తయారుచేయబడినవే.  అయితే ఖగోళ వస్తువులను చూడటానికి ఇప్పుడు వాడుతున్న టెలిస్కోప్ 1670 లో న్యూటన్ నిర్మించిన పరావర్తక దూరదర్శినిపై  ఆధారపడినవే. ఒక పెద్ద పుటాకార దర్పణం వస్తువు నుంచి వచ్చే కిరణాలను పరావర్తనం చేసి ప్రతిబింబాన్ని ఏర్పరుస్తుంది.  మరో అక్షి కటకం దీన్ని ఇంకా పెద్దదిగా కనబడేలా చేస్తుంది.  ఈ ప్రతిబింబం తలక్రిందులుగా ఏర్పడుతుంది కానీ ఖగోళ వస్తువులను చూడడానికి దీనివలన అంత ఇబ్బంది ఉండదు అంతరిక్ష రహస్యాలను కనుగొనడానికి మానవుడు అనేకమైన పనిముట్లను వాడాడు.  వీటన్నింటిలో ముందుగా వాడుకలోనికి వచ్చినది నిట్రాట.  దీనినే  ఆంగ్లంలో(gnomon) అంటారు. ఈ నిట్రాట ప్రసరించే నీడని బట్టి మన పూర్వీకులు ఎన్నో విషయాలు తెలుసుకున్నారు.  నిట్రాట తరువాత చెప్పుకోదగ్గది సూర్యఫలకం లేదా సూర్య యంత్రం లేదా నీడ గడియారం. దీనిని ఇంగ్లీషులో సన్‌డయల్ (sundial) అంటారు. ఇప్పుడు కాలాన్ని కొలవటానికి చాల సున్నితమైన గడియారాలు ఉన్నాయి. కాలాన్ని అతి నిక్కచ్చిగా కొలిచే శ్రేష్టమైన గడియారాన్ని క్రోనోమీటర్(chronometer) అంటారు. ఆ తరువాత చెప్పుకోదగ్గ పనిముట్టు దుర్భిణి. టెలిస్కోపులను ఆరు విధాలుగా వర్గీకరించారు అవి 1) గామా కిరణ దుర్భిణిలు, 2) ఎక్స్-రే టెలిస్కోపులు, 3) అతినీలలోహిత టెలీస్కోప్,  4)ఆప్టికల్ టెలిస్కోపు, 5) ఇన్ఫ్రారెడ్ టెలిస్కోపు, 6) రేడియో టెలిస్కోప్."},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-compare","answer":"ஒப்பிடு"},{"question":"பொதுவுடைமைக் கொள்கையின் முன்னோடிகளில் ஒருவர்?","answer":"பொதுவுடைமைக் கொள்கையின் முன்னோடிகளில் ஒருவர் ப. ஜீவானந்தம் ஆவார். ஏறத்தாழ நாற்பது ஆண்டுகள் பொது வாழ்க்கையில் ஈடுபட்டு தியாகங்கள் பல புரிந்த பொதுவுடமைத் தலைவர் ஆவார். ஏறத்தாழ பத்து ஆண்டுகளை சிறையில் கழித்தவர். காந்தியவாதியாக, சுயமரியாதை இயக்க வீரராக, தமிழ்ப் பற்றாளராக, அனைத்திற்கும் மேலாக ஒரு பொதுவுடைமை இயக்கத் தலைவராக படிப்படியாக உயர்ந்தவர். தம்மை நாத்திகராக அறிவித்துக் கொண்டவர்."},{"question":"أحاول معرفة إجابة السؤال \\"ما لقب القديس أنطونيوس الكبير باللغة القبطية؟\\"لقد وجدت هذا النص حول أنطونيوس الكبير على ويكيبيديا وأعتقد أنه يحتوي على الإجابة. هل يمكنك إخباري بالإجابة؟النص: ولقبه باللغة القبطية \\"بي نيشتي افا انطوني\\" وترجمتها العظيم الأب انطونيوس. لما قام به هذا الأب من تغيير في نفوس الآلاف من الناس علي مر العصور.","answer":"يلقب أنطونيوس ب بي نيشتي افا انطوني."},{"question":"வினா: எவற்றை அமைத்துக்கொள்வது, சிறந்த மதிநுட்பமும் பண்பாடும் உடைய மக்கட்கே இயலும்?","answer":"விடை:திருந்திய மக்களை மற்ற உயிரினின்றும் பிரித்துக் காட்டுவது மொழியாதலின், அதுவே ஒரு நாட்டாரின் அல்லது இனத்தாரின் நாகரிகத்தை அளந்தறிவதற்கும் சிறந்த வழியாகும்.பொருளைக் கூர்ந்து நோக்கி நுண்பாகுபாடு செய்து அவற்றிற்கேற்பப் பருப்பொருட் சொற்களும், நுண்பொருட்சொற்களும் அமைத்துக்கொள்வது, சிறந்த மதிநுட்பமும் பண்பாடும் உடைய மக்கட்கே இயலும்."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"மனிதனை முட்டாளாக்கும், பிரித்து வைக்கும் அமைப்பு மதம் ஆகும்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai bangsi buluh perindu\\"?","answer":"Suara yang lemah lembut dan merdu."},{"question":"Ahoana no hahafahanao manampy ireo mpiara-miasa ao an-toerana izay mitady fanazavana momba ny asa iray?","answer":"Raha hampitandrinao ny mpiara-miasa ao an-toerana mba hahafahanao manampy azy ireo momba ny asa iray, dia afaka mamorona lisitra na fanamarihanao amin'ny fiteny malagasy araka ny fomba fiasa atao ao amin'ny toerana. Afaka mampiasa mailaka, sary na sampandraharaha ny famarananao mba hahafahanao manazava ny fomba fiasa ara-tsosialy."},{"question":"برای یادگیری نواختن یک ساز روزانه چقدر تمرین لازم است؟","answer":"برای اینکه شما بتوانید از کلاس آموزش موسیقی که می روید نتیجه بگیرید احتیاج به تمرین دارید.برای بازدهی بهتر و افزایش سرعت پیشرفت باید این تمرین به صورت روزانه انجام شود، یعنی هنرجو هر روز تمرین داشته باشد که مقدار ساعت این تمرین حداقل ٣٠ الی ٤٥ دقیقه می باشد.اگر این تمرین روزانه هر روز در یک ساعت خاصی انجام شود بطور مثال یک هنرجو هر روز بین ساعت ٥ تا ٦ عصر تمرین کند بازدهی کار بسیار بالا خواهد رفت."},{"question":"Unsa ang kapital sa Pilipinas?","answer":"Ang kapital sa Pilipinas mao ang Maynila."},{"question":"Lihatlah bagian di bawah ini dan kemudian jawab pertanyaan setelahnya dalam bahasa yang sama dengan bagian:  Passage: Ceritanya terjadi pada tahun 3394, seribu tahun setelah umat manusia melarikan diri dari Bumi setelah dihancurkan oleh ras alien yang berubah bentuk menjadi the Gauna, di atas ratusan pesawat ruang angkasa besar yang dibuat dari sisa-sisa planet. Salah satu kapal seperti itu adalah Sidonia, yang telah mengembangkan budaya manusia sendiri berdasarkan pada budaya Jepang, di mana kloning manusia, reproduksi aseksual, dan rekayasa genetika manusia, seperti memberikan manusia fotosintesis, adalah hal biasa. Hal ini juga mengungkapkan bahwa eselon atas masyarakat ini telah diam-diam diberikan keabadian. Dengan populasi lebih dari 500.000 orang, Sidonia mungkin merupakan pemukiman manusia terakhir yang tersisa karena nasib kapal-kapal lainnya tidak diketahui.  Pertanyaan: Kapal Sidonia sebagian besar didasarkan pada budaya apa?","answer":"Jepang"},{"question":"No anime Attack on Titan, quem é Pixis?","answer":"Dot Pixis é um comandante militar de alta patente e é conhecido por sua estratégia e liderança."},{"question":"Waa maxay ereyga bili?","answer":" Ereyga Bili micnehisa waxey lamid tahay Haybad iyo Qurux."},{"question":"Which countries conquered Lanka?","answer":"The history of Sri Lanka, historically known as Lanka, is marked by several foreign invasions and periods of colonial rule. The main countries that conquered or ruled parts of Sri Lanka at different times include:1. Portuguese Empire (1505–1658): The Portuguese were the first European power to establish a foothold in Sri Lanka. They controlled coastal areas and converted many locals to Christianity.2. Dutch Empire (1658–1796): The Dutch took over from the Portuguese and controlled significant parts of the island, especially the coastal regions.3. British Empire (1796–1948): The British replaced the Dutch as the colonial power in Sri Lanka. They unified and controlled the entire island, marking the first time the entire island was governed by a foreign power. Sri Lanka, known as Ceylon under British rule, gained independence in 1948.Before the European colonial period, Sri Lanka experienced invasions from neighboring South Asian powers:1. Chola Empire: During the medieval period, the Chola dynasty from southern India invaded and controlled parts of Sri Lanka.2. Pandyan and other South Indian Kingdoms: At various times, other South Indian kingdoms also exerted influence or control over regions in Sri Lanka.These foreign influences have left a significant impact on Sri Lanka's culture, language, and history. However, throughout its history, Sri Lanka has also had periods of strong, independent kingdoms with rich cultural and architectural legacies."},{"question":"بیرونی حملوں اور جغرافیائی سیاسی چیلنجوں نے مغل سلطنت کے زوال کو کیسے تیز کیا؟","answer":"بیرونی حملوں اور جغرافیائی سیاسی چیلنجوں نے مغلیہ سلطنت کے زوال کا ایک اہم مرحلہ قرار دیا۔ 1739 میں نادر شاہ کا حملہ، جس کا اختتام دہلی کی بوری پر ہوا، ایک واٹرشیڈ لمحہ تھا۔ سلطنت اقتصادی طور پر تباہ ہو گئی تھی، اور اس کی سیاسی اتھارٹی بری طرح کمزور ہو گئی تھی۔ اس کے ساتھ ہی، علاقائی طاقتوں، جیسے مرہٹوں اور سکھوں کا عروج، اور یورپی استعماری مفادات کے تسلط نے اہم چیلنجز کا سامنا کیا۔1757 میں پلاسی کی جنگ نے ایک اہم موڑ کا نشان لگایا، جس میں برطانوی ایسٹ انڈیا کمپنی نے عروج حاصل کیا۔ اس جغرافیائی سیاسی تبدیلی نے مغل اقتدار کے خاتمے کو تیز کر دیا۔ سلطنت نے خود کو بیرونی دباؤ کا سامنا کرنے سے قاصر پایا اور اپنے وسیع خطوں پر کنٹرول برقرار رکھنے کے لیے جدوجہد کی، جس سے اس کے حتمی زوال کا سبب بنے۔"},{"question":"จงเขียนบทความเรื่อง \\"วิทยาศาสตร์กับเด็กไทย\\"","answer":"วิทยาศาสตร์ เป็นหนึ่งในสาขาวิชาที่เด็ก ๆ ทุกคนควรได้เรียนรู้ เพราะวิทยาศาสตร์เป็นพื้นฐานของทุกสิ่งทุกอย่างบนโลกใบนี้ การเรียนรู้วิทยาศาสตร์ตั้งแต่เด็กจะช่วยสร้างพื้นฐานความรู้และความเข้าใจที่ถูกต้องเกี่ยวกับธรรมชาติและสิ่งแวดล้อม ช่วยให้เด็กสามารถคิดวิเคราะห์และแก้ปัญหาได้อย่างมีเหตุผล รู้จักตั้งคําถามและหาคําตอบด้วยตนเอง ส่งเสริมให้เด็กมีความคิดสร้างสรรค์และกล้าแสดงออก ที่สําคัญวิทยาศาสตร์ยังช่วยพัฒนาทักษะการคิดอย่างมีวิจารณญาณ ทักษะที่จําเป็นต่อการดํารงชีวิตในอนาคต"},{"question":"Dubai ve Katar yakın mı?","answer":"Dubai - Doha arası mesafe 393 km'dir. Bu güzergahtaki en popüler havayolları şunlardır: Qatar Airways, Fly Dubai, Air Arabia, Kuwait Airways ve Emirates. Dubai ve Doha arasında 328 direkt uçuş vardır."},{"question":"Pirmasis šių filmų sukurtas 2004 m., antrasis – 2009 m. Abu filmai vadinasi beveik taip pat, tik antrojo filmo pavadinime dar yra minimi ir metai – 2009. Pirmasis filmas yra istorinis, režisuotas Algimanto Puipos, jo veiksmas vyksta Vilniuje II pasaulinio karo metais, antrasis – dokumentinis, režisuotas Andriaus Lelkaičio, pasakoja apie Vilniaus romų taboro gyvenimą. Parašykite pirmojo filmo pavadinimą.","answer":"Vilniaus Getas. 2004 m. pasirodęs Algimanto Puipos filmas vadinasi \\"Vilniaus getas\\",2009 m. pasirodęs Audriaus Lelkaičio filmas vadinasi \\"Vilniaus getas 2009\\"."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Video tổng hợp những sự kiện giới trẻ HOT nhất tuần qua Nguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/co-dau-mai-choi-game-bo-ca-ruoc-dau-khien-chu-re-gian-tim-mat-hot-nh...Nguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/co-dau-mai-choi-game-bo-ca-ruoc-dau-khien-chu-re-gian-tim-mat-hot-nhat-tuan-1382720.ngn ","answer":"Cô dâu mải chơi game bỏ cả rước dâu khiến chú rể giận tím mặt HOT nhất tuần"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Carl \\"Stefan\\" Tornberg, född 7 februari 1957 i Nikkala i dåvarande Nedertorneå kommun i Norrbottens län, är en svensk politiker (centerpartist) och sjuksköterska, som var riksdagsledamot 2006","answer":"–2010, invald för Norrbottens läns valkrets."},{"question":"இவன் வாலுக்கு வையகமே நடுங்கும் அவன் யார்?","answer":"விடை: தேள் "},{"question":"君子之交淡若水，小人之交甘若醴”出自哪部作品？","answer":"《莊子》"},{"question":"సీ॥ సూర్యాది గ్రహరాశి సుప్రభాతము పల్కికరముల స్పృశియించు పురము నిలనుకృష్ణాతరంగిణీ కృతశుద్ధ పావనగంభీరత నలరు కనక నగరిబుద్ధాది మౌనీంద్ర పుణ్యపాదములతోపరమపావనమైన పురము భువినిరాజాధిరాజుల రాజధానిగ వెల్గియాంధ్ర జాతికి వన్నె యమరపురముతే॥గీ॥ తెలుగు వెలుగుల జిలుగులు చిలకరించికలుములవెలది నిలయమై బలిమిబెంచిసకలసురల యాశీస్సుల సారమౌచువిశ్వయవనికపై వెల్లు వీటిఁగనుడుపద్యంలో ఏ పట్టణం గురించి చెప్పారు?","answer":"పద్యంలో అమరావతి పట్టణం గురించి చెప్పారు."},{"question":"Unsa ang tawag sa gamay nga bahin sa atoma nga adunay karga nga elektrika?","answer":"Ang electron."},{"question":"\\"Nahazo fisondrotana tany am-piasana izy, ary nitehaka ny fahombiazany ny mpiara-miasa aminy.\\"Inona ny fihetseham-po ao anatin'ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Ity fehezanteny ity dia manondro fihetseham-po tsara, mankalaza ny zava-bitan'ny tsirairay sy ny fankasitrahana."},{"question":"‘Awọn EFCC mẹẹẹdọgbọn fo fẹnsi wọle mi laarin oru, wọn lawọn ro pe ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ ni mi’","answer":"Ori lo ko obinrin oniroyin kan, Abilekọ Nora Okafor, yọ lọwọ iku ojiji latari bawọn ẹṣọ ajọ to n gbogun ti iwa jibiti ati ṣiṣe owo ilu  mọkumọku nilẹ wa nni, EFCC, ṣe ya bo ile rẹ lọganjọ oru, awọn ọkunrin firigbọn bii mẹẹẹdọgbọn, wọn da jinnijinni bo awọn olugbe ile naa, wọn ba awọn dukia wọn jẹ, lẹyin eyi ni wọn waa sọ pe awọn ṣi ile ya ni, awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ lawọn n wa kiri.Okafor royin pe:“Aago meji ku iṣẹju mẹrinlelogun geere ni aburo mi ji mi pẹpẹ lori bẹẹdi ti mo sun si, o ni awọn adigunjale ti fẹẹ wọle wa o, wọn ti wa lẹnu geeti, ti wọn n wa ọna lati wọle. Ha, ẹru ba mi. Mo kọkọ ro o pe nitori geeti ati waya ori fẹnsi wa maa n ba ina ẹlẹntiriiki ṣiṣẹ, pe ko le ṣee ṣe fun wọn lati wọle. Aṣe irọ ni, aago meji oru ni mo ri ọkan lara wọn lori fẹnsi, o fi irinṣẹ kan ge okun ina to wa lara waya, lo ba fo wọle, ẹlomi-in tun tẹle e, lẹyin eyi ni wọn bẹrẹ si i fi aake nla kan ja geeti latẹyin ki awọn to ku wọn le wọle, bi wọn ṣe ya bo ile wa niyẹn.Awọn bii mẹẹẹdọgbọn ni, gbogbo wọn lo da aṣọ dudu boju bii tawọn adigunjale, wọn dihamọra pẹlu ibọn lọwọ wọn, wọn tun ko aake, irin atawọn nnkan ija mi-in dani, ọkọ ọlọpọn meji ni wọn gbe wa, aṣọ dudu ni wọn si wọ.Mi o ki i wọṣọ sun, tori naa, mo sare wọ aṣọ tọwọ mi ba. Mo ti n sọ fun ara mi pe ‘mo gbe, wọn maa fipa ba mi lo pọ lonii, wọn si maa ji mọto mi gbe lọ.’ Adigunjale ni gbogbo wa fọkan si pe wọn jẹ.Mo fẹrẹ ma ti i wọṣọ tan ti wọn fi ja wọnu yara mi, ni wọn ba n paṣẹ bii ologun: ‘doju bolẹ, ẹ tan’na, dọbalẹ sibẹ yẹn, foonu ẹ da, kọkọrọ mọto ẹ n kọ, tibi nkọ, tọhun nkọ.’ Mo mu foonu mi fun wọn, mo gbe kọmputa agbeletan mi naa fun wọn, wọn ni ki n fi nọmba aṣiri (pasiwọọdu) mi si i, mo si ṣe bẹẹ pẹlu ojora. Bi wọn ṣe n tẹ oriṣiiriṣii lori foonu mi ati kọmputa mi lọwọ, mo gbọ ariwo bawọn kan lara wọn ṣe n da abọ ati awo ru ni kiṣinni (kitchen) mi, mo gbọ bi wọn ṣe n fọ awọn awo mi. Gbogbo yara mi ni wọn gbọn yẹbẹyẹbẹ, afi bii ẹni pe abẹrẹ ni wọn n wa. Wọn tun ṣe bakan naa si yara aburo mi, ko sibi ti wọn o fọwọ ba.Nigba to ya, wọn ni ki n dide, ki n tẹle awọn lọ sisalẹ ile. Mo ri i pe wọn ti ko awọn alajọgbele mi naa de ibẹ, wọn ti lu aburo mi ọkunrin bii ẹni lu aṣọ ofi. Wọn gbiyanju lati ṣi awọn ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ ti kaluku gbe sinu ọgba. Ẹnu ya mi nigba ti wọn ṣi aṣọ dudu ti wọn da bori, mo ri i pe ọlọpaa EFCC ni wọn, mo pariwo pe ‘kinla!’ ni ọga wọn ba paṣẹ pe ki n gbẹnu dakẹ. Wọn beere iṣẹ ti kaluku wa n ṣe, ẹmi ni akọroyin ni mi, aburo mi dahun pe dokita loun, ẹlomi-in ni ‘lọọya’ ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ, ni ọga wọn ba wo wa titi, o ni ‘a kan fakoko ṣofo wa sibi yii ni ṣa.’Mo beere pe ki wọn sọ adirẹsi wọn fun wa ki n le waa gba foonu ati kọmputa mi to wa lọwọ wọn, ọga naa ko fesi, o kan bẹrẹ si i da awọn dukia wa pada ni, pẹlu kọmputa ati foonu mi. O ni ka ma binu, awọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ kan lawọn n wa kiri.Ṣe bawọn EFCC ṣe n ṣe iṣẹ wọn ree? Bawo ni wọn ṣe de ile wa? Ta lo sọ fun wọn pe ki wọn wa? Gbogbo ẹ ko ye mi rara. Ọlọrun lo ni ki mama mi wa wa nibi lasiko naa.”Bẹẹ ni Nora royin ohun toju ẹ ri."},{"question":"Nitori ẹsun ipaniyan, adajọ sọ baba arugbo sẹwọn ni Kwara ","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ Majisreeti kan to wa niluu Ilọrin ti paṣẹ pe ki baba ẹni ọgọta ọdun le marun-un kan, Abdulsalam Saheed Akanbi, lọọ maa gbatẹgun lọgba ẹwọn Mandala, to wa ni Ilọrin, ipinlẹ Kwara, fẹsun pe o ṣeku pa ọmọkunrin ẹni ọdun mọkandinlogun kan, Sanni Abubakar, niluu Bode-Saadu, nijọba ibilẹ Moro, nipinlẹ Kwara.Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọṣẹ yii, ni Zacchaeus Folorunsho wọ Akanbi lọ siwaju Majisreeti Abdulraheem Bello, fẹsun pe o lọwọ ninu iku ọmọ oun ti wọn ba oku rẹ ninu igbo, tori pe wọn ri ibi ti baba naa ti da erupẹ bo ẹjẹ ọmọ ọhun mọlẹ ninu oko rẹ. O rọ ile-ẹjọ ko ma ṣe gba beeli baba naa.Majistreeti Bello ko fakoko ṣofo to fi ni ki wọn maa gbe ọmọkunrin naa lọ si ọgba ẹwọn Mandala titi ti igbẹjọ mi-in yoo fi waye ni ọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun 2021 yii."},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra an'ilay boky mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"The Vincent Boys\\"?","answer":"Ny mpanoratra an'ilay boky mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"The Vincent Boys\\" dia i Abbi Glines."},{"question":"சனிக்கிழமையைத் தொடர்ந்து வரும் நாள் என்ன?","answer":"சனிக்கிழமையைத் தொடர்ந்து வரும் நாள் ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை ஆகும். ஞாயிறு, பெரும்பாலும் \\"ஓய்வு நாள்\\" என்று குறிப்பிடப்படுகிறது, இது உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள பலரின் இதயங்களில் ஒரு சிறப்பு இடத்தைப் பிடித்துள்ளது. இந்த நேசத்துக்குரிய நாள், பொதுவாக பாரம்பரிய ஏழு நாள் வாரத்தின் முடிவில் அமைந்துள்ளது, அமைதி, பிரதிபலிப்பு மற்றும் பல்வேறு ஓய்வு நேர நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கான வாய்ப்பின் தனித்துவமான கலவையை வழங்குகிறது."},{"question":"ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਲਘੂ ਕਾਲੀਨ ਉਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਕੀ ਲਾਭ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ?","answer":"ਇਸਦਾ ਸਿਰਫ ਇੱਕ ਹੀ ਲਾਭ ਹੈ, ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਸਵਾਰਥ ਸੰਤੁਸ਼ਟੀ । ਪੇੜ-ਪੌਦਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੱਟ ਕੇ ਅਸੀਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਵਾਰਥ ਦੀ ਪੂਰਤੀ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਪਰ ਇਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੋਚਦੇ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਨ ਅਸੰਤੁਲਿਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਸੰਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਦੋਹਣ ਲਈ ਘੱਟ ਸਮਾਂ ਕਾਲ ਦੇ ਉਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਪਰਿਯੋਜਨਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੁੱਝ ਸੋਚ ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਬਣਾਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Cad a dhéanfá dá mbeifeá i do Thaoiseach ar an tír? An bhfuil tú sásta leis an Taoiseach ag an am sin?","answer":"Ar ndóigh post tábhachtach is ea post an taoisigh, agus tá go leor dualgaisí difriúla ag baint leis. Bíonn muid ag brath go mór ar chinntí an Taoisigh, mar sin bheadh orm a lán machnaimh a dhéanamh ar an gceist sin. Tá rudaí áirithe níos práinní ná a chéile, mar shampla chuirfinn níos mó áiseanna ar fáil do dhaoine óga. Chuirfinn stop le caimiléireacht dífhostaíocht agus fadhb na ndrugaí. Fairis sin, d'athródh mé an bonneagar i gceantair thuaithe, mar Iarthar Chorcaí"},{"question":"خلاصه مقاله رو بگو:  (CNN) -- سوریه می گوید که نتایج یک رای گیری در مورد تغییر در قانون اساسی این کشور در روز دوشنبه در دسترس خواهد بود، رای گیری که در حالی صورت گرفت که نیروهای دولتی به ضرب و شتم دژ مخالفان حمص و دیگر شهرها ادامه دادند. فعالان اپوزیسیون روز یکشنبه گزارش دادند که حداقل 55 نفر در سراسر کشور کشته شده اند، از جمله 25 نفر در حمص که بیش از سه هفته است تحت بمباران است. با وجود خشونت های مداوم، رای گیری در مورد آنچه که دولت رئیس جمهور بشار اسد به عنوان یک حرکت به سمت اصلاحات می نامد، برگزار شد. وزیر کشور محمد الشعیر گفت که رای گیری در اکثر استان ها \\"به طور عادی\\" انجام شد و مشارکت \\"بسیار زیاد بود... به جز در برخی مناطق\\" ، آژانس خبری دولتی سوریه گزارش داد. سانا گفت که نتایج این رای گیری در عصر دوشنبه اعلام خواهد شد. اما تحلیلگران و معترضان، رفراندوم قانون اساسی را مسخره می کنند و آن را به عنوان یک نمایش در نمایشگاه می دانند، آخرین اقدام در یک سری اقدامات سطحی که هدف آن آرام کردن منتقدان اسد است. سرهنگ محمد همادو، سخنگوی ارتش آزاد سوریه، گفت که غیرنظامیان گزارش داده اند که مقامات دولتی بر آنها فشار می آورند تا از قانون اساسی جدید حمایت کنند. خانواده اسد چهار دهه است که بر سوریه حکومت می کنند. اندرو تبلر، کارشناس سوریه در موسسه واشنگتن برای سیاست های خاور نزدیک، گفت که رئیس جمهور از این رفراندوم استفاده می کند تا \\"مردم را از خیابان ها خارج کند\\" پس از تقریبا یک سال شورش. کمیته های هماهنگی محلی سوریه، شبکه ای از فعالان مخالفان، گفته اند که از زمان آغاز سرکوب دولت علیه مخالفان در ماه مارس گذشته، حدود ۹۰۰۰ نفر کشته شده اند. دولت سوریه می گوید که بیش از ۲۰۰۰ نفر از نیروهای امنیتی آن در این دوره توسط \\"تروریست ها\\" کشته شده اند، از جمله هفت \\"شهید\\" که روز یکشنبه دفن شدند. سی ان ان و سایر رسانه ها نمی توانند گزارش های مخالفان یا دولت را به طور مستقل تأیید کنند، زیرا سوریه دسترسی روزنامه نگاران خارجی را به شدت محدود کرده است. ولي بيشتر گزارشات از زمين نشون ميده که نيروهاي دولت در تلاش براي از بين بردن مخالفان شهروندان رو کشتار ميکنن...","answer":"خلاصه مقاله:در سوریه علیرغم وجود جنگ داخلی، یک رای گیری در مورد تغییر قانون اساسی انجام شده است و نتایج آن روز دوشنبه اعلام خواهد شد. علیرغم بالا بودن درگیری‌ها در حمص، وزیر کشور اعلام کرده است که رای گیری در اکثر استان‌ها به صورت عادی و با مشارکت بالا برگزار شده است. این در حالی است که تحلیلگران و معترضان رفراندوم قانون اساسی را مسخره و نمایشی و آن را وسیله‌ای برای بازگرداندن مردم به خانه‌هایشان می‌دانند. همچنین از آمار کشته شدگان در درگیری‌های داخلی سوریه نمی‌توان مطمئن بود چون سوریه دسترسی روزنامه نگاران خارجی را به شدت محدود کرده است."},{"question":" Em qual esporte são usadas as mãos para fazer gol?","answer":"Handball."},{"question":"\\"Nandeha nijery lalao baolina kitra niaraka tamin'ny namako iray aho:\\"A. Niala teo amin'ny toerana vao voalohany ny lalao noho ny nahafaliana.B. Nijery sy nifaly tamin'ny lalao izahay.","answer":"Ny valiny B. \\"Nijery sy nifaly tamin'ny lalao izahay.\\" no fiafaran'ny tantara mitombona indrindra eto."},{"question":"रिझर्व्ह बँक ऑफ इंडियाचे डेप्युटी गव्हर्नर बनणारी पहिली भारतीय महिला कोण आहे?(A) के. जे. उदेशी(B) प्रतिभा राय(C) मधुर जाफरी(D) यांपैकी नाही=>","answer":"(A) के. जे. उदेशी"},{"question":"Ý chính của phần 5 trong bài Vì sao chúng ta phải đối xử thân thiện với động vật in trong Bách khoa tri thức tuổi trẻ xuất bản năm 2016 là gì?","answer":"Ý chính của phần 5 là con người cần thay đổi để bảo vệ động vật."},{"question":"Iza moa ny mpanjakavavy malagasy nanohitra ny fitaoman’i Eoropa tamin’ny taonjato faha-19?","answer":"ny mpanjaka Ranavalona I no mpanjakavavy malagasy nanohitra ny fitaoman’i Eoropa tamin’ny taonjato faha-19"},{"question":"‘To ba fi maa di ọdun 2023, ẹgbẹ APC yoo ti run Naijiria womuwomu’","answer":"Awọn agbaagba ilẹ Hausa ti wọn wa ninu ẹgbẹ Northern Elders Forum (NEF) ti figbe bọnu, wọn ni pẹlu bi nnkan ṣe n lọ yii, ti ko ba si ayipada, o da awọn loju pe ẹgbẹ oṣelu All Progressive Congress (APC) to n ṣakoso lọwọ yii yoo ti run Naijiria womuwomu to ba fi maa di ọdun 2023 ti gbogbo eeyan n foju sọna fun.Agbẹnusọ ẹgbẹ naa, Ọmọwe Hakeem Baba-Ahmed lo sọrọ yii lori eto tẹlifiṣan Channels kan lalẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, lorukọ ẹgbẹ naa.Ẹgbẹ naa di ẹbi ipo ti orileede yii wa ru awọn oloṣelu, o lawọn ni wọn fa a, ati pe aisi aabo to peye, to mu ki awọn janduku agbebọn ati ajinigbe maa jaye ọlọba ko ṣadeede ṣẹlẹ, awọn oloṣelu lo ti jẹ ki nnkan wọ latilẹ.O ni ere ti awọn ẹgbẹ oṣelu n sa bayii ko kọja bi wọn ṣe fẹẹ jawe olubori ninu eto idibo gbogbogboo lọdun 2023, wọn o tiẹ ronu bi wọn ṣe fẹẹ tun orileede yii ṣe ko too di ọdun naa.“Kin ni wọn fẹẹ ṣe lọdun 2023, leyii to jẹ pe laarin ọdun kan aabọ to ku yii, ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC yoo ti fẹyin Naijiria janlẹ, ṣe orileede ti wọn ti maa run womuwomu leeyan fẹẹ ṣe nnkan kan si, bẹẹ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP lo bi APC.‘‘Fun apẹẹrẹ, a ti ri mọkumọku ti APC n ṣe lọwọ, ṣugbọn eto to ṣe gunmọ wo lẹ ri lọdọ ẹgbẹ mi-in nipa ipese iṣẹ, atunṣe ọrọ-aje ati okoowo, tabi ti ọrọ eto aabo to mẹhẹ. Ko si.”Bakan naa ni Baba-Ahmed sọ pe bawọn gomina ṣe n yọ fokifoki lati ẹgbẹ oṣelu kan si omi-in ko ya oun lẹnu, ko si sidii fun ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP lati figbe ta lori eyi tori oun o ri iyatọ laarin ẹgbẹ oṣelu mejeeji, ọkan naa ni kan-un ni wọn, bi ẹnikan ṣe n bọ aṣọ PDP lọrun ti wọn n wọ ti APC, bẹẹ lawọn mi-in n fa ti APC ya, ti wọn n da agbada PDP."},{"question":"閣議に関する事項のまとめ役であり、同時に総理大臣のスポークスマンを務める内閣のポストは何でしょう？","answer":"（内閣）官房長官"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai benang dilanda ayam\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kusut masai"},{"question":"উদ্ভিজ্জ স্যুপ তৈরির প্রক্রিয়া ব্যাখ্যা কর","answer":"চিকেন স্টক বা রাইস স্টক প্রস্তুত করুন। তাজা টমেটো, আলু, ক্যাপসিকাম, পেঁয়াজ, মরিচ, গাজর, লাউ, কুমড়া এবং অন্যান্য সবজি কেটে নিন। এগুলিকে একটি বাটিতে যুক্ত করুন। এতে স্টক যোগ করুন এবং আধা ঘন্টা ফুটতে দিন। রুটির কাঠি দিয়ে পরিবেশন করুন।"},{"question":"Rumor has it that 6504 is the answer to 2011 సంవత్సర ఉలిందకొండ గ్రామ జనాభా సంఖ్య ఎంత?","answer":"ఉలిందకొండ, కర్నూలు జిల్లా, కల్లూరు మండలానికి చెందిన గ్రామము.[1]. పిన్ కోడ్:518 218. ఎస్.టి.డి కోడ్:08518.ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన కల్లూరు (కర్నూలు) నుండి 20 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన కర్నూలు నుండి 23 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 1378 ఇళ్లతో, 6504 జనాభాతో 2719 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 3137, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 3367. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 1302 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 420. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 593898[2].పిన్ కోడ్: 518218."},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira do Gabão.","answer":"A bandeira do Gabão é composta por três faixas horizontais de igual largura: verde no topo, amarela no meio e azul na parte inferior.O desenho da bandeira foi inspirado pela geografia do país:- O verde representa as florestas;- O azul o oceano Atlântico;- O amarelo representa o sol e a linha do equador, por isso está posicionada no centro da bandeira."},{"question":"Which British action actor played the part of Lee Christmas alongside Sylvester Stallone in the film The Expendables?","answer":"The British action actor who played the part of Lee Christmas alongside Sylvester Stallone in the film \\" The Expendables \\" is Jason Statham."},{"question":"Idayari yami: impelasontoA uSenzoEkugcineni, usuku ebengilufisa seluze lwafika. NguMgqibelo namuhla futhi usuku lwami lokuzalwanjengoba ngineminyaka eyishumi nesithupha. Angilicelanga ikhekhe elibhakwe ekhaya kulokhukodwa abazali bami bangithengele yonke into engibacele yona – angikholwa! Ngiyacabanga ukuthiudadewethu nomfowethu bese bekhathele yimi ngibaxoxela ngokuthi ngifisa lube njani lolu suku.Sekuphele amasonto amaningi ngilungiselela futhi ngicabanga ngalolu suku. Angikholwa ukuthiangilalanga ngicabanga ubumnandi esizoba nabo mina nabangane bami. Bonke abangane bamibangitshelile ukuthi bazofika ekhaya lami ngehora lokuqala. Ngiyathemba ukuthi abangane bamibangithengele izipho ezinhle. Ubani ngempela ongazithandi izipho.B uZandleLolu suku belulude kodwa futhi lube mnandi kakhulu. Abangane bami bangijabulise kakhulungokuzongihalalisela emva kokuphumelela emncintiswaneni wokugijima obungempelasontoedlule. Khona ngangingakholwa nami ukuthi yimi lo osekwazi ukugijima ibanga elide kangaka.Bengingakulindele ukuthi abangane bami bangihalalisele ngokungithelenga izinto eziningi kangaka.Noma ngingeyena umuntu othanda izipho kakhulu kodwa ngiyazi ukuthi uma uthola izipho lokhokukhombisa ukuthi abantu bakukhonzile. Mina kungenze ngaba namahloni kodwa ngabona futhiukuthi abangane bami bangithanda kangakanani. Angazi ukuthi yini engiyenzile ukuba ngifanelweukwenzelwa into enhle kangaka. Ngithole izinto eziningi kakhulu futhi ebengihlale ngifisa ukubanazo kodwa ebengingakabi nawo amandla okuzithengela zona. Ukuba nabangane abafana nalabakungikhumbuza izimfundiso zikamama wami zokuthi kubalulekile ukukhetha abangane abajabulanawe futhi bakweseke.C uMattAbantu abaningi bajwayele ukusho ukuthi abezwani nezingane zakubo. Bayaxabana njalo futhiabalekelelani. Lokhu kubi ngempela. Ngiyawuthanda umndeni wami. Senza izinto ezahlukene.Kwesinye isikhathi udadewethu uthanda ukulalela umculo ekamelweni lakhe kanti mina nomfowethusidlala ibhola. Sivame ukudlala umdlalo wamakhadi noma umdlalo webhodi ngempelasonto futhisiyahleka siphinde sikhale kwezinye izikhathi. Ngithemba ukuthi izingane zami ziyofana nathi. Nomasingefani, siyezwana kakhulu, futhi asithandi ukuxabana. Siyadumala uma oyeda wethu engaphilile.Nginesiqiniseko ukuthi ubaba nomama bayaziqhenya ngathi.D uKhethiweLolu bekuwusuku oluhle kimi. Ubaba wami ungisizile ukuthi sithenge yonke into engiyidingayoukubhaka ikhekhe futhi umama ungithembisile ukuthi uzongisiza uma esebuyile emsebenzini.Yisona sipho engizosipha umngane wami uSamantha. Ukubhaka kuyiyona ndlela engiziphumuzangayo nokuthatha ikhefu emsebenzini wami wesikole. Uthisha wami uthi kumele senze nezinyeizinto ngaphandle komsebenzi wesikole. Ukubhaka kungisize ukuba ngifunde ukuthi ezinye izintokumele zilindwe. Kumele ulandele iresiphi, ukuhlanganisa izithako, ulinde likhukhumale, ukulilindaliphole bese ulihlobisa bese uzwa ubumnandi. Ngiyazi umngane wami uzojabula ngoMsombulukouma esebona ngifika nekhekhe esikoleni.1. okukhonzile ukuchitha isikhathi nezingane zakubo?","answer":"C"},{"question":"No Egito antigo, quem foi a faraó Cleópatra?","answer":"Cleópatra VII, reinou de 51 a.C. até 30 a.C., e garantiu uma posição privilegiada para o Egito dentro do Império Romano."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Ở bảng A, U16 Việt Nam sẽ so tài với U16 Singapore, U16 Indonesia và U16 Philippines. Trong trận ra quân gặp U16 Singapore vào lúc 15h00 chiều nay, thầy trò HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn quyết giành chiến thắng để có sự khởi đầu thuận lợi tại giải. Ngay sau tiếng còi khai cuộc của trọng tài, U16 Việt Nam chủ động chơi tấn công và giành quyền kiểm soát thế trận. Phút thứ 8, đoàn quân của HLV Quốc Tuấn đã có bàn mở tỷ số. Hữu Trọng là người lập công sau pha dứt điểm chính xác. Việc được gặp U16 Singapore là cơ hội để thầy trò HLV Quốc Tuấn không chỉ chiến thắng, mà còn ghi nhiều bàn thắng để có hiệu số phụ tốt. Phút 23, Đức Thiện nâng tỷ số lên 2-0 cho U16 Việt Nam. Sau hai bàn dẫn trước, U16 Việt Nam bắt đầu giảm nhịp độ trận đấu. Thời tiết nắng nóng tại Yogiakarta (Indonesia) là một phần nguyên nhân khiến U16 Việt Nam buộc phải có sự điều chỉnh về lối chơi nhằm duy trì thể lực trong 90 phút. Trong khi đó, các cầu thủ U16 Singapore cũng không có nhiều cơ hội nguy hiểm. Đội bóng này chủ yếu sử dụng những đường chuyền dài nhưng không gây ra khó khăn với hàng phòng ngự U16 Việt Nam. Tuy nhiên, ngay trước khi hiệp 1 khép lại, U16 Singapore đã tận dụng được khoảng thời gian chơi chậm lại của U16 Việt Nam để ghi bàn rút ngắn tỷ số còn 1-2. Người lập công là Ramli. Tuy nhiên, chỉ đúng một phút sau, Xuân Toản sút tung lưới U16 Singapore, nâng tỷ số lên 3-1 cho U16 Việt Nam. Đây cũng là tỷ số cuối cùng của hiệp 1. Đầu hiệp 2, lưới của U16 Singapore tiếp tục rung lên. Người ghi bàn nâng tỷ số lên 4-1 cho U16 Việt Nam là Đức Thiện. Đây cũng là bàn thắng thứ 2 của chân sút này. Với khoảng cách an toàn, U16 Việt Nam không còn tràn lên tấn công như đầu hiệp đấu. HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn cũng có một số thay đổi về cách chơi và con người giúp các học trò đảm bảo được thể lực cho những trận đấu tiếp theo. Trước khi trận đấu khép lại, U16 Việt Nam ấn định chiến thắng 5-1. Với kết quả này, đội bóng áo đỏ tạm dẫn đầu bảng A. Ở lượt trận thứ 2, U16 Việt Nam gặp U16 Philippines vào lúc 15h00 ngày 3/8. Đội hình xuất phát U16 Việt Nam: Phạm Đình Hải, Nguyễn Hữu Trọng, Khúc Trung Hiếu, Nguyễn Lương Tuấn Khải, Lê Đình Long Vũ, Nguyễn Công Phương, Lê Văn Thuận, Vi Đình Thượng, Nguyễn Xuân Toàn, Bùi Hoàng Sơn, Phan Thanh Đức Thiện.","answer":"\\"U16 Việt Nam thắng đậm Singapore ở trận ra quân giải Đông Nam Á\\"."},{"question":"What happens when diffraction is observed with an increasing number of slits?","answer":"The sharpness and intensity of principal maxima increase with the increase in the numberof slits, and using a large number of slits. say couple of thousands, the principal maximaJust reduce to sharp, bright lines. This helps increase the resolving power of a grating."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kurang tambah-menambah, senteng bilai-membilai'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sesuatu pekerjaan hendaklah dikerjakan bersama-sama (dengan bergotong-royong) supaya sempurna"},{"question":"வினா:வீட்டுக்கு வந்த விருந்தாளியை வரவேற்க ஆளில்லை. அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை:செருப்பு. நடக்கும் போது காலில் அணிந்து செல்ல பயன்படும், பொதுவாக மிருகங்களின் தோலினால் செய்யப்பட்ட ஒரு அணிகலன்."},{"question":"A = {2, 6} అయిన A కి గల ఉపసమితుల సంఖ్య ?","answer":"4."},{"question":"menene maanar kalmar: \\"worry\\" ke nufi a harshen Hausa? ","answer":"Kalmar \\"worry\\" na nufin damuwa\\" a harshen Hausa"},{"question":"Nandritra ny firy taona i Didier Ratsiraka no nanao sesitany ny tenany tany Frantsa?","answer":"Nandritra ny sivy taona i DIdier Ratsiaraka no nanao sesitany ny tenany tany Frantsa."},{"question":"Tôi bị cân mắt trái 1.75 diop, mắt phải 2 diop. Tôi xin hỏi là có nên mổ cận không? Hay dùng biện pháp nào hiệu quả nhất để không bị cận nữa hoặc không tăng độ cận nữa?","answer":"Nếu bạn thực sự có những nhu cầu như lái xe, chơi thể thao, bơi, thẩm mỹ…. thì bạn hoàn toàn có thể phẫu thuật mắt để không còn phải đeo kính. Trước đây, phẫu thuật còn có những điểm hạn chế, và một tỉ lệ nhỏ biến chứng. Ngày nay phương pháp phẫu thuật đã an toàn hơn rất nhiều, tránh được các biến chứng, không đau, nhẹ nhàng, đem đến thị lực tốt nên cũng là sự tin tưởng để bạn có thể lựa chọn."},{"question":"Sheeg Ninkii Waqtigii Nabiga Scw Noolaa Nabinimada Sheegtay?","answer":"Waxa La Oran Jiray Musaylamatul Kadaab."},{"question":"Awọn araalu tun ṣawari ibi ti wọn ko ounjẹ korona si l’Akurẹ, ni wọn ba ko gbogbo rẹ","answer":"Kaakiri ipinlẹ ni awọn araalu ti n wa ile ẹru ti ijọba ko ounjẹ korona to yẹ ki wọn ti pin fun araalu, ṣugbọn ti wọn ko pin in bayii. Erongba wọn ni lati lọ sibe, ki wọn si pin ounjẹ naa laarin ara wa.Ni bayii, ipinlẹ bii mẹta ni wọn ti ri awọn ounje naa tẹle, ipinlẹ Ondo naa ti kun wọn bayii pẹlu bi wọn ṣe ri ile ti wọn ko ounjẹ naa si to wa nitosi ile-ẹjọ giga to wa niluu Akurẹ. N ni awọn araalu ba ya bo ibẹ. Yẹbẹyẹbẹ ni wọn gbọn ile ounjẹ naa. Afigba ti wọn ko gbogbo ounjẹ to wa nibe tan ni ọjọ Abamẹta ki wọn too kuro nibẹ.Ipinlẹ Eko ni wọn ti kọkọ bẹrẹ kinni naa, nigba ti wọn ri ile ẹru nla ti wọn ko awọn ounjẹ iranwọ korona yii si ni ibi kan ti wọn n pe ni Monkey Village, niluu Eko. Niṣe ni awọn eeyan ya bo ibẹ, ti wọn si ko gbogbo ohun jijẹ to wa nibẹ bii irẹsi, ororo, indomine ati bẹẹ beẹ lọ. Bẹẹ ni wọn ri ile ẹru yii mi-in ni Apapa, ti wọn si ko gbogbo ohun to wa nibẹ.Afi bo ṣe di aarọ ọjọ Abamẹta ti ariwo tun gbalẹ pe wọn ti ri iru ile ounjẹ yii kan naa ni ilu Ẹdẹ, nipinlẹ Ọṣun. N lawọn araalu ba ya bo ibẹ, wọn si ko o tan patapata. Bẹẹ ni wọn ni awọn ara Ileṣa lọ si Irojo, nibi ti ijọba apapọ maa n ko ounjẹ pamọ si, ti wọn si ko gbogbo rẹ.Ọrọ ko yọ ipinlẹ Kwara silẹ, niṣe lawọn eeyan ya bo ile ẹru yii, ti awọn naa si ko gbogbo ounjẹ to wa nibẹ.Ibeere tawọn eeyan n beere ni pe ki lo de ti ijọba ko ounjẹ yii pamọ ti wọn ko si pin in fun araalu titi ti korona fi tan nilẹ pẹlu bawọn eeyan ṣe n pariwo ebi to lasiko korona."},{"question":"知能指数をアルファベット２文字でいうと何でしょう？","answer":"ＩＱです。"},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Эже энеден кийинки эле жарчымсың , сиз жашоодогу эң мыкты насаатчысыз. Бул күн баары сиздики!"},{"question":"வினா: இந்திய டெஸ்ட் கிரிக்கெட் அணிக்கு 21 வயதிலேயே கேப்டனானவர் யார்? ","answer":"விடை: நவாப் பட்டோடி"},{"question":"कोष्ठकमा दिइएका मध्येबाट उपयुक्त शब्द भरी वाक्य पूरा गर्नुहोस् :(क) फूलको समावेश्य शब्द ............... हो । (भानु, जुनार, बेली)(ख) बोडीको समावेशक शब्द ............... हो । (तरकारी, फलपूmल, साग)(ग) अन्नको समावेश्य शब्द ............... होइन । (कोदो, केरा, फापर)(घ) रुखको समावेश्य शब्द ............... हो । (कटुस, अम्रिसो, दुबो)(ङ) जुनारको समावेशक शब्द ............... हो । (अन्न, तरकारी, फल)(च) नदीको समावेशक शब्द ..... होइन । (बाग्मती, सगरमाथा, नारायणी)","answer":"(क) फूलको समावेश्य शब्द बेली हो ।(ख) बोडीको समावेशक शब्द फलपूmल हो ।(ग) अन्नको समावेश्य शब्द फापर होइन ।(घ) रुखको समावेश्य शब्द अम्रिसो हो ।(ङ) जुनारको समावेशक शब्द तरकारी हो ।(च) नदीको समावेशक शब्द सगरमाथा होइन ।"},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de paragraaf: FC Twente begon al vroeg aan het nieuwe seizoen. Al in februari werd de eerste speler gecontracteerd. In aanloop naar de eerste training in juni werd deze periode vooral gekenmerkt door het vertrek van Theo Janssen naar Ajax en hoofdtrainer Michel Preud'homme naar Al Shabab. Daarnaast was de club natuurlijk nog volop bezig met het &lt;a href=\\"FC%20Twente%20in%20het%20seizoen%202010/11%20%28mannen%29\\"&gt;seizoen 2010/11&lt;/a&gt;. Ook waren er diverse speler actief voor hun land na het competitieslot. Onder andere Luuk de Jong, Nacer Chadli, Nikolaj Michajlov, Emir Bajrami, Ola John en Steven Berghuis speelden in deze periode nog. Voor Bryan Ruiz duurde het seizoen het lang. Met Costa Rica nam hij deel aan de Gold Cup","answer":". Zijn ploeg reikte tot aan de kwartfinales, waarna het werd uitgeschakeld. Voor Roberto Rosales duurt het seizoen echter nog langer. Hij werd geselecteerd voor de Copa América die voor Venezuela op 3 juli begon en op zijn vroegst op 13 juli eindigde."},{"question":"Pregunta: ¿Cuándo lanzó Linkin Park su primer álbum? Respuesta:","answer":"Hybrid Theory, el primer álbum de Linkin Park, fue lanzado en el año 2000."},{"question":"Qual o principal compositor da música “ Getaway Car”, além de Taylor Swift? ","answer":"Seu amigo e produtor, Jack Antonoff."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න.තරුමල් යායම පොඩිකර අහස් විලේඉර හඳ මිරිකා දියකර සාගරයේඅදුරේ උන්නෙමි ලොවම එපාවීමා හැර දා ඈ ගිය දවසේ","answer":"තරුමල් යායම පොඩිකර අහස් විලේඉර හඳ මිරිකා දියකර සාගරයේඅදුරේ උන්නෙමි ලොවම එපාවීමා හැර දා ඈ ගිය දවසේදුක පැවසූවෙමි අසනා කෙනෙක් නැතීපාළු නැසූවෙමි තනියට කෙනෙක් නැතීතැවුනේ දැවුනේ පිරිසිදු සිතකින්එකම ළඳක් වෙත පෙම්කළ උමතුවෙනිතරුමල් යායම පොඩිකර අහස් විලේඉර හඳ මිරිකා දියකර සාගරයේඅදුරේ උන්නෙමි ලොවම එපාවීමා හැර දා ඈ ගිය දවසේනුවර උයන් මැද හමුවූ ළඳුන් නැතීයටැසින් බැලු නෙත් රහසින් කතා නැතිතැවුනේ දැවුනේ පිරිසිදු සිතකින්එකම ළඳක් වෙත පෙම්කළ නිසාවෙනිතරුමල් යායම පොඩිකර අහස් විලේඉර හඳ මිරිකා දියකර සාගරයේඅදුරේ උන්නෙමි ලොවම එපාවීමා හැර දා ඈ ගිය දවසේ"},{"question":"من هو نجيب محفوظ؟","answer":"نجيب محفوظ عبد العزيز إبراهيم أحمد الباشا، والمعروف باسمه الأدبي نجيب محفوظ، هو روائي، وكاتب مصري، يُعد أول أديب عربي حائز على جائزة نوبل في الأدب. كتب نجيب محفوظ منذ الثلاثينات، واستمر حتى 2004. تدور أحداث جميع رواياته في مصر، وتظهر فيها سمة متكررة هي الحارة التي تعادل العالم. من أشهر أعماله: الثلاثية، وأولاد حارتنا، والتي مُنعت من النشر في مصر منذ صدورها وحتى وقتٍ قريب. بينما يُصنف أدب محفوظ باعتباره أدباً واقعياً، فإن مواضيع وجودية تظهر فيه. يُعد محفوظ أكثر أديب عربي نُقلت أعماله إلى السينما والتلفزيون. "},{"question":"问题：除了制冷，冰块还有其他用途吗？","answer":"回答：是的，冰块还可以用于冷敷和减轻肿胀、缓解疼痛等。"},{"question":"Emi o fẹ ipo olori Amọtẹkun o, alaafia ile Yoruba lo jẹ mi logun-Sunday lgboho","answer":"Lori ahesọ ọrọ kan to ni i ṣe pẹlu pe  Sunday Igboho nífẹẹ sí láti jẹ adari ìkọ Amọtẹkun, ọkunrin to laya bíi kinniun yìí fesi pe “Emi o fẹ ipo Amọtẹkun kankan. Ohun ti emi n so ni pe ki awọn Fúlàní to n ji awọn ọmọ iya mi (awọn Yorùbá) gbe, to n pa wọn nipakupa, fi ilẹ baba wa silẹ.”Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ni kete ti Sunday Igboho lọ si ilu Igangan, lagbegbe Ibarapa, nipinlẹ Ọ̀yọ́, lati koju awọn Fulani yii, to si le gbogbo wọn danu, làwọn eeyan kan nílẹ̀ Yoruba ti n pariwo pe ki wọn gba ọkunrin naa sinu ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun, ki wọn si fi i ṣe olori wọn.Ṣugbọn ọkunrin naa ti sọ pe ki i ṣe lati di adari ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun lo jẹ oun logun bi ko ṣe bi alaafia yoo ṣe jọba kaakiri ilẹ Yoruba, ti gbogbo eeyan yoo si wa ni ifọkanbalẹ lai si ipaya awọn Fulani."},{"question":"Berikan resepi membuat Kek Lapis Kacang Tanah berserta cara-cara penyerdiaanya. ","answer":"Resepi Kek Lapis Kacang TanahBahan:15 butir telur ayam utuh (pisahkan kuning dan putih) 500 grm gula pasir 1 kaleng susu kental manis 300 gram kacang tanah,disangray,dihaluskan.400 gram mentega1sdt panili.Caranya:Kocok mentega dengan setengah gula pasir sampai putih,masukan kuning telur kocok lagi sampai kembang,.Dilain tempat kocok putih telur dgn gula yang setengahnya lagi. Sampai kaku.Sesudah itu campurkan kocokan kuning sama putihnya tadi, aduk pelan pelan, masukan susu,panili, dan terahir kacang tanah, sesudah tercampur rata, siapkan loyang ukuran 18×18.Bakar selapis selapis dgn api atas saja. Selamat mencoba."},{"question":"පෘථිවියේ විශාලතම සාගරය කුමක්ද?","answer":"පෘථිවියේ විශාලතම සාගරය පැසිෆික් සාගරය වේ."},{"question":"I wonder అమెరికాలో అతి పెద్ద చర్చి ఎక్కడ ఉంది?","answer":"కాథలిక్ చర్చి అనేది ఇటలీ లోని రోమ్ ప్రధాన కేంద్రంగా స్థాపించారు గనుక రోమన్ కాథలిక్ చర్చి గా కూడా సుపరిచితం, ప్రపంచం మొత్తంమీద అతిపెద్ద క్రైస్తవ చర్చిగా ఉంటోన్న ఇందులో ఒక బిలియన్ మందికి పైగా సభ్యులుగా ఉన్నారు.[1] కాలేజ్ ఆఫ్ బిషప్స్‌కు అధిపతిగా ఉండే పోప్ కాథలిక్ చర్చికి నాయకుడిగా వ్యవహరిస్తుంటారు. యేసు క్రీస్తు యొక్క సువార్తను విశ్వవ్యాప్తం చేయడంతో పాటుగా, క్రీస్తు బోధించిన ప్రేమ, సేవల ఆధారంగా సమాజ సేవ కూడా చేస్తుంది.ప్రపంచంలోనే అతి ప్రాచీన సంస్థల్లో ఒకటైన ఈ చర్చ్, పాశ్చాత్య నాగరికతలో ఒక ప్రముఖ పాత్రను పోషించింది.[2] యేసు క్రీస్తు ద్వారా ఇది స్థాపించబడినట్టుగానూ, బిషప్‌లను క్రీస్తు యొక్క శిష్యుల వారసులుగానూ భావించే ఈ చర్చ్, పోప్‌ను క్రీస్తుని ప్రధాన సేవకునిగా, క్రైస్తవ జగద్గురువుగా భావిస్తారు. చర్చ్‌కి సంబంధించిన సిద్ధాంతాలన్నీ క్రైస్తవసంబంధ కౌన్సిళ్లు ద్వారా నిర్వచింపబడడంతో పాటు దాని విశ్వాసం మరియు అమోఘమైన నైతికతలను నిర్వచించగల హోలీ స్పిరిట్ (పవిత్ర ఆత్మ) ద్వారా చర్చ్ వీటిని నిర్వహిస్తుంది.[3][note 1][4] కాథలిక్ ఆరాధన అనేది యూచరిస్ట్ (మహాప్రసాదము) కేంద్రంగా సాగుతుంది, రొట్టె మరియు ద్రాక్ష సారాయిలు మహాద్భుతమైన రీతిలో క్రీస్తు యొక్క శరీరం మరియు రక్తం రూపంలోకి మార్పుచెందుతాయని చర్చ్ బోధించడంపై ఈ ఆరాధన ఆధారపడి ఉంటుంది.ఈ చర్చ్ ప్రత్యేకమైన రీతిలో ఆశీర్వదించబడిన కన్య మేరీని కలిగి ఉంటుంది. కాథలిక్ విశ్వాసాలు ప్రకారం, జీవిత చరమాంకంలో మేరీ, ఆమె పరిశుద్ధ మాతృత్వం ఎటువంటి ప్రాథమిక పాపము యొక్క మరక లేకుండా శరీరంతో పాటుగా స్వర్గం ప్రవేశం చేయడం జరిగింది.పేరుగ్రీకు పదమైన καθολικός (కాథోలికోస్ ) అంటే \\"విశ్వవ్యాప్త\\" లేదా \\"సాధారణ\\" అని అర్థం, మరియు ఈ పదం καθόλου (కాథోలు )కు సమానార్థకంగా ఉంటోంది, \\"సమస్తం ప్రకారం\\" అనే అర్థాన్ని సూచించే κατὰ ὅλου (కట హోలు ) అనే పదబంధానికి ఇది సంకేతాక్షరంగా ఉంటోంది.[5] 2వ శతాబ్దం ప్రారంభంలో చర్చిని వర్ణించడం కోసం ఈ పదం మొదటిసారిగా ఉపయోగించబడింది.[6] 1054 తూర్పు-పశ్చిమ విరోధం నాటినుంచి, సీ ఆఫ్ రోమ్ (రోమ్ అధికార పరిథి మరియు దాని బిషప్, పోప్, ప్రాచీన కులపెద్ద) సమ్మేళనంలో ఉండే చర్చిలన్నీ \\"కాథలిక్‌\\"గా సుపరిచితాలు, అదేసమయంలో పోప్ యొక్క అధికారాన్ని తిరస్కరించిన తూర్పు చర్చిలన్నీ సాధారణంగా \\"ఆర్థడాక్స్\\" లేదా \\"తూర్పు ఆర్థడాక్స్‌\\"గా సుపరిచతమయ్యాయి.[7] 16వ శతాబ్దంలో చోటుచేసుకున్న సంస్కరణకు కొనసాగింపుగా, తమ..."},{"question":"Apakah maksud kleptokrasi?","answer":"Kleptokrasi merujuk kepada sistem di mana golongan pemerintah menggunakan kuasa mereka untuk memberi kekayaan kepada diri mereka di atas kesempatan yang diambil daripada hak orang awam. Amalan ini melibatkan penyelewengan kuasa, rasuah dan penggubahan wang haram yang memberikan kesan buruk kepada masyarakat. Pada masa yang sama juga, kleptokrasi sering mengakibatkan penumpuan kekakayaan di tangan segelintir individu sahaja dan menyebabkan jurang antara mereka yang kaya dan miskin semakin jauh. Intihannya, amalan negatif ini boleh menjejaskan kedaulatan undang-undang dan menghakis kepercayaan terhadap institusi negara kerana orang ramai percaya bahawa mereka yang berkuasa tidak bertindak demi kepentingan terbaik orang awam."},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:–Mu ne: \\"Aadama xamal-leen seeni tur; \\" Ba mu leen xamalee seeni tur, Yàlla ne leen: \\"Ndax dama leen a waxuloon ne Man xam naa kumpag asamaan ak suuf si, te it xam naa xéll li ngeen feeñal ak li ngeen doon ñëbb? \\"","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:–Mu ne: \\"Aadama xàmalléen séen i tur; \\"Ba mu léen xàmalee séen i tur, Yàlla ne léen: \\"Ndàx da ma léen a wàxuloon ne Màn xàm naa kumpag àsamaan ak sùuf si, te àt xàm naa xéll li ngéen feeñal ak li ngéen doon ñëbb?\\""},{"question":"එදා මෙදා තුර වැඩිම ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මාන ගණනක් දිනා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය චිත්‍රපටය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"එදා මෙදා තුර වැඩිම ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මාන ගණනක් දිනා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය චිත්‍රපටය වන්නේ විෂම භාග වේ. එය ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මාන 51ක් දිනා ඇත."},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Maty tsy maimbo, hani-tsy mahavoky.\\"","answer":"Ny valiny dia fanorona. Milaza ny fomba filalaovana fanorona, hoe misy ny maty fa tsy maty ara-bakiteny akory, ary misy ny mihinana fa tsy ara-bakiteny ihany koa."},{"question":"Nitori eto idibo Satide, wọn fofin de igbekegbodo ọkọ l’Ondo","answer":"Ọga agba patapata fun ileesẹ ọlọpaa Naiijiria, M. A. Adamu, ti ni ko ni i si igbokegbodo ọkọ kaakiri ipinlẹ Ondo latari eto idibo sipo gomina tito yoo waye ni ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.Ni ibamu pẹlu atẹjade ti Frank Mba to jẹ alukoro wọn fi sita, ofin yii lo ni o gbọdọ fẹsẹ mulẹ bẹrẹ lati aago mejila ku isẹju kan loru ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee,  si aago mẹfa irọlẹ ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, to jẹ ọjọ idibo gan-an.O ni fífi ofin de lílọ ati bibọ awọn ọkọ lọjọ idibo maa n ran awọn ẹsọ alaabo lọwọ lati tete mọ awọn onisẹ ibi, onijagidijagan atawọn to n gbero ati hu iwa ibajẹ kan tabi omiiran lasiko ti idibo ba n lọ lọwọ.Mba ni ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti ṣetan ati fi iya to tọ jẹ ẹnikẹni to ba gbìyànjú lati ja apoti ibo gba atawọn to ba fẹẹ ta tabi ra ibo lọjọ naa.O rọ awọn araalu lati jade, ki wọn si lọọ ṣe ojuṣe wọn ní ibamu pẹlu ofin nitori pe awọn ẹsọ alaabo ti wa ni sẹpẹ lati peṣe aabo to yẹ fun wọn."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸੋ ਦਰੁ ਕੇਹਾ ਸੋ ਘਰੁ ਕੇਹਾ ਜਿਤੁ ਬਹਿ ਸਰਬ ਸਮਾਲੇ ॥ਵਾਜੇ ਨਾਦ ਅਨੇਕ ਅਸੰਖਾ ਕੇਤੇ ਵਾਵਣਹਾਰੇ ॥ਕੇਤੇ ਰਾਗ ਪਰੀ ਸਿਉ ਕਹੀਅਨਿ ਕੇਤੇ ਗਾਵਣਹਾਰੇ ॥ਗਾਵਹਿ ਤੁਹਨੋ ਪਉਣੁ ਪਾਣੀ ਬੈਸੰਤਰੁ ਗਾਵੈ ਰਾਜਾ ਧਰਮੁ ਦੁਆਰੇ ॥ਗਾਵਹਿ ਚਿਤੁ ਗੁਪਤੁ ਲਿਖਿ ਜਾਣਹਿ ਲਿਖਿ ਲਿਖਿ ਧਰਮੁ ਵੀਚਾਰੇ ॥ਗਾਵਹਿ ਈਸਰੁ ਬਰਮਾ ਦੇਵੀ ਸੋਹਨਿ ਸਦਾ ਸਵਾਰੇ ॥ਗਾਵਹਿ ਇੰਦ ਇਦਾਸਣਿ ਬੈਠੇ ਦੇਵਤਿਆ ਦਰਿ ਨਾਲੇ ॥ਗਾਵਹਿ ਸਿਧ ਸਮਾਧੀ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਗਾਵਨਿ ਸਾਧ ਵਿਚਾਰੇ ॥ਗਾਵਨਿ ਜਤੀ ਸਤੀ ਸੰਤੋਖੀ ਗਾਵਹਿ ਵੀਰ ਕਰਾਰੇ ॥ਗਾਵਨਿ ਪੰਡਿਤ ਪੜਨਿ ਰਖੀਸਰ ਜੁਗੁ ਜੁਗੁ ਵੇਦਾ ਨਾਲੇ ॥ਗਾਵਹਿ ਮੋਹਣੀਆ ਮਨੁ ਮੋਹਨਿ ਸੁਰਗਾ ਮਛ ਪਇਆਲੇ ॥ਗਾਵਨਿ ਰਤਨ ਉਪਾਏ ਤੇਰੇ ਅਠਸਠਿ ਤੀਰਥ ਨਾਲੇ ॥ਗਾਵਹਿ ਜੋਧ ਮਹਾਬਲ ਸੂਰਾ ਗਾਵਹਿ ਖਾਣੀ ਚਾਰੇ ॥ਗਾਵਹਿ ਖੰਡ ਮੰਡਲ ਵਰਭੰਡਾ ਕਰਿ ਕਰਿ ਰਖੇ ਧਾਰੇ ॥ਸੇਈ ਤੁਧੁਨੋ ਗਾਵਹਿ ਜੋ ਤੁਧੁ ਭਾਵਨਿ ਰਤੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਭਗਤ ਰਸਾਲੇ ॥ਹੋਰਿ ਕੇਤੇ ਗਾਵਨਿ ਸੇ ਮੈ ਚਿਤਿ ਨ ਆਵਨਿ ਨਾਨਕੁ ਕਿਆ ਵੀਚਾਰੇ ॥ਸੋਈ ਸੋਈ ਸਦਾ ਸਚੁ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਸਾਚਾ ਸਾਚੀ ਨਾਈ ॥ਹੈ ਭੀ ਹੋਸੀ ਜਾਇ ਨ ਜਾਸੀ ਰਚਨਾ ਜਿਨਿ ਰਚਾਈ ॥ਰੰਗੀ ਰੰਗੀ ਭਾਤੀ ਕਰਿ ਕਰਿ ਜਿਨਸੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਜਿਨਿ ਉਪਾਈ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਰਿ ਵੇਖੈ ਕੀਤਾ ਆਪਣਾ ਜਿਵ ਤਿਸ ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ॥ਜੋ ਤਿਸੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਸੋਈ ਕਰਸੀ ਹੁਕਮੁ ਨ ਕਰਣਾ ਜਾਈ ॥ਸੋ ਪਾਤਿਸਾਹੁ ਸਾਹਾ ਪਾਤਿਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਰਹਣੁ ਰਜਾਈ ॥੨੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 6 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਉਹ ਦਰ-ਘਰ ਬੜਾ ਹੀ ਅਸਚਰਜ ਹੈ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਬਹਿ ਕੇ, (ਹੇ ਨਿਰੰਕਾਰ !) ਤੂੰ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ। ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਤੇ ਅਣਗਿਣਤ ਵਾਜੇ ਤੇ ਰਾਗ ਹਨ; ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੀ ਜੀਵ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਜਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ) ਵਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਨ, ਰਾਗਣੀਆਂ ਸਣੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੀ ਰਾਗ ਕਹੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਹੀ ਜੀਵ (ਇਹਨਾਂ ਰਾਗਾਂ ਦੇ) ਗਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਨ (ਜੋ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ) !ਹੇ ਨਿਰੰਕਾਰ !) ਪਉਣ, ਪਾਣੀ, ਅਗਨੀ ਤੇਰੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਧਰਮ-ਰਾਜ ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ’ਤੇ (ਖਲੋ ਕੇ) ਤੈਨੂੰ ਵਡਿਆਇ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਉਹ ਚਿੱਤਰ-ਗੁਪਤ ਭੀ ਜੋ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਚੰਗੇ-ਮੰਦੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਲੇਖੇ) ਲਿਖਣੇ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ, ਅਤੇ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖੇ ਹੋਏ ਨੂੰ ਧਰਮ-ਰਾਜ ਵਿਚਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇਰੀਆਂ ਵਡਿਆਈਆਂ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।(ਹੇ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ !) ਦੇਵੀਆਂ, ਸ਼ਿਵ ਤੇ ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾ, ਜੋ ਤੇਰੇ ਸਵਾਰੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ, ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਕਈ ਇੰਦਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਤਖ਼ਤ ’ਤੇ ਬੈਠੇ ਹੋਏ ਦੇਵਤਿਆਂ ਸਮੇਤ ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ’ਤੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸਲਾਹ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।ਸਿੱਧ ਲੋਕ ਸਮਾਧੀਆਂ ਲਾ ਕੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, ਸਾਧ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸਲਾਹ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਜਤ-ਧਾਰੀ, ਦਾਨ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਤੇ ਸੰਤੋਖ ਵਾਲੇ ਪੁਰਸ਼ ਤੇਰੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ (ਬੇਅੰਤ) ਤਕੜੇ ਸੂਰਮੇ ਤੇਰੀਆਂ ਵਡਿਆਈਆਂ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।(ਹੇ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ !) ਪੰਡਿਤ ਤੇ ਮਹਾਂਰਿਖੀ ਜੋ (ਵੇਦਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਪੜ੍ਹਦੇ ਹਨ। ਵੇਦਾਂ ਸਣੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਸੁੰਦਰ ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀਆਂ, ਜੋ ਸੁਰਗ, ਮਾਤ-ਲੋਕ ਤੇ ਪਾਤਾਲ ਵਿਚ (ਭਾਵ, ਹਰ ਥਾਂ) ਮਨੱੁਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੋਹ ਲੈਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ।(ਹੇ ਨਿਰੰਕਾਰ !) ਤੇਰੇ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਰਤਨ ਅਠਾਹਠ ਤੀਰਥਾਂ ਸਮੇਤ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਵੱਡੇ ਬਲ ਵਾਲੇ ਜੋਧੇ ਤੇ ਸੂਰਮੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਚੌਹਾਂ ਹੀ ਖਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਜੀਅ ਜੰਤ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ, ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਖੰਡ ਅਤੇ ਚੱਕਰ, ਜੋ ਤੂੰ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਟਿਕਾ ਰਖੇ ਹਨ, ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ।ਹੇ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ !) (ਅਸਲ ਵਿਚ ਤਾਂ) ਉਹੋ ਤੇਰੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਤੇ ਰਸੀਏ ਭਗਤ ਜਨ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਗਾਉਣਾ ਸਫਲ ਹੈ) ਜੋ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਚੰਗੇ ਲੱਗਦੇ ਹਨ। ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਹੋਰ ਜੀਵ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਗਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਹੜੇ ਮੈਥੋਂ ਗਿਣੇ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੇ। (ਭਲਾ) ਨਾਨਕ (ਵਿਚਾਰਾ) ਕੀਹ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ?ਉਹ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਾਲਕ ਸੱਚਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਭੀ ਸਦਾ ਅਟੱਲ ਹੈ।ਜਿਸ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਐਸ ਵੇਲੇ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ, ਸਦਾ ਰਹੇਗਾ, ਨਾਹ ਉਹ ਜੰਮਿਆ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਨਾਹ ਹੀ ਮਰੇਗਾ। ਜਿਸ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਨੇ ਕਈ ਰੰਗਾਂ, ਕਿਸਮਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਜਿਨਸਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਰਚ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਹੈ, (ਭਾਵ, ਜੇਡਾ ਵੱਡਾ ਆਪ ਹੈ ਓਡੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਜਿਗਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਜਗਤ ਨੂੰ ਰਚ ਕੇ) ਆਪਣੇ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਭੀ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹੋ ਹੀ ਕਰੇਗਾ, ਕਿਸੇ ਜੀਵ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਅੱਗੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ (ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਖ ਸਕਦੇ-‘ਇਉਂ ਨ ਕਰੀਂ, ਇਉਂ ਕਰ’)।ਅਕਾਲ  ਪੁਰਖ ਪਾਤਿਸ਼ਾਹ ਹੈ, ਪਾਤਿਸ਼ਾਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਭੀ ਪਾਤਿਸ਼ਾਹ ਹੈ। ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਉਸ  ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿਣਾ (ਹੀ ਫਬਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੨੭।\\""},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dalam ayat berikut dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai: Kasih sayang Puan Aida ________ anaknya tidak pernah padam.","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah \\"terhadap\\"."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fiantraikan'ny Doppler amin'ny astronomia ary ahoana no ampiasana azy hianarana kintana sy vahindanitra?","answer":"Ny fiantraikan'ny Doppler amin'ny astronomia dia ny fiovan'ny fatran'ny onjam-pahazavana na ny halavan'ny onjam-pahazavana noho ny fihetsehana mifandray eo amin'ny loharanon-jiro sy ny mpanara-maso. Ampiasaina izy io mba hamaritana ny hafainganam-pandehan'ny radial ny zavatra eny amin'ny lanitra, toy ny kintana sy ny vahindanitra. Amin'ny fandrefesana ny fihodinana mena na manga amin'ny tsipika spectral, ny astronoma dia afaka mamaritra raha misy zavatra miala na mankany amin'ny Tany, manome fampahalalana sarobidy momba ny fihetsehan'izao rehetra izao."},{"question":"السؤال: من الشخصان اللذان أرسلهما كفار قريش إلى الحبشة ليدعوا الملك إلى طرد المسلمين منها؟","answer":"الإجابة: عبد الله بن ربيعة وعمرو بن العاص"},{"question":"અહીં ગુજરાતી નાટક ના કલાકારો વચ્ચેની વાતો નીચે મુજબ આપેલી છે:\\"ઝુમ૦-વારૂ, વૈદરાજ, ઈનું મન પાછું ઠેકાણે આવશે ખરૂં ?ભોળા૦-એ વિદ્યાર્થી બહુ હોશિયાર છે. જુવો કલાક અડધા કલાકમાં એ એવું કામ કરશે કે તમારે બોલવું જ નહિ રહે.ઝુમ૦-જોયું કની કેવી રાંડ હઠીલી છે ?ભોળા૦-હોય. છોકરીઓનાં કામ એવાંજ હોયછ.ઝુમ૦-અરે ! રોંડ છગનિયાની પછાડી ઘેલી થ‌ઇ ગઈછ.ભોળા૦-હોય, જુવાનીનો જુસ્સો છે. પણ ગાંડી કે આવા પૈસાદારને પરણવાની ના કહેછ. આનંદ પછી કહાં જતો રહેવાનોછ ? એટલી એનામાં બીજાં બૈરાં જેટલી સમજ નહિ.ઝુમ૦-મ્હેં જે દહાડાનું જાણ્યું કે છગનિયાને પરણવાનું મન છે ત્યારની એને તાળામાંજ રાખી હતી.ભોળા૦-બહુ ડાહ્યું કામ કીધું. તાળામાં મહા ગુણછે, દેવાયતો.ઝુમ૦-મ્હેં એમને જરી મળવા નથી દીધાં. લઈને હરામખોર નાશી જાય તો પછી આપણે શું કરીયે ?ભોળા૦-પછી આપણે તો શું કરિયે ?ઝુમ૦-શોડીઓને કાયદામાં રાખવામાં તો હું હુંશિયાર છું. બધાને માલમછે કે બૈરાંને દાબમાં રાખવાની કળા તો મ્હારી પાસે છે. ને વૈદરાજ, એ કળા કંઈ સહેલી નથી. બહુ બુદ્ધિનું કામછે. હંકારતો રાજા રાવણના નથી રહ્યા. પણ હંકાર કરૂં તોએ ચાલે એવું છે. બીજો કોઈ બાપ હોય કની તો તેના હાથમાંથી ક્યારની નજર ચુકવીને રોંડ છગનિયાની સાથે પરણી બેઠી હોત.(શિવકોર આવે છે.)શિવ૦-પેલો લુચ્ચો, જુઠો, પાપી, ઢોંગી, વૈદ કહાંછ ?ઝુમ૦-અરે ! આ કુણ આવ્યું ?શિવ૦-કેમ કેમ ! પીટ્યા મને મારી નાખવી ધારીતી કે ?ભોળા૦-અરે આ ગાંડી બૈરી કોણ છે ? કહાંથી આવી ?ઝુમ૦-વૈદરાજ, ગરીબ જાણીને બચારીને કંઈ ઓશડ કરો.ભોળા૦-દક્ષણા વગર ઓસડ થાય નહિ તો. તમે દક્ષણા આપતા હો તો હમણાંને હમણાં એને સારી કરૂં.શિવ૦-પીટ્યા મને ઓસડ કરવા નિકળ્યો છે કે ? આવતો ખરો.\\"આ કલાકારો ની આગળની વાતો શું હશે?","answer":"ભોળા-(શિવકોરના કાનમાં) રાંડ, રોજ બરફી બરફી કરતી તે તને બરફી ખવડાવી. બૂમ શેની પાડેછ ? રૂપિયો મને આપ.શિવ૦-ઉભો રહે, પીટ્યા, તને રૂપિયો આપુંછ.(હરિયો અને કમાલખાં આવેછે)હરિ-દગો થયો ! દગો થયો ! આનંદલાલ વિદ્યાર્થીનો વેશ લઈને આવ્યો હતો તેની સાથે ચંદા તો પરણી, અને આ ચોર વૈદે-નથ્થુ૦-હેં ! હેં ! હેં ! પકડો તો કમબખ્તને ! મ્હારી સાથે દગો કીધો ? જાતો કમલખાં, ઢોંડોબા દાદાને ત્હાં. હમણાં એ સુબા પાસે એની ખબર લેવાડુંછ, એનું આપણે ત્હાં ખાતુંછે એટલે એતો આપણા કાચા સુતરનો બાંધેલોછ.ભોળા-કે તુટતાં વાર નહિ લાગે.નથ્થુ-હમણાં એને સુળીએ દેવડાવુંછ.કમા-હકીમજી, અબ તો તુમેરી આવી બની. (જાય છે.)ભોળા-ભાઈ, ત્હેં મારીને વૈદ કીધો તો તે હવે મને પાછો મારીને ખેડુત કરાવાના જો, રાંડ, હવે શી વલે થવાની.શિવ-તમારી પાસે રૂપિયા છે તે મને આપી દો નહિ તો તમને સુળીએ પણ દેશે ને રૂપિયા પણ પીટ્યા જપત કરશે.ભોળા-જા રાંડ, હિયાંથી, મને દુઃખ નહિ દે.શિવ-હું તો તમને સુળી આગળ હિંમત આપવા ઉભી રહીશ. તમારા દેહમાંથી પ્રાણ જશે ત્યારેજ ડાઘુને તેડવા જઈશ. ગભરાતા નહિ, તમારૂં સબ અભડાવવા નહિ દઊં, મ્હારે પુતળું કરવું પડે તો.(આનંદલાલ અને ચંદા આવેછે)ચંદા-હવે ગમે તે કરો. હું આવી.ઝુમ-રોંડ, મીંઢળ ને પાનેતર કહાંથી લાવી. પરણી કે ?આનંદ-બધું થઈ ચૂક્યું, હવે થુંક ઉરાડશો તે મિથ્યા ?નથ્થુ-હરિયા, આ ચોરને પણ પકડ ! આવા દગાનાં કામ કરે છે !આનંદ-શેઠ, લોટમાં પાણી પડ્યું તે નહિ પડ્યું થવાનું નથી.નથ્થુ-છિ.-તને બતાવું છું. કમાલ ઓ આવ્યો !કમા-શેઠ, આ કાગજ તાકીદકા હૈં, બાંચો ખેપિયા લેકર આયાહૈં.નથ્થુ-હેં ! કોઈની દુકાન તો ભાગી નથી. "},{"question":"Gwam okoro ọcha nchiche biri imi","answer":"Ozu"},{"question":"வினா:  ஈசாப் நீதிக் கதைகள் ஏதேனும் ஒன்றினைக்   கூறுக .","answer":"விடை:                       கதையின் தலைப்பு                   விவசாயி மகன்- கழுதைஒரு முறை விவசாயி ஒருவர் தன்னுடைய கழுதையை விற்று விடத் தீர்மானித்தார். அருகிலுள்ள கிரமாத்துக்குத் தன் கழுதையையும், மகனையும் அழைத்துக் கொண்டு சென்றார். அவர்கள் இருவரும் கழுதையை இழுத்துக் கொண்டு நடந்தே போனார்கள்.செல்லும்போது அதைப்பார்த்த வழிப் போக்கர் ஒருவர் இவர்களைப் பார்த்துச் சிரித்தார். பிறகு, ‘கழுதை சும்மாதானே செல்கிறது. யாராவது ஒருவர் அதன் மீது ஏறிச் செல்லலாமே’ என்று  கூறினார். அதுவும் சரியென்று தந்தை மகனை கழுதையின் முதுகில் ஏற்றி விட்டார்  சிறிது தூரம் சென்றதும் எதிரே வந்த ஒருவர், ‘ஏனப்பா வயதான தந்தையை இப்படி நடக்க வைத்து விட்டு, நீ கழுதையின் மேல் அமர்ந்து செல்வது நியாயமா?’ என விவசாயி மகனைப் பார்த்து கேட்டார்.  உடனே மகன் கீழே இறங்கிக் கொண்டு தந்தையை கழுதை மீது அமரச் சொன்னான். தந்தையும் அவ்வாறே செய்தார்.இப்படியாக இன்னும் சிறிது தூரம் பயணித்த பிறகு, இன்னொருத்தர் தந்தையை பார்த்து கடிந்து கொண்டார். ‘ஏனய்யா இப்படி சின்ன பிள்ளையை நடக்க விட்டு நீங்கள் கழுதை மேல் பயணிக்கலாமா?’ என கேட்டார்.தந்தையும் மகனும் ஆளாளுக்கு இப்படிச் சொல்கிறார்களே என்ன செய்வது என பலவாறாக யோசித்து முடிவில் இருவருமே அந்த கழுதையிம் முதுகில் ஏறிச் செல்வோம் என ஏறிக் கொண்டனர்.சிறிது தொலைவு சென்றதும், இரண்டு பேருமாக கழுதை மீது அமர்ந்து செல்வதைப் பார்த்த சிலர், ‘அடக் கொடுமையே இப்படியா இந்த வாயில்லா பிராணியைத் துன்புறுத்துவார்கள். இவர்களுக்கு இரக்கமே இல்லையா?’ என எள்ளி நகையாடினர். அவர்கள் பேச்சைக் கேட்டவுடன் விவசாயிக்கு மிகவும் கோபம் ஏற்பட்டது. உடனே இருவரும் கழுதையின் மீதிருந்து கீழே குதித்தார்கள்.மனம் குழம்பிப் போன தந்தையும் மகனும், கழுதையைத் தூக்கிக் கொண்டு செல்வது தான் சிறந்தது என்று அவர்கள் இருவரும் தீர்மானித்தனர். மிகவும் சிரமப்பட்டுக் கழுதையின் கால்களைக் கட்டியபிறகு, ஒரு கொம்பில் அதைக் கட்டி அதைத் தோளில் தூக்கி வைத்துக் கொண்டு அவர்கள் தொடர்ந்து நடந்தனர்.கிராமத்தை அடைவதற்கு முன்னால் ஆற்றின் மீதிருந்த ஒரு பாலத்தை அவர்கள் கடக்க வேண்டியிருந்தது.விவசாயியும் அவன் மகனும் மிகவும் சிரமப்பட்டுக் கழுதையைத் தூக்கிக் கொண்டு வரும் வினோதக் காட்சியை, ஆற்றுக்கு அக்கரையில் இருந்த குழந்தைகள் பார்த்துக் கைகொட்டிச் சிரித்தனர். பெரிய சத்தத்தைக் கேட்டுப் பயந்து போன கழுதை பெரிதாக துள்ளிக்குதிக்க ஆரம்பித்தது. அதைத் தூக்கிக் கொண்டு வந்த தந்தை, மகன் இருவரின் பிடியும் நழுவியது. அந்தப் பரிதாபமான கழுதை ஆற்று நீரில் தூக்கி எறியப்பட்டது! கால்கள் கட்டப்பட்டிருந்ததால் அதனால் நீந்த முடியவில்லை! அது இறக்க நேரிட்டது.இப்படி சுயமாக சிந்தித்து முடிவெடுக்காமல் அடுத்தவர் சொல்வதைக் கேட்டதால் தங்களுக்கும் அடிபட்டதோடு கழுதையும் இறந்து போய்விட்டதே எனக் கவலை பட்டபடியே நடந்தனர்.நீதி: ஒவ்வொருவருக்கும் ஒவ்வொரு கருத்து. எல்லோரையம் திருப்திப் படுத்த முடியாது. சொல் புத்தியைவிட சுயபுத்தி மிக அவசியம்."},{"question":"ලන්ඩන් (London) නගරය හරහා ගලාබසින ගංගාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලන්ඩන් (London) නගරය හරහා ගලාබසි​නේ තේම්ස් නදියයි."},{"question":"වායුගෝලයේ වැඩිපුරම අඩංගු වායුව කුමක්ද?","answer":"නයිට්‍රජන් වායුව"},{"question":"ජීව විද්‍යාවෙහි , වර්ගීකරණය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ජීව විද්‍යාවෙහි , වර්ගීකරණය යනු, ජීව විද්‍යාත්මක ජීවීන් සමූහයන් අතර පොදුවේ පවතින ගුණාංග මත පදනම්ව, ඒවා නම් කිරීමෙහි, අර්ථ දැක්වීමෙහි (සීමා කිරීම) සහ වර්ගීකරණය කිරීමෙහි විද්‍යාව වෙයි."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'ibu ayam'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud perempuan yang memperdagangkan pelacur. Contoh ayat: Menjadi ibu ayam adalah pekerjaan yang dikutuk oleh Allah."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga:\\"Aza manao lahy antitra mahazo lamokan'atody akoho,_\\"","answer":"\\"Aza manao lahy antitra mahazo lamokan'atody akoho, ka tsy mitadi-zafy intsony.\\""},{"question":"Про яку подію йдеться в тексті: Особливо відзначився під час проведення Східно-Померанської наступальної операції та при знищенні Штеттинського угруповання ворога. В бою за населений пункт Хьокендорф (8 км південно-східніше Щецина) 17 березня 1945 року червоноармієць С. Ф. Орел вогнем з автомата знищив близько 20 гітлерівців, забезпечивши просування вперед своєї роти. Під час контратаки ворога при підтримці танків і самохідних гармат виникла загроза прориву оборони 1069-го стрілецького полку. Разом зі своїм відділенням С. Ф. Орел займав оборону в одному з будинків. Колона ворожої техніки рухалась вузькою вулицею селища. Червоноармієць С. Ф. Орел кинув зв'язку гранат під головний танк і підірвав його, але сам був вбитий кулеметною чергою. Танкову колону ворога було зупинено.","answer":"Про Східно-Померанську стратегічну наступальну операцію. "},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra an'ilay \\"manga\\" mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Tokyo Ghoul\\"?","answer":"Ny mpanoratra an'ilay \\"manga\\" mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Tokyo Ghoul\\" dia Sui Ishida."},{"question":"අතීත මියන්මාරය හැඳින්වූ නම ?","answer":"බුරුමය"},{"question":"ఆదర్శ రైతు రామయ్యను అభినందిస్తూ అభినందన పత్రాన్ని తయారుచేయండి.","answer":"అభినందన పత్రంఅభ్యుదయ రైతురాజు రామయ్య మహాశయా !మీకు అభినందన మందారాలు. భారతదేశ సౌభాగ్యం పల్లెలపై ఆధారపడియుంది. పల్లెల్లో రైతులు పండించే పంటలపైనే మన వర్తక పరిశ్రమలు ఆధారపడియున్నాయి. మేం కడుపునిండా అన్నం తింటున్నామంటే అది మీ వంటి కర్షకోత్తముల హస్తవాసి అనే చెప్పాలి.కర్షకోత్తమా !మీరు మన ప్రభుత్వ వ్యవసాయశాఖ వారు సూచించిన సూచనలను అందిపుచ్చుకొని, మీ పొలాల్లో ఈ సంవత్సరం ఎకరానికి 60 బస్తాల ధాన్యం పండించారు. చేల గట్లపై కంది మొక్కలు పాతి 20 బస్తాల కందులు పండించారు. రసాయనిక ఎరువులు, పురుగుమందుల జోలికి పోకుండా, మీ తోటలో 10 గేదెలను పెంచి, పాడి పరిశ్రమను ప్రోత్సహిస్తూ, ఆ పశువుల పేడతో సేంద్రియ ఎరువుల్ని తయారు చేసి వాటినే ఉపయోగించి మంచి పంటలు పండించారు. మీ కృషికి ప్రభుత్వ పక్షాన అభినందనలు అందిస్తున్నాము.రైతురత్న రామయ్య గారూ!నమస్కారం. ప్రభుత్వం మీకు ‘రైతురత్న’ అనే బిరుదునిచ్చి సత్కరిస్తోంది. మీరే ఈ జిల్లాలో రైతులకు ఆదర్శం. మీరు వ్యవసాయంలో మరిన్ని నూతన పద్ధతులు పాటించి, మన జిల్లాలో, రాష్ట్రంలో రైతులకు ఆదర్శంగా నిలవాలని కోరుతున్నాము. ఈ సందర్భంగా మీకు మన ముఖ్యమంత్రిగారి తరపున రూ. 25,000లు బహుమతి ఇస్తున్నాము. మీకు మా శుభాకాంక్షలు. మా నమస్సులు.అభినందనములు.ఇట్లు,జిల్లా వ్యవసాయాధికారి,ఏలూరు,ప|గో|| జిల్లా"},{"question":"Qual é a pergunta para: \\"O rendimento familiar médio dos EUA caiu de US 51.144 em 2010 para US 50.502 em 2011\\"? O tópico é a renda familiar nos Estados Unidos.","answer":"\\"Qual é a renda média familiar americana em 2011?\\""},{"question":"Ijọba Naijiria n ha dọla fawọn eeyan dudu l’Amẹrika, ki wọn le ṣewọde tako wa lọdọ Ajọ Iṣọkan Agbaye – Banji Akintoye","answer":"Alaga ẹgbẹ NINAS, iyẹn ẹgbẹ awọn to fẹẹ ya kuro lara Naijiria, Ọjọgbọn Banji Akintoye, ti tu aṣiiri pe niṣe nijọba Naijiria n hawo bii ẹlẹda l’Amẹrika bayii, wọn n fowo naa haaya awọn eeyan dudu l’Amẹrika pe ki wọn ba awọn ṣewọde tako iwọde ti ẹgbẹ NINAS fẹẹ ṣe aṣekagbara rẹ lolu-ileeṣẹ Ajọ Iṣọkan Agbaye lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii.Ọjọgbọn Akintoye sọrọ yii ninu atẹjade kan ti Akọwe ẹgbẹ NINAS to tun jẹ agbẹnusọ baba naa, Ọgbẹni Maxwell Adelẹyẹ, fi lede l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, lori bi nnkan ṣe n lọ si lorileede Amẹrika ti wọn ti n ṣe iwọde lọwọ.Wọn ni inu ibẹrubojo ni Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari ati ikọ to ko sodi wa si apero agbaye naa wa, paapaa bi ireti ṣe wa pe Aarẹ yoo ba awọn ijokoo awọn olori orileede agbaye naa sọrọ lọjọ Ẹti, bẹẹ ọjọ naa ni ẹgbẹ NINAS fẹẹ ṣe aṣekagba iwọde wọn, ti wọn ti ṣeto pe miliọnu kan eeyan lo maa yan bii ologun, ti wọn yoo si ṣe iwọde wọọrọwọ yika agbala ile naa.Ṣe lati ọjọ kẹrinla ni iwọde naa ti n waye nile ẹgbẹ naa, tawọn oluwọde naa n fi erongba wọn han, ti wọn si n parọwa si Ajọ Iṣọkan Agbaye to n ṣepade kẹrindinlọgọrin wọn lọwọ pe ki wọn ba awọn da si ọrọ Naijiria, ki wọn si ṣatilẹyin fun yiya kuro tawọn gun le ọhun.Ọjọgbọn Akintoye ni niṣe lara n fu ikọ tijọba Naijiria ko wa naa, wọn ni afaimọ ni aṣekagba iwọde ti ẹgbẹ NINAS fẹẹ ṣe ọhun ko ni i mu itiju ati abuku dani fun Aarẹ Buhari lasiko ti yoo maa ba awọn Ajọ Agbaye naa sọrọ, idi eyi ni wọn ṣe n nawo nara lati haaya awọn eeyan ti yoo ṣe iwọde mi-in tako NINAS ti wọn yoo si maa sọrọ rere nipa Aarẹ ati ijọba Naijiria.“Lai ka bi awọn eeyan bii Kinniun yii ṣe n nawo bii ṣekẹrẹ si, ko sọna ti wọn fi maa bori kọlọkọlọ tiwa, tori a wa niṣọkan, abẹ ijọba dẹmokiresi la si wa.Ọla ni aṣekagba iwọde naa maa waye niluu New York, l’Amẹrika, o si maa laami-laaka gidi, tori ẹ lẹru ṣe n ba ijọba Naijiria. Ọga agba kan nileeṣẹ ijọba Naijiria ati oniroyin kan lati ilu Eko ti wa l’Amẹrika bayii, awọn ni wọn n ṣe kukukẹkẹ kiri lati hawo fawọn eeyan dudu ti wọn ba ri, pe ki wọn le ba wọn ṣe iwọde tako wa, ẹẹdẹgbẹta owo dọla (500 USD) ni wọn ha fun wọn, ki wọn maa pariwo pe ijọba Buhari daa, ti Buhari lawọn fẹ.Ṣugbọn mimi kan ko mi wa nitori iyẹn, a o tiẹ ri tiwọn ro rara. Ko si ajẹgaba le ni lori kan to le bori awọn eeyan ti wọn nipinnu. Awọn araalu lo ni ijọba, awọn ni wọn si ni agbara, tori eeyan lo ṣe iwe ofin orileede. Ọwọ araalu laṣẹ wa, ibẹ si lawa ti ri agbara tiwa, eeyan la fi bora bii aṣọ. Tori naa, iwọde wa maa jẹ fun anfaani awọn araalu, iwọde alaafia si ni bii tatẹyinwa.A rọ gbogbo ẹyin eeyan wa ni Guusu ati Aarin-Gbungbun Amẹrika ati orileede Canada lati tu yaayaa jade lọpọ rẹpẹtẹ ni ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun 2021 yii, nileeṣẹ Ajọ United Nations, niluu New York, la ti maa ṣe iwọde wa, a fẹẹ taṣiiri niwaju agbaye pe ijọba-Fulani to wa lode yii ti ja ẹtọ ati aṣẹ araalu gba ni Naijiria, niṣe ni wọn n ṣe awa ati dukia wa yankanyankan nilẹ abinibi wa, ajọṣe wa ko rọgbọ, ko si le rọgbọ mọ, a fẹẹ maa lọ.” Bẹẹ latẹjade naa ka lapakan."},{"question":"’துரை மாணிக்கம்’ என்பது இவரின் இயற்பெயர்(1) கவிஞர் சுரதா                                                   (2) கவிஞர் மீரான்(3) பாரதிதாசன்                                                     (4) பெருஞ்சித்திரனார்","answer":" (4) பெருஞ்சித்திரனார்\\"பாவலரேறு\\" பெருஞ்சித்திரனார் (10 மார்ச் 1933 – 11 சூன் 1995) தமிழ்நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த தனித்தமிழ் அறிஞர், புலவர், இதழாளர் மற்றும் பெரியாரிய, பொதுவுடைமை, தமிழ்த் தேசியச் செயல்பாட்டாளர் ஆவார். தன் ஐம்பதாண்டு கால எழுத்துப்பணியில் கொய்யாக்கனி (1956), கனிச்சாறு உள்ளிட்ட 40-க்கும் மேற்பட்ட படைப்புகளை இயற்றினார். \\"திராவிட மொழிநூல் ஞாயிறு\\" என அறியப்படும் ஞா.தேவநேயப் பாவாணருடன் இணைந்து தென்மொழி இதழைத் தொடங்கி நடத்தினார்.சமுதாய - அரசியல் களத்தில் சாதி எதிர்ப்பு, இந்தித் திணிப்பு எதிர்ப்பு, நெருக்கடி நிலை எதிர்ப்பு,  தனித் தமிழ்நாடு ஆதரவு ஆகிய நிலைகளில் செறிவுடன் பணியாற்றியவர்."},{"question":"Geben Sie mir 6 Vorschläge für Aktivitäten an einem verregneten Tag. Es soll keine Arbeit sein, sondern lediglich Aktivitäten zur Erholung.","answer":"Hier sind sechs Vorschläge für einen regnerischen Tag:1. Ein Museumsbesuch2. Brettspiele3. Puzzle4. Kuchen backen5. Malen oder Zeichnen6. Einen Film ansehen"},{"question":"Nitori gareeji, awọn onimọto da wahala rẹpẹtẹ silẹ ni Orile-Iganmu","answer":"Titi di bi a ṣe n ko iroyin yii jọ lawọn eeyan to n gbe ni Doyin, lagbegbe Orile, l’Ekoo, ṣi wa ninu ibẹru-bojo pẹlu bi awọn onimọto ṣe kọju ija buruku sira wọn lati ọjọ Iṣẹgun, titi di owurọ kutu oni.ALAROYE gbọ pe gareeji ti awọn kan fẹẹ fagidi gba lagbegbe ọhun lo da ija yii silẹ laarin wọn, nibi ti wọn ti ṣa ẹlomi-in ladaa, ti wọn si tun yinbọn pẹlu.Gbogbo awọn adugbo wọnyi; Doyin-Orile, Alagba, Orowumi, Coker ati Ọpẹloyẹru ni wahala ọhun de, ti awọn eeyan ko si le foju kan oorun.Ọkunrin gbajumọ sọrọsọrọ ori redio to n gbe lagbegbe ọhun salaye pe, “Ẹni kan ni wọn sọ pe asiko ẹ ti to lati gbe gareeji ibi to ti n gba owo silẹ, ṣugbọn to kọ lati ṣe e, bi awọn eeyan kan ti inu n bi, t’awọn naa fẹẹ gba gareeji ọhun ṣe kọju ija sawọn ti ko fẹẹ fi gareeji silẹ niyẹn, nni walaha ba gba gbogbo adugbo kan.”O fi kun un pe awọn ṣọja kan to n kọja ni wọn kọkọ pana rogbodiyan ọhun ni kete to bẹrẹ lana-an, ṣugbọn nigba to dọwọ aṣaalẹ ni wọn tun bẹrẹ pada, ti wọn si yinbọn mọju.Ṣiwaju si i, a gbọ pe bi ilẹ ṣe mọ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ni wọn ti bẹrẹ wahala ọhun pada, ti ọlọja ko le patẹ, tawọn oniṣowo mi-in paapaa ko le ṣi ṣọọbu wọn lagbegbe naa ni Doyin-Orile.Wọn ni niṣe lawọn janduku kan n lo anfaani wahala yii fi ja foonu ati owo gba lọwọ awọn eeyan, ti idarudapọ gidi si gba gbogbo agbegbe ọhun kan.Ọkunrin oniṣowo kan naa wa lara awọn eeyan ti wọn kọ lu lagbegbe Orowunmi. Ninu ṣọọbu ẹ ni wọn ti lọọ ba a ti wọn si ṣe e leṣe, bẹẹ ni wọn tun ko o lowo ati foonu lọ.ALAROYE pe agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa l’Ekoo, Ọgbẹni Muyiwa Adéjọbí, o ni loootọ niṣẹlẹ ọhun waye, bẹẹ nileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ko dakẹ lori ọrọ ọhun."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Giá heo hơi tăng cao, Hoàng Anh Gia Lai của bầu Đức tham vọng vượt 20 - 30% kế hoạch năm.","answer":"Giá heo hơi cũng giúp hoạt động sản xuất kinh doanh của nhiều doanh nghiệp thuận lợi. Đơn cử như Công ty CP Hoàng Anh Gia Lai (HAGL - Mã: HAG), sản lượng heo tiêu thụ trong 6 tháng của Hoàng Anh Gia Lai đạt 82.529 con. Sản lượng trái cây tiêu thụ là 109.807 tấn, trong đó chuối xuất khẩu là 81.569 tấn và chuối dùng cho sản xuất thức ăn gia súc là 28.238 tấn. Luỹ kế 6 tháng, mảng chăn nuôi đem về cho Hoàng Anh Gia Lai 439 tỷ đồng doanh thu thuần, mảng cây ăn trái thu về 1.094 tỷ đồng và 334 tỷ đồng từ ngành phụ trợ. Tổng doanh thu thuần nửa đầu năm của tập đoàn là 1.867 tỷ đồng, gấp 2,24 lần cùng kỳ năm ngoái. Lợi nhuận sau thuế 6 tháng đầu năm là 531 tỷ đồng, gấp gần 64 lần cùng kỳ năm ngoái và đạt 47% mục tiêu năm. Như vậy, riêng quý II, Hoàng Anh Gia Lai ước đạt 1.064 tỷ đồng doanh thu. Từ nay đến cuối năm, khi giá bán chuối đi vào chu kỳ cao nhất trong năm khoảng từ tháng 9 trở đi và giá heo hơi tiếp tục tăng cao như hiện nay (tăng 20% so với mức giá lập kế hoạch) và sản lượng heo xuất bán dự kiến tăng gấp đôi so với sản lượng đã tiêu thụ trong 6 tháng đầu năm thì Hoàng Anh Gia Lai sẽ sớm đạt được kế hoạch đề ra cho cả năm và có thể vượt 20 - 30% kế hoạch. Thông tin từ Công ty cổ phần Tập đoàn Hòa Phát, 6 tháng đầu năm, sản lượng heo tiêu thụ các loại đạt gần 200.000 con heo thịt thương phẩm, heo giống… ngang bằng so với cùng kỳ năm ngoái. Với khả năng phát triển đàn tốt, sau 6 năm, quy mô chăn nuôi của Hòa Phát năm 2021 đã đạt gần 450.000 con heo thịt, heo giống,… Hệ thống trại chăn nuôi heo của Hòa Phát hiện diện tại các tỉnh Yên Bái, Hoà Bình, Bắc Giang, Thái Bình, Bình Phước. Nhìn lại 3 năm 2019-2021, Công ty Cổ phần Phát triển chăn nuôi Hòa Phát ghi nhận doanh thu và mức lợi nhuận tương đối tốt. Đến năm 2025, Công ty đặt mục tiêu đạt 25.000 con heo nái sinh sản và hàng năm cung cấp ra thị trường 750.000 con heo thịt thương phẩm thuần và lợi nhuận sau thuế 273 tỷ đồng; lần lượt gấp 2 và 3,1 lần cùng kỳ năm trước, đồng thời là quý cao nhất trong khoảng 5 năm trở lại đây."},{"question":"Đặt tiêu đề cho đoạn văn sau: Theo AP, phê chuẩn danh sách đề cử và thăng chức trong quân đội từ lâu đã là một trong những nhiệm vụ mà lưỡng đảng ở thượng viện Mỹ có sự nhất trí cao nhất. Song ông Tuberville đã phá vỡ thông lệ đó với việc \\"phong tỏa\\" toàn bộ danh sách này. Lầu Năm Góc cho biết số lượng sĩ quan cấp cao chưa được phê chuẩn vì ông Tuberville hiện là 260 và có thể tăng lên đến 650 vào cuối năm nay. CNN cho biết, theo truyền thống của thượng viện Mỹ nhiều thập niên qua, các đề cử trong quân đội thường được gom lại và được phê chuẩn đồng loạt theo luật \\"unanimous consent\\", tức chỉ cần không có thượng nghị sĩ nào phản đối (khác với việc toàn bộ thượng nghị sĩ phải đồng ý) thì danh sách này sẽ được thông qua. Song ngay khi một thượng nghị sĩ phản đối thì việc này sẽ không thể diễn ra.Trong trường hợp đó, thượng viện Mỹ vẫn có thể giải quyết bằng cách áp dụng quy trình tiêu chuẩn: tổ chức các cuộc biểu quyết \\"roll call\\" một cách riêng lẻ cho từng đề cử trong danh sách. \\"Roll call\\" có thể hiểu là biểu quyết theo kiểu điểm danh, tức gọi tên tới thượng nghị sĩ nào thì người đó nói sẽ nói đồng ý hay không. Vấn đề là làm vậy sẽ khiến quá trình phê chuẩn kéo dài, nhất là khi danh sách có tới hàng trăm người.Điêu này có nghĩa là sự cản trở của ông Tuberville không thể hoàn toàn ngăn chặn hoặc loại bỏ bất cứ một đề cử nào, mà chỉ là trì hoãn quá trình phê chuẩn. Chủ tịch Ủy ban Quân vụ thượng viện Mỹ Jack Reed tuần trước cho biết việc tổ chức biểu quyết phê chuẩn hơn 260 đề cử quân đội theo hình thức \\"roll call\\" sẽ mất 27 ngày nếu thượng viện làm việc “suốt ngày đêm” (24/24) hoặc 84 ngày nếu thượng viện làm việc 8 tiếng/ngày.Ông Tuberville không phản đối việc tổ chức bỏ phiếu riêng lẻ cho từng đề cử. \\"Tại sao chúng ta không bỏ phiếu cho từng người một? Chúng ta có thể làm điều đó, nhưng họ không muốn làm điều đó vì một số lý do\\", ông nói trong một chương trình của CNN hôm 10.7, cho rằng việc này \\"rất dễ thực hiện\\". Ông sau đó cũng cho biết ông \\"không ngăn cản việc phê chuẩn đối với bất kỳ ai\\".","answer":"Một người chống lại tất cả"},{"question":"Apakah maksud peribahasa \\"pahit dahulu manis kemudian\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah sesuatu perkara hendaklah dilakukan dengan tabah walaupun banyak rintangan, hasilnya pasti menyenangkan."},{"question":"Olumide pera ẹ loṣere tiata, ṣugbọn gbaju-ẹ gidi loun atọrẹ ẹ n ṣe n’Ibadan","answer":"Ọkunrin kan, Olumide Ọlajide, to sọ pe ọkan lara awọn oṣere onitiata ilẹ wa loun, wa lara awọn afurasi ọdaran tileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ ṣafihan wọn lọjọ Aje, Mọnde yii, ẹsun lilu awọn eeyan ni jibiti owo ninu akaunti banki wọn ni wọn fi kan an.Awọn meji ni wọn fẹsun kan pe wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ buruku ọhun, Wẹmimọ Adeyanju lorukọ ẹni keji, wọn ṣafihan oun naa, wọn nileewe poli kan loun ti n kawe, ipele giga HND lo si wa.Gẹgẹ bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe ṣalaye, wọn ni niṣe lawọn ọdaran yii maa n lọ sọdọ awọn to jẹ oniṣowo, wọn aa ṣa awọn ọja ti wọn fẹẹ ra ninu igba wọn, wọn yoo si sọ fun wọn pe niṣe lawọn maa fowo ṣọwọ si wọn latori ẹrọ tabi foonu awọn, eyi tawọn eleebo n pe ni Bank transfer.Wọn ni bi ọlọja naa ba ti gba, awọn afurasi yii maa ni ko fawọn ni nọmba akaunti rẹ ati orukọ banki tawọn maa fowo ṣọwọ si. Ti wọn ba ti tẹ koodu (code) to yẹ, wọn maa ri ohun gbogbo nipa ọlọja yẹn lori foonu wọn.Olumide fẹnu ara ẹ sọ fawọn oniroyin pe gbara tawọn ba ti mọ nọmba akanti ati banki ati orukọ onitọhun, oju-ẹsẹ loun maa wa ọkan ninu awọn atẹjiṣẹ ti banki naa ti fi ranṣẹ sonibaara wọn ri, awọn maa yi awọn nnkan kan pada ninu atẹjiṣẹ naa ko le jọ bii pe banki yẹn lo ṣẹṣẹ fi i ranṣẹ, o si maa ba owo to ba transifaa mu, ki tọhun too fura, wọn ti palẹ ọja mọ, wọn ti bẹsẹ wọn sọrọ.Lọjọ tọwọ palaba wọn segi, Wẹmimọ ni “obinrin kan tawọn ti ṣe kinni naa fun ri, ṣugbọn tawọn o ranti ẹ mọ lo ri awọn ninu ṣọọbu kan tawọn ti fẹẹ lu jibiti ọhun, lobinrin naa ba wo oju wa ninu fọto Wasaapu wa to wa lori foonu ẹ, niṣe lo pariwo nigba to ri i pe fọto naa jọra, bọwọ ṣe tẹ wa niyẹn.”Awọn ọlọpaa ni ogbologboo onijibiti ni Olumide yii, wọn ni ẹrọ kan (app) wa lori foonu ẹ to maa n pese atẹjiṣẹ banki eyikeyii ti wọn ba fẹẹ lo, to si maa jọra gẹlẹ bii atẹjiṣẹ ojulowo.Wọn ni iwadii ṣi n tẹsiwaju lori ọrọ wọn."},{"question":"What is Brazil's capital?","answer":"the capital of Brazil is Brasília."},{"question":"ماذا يطلق على شعار الولايات المتحدة؟","answer":"النسر الأصلع."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፡- በጀርመን Oktoberfest የሚከበረው በምን መጠጥ ነው? መልስ፡- ","answer":"ቢራ"},{"question":"Que palavras rima com a palavra amor?","answer":"Várias palavras rimam com a palavra amor, algumas delas são: Humor, Clamor, Temor e Tumor"},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta : ¿Qué presidentes estadounidenses de este siglo tenían menos de setenta año al ser elegidos?. ","answer":"Dos presidentes estadounidenses del siglo XXI fueron elegidos con menos de setenta años:1. Barack Obama : Nació el 4 de agosto de 1961 y fue elegido presidente en noviembre 2008 a los 47 años. Fue El 44° presidente de los Estados Unidos y sirvió dos mandatos, hasta enero de 2017.2.Bill Clinton: Nació el 19 de agosto de 1946 y fue elegido presidente en noviembre de 1992 a los 46 años. Aunque la mayor parte de su mandato se desarrolló en el siglo XXI, tuvo un segundo mandato que se extendió hasta enero del 2001.Cabe mencionar que otros presidentes estadounidenses del siglo XXI , como George W. Bush y Donald Trump, también fueron escogidos antes de cumplir los 70 años. Pero tanto Bush como Trump ya habrían cumplido esa edad en algún momento durante sus respectivos mandatos. "},{"question":"Qual país é famoso por sua migração anual de gnus, onde milhões de animais cruzam suas planícies?","answer":"Tal miração anual ocorre na Tanzânia, na planície do Serengeti. Gnus, outros bovinos e zebras participam numa migração anual em grande escala; a segunda maior migração de mamíferos terrestres do mundo."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Na manomboka _ ny androAleo hijanona eto ihanyEto anilanao eto aho mafanam-pitiaTaman-tsafosafoSambatsambatra anieIzay _Fantatrao ihany fa ...Tsy mba manana _Toa anao anie ahoIanao ilay _ hatrizay ka hatrizaoKa avelao hitiaAnao mandrakizayTena tiako _Ary ianao koa tia ahySadaikatra ahoNy hanambaraFa mahasaro-piaro ahyIanao sangin'olon-kafa inyMankarary ahySambatsambatra anieIzay tiavinaoFantatrao ihany fa ...Tsy mba manana _Toa anao anie ahoIanao ilay tiako hatrizay ka hatrizaoKa avelao hitiaAnao mandrakizayTena tiako ianaoAry ianao koa tia ahy\\"","answer":"Na manomboka maizina ny androAleo hijanona eto ihanyEto anilanao eto aho mafanam-pitiaTaman-tsafosafoSambatsambatra anieIzay tiavinaoFantatrao ihany fa ...Tsy mba manana tianaToa anao anie ahoIanao ilay tiako hatrizay ka hatrizaoKa avelao hitiaAnao mandrakizayTena tiako ianaoAry ianao koa tia ahySadaikatra ahoNy hanambaraFa mahasaro-piaro ahyIanao sangin'olon-kafa inyMankarary ahySambatsambatra anieIzay tiavinaoFantatrao ihany fa ...Tsy mba manana tianaToa anao anie ahoIanao ilay tiako hatrizay ka hatrizaoKa avelao hitiaAnao mandrakizayTena tiako ianaoAry ianao koa tia ahy"},{"question":"தக்கர்களை ஒடுக்கிய ஆங்கிலேய ஆளுநர்?","answer":"வாரன் ஹேஸ்டிங்ஸ் தக்கரை ஒடுக்கினார்."},{"question":"เหตุการณ์สำคัญที่เกี่ยวข้องกับข้อความนี้คืออะไร: ต่อมาเมื่อมีการก่อรัฐประหาร เมื่อวันที่ 22 พฤษภาคม พ.ศ. 2557 ทางคณะรักษาความสงบแห่งชาติออกคำสั่งเรียกให้ดารุณีไปรายงานตัว แต่เธอมิได้ไปตามคำสั่งดังกล่าว จึงถูกศาลทหารออกหมายจับ","answer":"รัฐประหาร"},{"question":"Tôi thấy mấy tháng nay mắt nhìn xa bị mờ. Lòe chữ đi kiểm tra thì họ bảo bị cận 1.5 mà tôi đang phân vân giữa việc dùng kính và không dùng kính. Tại tôi nhìn gần vẫn rõ nên chưa quyết định. Vậy xin hỏi tôi không dùng kính mắt có bị ảnh hưởng gì không ạ?","answer":"Bạn cận 1,5 độ thông thường bạn vẫn có thể tự điều tiết để nhìn được trong sinh hoạt hàng ngày nhưng nếu điều tiết lâu liên tục thì dễ dẫn đến tăng độ. Nếu bạn thấy sử dụng kính không phù hợp thì có thể tham khảo các phương pháp phẫu thuật. Hiện nay có các phương pháp phẫu thuật ReLEx SMILE, Femto-Lasik, Lasik. Các phương pháp này đều rất hiện đại và an toàn, không đau, không chảy máu, thị lực phục hồi ngay sau khi phẫu thuật."},{"question":"Write a continuation for this paragraph - Опублікував монографії, присвячені коронному канцлерові Єроніму Радзейовському («Hieronim Radziejowski. Studium władzy i opozycji», 1988) та повстанню Олександра-Леона Костки-Наперського 1651 («Na tropach Napierskiego. W kręgu mitów i faktów», 1972). Переклав і прокоментував видання тієї частини хроніки Веспасіяна Коховського, де йдеться про ","answer":"роки війни шведсько-польскої, званої Потопом (1655—1657). Упорядкував та видав із власним вступом класичну працю В. Чермака про Яна ІІ Казимира Ваза. Був науковим консультантом фільму Єжи Гоффмана «Потоп» (1969, за романом Генрика Сенкевича). Завжди прагнув до об'єктивного висвітлення історичних подій, у тому числі й національно-визвольного руху українського народу в 17 cт., у зв'язку з чим розвінчав низку міфів створених Генриком Сенкевичем."},{"question":"بحثت في الإنترنت عن إجابة لهذا السؤال ما هي منظمة الأوبك ؟. لكني لم أجد إجابة ، هل تستطيع الإجابة عليه؟","answer":"بالتأكيد، منظمة الأوبك هي منظّمة عالمية تضم أحد عشر دولة تعتمد على صادراتها النفطية اعتمادا كبيرا لتحقيق مدخولها."},{"question":"ජනතාවගේ 'මාළු මිලදී ගැනීමේ' හැකියාවට මොකද වුණේ?","answer":"විදුලි බිල වැඩි කිරීමෙන් දැඩි පහරක් එල්ල වී ඇති එක් ක්ෂේත්‍රයක් වන්නේ ධීවර කර්මාන්තයයි. විශේෂයෙන් සාගරයෙන් අල්ලා ගන්නා මත්ස්‍ය සම්පත කල්තබා ගැනීම වෙනුවෙන් අවශ්‍ය කෙරෙන විදුලි බලය වෙනුවෙන් තවදුරටත් අධික මිල ගෙවීමට අපහසු වීමත්, එම මිල ගෙවූවද, එම වැය එක්කර ජනතාවට අධික මිලට 'මාළු විකිණීමට' නොහැකි වීමත් ධීවරයින් මේ වන විට මුහුණ පා ඇති ප්‍රධාන ගැටලුවක් වී ඇත.මෙලෙස ඉහළ ගිය විදුලි බිලෙන් ධීවර ක්ෂේත්‍රයට කුමන බලපෑමක් වූයේද? ජනතාවගේ 'මාළු මිලදී ගැනීමේ' හැකියාවට කුමක්වී ඇද්දැ යි විමසා බැලීම සදහා බීබීසී සිංහල සේවය මීගමුව දූව මහ ලෙල්ලමේ සහ මීගමුව ප්‍රධාන මත්ස්‍ය වෙළඳපොළේ සංචාරයක නිරත විය."},{"question":"Inty misy toe-javatra mitranga: “Taraiky vao tafafoha tamin'ny torimasony i Sitraka, fefan-kadiny sisa no ananany hamonjena ny toeram-piasana, kanefa ny lalany mamonjy izany toeram-piasana izany dia maharitra 10 minitra eo ho eo raha mandeha fiara karetsaka.”Valio ny fanontaniana hoe “Mbola afaka manao tonga ara-potoana ve i Sitraka, raha izany, inona no tokony ataony mba tsy ho tara ?” Inty misy hevitra tsara ho fantatra hahafana mamaly ilay fanontaniana: “Mbola tsy nanao ninoninona mihitsy izy fa vao nifoha mihitsy.”","answer":"Afaka tonga ara-potoana ihany i Sitraka raha toa ka afaka misasa sy miakanjo kintakintana ary tsy misakafo maraina fa tonga dia mandeha mamonjy toeram-piasana avy hatrany. Tsara ihany koa anefa raha azo oetina an-tanana ny sakafo dia hoanina eny an-dalana satria zava-dehibe amin'ny fahasalamana ny fisakafoanana maraina ary manampy azy mba amokatra bebe kokoa mandritran'ny tontolo andro."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙම පෞරාණික ගස් වැදගත් වන්නේ ඇයි, සහ රටේ සංස්කෘතික හා ස්වභාවික උරුමයන් තුළ ඒවා ඉටු කරන කාර්යභාරය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙම පැරණි ගස් ඒවායේ ලේඛනගත ඉතිහාසය, හොඳින්ඔ රොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව සහ සංස්කෘතික වැදගත්කම හේතුවෙන් වැදගත් වේ. ඔවුන් ඓතිහාසික සිදුවීම් සඳහා ජීවමාන සාක්ශිකරුවන් වන අතර රටේ සංස්කෘතික හා ස්වභාවික උරුමයේ කොටසකි. දේශගුණික දුෂ්කරතා මධ්‍යයේ සියවස් ගණනාවක් පුරා මෙම ගස් විරාජමානව පවතින්නේ රටේ ඓතිහාසික සිදුවීම් වලට සාක්ශ්‍ය සපයමිනි."},{"question":"Дидактиканын принциптерин киргизген педагог:а)К.Ушинскийб)Ж.Ж.Руссов)Я.Коменский","answer":" Тураа жообу:в)Я.Коменский"},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Aleoko kokoa ny sakafo italiana noho ny sakafo sinoa, izay no matsiro kokoa amiko.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Tsia, tsy misy resaka fankahalana io fanambarana io. Izy io dia maneho ny filan'ny tena manokana amin'ny sakafo tsy misy lasibatra na manaratsy vondrona."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الوحيد الي هاجر إلى المدينة علنًا ؟","answer":"الإجابة: عمر بن الخطاب"},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Cara-cara Menjaga Diri dan Keluarga.","answer":"Era pasca perindustrian dan pasca globalisasi yang serba mencabar akal dan minda kita telah menunjukkan graf masalah kesihatan dalam kalangan masyarakat kita semakin meningkat dari hari ke hari. Walaupun kemudahan dan infrastruktur kesihatan bertambah maju dan lengkap, pelbagai wabak dan penyakit yang melanda setiap golongan tanpa mengira usia. Mengikut kajian statistik yang dikeluarkan oleh Kementerian Kesihatan Malaysia pada tahun 2011, angka pesakit yang menghadapi masalah kesihatan telah meningkat sebanyak 200 000 orang pesakit melebihi bilangan pesakit pada tahun sebelumnya. Angka yang membimbangkan ini sepatutnya menjadi polemik yang perlu diambil tindakan oleh semua pihak. Justeru, wajar untuk kita mengenal pasti cara-cara menjaga kesihatan diri dan keluarga bagi mengelakkan masalah kesihatan menimpa diri dan orang sekeliling kita.Antara cara bagi memastikan kesihatan diri berada dalam keadaan baik adalah dengan melakukan aktiviti riadah. Pada masa lapang, setiap di antara kita digalakkan untuk melakukan aktiviti riadah seperti bersukan dan bersenam. Senaman adalah aktiviti regangan badan yang mudah dan boleh diaplikasikan di mana-mana pada tempoh masa yang singkat. Bagi mereka yang meminati aktiviti yang mencabar kekuatan fizikal dan mental, bersukan adalah aktiviti terbaik dalam memastikan kesihatan diri terjamin. Tambahan pula, melakukan aktiviti riadah akan mendatangkan manfaat lain yang cukup baik untuk diri, keluarga dan masyarakat secara amnya. Pembangunan kawasan rekreasi dan infrastruktur sukan yang lain hendaklah dimanfaatkan sepenuhnya oleh masyarakat yang cergas. Natijahnya, aktiviti riadah dapat membantu kita untuk memperkasa kekuatan fizikal dan mental supaya imun terhadap serangan penyakit yang menjejaskan kesihatan diri.Pada masa yang sama, mengamalkan pemakanan seimbang juga mustahak bagi memastikan kesihatan diri terjamin. Untuk makluman, Malaysia telah dikategorikan antara negara yang mempunyai masalah obesiti yang tinggi di rantau Asia. Kenyataan ini menunjukkan bahawa masyarakat kita kurang sedar akan faktor pemakanan dalam kesihatan. Kesibukan dalam pekerjaan dan pengaruh iklan mungkin telah menyebabkan ramai dalam kalangan masyarakat di negara ini tidak mengamalkan pemakanan yang seimbang dan sihat. Walaupun pelbagai kempen telah dilaksanakan seperti penggunaan piramid makanan, namun kadar penghidap obesiti tidak berkurangan. Tindakan yang sepatutnya setiap ahli masyarakat lakukan adalah dengan mengurangkan pemakanan makanan segera dan makanan ringan. Sebaliknya, kerapkan memasak makanan sendiri di rumah dan bawa bekal ke tempat kerja atau institusi pengajian. Dengan kaedah ini, kita dapat menentukan keseimbangan makanan yang kita sediakan serta berjimat cermat dalam ketidak tentuan ekonomi hari ini.Selain itu, penjagaan kebersihan diri, keluarga dan kawasan sekitar juga adalah penting dalam menjaga kesihatan. Hal ini kerana, penyakit boleh berpunca daripada pelbagai sudut terutamanya apabila terdapat kekotoran daripada sisa sampah dan sebagainya. Sebagai contoh, wabak denggi yang seringkali melanda negara kita adalah disebabkan takungan air yang terbiar lama dan membolehkan nyamuk aedes untuk membiak. Maka, setiapa ahli masyarakat bertanggungjawab memastikan kawasan perumahan serta premis perniagaan atau tempat kerja masing-masing dibersihkan dengan baik secara berkala. Perkara yang mudah ini dapat membantu kita melawan musuh yang tidak zahir di mata kita. Di samping itu, pastikan bahan-bahan mentah yang ingin dimakan, dimasak dan disediakan dengan bersih. Pembuangan sampah diuruskan dengan betul serta berusaha mengurangkan pencemaran alam dengan menjaga kebersihan akan menyumbang kepada kesihatan yang baik.Akhir sekali, sudah terang lagi bersuluh dimana pemeriksaan kesihatan yang kerap dapat membantu menjamin kesihatan diri dan keluarga. Kita sepatutnya bersyukur dengan kemudahan kesihatan awam yang disediakan oleh Kementarian Kesihatan Malaysia kerana ia adalah sangat berpatutan berbanding negara lain. Tambahan pula, kemudahan kesihatan disediakan di setiap pelusuk di seluruh negara kita samada klinik desa, klinik kesihatan daerah dan juga hospital-hospital besar yang semakin lengkap dengan peralatan perubatan yang terkini. Maka, sebagai rakyat Malaysia yang bertuah, kita hendaklah memanfaatkan kemudahan ini dengan melakukan pemeriksaan atau rawatan kesihatan mengikut arahan yang dinasihatkan oleh pegawai kesihatan. Bagi yang berkemampuan, institusi kesihatan swasta juga turut menawarkan pemeriksaan kesihatan yang lebih lengkap dan menyeluruh. Bak kata peribahasa Melayu, mencegah adalah lebih baik daripada merawat. Tuntasnya, pemeriksaan kesihatan dapat menjamin kesihatan diri, keluarga dan masyarakat.Intihannya, setiap individu bertanggungjawab untuk memastikan kesihatan diri terjaga dengan melakukan cara-cara yang telah dihuraikan di atas. Usaha menjaga kesihatan diri dan keluarga adalah usaha yang mulia dan wajar menerima sokongan yang positif oleh setiap pihak. Secara tidak langsung, setiap di antara kita adalah agen penyampai kepada orang disekililing kita. Maka jika diri kita, orang sekeliling dan masyarakat secara amnya menjaga kesihatan masing-masing, pasti generasi yang cergas dapat dilahirkan. Minda yang cergas menjamin kualiti hidup yang lebih baik. Semoga kita terhindar daripada masalah kesihatan dan penyakit kerana pepatah Melayu ada berkata, sesal dahulu pendapatan, sesal kemudian tidak berguna."},{"question":" من هو النبي الذي بعثه الله إلى قوم عاد؟\\t","answer":"هود عليه السلام."},{"question":"Firy ny salan'isan'ny androm-piainan'ny tantely?","answer":"Amin'ny fahavaratra dia miaina eo amin'ny 6 herinandro eo ho eo ny tantely iray."},{"question":"Suaal: Waxaad sheegtaa Muhaajiriintii u hijrootay magaalada Madiina qofkii ugu horeeyay oo galay kee buu ahaa?","answer":"Jawaab: Abuu Salama oo looyiqiinay Ibnu Cabdi Asad.    "},{"question":"Inona ny lalao ahitana ny Loka Davis ? ","answer":"Ny tennis no lalao ahitana ny Loka Davis."},{"question":"Ka amsa tambayar da ke gaba. wanda ya lashe gasar zakarun mata ta softball ta duniya a 2023?","answer":"Gasar cin kofin duniya ta mata ta 2023 ta ƙare tare da Oklahoma ta doke jihar Florida don share jerin gasar."},{"question":" كم يعادل كوكب زحل كوكبا من الأرض ؟","answer":" حوالي 750 كوكب"},{"question":"கடலைக் குறிக்கும் வேறு பெயர்களைக் குறிப்பிடுக.","answer":"அரலை, அலை, அழுவம், அளம், அளக்கர், ஆர்கலி, அரி, உவரி, திரை, பானல், பெருநீர், சுழி, நீராழி, புணர்ப்பு, ஆழி, ஈண்டு நீர், தென்நீர், பௌவம், முந்நீர், வரி, ஓதம், வலயம்."},{"question":"¿Cuándo se extinguieron los mamuts?","answer":"Se estima que este tipo de animal desapareció del planeta hace unos 4.000 años, cuando ya habían aparecido los primeros sistemas de escritura."},{"question":"Ọkada ni Umar ji gbe tọwọ fi tẹ ẹ n’llọrin","answer":"Ajọ ẹṣọ alaabo ṣifu difẹnsi, ẹka ti ipinlẹ Kwara, ti mu ọkunrin kan to n jẹ Umar Ibrahim niluu Ilọrin, fẹsun pe o ji ọkada gbe lagbegbe lfẹsowapọ Oke, Oko Olowo, n’llọrin.Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to lọ yii ni agbẹnusọ ajọ ṣifu difẹnsi, Ọgbẹni Babawale Zaid Afolabi, fi atẹjade sita pe ọwọ ba Umar Ibrahim nibi to ti lọọ ji ọkada gbe lagbegbe Okoolowo.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, o ni ṣe ni ọdaran naa wọle Aminu Ibrahim lagbegbe Kanike, loruganjọ, to si ji ọkada ọhun, lo ba na pápá bora. Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọṣẹ yii, ni ọwọ tẹ ẹ, ti wọn si gbe e wa si ọfiisi ajọ ẹsọ alaabo niluu Ilọrin.Afọlabi tẹsiwaju pe lẹyin ọpọlọpọ iwadii, o han pe afurasi ọhun wọ ile Ibrahim, o si ji ọkada Bajaj, aago ọwọ, foonu i-tel kan ati ẹgbẹrun mẹjọ nairagbe.Ọga ajọ ṣifu difẹnsi ni Kwara, Ọgbẹni Makinde Iskil Ayinla, ti pasẹ pe ki wọn ṣe ẹkunrẹrẹ iwadii lori iṣẹlẹ naa, ki wọn si foju afurasi naa ba ile-ẹjọ laipẹ."},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Жашоо туулган күндөрдү бергенде, тортторду жеп, белектерден ыракат алыңыз. Туулган күнүң менен куурчак."},{"question":"Tổng của tất cả các số tự nhiên gồm năm chữ số khác nhau được tạo thành bằng cách sử dụng các chữ số 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 là bao nhiêu?","answer":"1. Xác định số các số có năm chữ sốGọi Tập A ={1, 2, 3, 4, 5} và số phải tìm là abcde.Sử dụng quy tắc nhân trong cấu tạo số ta thấy:Có 5 cách chọn chữ số a lấy từ tập A.Có 4 cách chọn chữ số b lấy từ tập A và khác a.Có 3 cách chọn chữ số c lấy từ tập A và khác a, b.Có 2 cách chọn chữ số d lấy từ tập A và khác a, b, c.Có 1 cách chọn chữ số e lấy từ tập A và khác a, b, c, dVậy số các số abcde cần tìm là 5x4x3x2x1=120 số2. Tính tổng tất cả các số có năm chữ sốDo vai trò của mỗi chữ số xuất hiện trong mỗi hàng là như nhau nên mỗi hàng có120 : 5 = 24 lần xuất hiện của mỗi chữ số 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 trong mỗi hàngVậy tổng tất cả các số có năm chữ số được lập từ các chữ số 1,2,3,4,5 không lặp lại là:24 x (1 + 2 + 3 + 4 + 5) x 11111 = 3999960"},{"question":"ماهو شعار المملكة العربية السعودية؟","answer":"يتألف شعار المملكة العربية السعودية من سيفين عربيين منحنيين متقاطعين تعلوها نخلة، ويرمز السيفان للقوة والمنعة والتضحية أما النخلة فترمز للحيوية والنماء والرخاء. "},{"question":"Denetimsiz makine öğrenimi nedir?","answer":"Denetimsiz öğrenme algoritmaları, etiketsiz veriler kullanılarak eğitilir. Bu algoritmalar yeni verileri tarayarak girdiler ve önceden belirlenmiş çıktılar arasında anlamlı bağlantılar kurmaya çalışır. Düzenleri tespit edebilir ve verileri kategorilendirebilirler. Örneğin, denetimsiz algoritmalar farklı haber sitelerindeki haber yazılarını spor, suç vb. genel kategoriler altında gruplandırabilir. Bir yazıdaki anlamı ve duyguyu anlamak için doğal dil işleme araçlarını kullanırlar. Perakende sektöründe, denetimsiz öğrenme müşterilerin satın alma işlemlerinin düzenlerini tespit edebilir ve \\"müşteri tereyağ satın alıyorsa büyük olasılıkla ekmek de satın alacaktır\\" gibi veri analizi sonuçları sağlayabilir.Denetimsiz öğrenme, düzenlerin tanınmasında, anormalliklerin saptanmasında ve verilerin otomatik olarak kategorilere ayrılmasında yararlı olur. Eğitim verisi, etiketleme gerektirmediği için kurulum süreci kolaydır. Bu algoritmalar ek modelleme için verileri otomatik olarak temizlemek ve işlemek amacıyla da kullanılabilir. Bu yöntemin sınırlaması kesin tahminler sunamamasıdır. Ek olarak, belirli veri sonucu türlerini bağımsız olarak ayıramaz."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : పటాలు ఎన్ని రకాలు? అవి ఏవి? వివరణాత్మకంగా తెల్పండి.","answer":"పటంలో చూపిన అంశం లేదా వాటి ఉపయోగాన్ని బట్టి పటాలను మూడు రకాలుగా వర్గీకరించవచ్చు.రాజకీయ పటాలుభౌతిక పటాలువిషయ నిర్దేశిత పటాలు.1. రాజకీయ పటాలు :గ్రామాలు, నగరాలు, పట్టణాలు, జిల్లాలు, రాష్ట్రాలు మరియు దేశాల సరిహద్దులను చూపేవి రాజకీయ పటాలు.2. భౌతిక పటాలు :పర్వతాలు, పీఠభూములు, మైదానాలు, సముద్రాలు, నదులు, ఎడారులు వంటి భౌగోళిక స్వరూపాలను గూర్చి వివరిస్తాయి.3. విషయ నిర్దేశిత పటాలు :ఈ పటాలను భూమి వినియోగం, ఉష్ణోగ్రత, వర్షపాతం, జనాభా, నేలలు, అడవులు, పంటలు, ఖనిజాలు, పరిశ్రమలు, రైలుమార్గాలు, రోడ్డు మార్గాలు, జల మార్గాలు వంటి కొన్ని నిర్దిష్ట అంశాలను గురించి వివరించడానికి ఉపయోగిస్తారు."},{"question":"நத்தையால் தொடர்ந்து எத்தனை ஆண்டுகள் வரை தூங்க முடியும்?","answer":"நத்தைகள் உயிர்வாழ ஈரப்பதம் தேவை; வானிலை ஒத்துழைக்கவில்லை என்றால், அவர்கள் உண்மையில் மூன்று ஆண்டுகள் வரை தூங்கலாம். புவியியலைப் பொறுத்து, நத்தைகள் உறக்கநிலைக்கு (குளிர்காலத்தில் ஏற்படும்) அல்லது மதிப்பீட்டிற்கு ('கோடை தூக்கம்' என்றும் அழைக்கப்படும்) வெப்பமான காலநிலையிலிருந்து தப்பிக்க உதவும் என்று தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது"},{"question":"چرا توله سگ من دوست ندارد توسط بچه ها به آغوش کشیده شود؟","answer":"اکثر بچه ها از سیگنال ها و رفتارهایی که سگ ها درباره چیزهایی که دوست ندارند و می خواهند از آن دور شوند بی اطلاع هستند. کودکان غالبا نمی دانند که با سگ ها چگونه رفتار کنند. به خاطر همین هنگامی که بچه ها توله سگ ها را بغل می کنند ناخواسته سگ ها در شرایط و موقعیت ناراحت کننده ایی قرار می گیرند. این موقعیت حتی ممکن است برای توله سگ دردناک هم باشد. در این شرایط سگ ها مکررا در حال ارسال سیگنال لطفا متوقف شوید هستند."},{"question":"Waa maxay waxtarka biyaha.","answer":"Biyuhu waxtar weyn ayaa ay jirka u leeyihiin. Waxa ay suurageliyaan milidda cuntada iyo qashinka, si cuntadu u gasho dhiigga oo unugyada loo gaadhsiiyo, qashinka unugyadu soo bixiyaanna dhiigga u soo raaco dabadeedna dibadda loogu saaro. Siyaabaha biyuhu ay lagama maarmaan u yihiin waxaa ka mid ah: baahida loogu qabo in ay ka qayb galaan dhiska nudaha jirka, dheecaannada iyo insaaymyada shida cuntada, iyo qashin saarka, qoynta xubnaha jirka korkooda si aanay isu xoqin, iyo qaboojinta jirka oo uu keeno uumibaxa dhididku."},{"question":"Ndeupi muzivi weAtene haana kunyora chinhu - asina kufa naPlato?","answer":"Muzivi weAtene asina chaanonyora asi akasafa naPlato ndiSocrates. Socrates haana kunyora pfungwa dzake dzouzivi pachake; panzvimbo pezvo, dzidziso dzake nekurukurirano zvakanyorwa nomudzidzi wake nomuteveri, Plato. Mabasa aPlato, kunyanya nhaurirano, anowanzo ratidza Socrates semutambi wepakati ari kuita hurukuro dzehuzivi nevamwe. Nhaurirano idzi ndiwo musimboti wekunzwisisa kwedu pfungwa dzeuzivi hwaSocrates, nzira yake yeSocrates yekubvunza, uye maitiro ake ekubvunza nekuongorora pfungwa. Kuburikidza nezvinyorwa zvaPlato, nhaka yaSocrates sechinhu chekutanga muuzivi hwekuMadokero yakachengetedzwa uye inoramba ichipesvedzera pfungwa dzeuzivi nanhasi."},{"question":"Porsche ලාංඡනයේ දැකිය හැක්කේ කුමන සත්ත්වයාද?","answer":"Porsche සංකේතය හෝ ලාංඡනය අශ්වයෙකු දක්වයි. ස්ටුට්ගාර්ට් හි පෝර්ෂේ මූලස්ථානය පිහිටා ඇති අතර අශ්වයා පෝර්ෂේ ලාංඡනයට ඇතුළත් කර ඇත්තේ නගරයේ උරුමය අගය කිරීමක් ලෙස ය. "},{"question":"Murti looga hadalay qabyaalada oo tiriyay abwan Cabdullaahi suladaan timo cadde:","answer":"Ubadkiinii waad daadiseen                 waana dubateeneDubaaxdiisii waad wada cunteen      duhur dharaareedeDariiq toosan Soomaaliyey                 waa lagaa deyeyeDarajada Ilaahay ninkii                         doonayaa hela eNin ka duday distoorkioy waxyiga     diinti ka carrowyeDugsi malaha qabyaaladi waxay       dumiso mooyaaneHadaynaan xumaanta iyo dilkiyo      daynin kala qaadkaDibaddaan ka joognaa sharciga         daacadda IlaaheDanbarkeedu waa Jahannama           iyo dogobkii naareede Dugsi ma leh qabyaaladi                    waxay dumiso mooyaane Dir dir la isu laayiyo intaan                 weerar daba joogno Ooy dumarku weerkii sitaan               danabadii waayey Uu sida dureemada u yaal                  meydku dibaddiinna Wallee doogsan maysaan haddaad      dunida joogtaane Dugsi male qabyaaladi                       waxay dumiso mooyaanee."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity: \\"Ny tody tsy misy fa ...........\\".","answer":"Ity ary ilay ohabolana feno : \\"Ny tody tsy misy fa ny atao no miverina\\"."},{"question":"Apakah langkah mengatasi kenaikan harga barang? ","answer":"1. Memastikan bekalan secara domestik mencukupi 2. Menetapkan harga siling dan pemantauan secara kerap 3. Mempraktikkan amalan jimat-cermat 4. Mengawal aktiviti import dan eksport 5. Memberikan tindakan tegas kepada peniaga yang melanggar undang-undang 6. Memudahkan proses aduan daripada pengguna"},{"question":"Манас эпосу 📚―Кыргыздын баатырдык эпосторунун өзгөчөлүктөрү жөнүндө илимий монографиянын автору а) С. Аксыкенти  б) Ч. Валиханов в) М. И. Богданова г) Б. Сазанов","answer":"в) М. И.Богданова"},{"question":"Ano ang isa pang pangalan ng Philippine men's national basketball team?","answer":"Ang \\"Gilas Pilipinas\\" ang isa pang pangalan ng Philippine men's national basketball team. Nagsimula ang paggamit ng pangalang ito noong 2010 bilang pamalit sa dating pangalan na \\"Team Pilipinas\\". Ipinalangan ito kay Gilas, ang mascot ng 2005 Southeast Asian Games na ginanap sa Manila."},{"question":"Qual é o diâmetro de uma cesta de basquete em centímetros?","answer":"45 centímetros"},{"question":"பூமியில் கிடைக்கும் கடினமான பொருள் எது?","answer":"வைரம்"},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Mengapakah kemalangan berlaku di jalan yang lurus?A. Cuaca yang baikB. Kenderaan dipandu terlalu lajuC. Tidak mencuci kenderaan","answer":"Jawapannya ialah B. Kenderaan dipandu terlalu laju"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Nhiều bà bầu thường lo lắng về việc ăn rau muống con sinh ra sẽ bị rốn lồi hoặc chậm lành vết thương. Tuy nhiên, trên thực tế, rau muống là loại rau có chứa rất nhiều thành phần acid folic tự nhiên tốt cho sức khỏe. Không ít mẹ bầu lo lắng về việc ăn rau muống 3 tháng đầu. (Ảnh minh họa) Như đã chia sẻ, rau muống chứa nguồn axit folic tự nhiên rất tốt. Vì thế, mẹ bầu nên ăn để bổ sung nguồn dưỡng chất này trong 3 tháng đầu tiên nhằm hạn chế nguy cơ bị dị tật ống thần kinh ở thai nhi. Nhưng nếu như giai đoạn 3 tháng đầu của thai kỳ, thể trạng của mẹ bầu không được tốt thì tuyệt đối không nên ăn rau muống nhé. Ngoài ra, nếu muốn ăn rau muống, mẹ bầu cần phải chế biến kỹ và mua rau muống từ nguồn cung cấp an toàn, đảm bảo vệ sinh, không bị nhiễm thuốc trừ sâu. Đảm bảo vệ sinh bằng cách ngắt từng ngọn và ngâm rửa sạch trong nước muối pha loãng. Rau muống rất giàu axit folic nên giúp mẹ bầu hạn chế nguy cơ sinh non hoặc khuyết tật bẩm sinh ở thai nhi. Rau muống có chứa thành phần canxi, đây là khoáng chất rất cần thiết cho sự phát triển xương, răng của trẻ cũng như bảo vệ mẹ khỏi chứng loãng xương sau sinh. Không những thế, mẹ bầu ăn rau muống còn bổ sung thêm nhiều thành phần vitamin A, tốt cho sức khỏe thị lực, hỗ trợ ngăn ngừa các dấu hiệu đục thủy tinh thể. Rau muống hỗ trợ bổ sung vitamin A, vitamin D cho bà bầu 3 tháng đầu. (Ảnh minh họa) Ăn rau muống đều đặn sẽ giúp nâng cao hệ miễn dịch và hỗ trợ mẹ bầu chống lại các bệnh nhiễm trùng. Hoạt chất glycolipid của rau muống cũng có khả năng làm giảm đau nhức toàn thân do sự tăng trọng và thay đổi nội tiết tố khi mang thai. Nhờ có thành phần giàu chất sắt nên lá rau muống non cực kỳ có lợi cho những người bị thiếu máu và phụ nữ mang thai cần chất sắt trong chế độ ăn uống. Sắt là một khoáng chất quan trọng cần thiết cho cơ thể, đặc biệt là các tế bào hồng cầu, để hình thành hemoglobin. Rau muống rất giàu chất xơ nên có khả năng hỗ trợ tiêu hóa, giúp giảm các rối loạn tiêu hóa khác nhau một cách tự nhiên. Đặc tính nhuận tràng của rau muống cũng","answer":"có lợi cho những mẹ bầu bị chứng khó tiêu và táo bón. Hầu hết, tất cả rau muống đều được trồng tại các ao hồ. Đây là môi trường có chứa nhiều loài giun sán ký sinh, đặc biệt là loại sán lá ruột lớn (Fasciolopsis buski) gây đau bụng, khó tiêu khi vào cơ thể. Do vậy, thay vì ăn rau muống sống, tốt nhất là nên ăn rau đã rửa sạch và nấu chín kỹ. Bà bầu chỉ nên ăn loại rau muống đã được nấu chín kỹ. (Ảnh minh họa) Rau muống xào tỏi là món ăn ngon, đã được nấu chín nên bà bầu hoàn toàn có thể ăn món ăn này. Tuy nhiên, khi trồng rau muống, một số người có thể dùng thêm hóa chất để giúp rau tăng trưởng nhanh hơn và ít bị sâu. Vì vậy, khi chế biến rau muống xào tỏi, mẹ bầu cần ngâm nước muối, rửa lại nhiều lần dưới vòi nước sạch trước khi nấu để giúp phòng tránh tình trạng ngộ độc thức ăn. Rau muống xào tỏi là món ăn ngon được mẹ bầu yêu thích. (Ảnh minh họa) - Với những mẹ bầu 3 tháng đầu đang có những vết thương ngoài da không nên ăn rau muống do chúng sẽ làm kích thích tăng sinh tế bào gây sẹo lồi, ảnh hưởng đến tính thẩm mỹ. - Mẹ bầu bị bệnh gout không nên ăn do rau muống có chứa khá nhiều đạm thực vật. - Mẹ bầu 3 tháng đầu đang bị suy nhược cơ thể hoặc có các vấn đề về đường tiêu hóa cũng không nên ăn rau muống để tránh ảnh hưởng cho sức khỏe. - Mỗi tuần chỉ nên ăn rau muống khoảng 2-3 bữa. Nguồn: https://arttimes.vn/gia-dinh/ba-bau-3-thang-dau-an-rau-muong-duoc-khong-c59a8435.htmlNguồn: https://arttimes.vn/gia-dinh/ba-bau-3-thang-dau-an-rau-muong-duoc-khong-c59a8435.html"},{"question":"Ответьте на вопрос: Какого числа закончилась Вторая мировая война?","answer":"Вторая мировая война завершилась официально 2 сентября 1945 года, когда Япония подписала акт о безоговорочной капитуляции на борту военного корабля USS \\"Миссури\\" в Токийском заливе. Эта дата стала известной в США как \\"День Победы над Японией\\" и ознаменовала официальное завершение Второй мировой войны."},{"question":"ઉમાશંકર જોશી ની \\"રામમઢી રે મારી\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"રામમઢી રે મારી રામમઢી,ગંગાને કાંઠે મારી રામમઢી;રામમઢી રે મારી રામમઢી,જમનાને કાંઠે મારી રામમઢી.કોઈ સંતન આવે, મંગલ ગાવે,અલખધૂન રસરંગ લગાવે;આવે કોઈ અવધૂત ચઢી.રામમઢી રે મારી રામમઢી..રસભર હૈયાંની ડોલે નૈયા,પિયુપિયુ બોલે પ્રાણબપૈયા;ચેતનની વરસંત ઝડી.રામમઢી રે મારી રામમઢી.."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：什麼是地質學中的「地殼構造」？","answer":"答案：地殼構造是指地球表面的地殼的形狀、結構和構造特徵。它包括山脈、斷層、褶皺、地層和板塊等地球的結構元素，揭示了地球的地質演化和板塊運動。"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Goorma Ayuu Dhacay Dagaalkii Qanda?","answer":"Jawaab: Wuxu Dhacay Sanadkii 8-Aad Ee Hijriyada."},{"question":"شكون هو وزير فرعون اللي مذكور فالقرآن ؟","answer":"هامان"},{"question":"Stelling 1: De constructie van kompas en lijntje in het eerste geval is dezelfde constructie als de LPP-constructie voor de speciale gevallen van het Apollonius-probleem. Zinsnede 2: De constructie van kompas en lijntje in het speciale geval is dezelfde structuur als de LPP-constructie voor de eerste gevallen van het Apollonius-probleem. Vraag: Hebben zin 1 en zin 2 dezelfde betekenis? Ja of nee?","answer":"Nee, de twee zinnen hebben verschillende betekenissen."},{"question":"கர்பகோசதாது பற்றி எழுதுக.","answer":"வஜ்ரயான பௌத்தத்தில், கர்பகோசதாது அல்லது கர்ப மண்டலம் என்பது ஐந்து வித்யாராஜாக்கள் வசிக்கும் மண்டலம் ஆகும்.கர்மகோசதாதுவை குறித்த விவரங்கள் மகாவைரோசன சூத்திரத்தில் காணப்படுகிறது. இந்த மண்டலத்தின் பெயர் மகாவைரோசன சூத்திரத்தின் இரண்டாம் அதிகாரத்தில் இருந்து பெறப்படுகிறது. அதில் மஹாவைரோசனர் இந்த மண்டலத்தின் ரகசிய போதனைகளை வஜ்ரசத்துவருக்கு தன்னுடைய காருண்ய கர்பத்தில் இருந்து உபதேசித்ததாக கூறப்பட்டுள்ளது.அனைத்து மண்டலங்களுள் கர்பகோசதாதுவும், வஜ்ரதாதுவும் மிகவும் புகழ்பெற்றவை. இவ்விரு மண்டலங்களும் இணைந்து இரு பிரிவு மண்டலம் என்ற ஒன்றை உருவாக்குகின்றன. கர்பகோசதாதுவும் வஜ்ரதாதுவும் இணைந்து ஷிங்கோன் பௌத்த சடங்கான அபிஷேகத்தில் மிகவும் முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்தவையாக உள்ளன. பாரம்பரிய ஷிங்கோன் பௌத்த அறைகளும், இந்த கர்ப மண்டலத்தின் படம் கிழக்கு சுவரின் மாட்டப்படுகிறது. இது மஹாவைரோசன புத்தரின் போதியின் இளைய நிலையை குறிப்பதாக கருதப்படுகிறது. அதே நேரத்தில் வஜ்ரதாதுவின் படம் மேற்கு சுவரின் மாட்டப்படுகிறது. இது வைரோசனரின் இறுதி நிலையை குறிப்பதாகும்."},{"question":" महाराष्ट्रातील वन्यजीवांची प्रमुख अभयारण्ये कोठे आहेत?","answer":"महाराष्ट्रातील वन्यजीवांची  प्रमुख अभयारण्ये  मेलघाट, पेन्च, टाडोबा-अंधरी, नागझिरी, आणि ताडवदा येथे आहेत."},{"question":" Sheeg dhulka uuku dhashay sayid Maxamed Cabdule Xasan? ","answer":" Dhulka uu ku dhashay sayid Maxamed Xasan waxa layiraah Da Nugaal. "},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: കേരള സർവകലാശാലയുടെ സ്ഥാപകൻ ആരാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"ചിത്തിര തിരുനാൾ ബലരാമവർമ്മ."},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?අදක්ෂ ","answer":"දක්ෂ"},{"question":"السؤال: الهجرة النبوية من أين كانت وإلى أين؟","answer":"الإجابة: هاجر النبي صلى الله عليه وسلم من مكة المكرمة إلى المدينة المنورة."},{"question":"عايزك تجاوب بأبسط اجابة ممكنة للسؤال ده: واحد مصرى طلع الفضاء، ايه اللى هيحصل؟","answer":"سؤال شيق و بيحتمل اجابات كتير. لكن بما انك طلبت أبسط اجابة، فممكن نقول ان: لو واحد مصرى طلع الفضاء عدد المصريين هيقل واحد.عندك أسئلة تانية؟"},{"question":"Unsa imong nakat-unan gikan sa imong mga eksperyensya?","answer":"Daghan kong natun-an sa pag-agi sa mga kahimtang sa kinabuhi."},{"question":"Unsa ang brother sa Bisaya?","answer":"Ang \\"brother\\" sa Bisaya mao ang \\"igsoon nga lalaki\\" or \\"igsuon nga lalaki.”"},{"question":"Mi o fẹ Senabu mọ, igo lo maa n pa mọlẹ ta a ba n ja, bẹẹ lo maa n gbe mi ṣepe-Suraaju","answer":"Ọgbẹni Surajudeen Sanyaolu lọkọ Senabu Sanyaolu, ọdun meji naa ni wọn ṣi fi ṣọkọ ara wọn ti Suraju fi n beere ikọsilẹ bayii. O ni Senabu ko mọ ju ko maa pago mọlẹ lati fi gun oun lọ bawọn ba n ja, ko si mọ bi wọn ṣe n ṣadua fọkọ, afepe. Fun idi eyi, ọkunrin naa loun ko fẹyawo mọ o.Kootu ti wọn ti n gbọ ẹjọ tọkọ-taya l’Ake, niluu Abẹokuta, ni Suraju gbe iyawo rẹ yii lọ. O ṣalaye pe ọmọ meji lawọn bi, ṣugbọn ko si ayọ ninu igbeyawo awọn, afi ija, afi iregbe ojoojumọ latẹnu iyawo oun.Ohun to ba ọrọ naa jẹ ni ti igo to ni Senabu maa n pa mọlẹ ti yoo fẹẹ fi gun oun.Ija naa ki i ṣe ẹẹkankan, o ni loorekoore lawọn maa n ja, oun si ti fi ẹjọ rẹ sun iya rẹ atawọn famili rẹ yooku titi, ṣugbọn ko sẹni ti iyawo oun gbọrọ si lẹnu ninu wọn, bẹẹ ni ija n tẹsiwaju.Ọgbẹni Sanyaolu sọ pe lojiji ni Senabu ko jade nile oun lọdun 2019, ko tiẹ sọ nnkan kan foun to fi lọ. O ni ṣugbọn o kan kuro nile oun ni, o ṣi maa n wa si ibiiṣẹ oun lati waa ba oun ja, ti yoo maa pariwo pe oun ki i ṣe ọkunrin gidi, ti yoo maa doju toun loju awọn oṣiṣẹ yooku.Ki eyi le ma ṣẹlẹ mọ, ki kaluku si le maa lọ nilọ ẹ labẹ ofin lo ni o jẹ koun wa si kootu, ki wọn tu igbeyawo yii ka, oun yoo maa ṣẹtọ fawọn ọmọ oun bo ṣe yẹ, ṣugbọn oun ko fẹ Senabu mọ ṣa.Nigba to n ṣalaye ara ẹ, Senabu sọ pe oun ko deede fi ọkọ oun silẹ. O ni Suraju ni ko to lọkunrin, nitori ki i tọju oun atawọn ọmọ toun bi fun un, ohun to si maa n faja naa niyẹn.O loun ki i yọgo sọkọ oun, ko le to bẹẹ yẹn rara. Senabu sọ pe nigba toun ri i pe ko nifẹẹ oun mọ rara loun kuro nile fun un.Aarẹ A.O Abimbọla lo gbọ ẹjọ wọn, o paṣe pe kawọn ọmọ wa lọdọ iya wọn bi wọn ṣe wa, ki baba wọn si maa ṣẹtọ to yẹ lori wọn. Adajọ sọ pe ki wọn pada wa si kootu fun apero abẹle, lẹyin naa lawọn yoo mọ ohun ti yoo ṣẹlẹ lori ọrọ wọn."},{"question":"வினா :சர்வ தேச விமானப்போக்குவரத்து தினம் எப்போது கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது?","answer":"விடை :சர்வ தேச விமானப்போக்குவரத்து தினம் டிசம்பர் 9 ஆம் தேதி கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Raha voan'ny epistaxis ianao dia inona no tsy mety ? ","answer":"Mandeha rà orona no tsy mety raha voan'ny epistaxis. "},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang membincangkan kesan pembalakan haram di Malaysia. ","answer":"Sebagai seorang rakyat Malaysia, kita seharusnya bersyukur kerana dikelilingi pelbagai sumber alam semula jadi seperti gas asli, air dan tanah yang subur. Daripada khazanah alam ini, pelbagai manfaat yang kita peroleh seperti punca ekonomi, tempat tinggal yang selamat serta keindahan alam untuk dinikmati. Namun, segelintir daripada masyarakat kita telah mengambil kesempatan dengan menghancurkan sebahagian daripada khazanah alam ini Keunikan hutan di negara kita kaya dengan kayu-kayu balak yang tinggi nilainya. Pembalakan sebenarnya dibenarkan di Malaysia tetapi perlu mendapatkan lesen dan mematuhi syarat yang ditetapkan. Tetapi apabila telah dikaburi dengan kekayaan wang ringgit, mereka yang tidak bertanggungjawab telah memilih jalan mudah dengan melakukan pembalakan secara haram. Bagi membuka mata masyarakat awam, wajar untuk kita huraikan kesan-kesan pembalakan haram di Malaysia untuk kepentingan kita bersama.Antara kesan pembalakan haram di Malaysia adalah flora dan fauna diancam kepupusan. Apabila pembalakan haram dibuat di hutan simpan yang telah digazet untuk pemeliharaan flora dan fauna, gejala ini telah memusnahkan habitat haiwan dan tumbuh-tumbuhan. Pembalakan haram lazimnya berlaku di kawasan hutan yang dalam agar tidak dilihat oleh orang awam dan juga penguatkuasa. Lokasi tersebut pula adalah dimana haiwan dan tumbuh-tumbuhan hidup dengan baik kerana jauh daripada populasi manusia. Sebelum menebang kayu-kayu balak, mereka pasti perlu membuat laluan masuk dan keluar untuk jentera berat mereka. Bukan sahaja kayu balak yang haram diambil tetapi juga kawasan sekitar yang dimusnahkan untuk memberi laluan kepada kegiatan haram ini. Jika flora dan fauna ini pupus, ekosistem hutan akan terganggu di mana tanah menjadi kurang subur dan sebagainya. Tegasnya, pembalakan haram akan meninggalkan kesan yang sangat buruk kepada ekosistem kita iaitu ancaman kepupusan flora dan fauna.Pada masa yang sama, kegiatan pembalakan haram meninggalkan kesan seperti mengurangkan kawasan tadahan hujan. Negara kita yang terletak di garisan Khatulistiwa mempunyai iklim tropikal dimana jumlah hujan yang turun adalah tinggi berbanding negara lain. Maka, pokok-pokok yang bertaburan di hutan menjadi kawasan tadahan air hujan dan mengurangkan risiko banjir kepada kawasan yang rendah dan berdekatan sungai. Pembalak haram pula pasti akan menebang pokok yang berdiameter besar dan berusia dimana akar dan rimbunannya memberikan fungsi terbaik untuk menyerap air hujan. Selepas pembalakan di buat, hujan yang turun akan terus meresap ke tanah sehingga mengakibatkan tanah runtuh. Manakala air sungai akan bertambah deras dan berlaku kejadian kepala air dimana sejumlah air yang banyak turun dari kawasan air terjun dengan begitu deras. Kawasan yang berdekatan dengan sungai akan diancam kejadian banjir dan kawsan rekreasi di sungai dan air terjun menjadi bahaya untuk dilawati. Jelaslah bahawa kawasan tadahan hujan merupakan kesan buruk daripada kegiatan pembalakan haram.Kesan lain pembalakan secara haram oleh individu yang tidak bertanggungjawab adalah berlaku peningkatan suhu bumi. Setelah aktiviti menebang pokok secara haram dilakukan, proses penanaman semula tidak dilakukan kerana mereka membalak secara haram. Kesannya bukit-bukau yang ditarah akan terdedah dan jumlah pokok akan berkurangan. Perkara ini menyumbang kepada peningkatan kandungan karbon dioksida di atmosfera bumi kerana tiada pokok untuk menyerap gas tersebut. Secara langsung, suhu bumi akan meningkat dan seterusnya mengakibatkan glasier di kutub utara dan selatan untuk mencair dan meningkatkan paras air laut. Kesan daripada peningkatan paras laut pula akan menyebabkan hakisan pantai yang teruk kemudian menenggelamkan kawasan-kawasan persisiran pantai. Kesan berganda ini hanya bermula daripada kegiatan membalak kayu hutan demi keuntungan sendiri tetapi akhirnya merugikan ramai pihak yang lain. Bak kata pepatah, kerana nila setitik, rosak sesusu belanga. Intihannya, Pembalakan haram akan menyebabkan kenaikan suhu bumi dan pemanasan global.Akhir sekali, kesan yang terjadi hasil daripada kerakusan membalak hasil hutan yang diberikan secara percuma oleh Tuhan adalah akan berlakunya kejadian bencana alam seperti banjir dan tanah runtuh. Mutakhir ini, kerap kali kita dikejutkan dengan berita bencana banjir berlaku di kawasan yang tidak pernah dilanda banjir sebelum ini. Sekiranya pembalakan haram dilakukan di kawasan hutan simpan atau kawasan yang telah ditetapkan bukan untuk membalak, kawasan tadahan hujan akan berkurangan. Perkara ini membawa kepada hakisan tanah ke dalam sungai dan menjadikan mendapan di dalam sungai. Sekiranya berlaku hujan yang lebat maka paras air sungai akan meningkat dan melimpah ke kawasan sekitar sehingga menyebabkan banjir. Keadaan akan bertambah teruk apabila kayu-kayu balak yang telah ditebang hanyut bersama air sungai dan melanggar rumah di kawasan sekitar. Bayangkan jika situasi ini berlaku di kediaman anda? Oleh itu, gejala pembalakan haram harus diabnteras demi kesejahteraan masyarakat. Izharnya, membalak secara haram akan menyebabakan kejadian seperti banjir dan bencana alam yang lain untuk berlaku.Sebagai kesimpulan, pelbagai kesan buruk yang akan diperoleh daripada kegiatan pembalakan haram di negara kita khususnya. Sebagai rakyat marhaen, kita tahu bahawa kita tidak mampu untuk melakukan aktiviti seperti pembalakan haram dan mereka yang mempunyai sumber kewangan yang kukuh sahaja melakukan aktiviti ini demi mengaut keuntungan. Pihak berkuasa yang bertanggungjawab melakukan penguatkuasaan seharusnya mempunyai integriti yang tinggi dan tidak melakukan layanan mengikut darjat. Selain penguatkuasaan undang-undang dan hukuman yang berat kepada pembalak-pembalak haram, pendidikan mengenai pemeliharaan dan pemuliharaan alam sekitar dalam kalangan masyarakat perlu diperkasa. Semoga warkah perbincangan ini memberi impak kepada pembaca dan melakukan obligasi masing-masing untuk menjaga khazanah kurniaan Tuhan kepada tanah air kita."},{"question":"اذكر خمس دول في منطقة البحر المتوسط. ","answer":"حسنأ الدول هي: - اليونان - إيطاليا - إسبانيا- تركيا- فرنساتشكل حوض البحر الأبيض المتوسط من خلال الاصطدام القديم للقارة الأفريقية العربية المتجهة شمالًا مع القارة الأوراسية المستقرة. عندما تحركت أفريقيا-الجزيرة العربية شمالًا، أغلقت بحر تيثيس السابق، الذي كان يفصل سابقًا أوراسيا عن القارة القديمة العملاقة جوندوانا، والتي كانت أفريقيا جزءًا منها. في نفس الوقت تقريبًا، منذ 170 مليون سنة مضت في العصر الجوراسي، تشكل حوض صغير في محيط نيوتيثيس قبل وقت قصير من إغلاق بحر تيثيس في الطرف الشرقي. وقد أدى الاصطدام إلى صعود نظام واسع من الجبال، يمتد من جبال البيرينيه في إسبانيا إلى جبال زاغروس في إيران. حدثت هذه الحلقة من تكوين الجبال، والمعروفة باسم تكون الجبال في جبال الألب، في الغالب خلال عصر الأوليجوسين (منذ 34 إلى 23 مليون سنة (ميا)) والميوسين (23 إلى 5.3 ميا). أصبح نيوتيثيس أكبر خلال هذه الاصطدامات وما يرتبط بها من الطي والاندساس.يعتبر حوض البحر الأبيض المتوسط موطن العالم القديم. إذ على ضفافه ازدهرت الحضارة الفرعونية والإغريقية والبيزنطية، الفنيقية، القرطاجية، الرومانية، العربية الإسلامية. دول البحر الأبيض المتوسط متعددة. ومقسمة على ثلاث قارات. "},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut:  Di manakah pokok yang tertinggi di dunia?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Gunung Everest. Ini kerana Gunung Everest ialah gunung tertinggi di dunia. "},{"question":"Sanaa ina mchango gani?","answer":"Sanaa ina mchango mkubwa sana katika jamii na utamaduni wetu. Inatuunganisha na hisia, maono, na mawazo ya watu wengine, ikileta pamoja tamaduni tofauti na kutoa jukwaa la kuelezea hisia zetu na kushiriki uzoefu wetu. Sanaa inaweza kuwa chanzo cha burudani, kutafakari, na kuelimisha. Pia, inaweza kutumika kama zana ya kuleta mabadiliko na kuibua mjadala katika masuala muhimu kijamii na kisiasa. Kwa hivyo, sanaa ni njia muhimu ya kushirikiana na kuelimisha jamii yetu, na ina jukumu muhimu katika kuunda utambulisho wetu wa kitamaduni"},{"question":"Unsa ang imong gisugid sa imong mga anak kabahin sa Diyos?","answer":"Gisugid nako sa akong mga anak ang kahinayangan sa pagtoo ug pag-ampo sa Diyos."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: \\"Trung Quốc bắt đầu chiến lược công nghiệp về năng lượng xanh khoảng 15 năm trước. Họ đã làm rất tốt, đảm bảo các nguồn tài nguyên thiên nhiên như lithium để sản xuất pin, thép để chế tạo tuabin gió và xây dựng năng lực sản xuất để đáp ứng nhu cầu phát triển tất cả những điều này\\", Adam Bell, cựu quan chức năng lượng Anh, nói.Bell thêm rằng châu Âu trong khi đó tỏ ra không có đủ khả năng và có lẽ không thể tránh khỏi kịch bản \\"Trung Quốc sẽ đóng vai trò quan trọng trong tương lai xanh của châu Âu\\".","answer":"Điều này lại đặt ra cho châu Âu những thách thức liên quan đến địa chính trị và an ninh, theo giới quan sát. Velina Tchakarova, chuyên gia hàng đầu về an ninh châu Âu, cho rằng với nguồn nguyên liệu thô đáng kể và sự bảo hộ của nhà nước, ngành công nghiệp Trung Quốc có lợi thế cạnh tranh mà các công ty châu Âu ngày càng khó bắt kịp."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"arang di dahi\\"?","answer":"Mendapat malu"},{"question":"அல்பேனிய அணி 1946 பால்கன் கோப்பை, 2000 மால்ட்டா ரொத்மன்சு பன்னாட்டுப் போட்டிகளில் பங்குபற்றி வெற்றி பெற்றது. ஆனாலும், அது எந்தவொரு முக்கிய ஐரோப்பிய கால்பந்து சங்கம் அல்லது பன்னாட்டு கால்பந்து சங்கப் போட்டிகள் எதிலும் விளையாடவில்லை. முதற்தடவையாக யூரோ 2016","answer":"போட்டிகளில் விளையாடத் தகுதி பெற்றது."},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Tsy mpankafy an'io fomba fanaovana maritrano io aho; ankafiziko ny fomba famolavolana hafa.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Tsia, tsy misy resaka fankahalana io fanambarana io. Izy io dia manolotra safidy manokany ny amin'ny maritrano tiany, sady tsy manambany olona."},{"question":"સૂર્ય નમસ્કારના ફાયદા જણાવો.","answer":"સૂર્ય નમસ્કાર એ મુદ્રાઓનો એક શક્તિશાળી ક્રમ છે જે શારીરિક અને માનસિક સ્વાસ્થ્ય બંને માટે વિવિધ પ્રકારના ફાયદા પ્રદાન કરે છે. સૂર્ય નમસ્કારના કેટલાક ફાયદાઓમાં નીચેનાનો સમાવેશ થાય છે:લવચીકતા અને ગતિની શ્રેણીમાં સુધારો કરે છે.સ્નાયુઓ અને કોરને મજબૂત બનાવે છે.પરિભ્રમણ વધારે છે.તાણ અને ચિંતાથી રાહત મળે છે.માનસિક સ્પષ્ટતા અને ફોકસને પ્રોત્સાહન આપે છે.એનર્જી લેવલ વધારે છે.થાક ઓછો કરે છે.મુદ્રા અને સંતુલન સુધારે છે.આરામ અને શાંત ઊંઘને પ્રોત્સાહન આપે છે."},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang membincangkan kepentingan negara menjalinkan hubungan baik dengan negara lain. ","answer":"Diplomasi dari segi definisi bermaksud amalan mengurus hubungan antara satu sama lain. Kemahiran yang cukup penting ini merupakan satu cabang dalam pentadbiran sesebuah negara masa kini untuk tampil secara baik di antara negara-negara lain. Menurut catatan sejarah, Kerajaan Melayu Melaka mempunyai hubungan yang baik dengan Dinasti Pemerintah Cina yang menjadikan mereka selamat daripada ancaman penjajah sehinggalah kedatangan Portugis. Mutakhir ini, kerajaan Malaysia memperuntukkan sebuah kementerian untuk menjaga hubungan diplomatik dengan negara-negara asing. Dengan persekitaran politik dunia yang dinamik dan berubah-rubah, negara kita perlu mempunyai sepasukan pegawai yang mampu untuk memastikan dasar luar negara kita menjamin kedudukan Malaysia sebagai sebuah negara yang merdeka. Justeru, penting untuk setiap diantara kita untuk mengetahui apakah kepentingan negara menjalinkan hubungan baik dengan negara luar.Kepentingan utama menjalinkan hubungan yang baik dengan negara luar adalah untuk menjamin keselamatan dan kedaulatan negara. Selepas mengecapi kemerdekaan pada tahun 1957, Malaysia telah berjaya mengekalkan kedaulatan negara sehingga kini. Walaupun negara kita kecil dan mempunyai pelbagai sumber asli seperti minyak dan gas asli yang menjadi rebutan negara-negara yang lebih berkuasa, kekuatan diplomasi dan pentadbiran menjamin hak milik negara kita. Hubungan yang baik dengan negara serantau juga dapat mengelakkan ancaman keselamatan dan memastikan rantau asia tenggara khususnya aman dan berkecuali. Penubuhan Persatuan Negara-Negara Asia Tenggara (ASEAN) mengukuhkan lagi hubungan serantau di samping keahlian Malaysia di pertubuhan-pertubuhan kesatuan negara yang lain. Ingat antara belum kena, hemat antara belum habis. Perumpamaan ini jelas menunjukkan Kepentingan Hubungan Luar Malaysia untuk kita menjalinkan hubungan yang baik dengan negara lain agar keselamatan dan kedaulatan negara terjamin.Pada masa yang sama, jalinan hubungan yang baik antara negara-negara asing dapat mengembangkan potensi ekonomi negara. Di mana ada gula, di situ pasti ada semut. Peribahasa yang membawa maksud jika sesuatu tempat itu mudah untuk menjalankan ekonomi pasti ramai akan datang berkunjung. Apabila kita menjalinkan hubungan dengan negara luar, kita dapat memasarkan produk tempatan dan melakukan aktiviti import dan eksport. Sebagai contoh, sumber asli petroleum dan gas asli yang digali di perairan negara diproses dan diperdagangkan ke pasaran antarabangsa. Syarikat yang mengendali industri ini kini menjadi salah satu syarikat tempatan terkemuka di dunia iaitu Petronas. Kesannya, masyarakat tempatan mendapat peluang pekerjaan dan mampu meningkatkan ekonomi diri, keluarga dan juga negara.Di samping itu, hubungan yang baik antara dua atau pelbagai hala dapat membuka ruang perkongsian penyelidikan dan pendidikan. Sejak dahulu lagi, dasar luar negara yang dijalinkan oleh pemimpin negara telah membuka peluang untuk rakyat Malaysia menyambung pelajaran di negara luar. Begitu juga dengan institusi-institusi pengajian tinggi dalam negara yang menawarkan pengajian kepada pelajar asing. Perkongsian penyelidikan dan pendidikan ini penting untuk melahirkan tenaga kerja tempatan yang boleh menyumbang kepada penyelesaian masalah yang dihadapi oleh negara kita. Tambahan pula, kemajuan dari segi pendidikan akan meningkatkan imej negara di tahap antarabangsa kerana negara lain akan merujuk kajian atau pendapatan yang diperoleh daripada para akademik negara. Bak kata pepatah, laut yang ditimba tidak akan kering. Begitu juga ilmu dan kemahiran di mana usaha untuk mengembangkan boleh dicapai dengan adanya hubungan yang baik dengan negara-negara asing.Akhir sekali, Kepentingan Hubungan Luar Malaysia dan tindakan menjalinkan hubungan yang baik antara negara luar dapat memudahkan bantuan jika berlaku krisis atau bencana alam. Baru-baru ini, kita digemparkan dengan bencana gempa bumi yang melanda Turkiye dan Syria. bencana tersebut mengorbankan banyak nyawa serta memusnahkan pelbagai infrastruktur mereka. Oleh sebab Malaysia mempunyai hubungan yang baik dengan kedua-dua negara, pasukan bantuan dari tentera dan pelabagi NGO dapat dihantar ke sana untuk misi bantuan kebajikan. Sekiranya, Malaysia menghadapi sebarang bencana alam yang teruk, pasti negara-negara yang pernah dibantu oleh negara kita akan datang menawarkan pertolongan daripada pelbagai segi. Bagai aur dengan tebing, itulah semangat yang cuba kita amalkan di peringkat antarabangsa dalam menghadapi zaman globalisasi ketika ini. Tuntasnya, hubungan pelbagai hala yang baik diamalkan oleh Malaysia akan membantu memudahkan bantuan jika berlaku krisis atau bencana alam.Konklusi daripada perbincangan di atas berkaitan kepentingan hubungan luar Malaysia adalah menjalinkan hubungan yang baik antara negara-negara asing menjamin pelabagai kepentingan negara. Sebagai rakyat marhean, kita dilihat tidak mempunyai peranan dalam perkara ini tetapi sedarlah bahawa kita bertanggungjawab dalam memilih pemimpin negara yang akan mencorak pentadbiran negara. Kita hendaklah peka dan cakna dengan tindakan pemimpin negara di peringkat antarabangsa supaya hubungan diplomatik yang sebelum ini berjaya dilaksanakan kekal kukuh dan berfungsi dengan baik. Semoga kedaulatan dan keamanan negara kita terjamin dalam menghadapi sosio ekonomi dan geo politik yang semakin mencabar ketika ini."},{"question":"２００１年結成の３人によるお笑いグループ。元力士のＨｉｒｏ（ヒロ）、ソプラノボイスのクロちゃん、リーダーの安田団長といえばそのグループ名は？","answer":"安田大サーカスです。"},{"question":"Gabay waa tumo Somalida","answer":"Wax cirkaa madow kuu jiraa u cirba taagleyneAdoo culay jirkaa u egyahay yaad carab is "},{"question":"Ko pẹ ti Abiọdun ati Mustapha tẹwọn de ni wọn tun fibọn ja ọkada gba ni Ṣagamu","answer":"Akọsilẹ ijọba lori Abiọdun Ọshọba ati Mustapha Ṣakiru ni pe ẹlẹwọn ni wọn. Ọdun 2020 to kọja yii ni wọn ṣẹṣẹ fi wọn silẹ lọgba ẹwọn Igbeba, n’Ijẹbu-Ode. Afi bi wọn ṣe jade tan to tun jẹ ọkada ni wọn fibọn gba lọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu keji yii, ni Ṣagamu, nibi ti wọn ti n sa lọ lọwọ palaba wọn ti segi.Ọlọkada kan torukọ ẹ n jẹ Aminu Iliyasu ni wọn ni ko gbe awọn lọ si otẹẹli kan ni Ṣagamu, nigba tiyẹn ko si mọ pe wọn lero mi-in lọkan, o gbe wọn loootọ.Nibi ti wọn ti n rin irinajo naa lọwọ ni wọn ti yọ ibọn si ọlọkada Bajaj ti nọmba ẹ jẹ SGM 965VQ naa, wọn ni ko duro bẹẹ ko sọkalẹ, ko gbe ọkada naa fawọn, ko si fa eti ẹ mejeeji, ko maa sa lọ.Aminu ọlọkada ṣe bi wọn ṣe wi, ṣugbọn ko gba kamu sara bẹẹ, teṣan ọlọpaa Ṣagamu lo gba lọ gẹgẹ bi Oyeyẹmi Abimbọla, Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun ṣe fidi ẹ mulẹ.Teṣan yii ni wọn ti mu awọn fijilante mọra, n ni wọn ba di gbogbo ọna to jade ni GRA Ṣagamu yii, ohun to si ran wọn lọwọ ti wọn fi ri awọn afurasi mejeeji naa mu niyẹn.Abiọdun ati Mustapha ti ka nọmba ara ọkada naa penpe, ko see ri i lara rẹ mọ.Ṣugbọn bi Abiọdun ṣe ri awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn n ṣọ ọna ti wọn n gba bọ, niṣe lo fi ọkada naa silẹ, to bẹrẹ si i fi ẹsẹ rẹ sare lọ. Awọn ọlọpaa naa gba tọ ọ, wọn si ri i mu.Bi wọn ṣe mu un ni wọn mu Mustpaha, iwadii si fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ọdun 2016 ni Ṣakiru Mustpha wọ ọgba ẹwọn, nitori tirela ti wọn lo ko lọna, to si fẹẹ ja gba. Ọdun 2019 ni Abiọdun ṣẹwọn ni tiẹ, Alukoro sọ pe foonu lo ja gba to fi di ero ọgba ẹwọn.Inu ẹwọn ọhun ni wọn ti pade, ni wọn ba di ọrẹ ojiji, wọn si pinnu lati da ikọ adigunjale tiwọn silẹ bi wọn ba ti jade. Bi wọn si ti gba ominira ni 2020 naa ni wọn bẹrẹ iṣẹ alọkolohun kigbe ọhun pada, to fi di pe wọn tun ko sọwọ lẹẹkeji. Ibọn ilewọ ibilẹ kan ati ọta ibọn ti wọn ko ti i yin lawọn ọlọpaa ba lọwọ wọn.Ọga ọlọpaa pata nipinlẹ yii, CP Edward Ajogun, ti ni ki wọn ko wọn lọ sẹka iwadii, ibẹ ni wọn wa lasiko yii ti wọn n ṣe faaji wọn."},{"question":"Mihin tarkoituksiin lisäaineita käytetään?","answer":"Elintarvikelisäaineita voidaan käyttää useisiin eri tarkoituksiin. EU:n lainsäädännössä määritetään 26 teknologista syytä niiden käytölle. Lisäaineita ovat muun muassa seuraavat:väriaineita käytetään lisäämään tai antamaan väriä elintarvikkeeseensäilöntäaineet pidentävät elintarvikkeiden säilyvyyttä suojelemalla niitä mikro-organismeiltahapettumisenestoaineet ovat aineita, jotka pidentävät elintarvikkeiden säilyvyyttä suojaamalla niitä hapettumiselta, kuten rasvan härskiintymiseltä ja värinmuutoksiltajauhon käsittelyaineita lisätään jauhoon tai taikinaan sen leivontaominaisuuksien parantamiseksi."},{"question":"காகிதப் பணத்தைப் பயன்படுத்திய முதல் நாடு எது?","answer":" சீனா"},{"question":"Qual è l'evento storico a cui si riferisce il seguente testo?\\"Il Venom venne utilizzato dalla RAF anche durante la Crisi di Suez, conflitto per l'occupazione militare del canale di Suez conteso tra Egitto, guidato dal Presidente, col. Gamāl ʿAbd al-Nāsser, ed una coalizione franco-britannico-israeliana, durante l'operazione Musketeer del 1950 con i 6, 8 e 249 Squadrons RAF che operavano dalla base RAF Akrotiri, nell'isola di Cipro. La battaglia aerea che avvenne il 31 ottobre 1956 diede ufficialmente inizio alla Crisi di Suez e vide i Venom della RAF impegnati nell'ingaggiare una serie di installazioni militari sul territorio egiziano.\\"","answer":"L'evento storico a cui si riferisce il testo è la Crisi di Suez."},{"question":"Tôi đang có khoảng 2 tỷ đồng, muốn mua một căn chung cư giá khoảng gần 3 tỷ đồng. Chung cư đó mới hoàn thành được 3 năm, chưa có sổ hồng. Với số tiền đang có, vợ chồng tôi sẽ phải vay thêm 700-800 triệu và thế chấp bằng căn chung cư đó. Nhưng vợ chồng tôi hiện đều làm việc tự do, thu nhập khoảng 50 triệu đồng mỗi tháng và không thể chứng minh thu nhập của mình.Vậy tôi có thể vay thế chấp được không? Được biết chủ nhà cũng đang vay ngân hàng và thế chấp bằng hợp đồng mua bán với chủ đầu tư. Cảm ơn mọi người đã tư vấn.","answer":"Trước hết, bạn cần xác định rõ khi mua dự án căn hộ chưa có sổ, chỉ có những ngân hàng nằm trong danh sách tài trợ cho dự án mới có thể cung cấp khoản vay cho bạn. Lúc này, lãi suất cũng như điều kiện vay và các loại phí, lãi phạt... sẽ phụ thuộc vào các ngân hàng trong danh sách này và bạn sẽ không có quá nhiều sự lựa chọn.Nếu bạn vay 800 triệu đồng trong 15 năm, lãi suất lấy ví dụ là 10% một năm, hàng tháng phải trả nợ trung bình khoảng 11 triệu đồng. Với thu nhập khoảng 50 triệu mỗi tháng, trung bình các gia đình tại Việt Nam có thể tiết kiệm được 20-30% thu nhập, tương ứng 10-15 triệu đồng. Như vậy, bạn có thể đảm bảo khả năng trả nợ ngân hàng mà vẫn giữ được các mức chi tiêu thông thường trong cuộc sống.Cần lưu ý \\"bẫy\\" lãi suất thả nổi, với lãi suất ưu đãi rất hấp dẫn trong ngắn hạn và sau đó lãi suất thả nổi cao khiến chúng ta bị động, rơi vào tình trạng khó khăn, đặc biệt trong giai đoạn tình hình kinh tế xã hội có nhiều biến động.Hiện nay, Thông tư 06 của Ngân hàng Nhà nước cho phép người dân vay ngân hàng này trả nợ ngân hàng khác. Tuy nhiên theo khảo sát mới đây của VnExpress, việc vay ngân hàng mới để trả nợ cũ thực tế không dễ tiếp cận vì khẩu vị rủi ro về tài sản đảm bảo của mỗi ngân hàng khác nhau, thị trường biến động khiến mất giá tài sản đảm bảo, phát sinh chi phí cho khoản vay mới. Bên cạnh đó, khách hàng còn phải vượt qua khâu xét duyệt hồ sơ theo qui định của từng ngân hàng. Trong tương lai, bạn cần theo dõi sát khả năng thực hiện và các điều kiện áp dụng, các chi phí phát sinh cho việc \\"đảo nợ\\" để có hướng xử lý tối ưu.Bạn nên vay với thời gian càng dài càng tốt, để giảm áp lực tài chính hàng tháng. Cũng cần lưu ý về khả năng thanh toán nợ trước hạn mà không bị lãi phạt để có thể giảm lãi phải trả nếu có thể tăng thêm tiền trả nợ gốc hàng tháng cho ngân hàng.ạn cũng nên thiết lập một quỹ dự phòng khẩn cấp có giá trị tối thiểu là 6 tháng chi phí chi tiêu và khoản trả ngân hàng. Khi gặp vấn đề ảnh hưởng đến sức khỏe hay thu nhập, quỹ dự phòng là \\"chiếc phao\\" để bạn có thể vượt qua khó khăn tạm thời. Khi không có sẵn quỹ dự phòng, chúng ta có khuynh hướng vay nợ để chi trả cho các chi phí nằm ngoài dự tính, dễ lâm vào cảnh nợ nần chồng chất."},{"question":"Completa la seguente frase: Ebbe un ruolo chiave nella creazione del grande impero marittimo ateniese in seguito al fallimento dell'","answer":"invasione persiana della Grecia da parte di Serse nel 480-479 a.C. Cimone divenne un riconosciuto eroe militare e fu elevato al rango di ammiraglio dopo aver combattuto la Battaglia di Salamina."},{"question":"ලෝකයේ දෙවන විශාලතම ජනගහනය සිටින රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලෝකයේ දෙවන විශාලතම ජනගහනය සිටින රට ඉන්දියාව යි."},{"question":"Ọwọ tẹ ọmọde Fulani pẹlu ibọn n”Iwoye-Ketu","answer":"Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹjọ yii, lọwọ awọn agbofinro ipinlẹ Ogun ba ọmọkunrin Fulani kekere yii pẹlu ibọn AK 47 lọwọ rẹ, ninu igbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Ọha, n’Iwoye -Ketu, nijọba ibilẹ Imẹkọ-Afọn, nipinlẹ Ogun.Mohammed lọmọdekunrin naa pe orukọ ara ẹ, darandaran lo ni oun n ṣe. Ṣugbọn ko ri alaye ṣe fun ohun ti Fulani nilo ibọn fun to ba n daran, n lawọn ọlọpaa fijilante So-Safe atawọn ọlọdẹ ibilẹ ti wọn ri i ninu igbo naa ba yaa mu un.Awọn kan ni wọn ta DPO Imẹkọ lolobo pe awọn ri awọn omọde Fúlàní ọkunrin meji kan ninu igbo Ọha ti wọn gbebọn dani.Eyi lo mu awọn ọlọpaa atawọn ma-jẹ-o-bajẹ mi-in wọnu igbo naa lọ, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i fọgbo kiri lati ri awọn ọmọde agbebọn yii mu.Lẹyin ọpọlọpọ wakati ti wọn ti wọgbo naa kiri ni wọn ri Muhammed yii mu nibi to sa pamọ si toun tibọn to ju ọjọ ori rẹ lọ.Gẹgẹ bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe wi, wọn ni gbogbo oye lo foju han pe ọkan ninu awọn ikọ ajinigbe to n da agbegbe naa laamu lọmọ yii yoo jẹ.Wọn ti gbe ọmọde naa lọ sẹka itọpinpin, bẹẹ lawọn ọlọpaa ṣi n wa inu igbo naa lati ri awọn yooku rẹ."},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Mengapakah warga tua yang berjalan kaki perlu diberikan lebih perhatian?A. Pendengaran dan penglihatan mereka kurang baikB. Mereka suka melintas secara meluluC. Mereka kurang sabar","answer":"Jawapannya ialah A. Pendengaran dan penglihatan mereka kurang baik"},{"question":"أجب على السؤال 'ما هو الإستراديول ؟' بشكل مطول:","answer":"الإستراديول هو مركب مطابق حيوي للإستروجين يُنتج بشكل طبيعي، أو ناهض لمستقبلات هرمون الإستروجين، المستهدَف الحيوي لهرمون الإستروجين مثل الإستراديول ذو التنشؤ الداخلي. نظرًا لنشاطه الإستروجيني، فإن الإستراديول يملك تأثيرات مضادة لموجهة الغدة التناسلية ويمكنه تثبيط الخصوبة ويمنع إنتاج الهرمون التناسلي لدى كل من النساء والرجال، يختلف الإستراديول عن المركبات الإستروجينية غير المطابقة حيويًا مثل البريمارين والإثينيل استراديول بنواحي مختلفة، مثل عواقب التحمل والسلامة الدوائية."},{"question":"Кыргыз 🎥 тасмалары жөнүндө кандай кызыктуу окуяларды билесиз?","answer":"🎬 1941-жылдын 17-ноябры кыргыз киносунун жаралган күнү деп эсептелет. Бул күнү Совет элдик комитети “Фрунзе шаарында кинохроникалык студия курулсун” деген буйрук чыгарган. Кыргыз киносунун тарыхы 1942-ж. түзүлгөн көркөм, документалдык жана анимациялык тасмаларды өндүрүүчү \\"Кыргызфильм\\" киностудиясы менен тыгыз байланышкан. 1955-ж.- «Кыргызфильм» улуттук киностудиясынын базасында \\"Мосфильм\\" киностудиясынын режиссёру В.Пронин «Салтанат» көркөм фильмин тарткан. 1964-ж. «Кыргызфильм» киностудиясынын өз режиссеру М. Убукеев кыргыз киносундагы алгачкы кинотасма болуп эсептелген \\"Тайгак кечүү\\" толук метраждуу көркөм фильмин тарткан."},{"question":"السؤال: شكون هو النبي الذي كان تاي يحيي الموتى؟","answer":"الإجابة: عيسى عليه السلام"},{"question":"సమాచార హక్కు ఎప్పటి నుండి అమల్లోకి వచ్చింది?","answer":"12 అక్టోబర్ 2005"},{"question":"*ما عاصمة ولاية ألاسكا ؟","answer":"جونو"},{"question":"\\"सफाईचे महत्व कसे आहे आणि आपल्याला यात्रेच्या अवस्थेतील कसे मदतील आहे?\\"","answer":"\\"सफाईच्या महत्वाच्या कामामुळे आपल्याला आरोग्यपूर्ण आणि सुरक्षित यात्रा करण्याची संधी मिळते. यात्रेच्या अवस्थेतील सफाई मेडिकल संगणकांना आपल्याला रोगाची व संक्रमणाची नोंद घेतली पाहिजे आणि त्यानुसार कृती करण्यात मदतील आहे.\\""},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：什么是印度拉格音乐？","answer":"答案：印度拉格音乐是印度古典音乐中的一个重要概念。拉格是指一种特定的旋律模式，每个拉格都有其独特的音阶和表演规则。拉格音乐的作用是通过演唱和演奏不同的拉格来表达不同的情感和氛围。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bawa hati\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud merajuk. Setelah pinangannya ditolak, Amar bawa hati dan belayar ke negeri orang."},{"question":"Ileegbimọ aṣofin agba mejeeji buwọ lu aba eto iṣuna ọdun 2021","answer":"Awọn aṣofin ilẹ wa ti buwọ lu aba eto isuna owo ti Naijiria yoo na lọdun 2021 ta a fẹẹ mu yii. Tiriliọnu mẹtala ati ẹgbẹta naira din diẹ (N13.588 trillion) ni wọn fọwọ si.Ọsan ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ni ile-aṣofin mejeeji faṣẹ si aba naa, wọn si pinnu lati fi i ṣọwọ si Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari lati fọwọ si i, ki eto iṣuna naa le bẹrẹ iṣẹ.Ninu aba naa, owo to fẹrẹ to ẹgbẹta miliọnu lawọn aṣofin naa tun fi kun iyẹ tijọba gbe siwaju wọn lati yẹ wo. Tiriliọnu mẹtala ati mejilelọgọrin naira (N13.082 trillion) ni Buhari gbe kalẹ niwaju wọn lọjọ kẹjọ, oṣu kẹwaa yii, ṣugbọn tiriliọnu mẹtala ati ẹgbẹta naira din diẹ (N13.588 trillion) lawọn aṣofin naa panu-pọ le lori, oun si ni wọn fọwọ si lọjọ Aje.Wọn ni bọjẹẹti ti wọn pe akọle ẹ ni ‘Amusọji ọrọ-aje’ naa maa jẹ ki ọrọ-aje Naijiria sunwọn si i, o maa jẹ ki a wo awọn ọna mi-in ti owo le gba wọle yatọ si ti epo rọbi, o si maa din iṣẹ ati inira to n ba awọn araalu finra ku gan-an.Nnkan bii tiriliọnu mẹta aabọ ni wọn yoo fi san pada ninu awọn gbese ti orileede wa jẹ, tiriliọnu mẹrin o le diẹ lo maa ba iṣẹ ilu ati awọn ohun amayedẹrun lọ, nigba ti tiriliọnu marun-un aabọ maa lọ sori awọn owo-oṣu ati ajẹmọnu gbogbo.Iṣiro ogoji owo dọla Amẹrika fun agba epo kan ni wọn lawọn fi ṣiro aba eto iṣuna naa.Awọn aṣofin naa ni tijọba ba buwọ lu u, ti wọn si tẹle e, nile loko lafẹfẹ igbe aye ọtun yoo fẹ de lorileede yii."},{"question":"ෆෙඩරල් රජය හැර ඔටාවාගේ ආර්ථිකයට සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස දායක වන අංශ මොනවාද?","answer":"බොහෝ විදුලි සංදේශ, මෘදුකාංග, ආරක්‍ෂක සහ ආරක්‍ෂාව, ජෛව තාක්‍ෂණය සහ රැහැන් රහිත සමාගම් අගනුවර පිහිටා ඇති ඔටාවා ආර්ථිකයට තාක්‍ෂණ අංශය සැලකිය යුතු දායකත්වයක් සපයයි."},{"question":"Qual é o papel de um arqueólogo?","answer":"Um arqueólogo pesquisa e escava sítios históricos para descobrir evidências do passado."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر الخفيف. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"كَيف يَنسى مَن لَيسَ في الدَهر يَنسىغُصنٌ طابَ في فُؤادي غَرسابَدرٌ تَمَ تَود لَو كانَت الأَنجم نَقلاً إِذا تَناوَلَ شَمسايَتَمناهُ كُل قَلب وَلا يُدرك مِن أَخمصي ذاكَ لَمسا"},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Tahap kehidupan seseorang di mana dia tahu dan tidak tahu pada masa yang sama.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah remaja"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai anai-anai sukakan kayu\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa ini bermaksud sangat seronok dengan kerja yang dilakukan,"},{"question":"Hình nào sau đây không có tâm đối xứngA. Hình vuôngB. Hình chữ nhậtC. Hình bình hànhD. Hình tam giác đều","answer":"Trả lời:- Tâm đối xứng của hình vuông là giao điểm của hai đường chéo.- Tâm đối xứng của hình chữ nhật là giao điểm của hai đường chéo.- Tâm đối xứng của hình bình hành là giao điểm của hai đường chéo.- Hình tam giác đều không có tâm đối xứng.Đáp án cần chọn là: D"},{"question":"Apakah tema sambutan Hari Kebangsaan Malaysia pada tahun 2017?","answer":"Tema sambutan Hari Kebangsaan Malaysia pada tahun 2017 ialah Negaraku Sehati Sejiwa."},{"question":"Mejupụta okwu a bụ: Nwata akwọ n'azụ","answer":"Mmejupụta: Amaghị n'ụzọ dị anya"},{"question":"ما هو دور أمانة المنظمة في عملية الفريق العامل المعني بتعديلات اللوائح الصحية الدولية؟","answer":"بناءً على طلب الدول الأعضاء، تدعم أمانة المنظمة الفريق العامل بتنظيم اجتماعاته وتزويده بالخدمات والمرافق اللازمة لعمله، وبالمعلومات والمشورة."},{"question":"Зумурут деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Зумурут  бул - асыл таштын бир түрү - изумруд."},{"question":"Zein kirolak dira Euskal Herrian gehien praktikatzen direnak eta zer garrantzi dute gizartean?","answer":"Euskal Herrian gehien praktikatzen diren kirolen artean, pilota da bereziki nabarmena, hainbat modalitatetan jokatzen dena. Pilota euskal kulturaren eta identitatearen parte garrantzitsua da, eta herri kirolak ere ospe handia dute, adibidez, harri-jasotzea eta aizkolariak. Kirol hauek ez dira soilik aisialdirako jarduerak; gizartean batasuna eta komunitatearen sentimendua sustatzen dute, eta belaunaldi arteko loturak indartzen dituzte."},{"question":"Resize වචනයට සමාන සිංහල වචනයක් ලබාදෙන්න. පරිගනක අතුරු වතකට යෙදීම සඳහාය.එහිදී මෙම කාරණා  සපිරිය යුතුයි.හෙළ වදනක් නම් වඩා හොඳයි.තනි වචනයක් විය යුතුයි.ක්‍රියා පදයක් සෑදීමේදී අගට “කරනවා“ යනුවෙන් එක්කරන්න අවශ්‍ය නොවිය යුතුයි.හැකිතාක් කෙටි විය යුතුයි.පහසුවෙන් අවබෝධ වෙන එකක් විය යුතුයි.","answer":"ප්‍රතිප්‍රමාණනය"},{"question":"आवळ्यामध्ये कोणते जीवनसत्व मुबलक प्रमाणात आढळते? ","answer":"व्हिटॅमिन सी"},{"question":"请用简洁的语言回答以下问题：问题：临床心理学的发展趋势是什么？","answer":"答案：临床心理学的发展趋势包括整合新的治疗方法和技术、重视心理预防和心理教育、关注跨文化和多元性等。"},{"question":"Wat zijn veelvoorkomende ingrediënten van een volledig Engels ontbijt?","answer":"Een typisch Engles ontbijt bevat de volgende ingrediënten: Spek, eieren, worstjes, bonen, toast, champignons, tomaten. Sommige mensen voegen ook bloedworst en hash browns toe. Eieren worden vaak gebakken of geroerd."},{"question":"Өз бактысына өзү кедерги болуу, кесирленүү. Таалайыңды теппе, Шарапат жаным ! Шарапат өз таалайынын кайда бурулуп баратканын билди (Абдукаимов).Суроо: сүйлөмдөгү фразеологиялык сөз айкашы кайсы?","answer":"Жооп: таалайын тебүү"},{"question":"متن کامل: \`\` هیچکس تا حالا این سوال رو از من نپرسیده.'' اون به هوا نگاه می کنه و صورتش سفت می شه. \`\` این همیشه یه مبارزه قدرته.","answer":"این اصلا یک سوال نیست. من نه علامت سوال میبینم، و نه متوجه میشم که سوال درباره چی هست.دارید میگید که یک نفر به دوردست ها در آسمان نگاه میکنه و عضلات صورتش منقبض میشه، یعنی احتمالا داره اراده خودش برای یک مبارزه رو جمع میکنه و تصمیم میگیره که حتما در یک مبارزه پیروز بشه. در صورتش خشم و نوعی حس برتری طلبی دیده میشه که باعث میشه عضلات صورت جمع بشن، قدرت در عضلات دیده بشه، اخم کنه، چشم ها بیرون زده بشن، و دندون ها به هم فشرده بشن. خب این که سوال نیست، این یک توصیفه."},{"question":"Qual estado brasileiro tem a sigla PB?","answer":"O estado brasileiro com a sigla \\"PB\\" é a Paraíba."},{"question":"வினா : 1992-ம் ஆண்டு பாரதரத்னா விருது பெற்ற தொழிலதிபர்?","answer":"விடை : ஜே.ஆர்.டி.டாட்டா"},{"question":"കണ്ണൂർ ജില്ലയെക്കുറിച്ച് ഒരു ചെറിയ ഖണ്ഡിക എഴുതുക? വിഷയം: കണ്ണൂർ","answer":"കേരളത്തിന്റെ വടക്കെ അറ്റത്തു നിന്നും രണ്ടാമതായി സ്ഥിതി ചെയ്യുന്ന ജില്ലയാണ് കണ്ണൂർ. കണ്ണൂർ നഗരമാണ് ഇതിന്റെ ആസ്ഥാനം. വലിപ്പത്തിന്റെ കാര്യത്തിൽ കേരളത്തിൽ അഞ്ചാം സ്ഥാനത്താണ്. കേരളത്തിലെ നാലാമത്തെ വിമാനത്താവളം കണ്ണൂർ ജില്ലയിൽ ആണ്. കണ്ണൂർ കണ്ണന്നൂർ, കണ്ണനൂർ, കേനന്നൂർ എന്നീ പേരുകളിൽ അറിയപ്പെട്ടിരുന്നു. തറികളുടെയും തിറകളുടെയും നാട് എന്നാണു കണ്ണൂർ അറിയപ്പെടുന്നത്. ഭാഷയുടെയും ഭൂഘടനയുടെയും അടിസ്ഥാനത്തിലുള്ള അതിർവരമ്പുകൾ ആവിർഭവിക്കുന്നതിനും ഏറെ മുമ്പു തന്നെ പുരാതന തമിഴകത്തിലെ ഒരു പ്രധാന ആവാസകേന്ദ്രമായി ഇപ്പോഴത്തെ കണ്ണൂർ അറിയപ്പെട്ടിരുന്നു. പഴയ കാലത്തെ വീരന്മാരും പോരാളികളും ദേവതകളും ഒക്കെ അവരുടെ കാലശേഷവും നാട്ടുകാരുടെ മനസ്സിൽ കഥകളിലൂടെയും പാട്ടുകളിലൂടെയും നിലനിന്നു. ക്രമേണ അവർ തെയ്യക്കോലങ്ങളായി മാറി. അവരുടെ ഓർമ്മപ്പെടുത്തലുമായി ഇന്നും ആണ്ടു തോറും തെയ്യക്കോലങ്ങളായി കെട്ടിയാടപ്പെടുന്നു. തെയ്യക്കോലങ്ങൾ ഗ്രാമീണരുടെ പ്രത്യക്ഷ ദൈവങ്ങൾ ആണ്."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਅਸੰਖ ਮੂਰਖ ਅੰਧ ਘੋਰ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 4 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"(ਨਿਰੰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਰਚੀ ਹੋਈ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਵਿਚ) ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਹੀ ਮਹਾਂ ਮੂਰਖ ਹਨ, \\""},{"question":"Наркескен - сөзүнүн түшүндүрмөсү кандай ?","answer":"\\"Наркескен\\" сөзү - кылычтын энчилүү аты, Манастын кылычы болгон делет."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ayam tidur senang dalam reban, musang yang susah beredar keliling'","answer":"Maksudnya ialah orang yang berperasaan dengki, tidak suka melihat orang lain senang"},{"question":"Menene taken jihar Katsina?","answer":"Katsina ita \\"Home of Hospitality\\" wato \\"Gidan Baƙi\\""},{"question":"आसवन प्रक्रियाहरूमा अजियोट्रोपको अवधारणा व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"आसवनमा Azeotropes ले तरल पदार्थको मिश्रणलाई जनाउँछ जसमा निरन्तर उमाल्ने संरचना हुन्छ। यो घटनाले पृथकीकरण प्रक्रियाहरूलाई जटिल बनाउँछ, किनकि एजियोट्रोपिक मिश्रणमा भएका अवयवहरूलाई सरल आसवनद्वारा सजिलैसँग अलग गर्न सकिँदैन। यी चुनौतिहरू पार गर्न दबाब स्विङ डिस्टिलेसन जस्ता उन्नत प्रविधिहरू प्रयोग गर्न सकिन्छ"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Mampaharary vao _ ohatry ny fitiavana\\"","answer":"Mampaharary vao mihà-tiana ohatry ny fitiavana"},{"question":"Horey ayaan ugu jirey liiska sugitaanka Sekshan 8. Ma in aan marlabaad dib u codsadaa?","answer":"Maya, waxaan dhaxmareynaa dhamaan qof walba oo ku jira liiska sugitaanka ee haatan ka hor inta aanan ka soo bixin arjiyo codsi cusub liiska cusub."},{"question":"Sheeg Noocyada Kala Duwan Ee Balaasmoodiyamka Keena Malaariyada?","answer":"b) Balaasmoodiyam Falisbaram (Plasmodium Falicparum)t) Balaasmoodiyam Fiikakis (Plasmodium Vivax)j) Balaasmoodiyam Ofeli (Plasmodium Ovali)x) Balaasmoodiyam Malaariyo (Plasmodium Malaria)"},{"question":"\\"ഞാൻ ഹിന്ദി പരീക്ഷയിൽ പരാജയപ്പെട്ടു, എനിക്ക് അത് വീണ്ടും എഴുതേണ്ടി വരും\\" മുൻ പ്രസ്താവനയുടെ വികാരം എന്താണ്?","answer":"പരീക്ഷയിൽ പരാജയപ്പെട്ടതിൽ ആ വ്യക്തി നിരാശനായതിനാൽ ഈ വാചകം സങ്കടത്തെ സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து சிலோன் பரோட்டா சிக்கன் சால்னா செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:2 கப் மைதா மாவு½ கிலோ சிக்கன் எலும்பு1 முட்டை2 பெரிய வெங்காயம்2 தக்காளி½ கப் துருவிய தேங்காய்3 பூண்டு பல்1 இஞ்சி துண்டு2 பச்சை மிளகாய்2 பட்டை துண்டு2 ஏலக்காய்3 கிராம்பு2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி பொட்டுக்கடலை1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி மிளகு1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சர்க்கரை3 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சோம்பு2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சீரகம்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி கசகசா2 பிரியாணி இலை½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி மஞ்சள் தூள்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி மல்லி தூள்தேவையான அளவு மிளகாய் தூள்தேவையான அளவு உப்புதேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்","answer":"பரோட்டா பொதுவாகவே அனைவருக்கும் பிடித்தமான ஒரு உணவு. தென்னிந்தியாவில் இதற்கு இருக்கும் வரவேற்பே தனி தான் என்றால் அது மிகை அல்ல. பரோட்டாக்களில் பல வகை உண்டு. அதில் மதுரை கொத்து பரோட்டா, பன் பரோட்டா, முட்டை வீச்சு பரோட்டா, மற்றும் சிலோன் பரோட்டா மிகவும் பிரபலமானவை. இதில் நாம் இன்று இங்கு காண இருப்பது சிலோன் பரோட்டா.செய்முறை:முதலில் வெங்காயம், தக்காளி, மற்றும் பச்சை மிளகாயை நறுக்கி, இஞ்சி பூண்டை பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி, தேங்காயை துருவி, மற்றும் சிக்கன் எலும்புகளை நன்கு சுத்தம் செய்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.அடுத்து ஒரு bowl லை எடுத்து அதில் மைதா மாவை கொட்டி அதனுடன் சர்க்கரை மற்றும் உப்பை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.பின்பு மாவின் நடுவே சின்ன குழியை உருவாக்கி அதில் ஒரு முட்டையை உடைத்து ஊற்றி உடைத்து ஊற்றிய முட்டையை சுற்றி ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.பின்னர் அதில் கொஞ்சம் கொஞ்சமாக தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து அதை சுமார் 10 லிருந்து 15 நிமிடம் வரை பிசைந்து அதை சப்பாத்தி மாவு பதத்திற்கு கொண்டு வரவும்.பிறகு அந்த மாவை ஒரு பாத்திரத்தில் வைத்து மூடி போட்டு சுமார் 30 லிருந்து 40 நிமிடம் வரை ஊற விடவும்.40 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு மூடியை திறந்து மாவை எடுத்து மீண்டும் ஒரு முறை சிறிது நேரம் பிசைந்து அதன் மேலே நன்கு எண்ணெய்யை தடவி பாத்திரத்தில் வைத்து மூடி போட்டு அதை மீண்டும் சுமார் ஒரு மணி நேரம் வரை ஊற வைக்கவும்.ஒரு மணி நேரத்திற்கு பிறகு நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் மாவை எடுத்து அதை சிறு சிறு உருண்டைகளாக ஆகி அதன் மீது எண்ணெய்யை தடவி அதை ஒரு பாத்திரத்தில் வைத்து மூடி போட்டு மீண்டும் சுமார் ஒரு மணி நேரம் வரை ஊற வைக்கவும்.மாவு ஊறுவதற்குள் ஒரு pan ஐ மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி எண்ணெய்யை சுட வைக்கவும்.எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் ஒரு துண்டு பட்டை, ஏலக்காய், கிராம்பு, மிளகு, 2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சோம்பு, சீரகம், கசகசா, மற்றும் பொட்டுக்கடலையை போட்டு அதை நன்கு வறுக்கவும்.அடுத்து அதில் நாம் துருவி வைத்திருக்கும் தேங்காயை போட்டு அது நன்கு பொன் நிறம் வரும் வரை அதை வறுக்கவும்.தேங்காய் வறுபட்டதும் அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு அதை இறக்கி கீழே வைத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விட்ட பின் அதை ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாரில் போட்டு நன்கு அரைத்து எடுத்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.அடுத்து ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் 3 மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.எண்ணெய் சுட்டதும் அதில் ஒரு துண்டு பட்டை, பிரியாணி இலை, மற்றும் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி சோம்பை சேர்த்து அதை வறுக்கவும்.சோம்பு வறுபட்டதும் அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயம் மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பை சேர்த்து வெங்காயம் கண்ணாடி பதம் வரும் வரை அதை வதக்கவும்.வெங்காயம் கண்ணாடி பதம் வந்ததும் அதில் நாம் தயார் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட், பச்சை மிளகாய், மஞ்சள் தூள், மல்லி தூள், அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கு ஏற்ப மிளகாய் தூள், மற்றும் நாம் அரைத்து வைத்திருக்கும் மசாலாவை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.பின்பு அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் தக்காளியை போட்டு தக்காளி வதங்கியவுடன் அதில் நாம் சுத்தம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் சிக்கனை சேர்த்து அது நன்கு மசாலாவுடன் சேருமாறு அதை நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.பிறகு அதில் தேவையான அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி ஒரு மூடி போட்டு சிக்கன் நன்கு வேகும் வரை அதை வேக விட்டு எடுத்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.இப்பொழுது நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் மாவை எடுத்து அதை ஒரு சப்பாத்தி தேய்க்கும் கல்லில் வைத்து நம் கைகளில் எண்ணெய்யை தடவி அந்த உருண்டையை கைகளின் மூலம் நன்கு மெல்லிசாக வரும் வரை அதை விரித்து விடவும்.அடுத்து அதை இடது புறத்தில் இருந்து ஒரு மடி வலது புறத்தில் இருந்து ஒரு மடி மடித்து பின்பு மேலிருந்து ஒரு மடி கீழிருந்து ஒரு மடி மடித்து கொள்ளவும்.இவ்வாறு மீதமிருக்கும் உருண்டைகளையும் செய்து அதன் மீது நன்கு எண்ணெய்யை தடவி ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.பின்பு ஒரு pan ஐ மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் தேய்த்து வைத்திருக்கும் மாவை போட்டு அது ஒரு பக்கம் வெந்ததும் அதை மறு புறம் திருப்பி போட்டு அது வெந்ததும் அதை எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் சிக்கன் சால்னா உடன் சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் மிகவும் சுவையாக இருக்கும் சிலோன் பரோட்டா மற்றும் சிக்கன் சால்னா தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்.பரோட்டா பொதுவாகவே அனைவருக்கும் பிடித்தமான ஒரு உணவு. தென்னிந்தியாவில் இதற்கு இருக்கும் வரவேற்பே தனி தான் என்றால் அது மிகை அல்ல. பரோட்டாக்களில் பல வகை உண்டு. அதில் மதுரை கொத்து பரோட்டா, பன் பரோட்டா, முட்டை வீச்சு பரோட்டா, மற்றும் சிலோன் பரோட்டா மிகவும் பிரபலமானவை. இதில் நாம் இன்று இங்கு காண இருப்பது சிலோன் பரோட்டா."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : పద్మ తల్లి, తన పిల్లలను ఆదివారం ఎక్కడికి వెళ్తాం అని అడిగింది. ఇద్దరు పిల్లలు సినిమాకు వెళ్తామని, ముగ్గురు పార్కుకు వెళ్లాని అన్నారు. మీరు పద్మ స్థానంలో ఉంటే ఏ నిర్ణయం తీసుకుంటారు? కారణాలు చెప్పండి.","answer":"నేను పద్మని అయితే (ఆమె స్థానంలో ఉంటే) నేను పిల్లలను పార్కుకి తీసుకువెళ్ళే దానిని.ఎందుకంటే ఎక్కువమంది (మెజారిటి) పిల్లలు పార్కుకి వెళ్తామని చెప్పారు కాబట్టి."},{"question":"கேள்வி :பகுபதத்தில் சந்தி, சாரியை எவ்விடங்களில் அமையும்?","answer":"பதில் சந்திபகுதிக்கும் இடைநிலைக்கும் இடையில் அமையும், சிறுபான்மை இடைநிலைக்கும், விகுதிக்கும் இடையில் அமையும்சாரியைஇடைநிலைக்கும் விகுதிக்கும் இடையில் அமையும், சிறுபான்மை பகுதிக்கும், இடைநிலைக்கும் இடையில் அமையும்"},{"question":"Mikä on päätäi?","answer":"Päätäi eli Pediculus humanus capitis on ihmisen loinen. Päätäi käyttää ravinnokseen verta, jota se imee päänahasta. Päätäi lisääntyy munimalla. Munat tarttuvat hiusten tyveen ja kuoriutuvat keskimäärin viikon kuluttua. Täit kehittyvät aikuiseksi 2 viikossa ja elävät noin kuukauden. Päätäi on 2–4 millimetriä pitkä ja sen munat vaaleita, noin yhden millimetrin pituisia."},{"question":"වේගය යන ඒකකය හඳුන්වන්න.","answer":"වේගය යනු කිසියම් යොමු ලක්ෂ්‍යයකට හෝ සමුද්දේශ රාමුවකට අදාළව වස්තුවක් හෝ වස්තුවක් කෙතරම් වේගයෙන් චලනය වන්නේද යන්න පිළිබඳ මිනුමක් වේ. එය අදිශ ප්‍රමාණයකි, එයින් අදහස් වන්නේ එහි විශාලත්වය ඇති නමුත් නිශ්චිත දිශාවක් නොමැති බවයි. වස්තුවක වේගය තීරණය වන්නේ ගමන් කළ දුර එම දුර ආවරණය කිරීමට ගතවන කාලයෙන් බෙදීමෙනි."},{"question":"મને કંટાળો આવે છે, શું તમે મને હસાવી શકશો?","answer":"હા કેમ નહિ! હું તમને પતિ પત્ની વિશે એક ગમ્મત વાળો જોક કહું:પત્ની : આપણો સંસાર સુખેથી ચાલે એટલે હું એકાદશી રહું છું, બીજ રહું છું, પૂનમ રહું છું, જન્માષ્ટમી રહું છું, રામનવમી રહું છું, વડસાવિત્રી રહુ છુ, નવરાત્રી રહુ છુ.પતિ : એમાં શું થઈ ગયું.?પત્ની : તમે શું કરો છો, બોલો!પતિ : હું કરુ છું એ તું ના રહી શકે…પત્ની : એવું તો તમે શું કરો છો જે હું ના કરી શકું, બોલો .?પતિ : *હું મૂંગો રહું છું….*"},{"question":"Insan Kacakciliginin cezası ne kadar?","answer":"a) Bir yabancıyı ülkeye sokan veya ülkede kalmasına imkan sağlayan, b) Türk vatandaşı veya yabancının yurt dışına çıkmasına imkan sağlayan, kişi, beş yıldan sekiz yıla kadar hapis ve bin günden on bin güne kadar adlî para cezası ile cezalandırılır."},{"question":"1947 میں برٹش انڈیا کی تقسیم نے مشرقی پاکستان، بعد میں بنگلہ دیش بننے میں کس طرح کردار ادا کیا؟","answer":"1947 میں برطانوی ہند کی تقسیم نے بنگلہ دیش کی تاریخ کی تشکیل میں اہم کردار ادا کیا۔ جیسے ہی ہندوستان نے آزادی حاصل کی، برصغیر دو الگ الگ قوموں - ہندوستان اور پاکستان میں تقسیم ہوگیا۔ برصغیر کے مشرقی جانب واقع مشرقی پاکستان اور مغربی پاکستان، مغربی جانب، ہندوستان نے الگ کر دیا تھا۔ مشرقی پاکستان کی تخلیق مذہبی خطوط پر مبنی تھی جس کی اکثریتی آبادی مسلمان تھی۔ تاہم، مشترکہ مذہب کے باوجود، مشرقی اور مغربی پاکستان کے درمیان لسانی اور ثقافتی اختلافات نے مشرقی پاکستان کی بنگالی بولنے والی آبادی میں بیگانگی کے بڑھتے ہوئے احساس کو جنم دیا۔ مغربی پاکستان میں مرکزی حکومت کی طرف سے اپنائی گئی اقتصادی پالیسیوں نے ان اختلافات کو مزید بڑھا دیا، جس سے مشرقی پاکستان میں خود مختاری کی بڑھتی ہوئی مانگ میں اضافہ ہوا۔ ان عوامل کا خاتمہ بالآخر بنگلہ دیش کی آزادی کی جنگ کے دوران ایک طویل اور شدید جدوجہد کے بعد 1971 میں بنگلہ دیش کی آزادی کا باعث بنا۔"},{"question":"Чи важко було займатись етнографією за часів Радянського Союзу?","answer":"У жодному з вищих навчальних закладів радянської України не було спеціалізації з етнографії, у шкіль­них програмах не знаходилося місця бодай для найелемен­тарніших відомостей з українського народознавства, не було відповідних підручників, посібників, літератури для широкого загалу. А зусилля тих небагатьох етнографів, які працювали в Україні, нерідко штучно спрямовувалися на написання праць, що мали на меті знівелювання національної свідомості й гід­ності, утвердження соціалістичної дійсності, радянського спо­собу життя, \\"нових\\" звичаїв і обрядів, \\"нової\\" сім'ї і т. ін. Однак українська етнографічна наука творилася й розвивалася навіть у надзвичайно складних і несприятливих умовах бездержав­ності, переслідувань, цькувань, і репресій. "},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Przed Mistrzostwami Europy w Piłce Nożnej 2012 kadra przeprowadziła obóz treningowy w Austrii, a trener reprezentacji Franciszek Smuda zaplanował...","answer":"...następujące spotkania sparingowe przed Mistrzostwami Europy w 2012, które zostały rozegrane przez Reprezentację Polski."},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、このトピックに関する記事を書きなさい： もうすぐ中国に返すパンダにバレンタインデーのプレゼント","answer":"和歌山県白浜町の「アドベンチャーワールド」は14日、来週中国に返すパンダにバレンタインデーのプレゼントを贈りました。プレゼントをもらったのは、30歳の雄のパンダの「永明」です。永明は、「ありがとう」という字の形に並べた竹と、竹の粉でつくったパンダの形のだんごをおいしそうに食べていました。アドベンチャーワールドには今パンダが７頭いて、この中の3頭を来週中国に返します。「永明」と、子どもで雌の「桜浜」と「桃浜」です。3頭は22日に日本を出発して、中国の四川省に行きます。パンダの世話をしている人は「永明は喜んでいたと思います。元気に中国に行くことができるように、出発までの短い間も健康でいてほしいです」と話していました。"},{"question":"අඳ කුඹුරු යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"අයිතිකරු විසින් වගාකිරීම සඳහා අඳයට දුන් කුඹුරු.මෙහි අඳ යන්න අඩ යන්නෙන් ආ බවට කියවුණද ඉඩම් හිමියාට දෙන අස්වැන්න ප්‍රමාණය සෑමවිටම අඩක් වූයේ නැත. "},{"question":"नेवार समुदायको \\"मजिपा लाखे\\" नृत्यसँग सम्बन्धित सांस्कृतिक प्रचलन र विश्वासहरूको वर्णन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"माजिपा लाखे एक परम्परागत नेवार नृत्य हो जसमा दानव चरित्र हुन्छ, इन्द्रजात्रा र अन्य चाडपर्वहरूमा प्रदर्शन गरिन्छ।"},{"question":"Pergunta: Em que filme toca a canção \\"Can't Help Falling In Love\\"? Resposta:","answer":"Hawaii Azul"},{"question":"තේ නිෂ්පාදනය සසඳහා වැඩිම වියදමක් දරන රට","answer":"චීනය"},{"question":"Biberiye suyu yüze sürülür mü?","answer":"Kuru ve cansız ciltlerden karma ve yağlı ciltlere kadar, çok hassas ciltler hariç tüm cilt tiplerine uygundur."},{"question":"ભારતમાં કયા પ્રકારની નદીઓ છે?","answer":"ભારતમાં મૂળભૂત રીતે ચાર નદીઓનો પ્રવાહ વહે છે . સિંધુ નદી ઉત્તર ભારતમાં, ગંગા નદી ઉત્તર-મધ્ય ભારતમાં અને બ્રહ્મપુત્રા ઉત્તર-પૂર્વ ભારતમાં. નર્મદા, કાવેરી જેવી મહા નદીઓ પણ આ વ્યવસ્થાનો ભાગ છે."},{"question":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ogun tẹwọ-gba iṣi abẹrẹ mi-in to n dena Korona","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ogun labẹ akoso Gomina Ọmọọba Dapọ Abiọdun ti tẹwọ gba iṣi abẹrẹ mi-in to n dena arun Korona, wọn yoo si bẹrẹ si i fun awọn eeyan ilu naa lati ọsẹ tuntun yii lọ.Kọmiṣanna eto aabo nipinlẹ Ogun, Dokita Tomi Coker, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ẹgbẹrun kan le mẹtadinlaaadọrun-un ati irinwo le mẹrindinlọgbọn (187,426) ni onka abẹrẹ naa ti orukọ rẹ n jẹ Moderna COVID-19 vaccines to balẹ sipinlẹ Ogun lalẹ Ọjọbọ, ọjọ kọkandinlogun, oṣu kẹjọ ọdun 2021.Dokita Coker sọ pe pẹlu bi abẹrẹ ajẹsara naa ṣe ti de yii, ijọba ko ni i fi falẹ ko too maa fun awọn eeyan, bẹrẹ lati ẹni ọdun mejidinlogun soke lọ.Lati fi orukọ silẹ fun gbigba abẹrẹ ajẹsara Koro yii, oju opo https:#www.vaccination.gov.ng. ni kọmiṣanna sọ pe kawọn eeyan lọ. O fi kun alaye ẹ pe ṣaaju ni ijọba Ogun ti gba awọn firiiji agbayanu ti wọn yoo maa tọju awọn abẹrẹ naa si ti ko fi ni i bajẹ, o ni wọn ti ṣeto awọn firiiji alagbara naa saaye to yẹ.Ni gbogbo ipinlẹ Naijiria pata, ipinlẹ Ogun lo kọkọ tẹwọ-gba abẹrẹ ajẹsara akọkọ ti wọn n pe Azra Zeneca, iyẹn loṣu, kẹta ọdun 2021 yii, ti wọn si fun awọn eeyan ibẹ ni ipele akọkọ ati ikeji.‘‘Aarin ipele kẹta aisan Korona la wa bayii, akọsilẹ si fi han pe bo ṣe paayan laarin ọsẹ mẹrin si asiko yii lọ soke si i.“Ba a oo ṣe maa fun awọn eeyan ni abẹrẹ to de yii lati ọsẹ to n bọ lọ, a rọ wọn lati maa tẹle awọn ofin to de Korona, bii lilo ibomu deede ta a ba wa nita gbangba, fifọwọ wa deede, lilo ọṣẹ apakokoro (sanitizer) lati fi pa ọwọ wa, titakete sira ẹni ati yiyago fun awujọ ero.”Bẹẹ ni kọmiṣanna wi."},{"question":"عندما توفي قال عنه عمر: مات اليوم سيد المسلمين فمن هو ؟","answer":"\\tأبي بن كعب رضي الله عنه"},{"question":"Menene sunan littafin musulmi mai tsarki?","answer":"Littafin da musulmai ke amfani dashi shine Kur'ani mai tsarki."},{"question":"Apakah nama bunga kebangsaan?","answer":"Bunga Raya"},{"question":"(ephakamisa ikhanda) Sekunguwe njalo baba?(sakuncokola) Ubuza ibhasi libhaliwe?(naye athi ukumamatheka) Hawu! Kanti wena sewaba yibhasi? (bahlekebobabili)(ahlale kwesinye isihlalo) Uboshiwe ngempela uDlamini. Kusasa uzoyakobingelela imantshi.Ashile! Kuhle-ke uma eboshiwe. (athule kancane)Nginovadlwana kodwa mina baba.Kodwa! Kodwa! Uvadlwana! Yini manje?(ngokuzithoba) Baba! Igazi likaMbandlwa lichithekile, induna yaboshwa.Konke lokhu akusho lutho kuwe?(ngolaka) Uthini manje? Mina ngibona kuzobathambisa ukuboshwakwenduna.(aphakamise izwi nomoya wakhe wenyuke) Hhayi bo! Ubathathakancane wena abantu bakule ndawo. Uyakhumbula ngesikhathi sodlame?Iningi labantu balapha bayayithanda inkosi futhi bayayihlonipha. (ehliseumoya) Baba, ngicela ukubone lokhu engikushoyo. Mina bengingacabangiukuthi lesi simo sizoze sifike kuleli banga esesikulo. Uyabona, nenja umaikhonkotha uke unganaki. Wethuke uphele uma isizifikela ngamazinyokuwe. Baba, izwe lizobheduka. Mina ngibona kungcono wena uzehliseenkosini noma uyeke kwabona ubukhansela lobu.(ethukuthela) Hheyi! Hheyi! Kanti usudleni wena? Lezi zinto ozishoyozombili angizamukeli! Lungamane luchitheke uphoko! Lutho mfazi! Ngeke!(enyuke ngolaka naye) Ubani umfazi weBafana? Ubiza mina ngomfazi?Wena awufuni ukuboniswa! Ngiyakutshela, uyongikhumbula seluchithekilelolu phoko lwakho.(abhoke kakhulu) Uzwa kanjani wena! Angisilo ivaka mina! Futhi, vala lomlonyana wakho singaze sethusane.1. Babunjani ubudlelwane phakathi kwenkosi nabantu bomphakathi wayo?","answer":"Babubuhle ngoba babeyithanda inkosi beyihlonipha bethi bangayifelanokuyifela."},{"question":"පහන් සිළුවමෙහි 'සිළුව' යන්න නිවැරදිද පහදා දෙන්න. ","answer":"පහන් සිළුව නිවරදියි.පහන් සිළු, කව්සිළුමිණ.සුළු ජාතීන් හුළු අත්ත."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഭാഗം വായിച്ച് ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക. ഖണ്ഡിക:14-ആം നൂറ്റാണ്ടിൽ ഇറ്റലിയിൽ ആരംഭിച്ച നവോത്ഥാനം യൂറോപ്പിലുടനീളം വ്യാപിച്ചു, കല, ശാസ്ത്രം, മാനവികത എന്നിവയിൽ നവോത്ഥാന താൽപ്പര്യത്തിന്റെ കാലഘട്ടമായിരുന്നു. ഇത് ഒരു സുപ്രധാന സാംസ്കാരികവും ബൗദ്ധികവുമായ പ്രസ്ഥാനമായി അടയാളപ്പെടുത്തി, ക്ലാസിക്കൽ വിജ്ഞാനത്തിന്റെ പുനരുജ്ജീവനം, നൂതന കലാപരമായ നേട്ടങ്ങൾ, വ്യക്തിത്വത്തിലും മാനുഷിക ശേഷിയിലും ശ്രദ്ധ കേന്ദ്രീകരിക്കുന്നു.ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: 14-ആം നൂറ്റാണ്ടിൽ ഇറ്റലിയിലും പിന്നീട് യൂറോപ്പിലുടനീളം വ്യാപിച്ച കല, ശാസ്ത്രം, മാനവികത, ക്ലാസിക്കൽ വിജ്ഞാനത്തിന്റെ പുനരുജ്ജീവനം എന്നിവയിൽ നവോത്ഥാനത്തിന്റെ ഒരു ചരിത്ര കാലഘട്ടത്തെ ഈ ഭാഗം സംഗ്രഹിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Wọ́n fi ẹ̀sùn ìjówókó lọ sókè òkun kan ìyàwó ààrẹ Ali Bongo Gabon táwọn ológun gbàjọba rẹ̀","answer":"Wọn ti ẹsun ijowoko lọ soke okun, gbigba ẹru ole ati ṣiṣe ayederu kan Sylvia Bongo ti i ṣe iyawo aarẹ Ali Bongo tawọn ologun gba ijọba rẹ.Olupẹjọ, Andre Patrick Roponat kede lọjọ Ẹti pe awọn ẹsun naa ti de iwaju adajọ bayii.Bakan naa ni Roponat sọ pe ofin si de Arabinrin Sylvia sibẹ lati ma jade kuro nile.Ọrọ jẹ jade lẹyin ọpọlọpa awuyewuye lori ibi ti iyawo aarẹ ana orilẹ ede Gabon wa.Ọgbọnjọ oṣu Kẹjọ tawọn ologun gba ijọba ọkọ rẹ ni wọn fofin de e wi pe ko gbodọ jade kuro nile.Gbesẹ lati fẹsun kan arabinrin Sylvia waye lẹyin ti wọn ti fẹsun iwa ibajẹ ati ṣiṣe owo ilu kumọkumọ kan ọmọkunrin rẹ, Noureddin Bongo Valentin tan.Amọ, ijọba ologun orilẹede Gabon ti fun aarẹ naa Ali Bongo lominira lati rinrin ajo lọ soke okun fun itọju ara rẹ ti o ba fẹ.Oniruuru ẹsun iwa ibajẹ, ṣiṣe owo ilu kumọkumọ ati iwa ajẹbanu ni wọn fi kan aarẹ Bongo ki wọn to doju ijọba rẹ bolẹ."},{"question":"في أي قارة تقع دولة ليبيا؟","answer":"تقع دولة ليبيا في قارة إقريقيا."},{"question":"ቴምፕላሮች የገዳማዊ ኑሮዋቸውን ማን በደነገገው ሕግ መሰረት ነው የሚመሩት?","answer":"ቴምፕላሮች የገዳማዊ ኑሮዋቸውን ክላርቮው በርናርድ በደነገገው ሕግ መሰረት ነው የሚመሩት።"},{"question":"为以下的原文给译文：濮州刺史庞相寿坐贪污解任，自陈尝在秦王幕府；上怜之，欲听还旧任。魏征谏曰：“秦府左右，中外甚多，恐人人皆恃恩私，是使为善者惧。”上欣然纳之，谓相寿曰：“我昔为秦王，乃一府之主；今居大位，乃四海之主，不得独私故人。大臣所执如是，朕何敢违！”赐帛遣之。相寿流涕而去。","answer":"濮州的刺史庞相寿因为贪污而被解除职任，自己说曾经在唐太宗作秦王是在他手下工作。皇上可怜他，想让他重新归来担任(职务)。魏徽规劝说：“秦王身边宫内宫外的故人很多，恐怕人人都依赖亲情私交，足以使善良的人害怕。”皇上开心的接纳了他，对相寿说：“我今天总秦王，是一府的王，现在居于重要的地位，是整个国家的主人，不能够独自偏私故人，魏徽等大臣所坚持的是对的，我怎敢违背！”皇上赐他帛之后打发他走，相寿流着眼泪而去。"},{"question":"Per Jonines lietuviai tradiciškai ieško paparčio žiedo. Tačiau ar papartis iš tikrųjų kada nors žydi? Atsakykite į šį klausimą vienu žodžiu – taip arba ne.","answer":"Ne."},{"question":"Анафора деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Анафора—(гр.— жогору көтөрүү, чыгаруу)—речтин баш жагында эки же андан артык жолдордо окшош сөздөрдүн кайталанып келишин билдирген стилистикалык фигура.Ыр саптарындагы сөздөр тыбыштык жагынан да окшошуп анафора түзүлө берет:Карагаттай көзүңдөн,Кагылайын өзүңдөн.(А. Токомбаев)Букардын тоосу бурулуш,Бурулуп учат улуу куш.(Токтогул)."},{"question":"Rédigez une phrase qui signifie la même chose que celle-ci : \\"La plupart des séries antérieures à 1976 produites par CBS ou distribuées par CBS Films ont ensuite été distribuées par Viacom et Paramount Television.\\"","answer":"Voici une phrase avec le même sens: \\"Viacom et Paramount Television ont ensuite été distribuées la plupart des séries produites par CBS ou distribuées par CBS films avant 1976.\\""},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Mới đây, Hà Gia Kính thu hút sự chú ý của đông đảo người hâm mộ khi đăng ảnh tắm hồ bơi cùng hai bé gái. Bên cạnh những lời khen ngợi vẻ ngoài trẻ trung, cường tráng của nam diễn viên, nhiều người suy đoán về danh tính hai em bé được tài tử U70 bồng bế trên tay. Đặc biệt, cô bé áo tím được nhận xét có nhiều nét tương tự \\"Triển Chiêu\\". Trước suy đoán của dân mạng, Hà Gia Kính không chính thức đáp lại, chỉ trả lời ẩn ý bằng biểu tượng cảm xúc vỗ tay, cùng lời bình luận: \\"Bờ vai của người đàn ông là đáng tin cậy nhất\\".  Hà Gia Kính khiến dân mạng suy đoán đã có gia đình sau nhiều năm kín tiếng Hà Gia Kính chưa bao giờ công khai tình trạng hôn nhân. Nam tài tử cũng rất kín tiếng trong chuyện đời tư, mỗi lần bị đề cập đến đều tìm cách tránh né. Ở tuổi 63, Hà Gia Kính từng 2 lần công khai 2 mối tình đẹp với hai mỹ nhân nổi tiếng là Kim Tố Mai và Lý Uyển Hoa nhưng sau đó đều chia tay. Đáng chú ý, trong một bài đăng cách đây không lâu, khi cư dân mạng để lại lời nhắn giục kết hôn: \\"Hà Gia Kính, sao anh chưa lập gia đình?\\", nam tài tử gây xôn xao khi trả lời: \\"Con gái tôi lớn hơn bạn\\", khiến nhiều người hâm mộ đồn đoán rằng anh đã lập gia đình và có con gái. Điều này càng được chứng minh khi vào Ngày của Cha tháng 6, Hà Gia Kính từng đăng tải chiếc tách trà có khắc dòng chữ: \\"Cha, con yêu cha\\".  Hà Gia Kính được gọi là \\"Triển Chiêu kinh điển nhất màn ảnh\\" Nổi tiếng với vai Triển Chiêu trong bộ phim Bao Thanh Thiên (1993), Hà Gia Kính là hình mẫu người trong mộng của rất nhiều cô gái ở thập niên 90. Dù sau này, nhiều diễn viên khác vào vai Triển Chiêu nhưng không ai \\"qua mặt\\" được Hà Gia Kính. Hiện tại, nam diễn viên đã rút khỏi làng giải trí, chỉ tham gia các hoạt động công ích và tập trung vào việc kinh doanh thực phẩm sạch. Anh là doanh nhân có tiếng tại Huệ Châu, Quảng Đông (Trung Quốc) khi sở hữu ba công ty cùng một cơ sở sản xuất kinh doanh quy mô lớn, tổng giá trị tài sản lên tới 400 tỷ đồng. Ở tuổi 63, nam tài tử vẫn giữ được phong độ với làn da căng mịn, khóe mắt không có nhiều nếp nhăn. \\"Chú không hề già tí nào, mà lại còn quá điển trai nữa\\", \\"Trông anh ấy giống như đang ở độ tuổi 40 vậy đó\\", \\"Không tin là anh đã 63 tuổi\\", \\"Anh có bí quyết nào để trẻ mãi không già không?\\", \\"Ngưỡng mộ thể lực Hà Gia Kính quá, lực cánh tay mạnh thật, có thể nâng bế 2 bé mà mặt không đổi sắc luôn\\"… là những bình luận khen ngợi vẻ trẻ trung của Hà Gia Kính.  Nam diễn viên thường xuyên cập nhật hình ảnh của bản thân trên trang cá nhân, nhận về sự quan tâm của người hâm mộ  Bức ảnh gây bão mạng xã hội khi Hà Gia Kính trông như thanh niên khi đi cắt tóc, bên cạnh những bạn đồng trang lứa Nguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/trien-chieu-ha-gia-kinh-co-con-o-tuoi-63-1382794.ngnNguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/trien-chieu-ha-gia-kinh-co-con-o-tuoi-63-1382794.ngn ","answer":"\\"Triển Chiêu\\" Hà Gia Kính có con ở tuổi 63?"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Franz Bopp. ","answer":"Ba theangeolaí Gearmánach é Franz Bopp. Tá clú agus cáil air mar gheall ar an obair a rinne sé ar theangeolaíocht chomparáideach na dteangacha Ind-Eorpacha. Tá sé 76 bliana d'aois. "},{"question":"Tambaya: Mi ake nufi da \\"front door\\" da Hausa?\\t\\t\\t","answer":" Amsa: tana nufin \\"kofar gaba\\"\\t\\t"},{"question":"Inona no tsy maintsy tsofinao mba hitsokafana labozia fitsingerenan'ny andro nahaterahana amin'ny mofomamy?","answer":"Mitsoka ny labozia ho an'ny fitsingerenan'ny andro nahaterahana izahay hamonoana azy sy hanao firariantsoa."},{"question":"စက်တင်ဘာ ၅ ရက်နေ့က ဘာနေ့လဲ","answer":"စက်တင်ဘာလ ၅ ရက်နေ့ဟာ ကမ္ဘာ့ဆရာများနေ့ ဖြစ်တယ်မြန်မာနိုင်ငံမှာတော့ ဒီနေ့ ၂၀၂၃၊ စက်တင်ဘာလ ၅ ရက်နေ့ဟာ  ကျပ်ငွေ ၂၅ ကျပ်တန်၊ ၃၅ကျပ်တန် နှင့် ၇၅ ကျပ်တန်များကို သုံးစွဲရန်တရားမဝင်တော့ကြောင်း မဆလအစိုးရက ကြေညာခဲ့တာ (၃၆)နှစ်ပြည့်မြောက်တဲ့နေ့ပဲ ဖြစ်ပါတယ်။ကြိုတင်အကြောင်းကြားခြင်းမရှိဘဲ ထုတ်ပြန်ကြေညာခဲ့မှုကြောင့် ဗမာပြည်သူတွေ လက်ဝယ်မှာ ကိုင်တွယ်အသုံးပြုနေတဲ့ငွေတွေဟာ တန်ဖိုးမဲ့ခဲ့ရပြီး နေ့စဉ်စားဝတ်နေရေးမှာပါ ဒုက္ခများခဲ့ကြရပါတယ်။ ဒီ ငွေကြေးတွေဟာ တစ်နိုင်ငံလုံး သုံးစွဲနေမှုရဲ့ ၇၅% ကို ကိုယ်စားပြုပြီး သန်းနဲ့ ချီတဲ့ ဗမာနိုင်ငံသားများစွာရဲ့ ဘဝကို ဒုက္ခရောက်စေခဲ့ပါတယ်။ သတ်သေကြတဲ့ မိသားစုများ အမြောက်အများ ရှိခဲ့တယ်။ ယခုအချိန်ထိ မြန်မာနိုင်ငံရဲ့  ဒီငွေကြေးဖျက်သိမ်းမှုဟာ သမိုင်းမှာ အဆိုးဆုံး ငွေကြေးဖျက်သိမ်းမှုဖြစ်တယ်လို့ နိုင်ငံတကာမှာ မှတ်တမ်းတင် ခံထားရပါတယ်။"},{"question":"Ibo 1979 ku si dẹdẹ, n lawọn adigunjale ba ko girigiri ba awọn oloṣelu atijọba Ọbasanjọ (Ipari)","answer":"Ariwo, ‘yaa-fun-un yaa-fun-un’ motọ ọlọpaa lawọn eeyan to wa nile-ẹjọ giga n’Ikẹja kọkọ gbọ. Bi wọn ti gbọ ọ ni wọn dẹ eti wọn silẹ, bẹẹ lariwo fere ọlọpaa naa n sun mọ wọn si i. Oju lo n kan wọn! Ẹni ti a n gbeyawo bọ waa ba ni wọn, ko yẹ ki wọn maa garun rara, nitori ọdọ wọn kuku ni mọto awọn ọlọpaa naa n bọ, awọn lo si fẹẹ ja ẹru to n ko bọ gan-an fun. Ẹru wo lawọn ọlọpaa yii wa n ko bọ? Awọn adigunjale mẹfa ti wọn fẹẹ dajọ wọn nijọ naa ni. Awọn adigunjale mẹfa ti wọn fibọn ja ọgọrin ẹgbẹrun (N80,000) owo ileeṣẹ Boulos gba, ti wọn pa ọlọpaa meji, ti wọn si ṣe ọkan leṣe rẹkẹrẹkẹ ninu wọn. Kaluku ti gbọroyin pe ọjọ naa ni wọn fẹẹ dajọ wọn, ko si sẹni to fẹ ki kinni naa ṣeyin oun. Lọdọ igbimọ to n gbọ ẹjọ awọn adigunjale ni Ikẹja ni wọn yoo ti yanju ọrọ ọhun, Adajọ E. A. Hotonu si ni adajọ wọn.Lẹẹkan naa ni ariwo ‘yaa-fun-un yaa-fun-un naa wọ inu ọgba ile-ẹjọ giga yii ni deede aago mẹsan-an kọja ogun iṣẹju, lọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu karun-un, ọdun 1979. N lawọn ọlọpaa mẹrin ti wọn gun motosaikulu mẹrin ba kọkọ gun alupupu wọn naa wọle, ti wọn mura bii ẹni to n tẹle olori ijọba lọ sibi kan. Iyatọ to kan wa nibẹ ni pe ki i ṣe olori ijọba ni wọn n tẹle lọjọ yii, mọto Bulaaki-Maria (Black Maria), mọto ti wọn fi n ko awọn ọdaran kiri, ni wọn ṣaaju, bi awọn ọlọpaa alalupupu mẹrẹẹrin si ti wọle, bẹẹ ni mọto naa yọ lẹyin wọn, agbarigo ni, o dudu kirimu! Igba naa lawọn ọlọpaa, lọọya, oniroyin atawọn ero iworan bẹrẹ si i sare girigiri lọ sinu kootu ti wọn ti fẹẹ gbọ ẹjọ yii, wọn n wa ibujokoo to dara funra wọn. Oju awo lawo fi i gbọbẹ, wọn ko fẹ kẹnikan royin ohun to ba ṣẹlẹ nibẹ fun wọn, wọn fẹẹ foju ara wọn ri i.Nigba naa, nita, mọto agbarigo naa ti rọ tikẹtikẹ, o si ti duro, n lawọn ọlọpaa ti wọn ti wa nitosi nibẹ ba yi i po. Awọn ọlọpaa lasan kọ lawọn eleyii, awọn ti oju wọn le koko ni, wọn wọ bata konko, wọn de fila irin sori wọn, ibọn to wa lọwọ wọn gun jalami, ko sẹnikan to jẹ sun mọ wọn. Ninu awọn ọlọpaa yii, awọn kan gbe kinni kan ti wọn n pe n maṣinni-gan-an-nu dani, wọn ni ibọn ti i fọ ile, ti i fọ ogiri ni, wọn lo le pa bii ogun si ọgbọn eeyan lẹẹkan, yoo kan maa rẹ wọn bii ẹni rẹla ni. Lẹyin ti awọn ọlọpaa naa ti duro kaakiri, ti wọn si mura ija bẹẹ ni wọn too silẹkun mọto agbarigo yii, nigba naa ni awọn ero inu rẹ bẹrẹ si i bọ silẹ nikọọkan. Ṣugbọn wahala igo lasan lọrọ awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn n fidi fọgba yii jọ loju awọn eeyan, nitori nigba ti awọn ti wọn n reti yii bọ silẹ, wọn ri i pe adiẹ ti kọọli ti gbe ni wọn, ko si ifun ninu wọn.Bi wọn ti bọ silẹ lawọn eeyan ri wọn, wọn ko le rin daadaa rara, nitori niṣe ni wọn da bii alaaarẹ, wọn si ti ru hangogo, wọn waa n mi lẹgẹlẹgẹ. Yatọ si eyi, wọn ti de wọn ni ṣẹkẹṣẹkẹ lọwọ, wọn de wọn ni ṣẹkẹṣẹkẹ lẹsẹ, eyi to tumọ si pe bi agidi kan ba tilẹ wa ninu wọn, tabi ti ẹmi ija kan ba n gbe wọn ninu, ko si ọwọ tabi ẹsẹ ti wọn yoo fi ṣe’yẹn. Eeyan ko tilẹ le mọ pe itosi nibi, ni Adeniji Adele, ti wọn ti wọn mọle si, ni wọn ti n ko wọn bọ, eeyan yoo ro pe lati apa ọna ilẹ Hausa ni. Niṣe ni wọn fara balẹ gẹgẹ bii ọwọ onijangbọn ẹda ti i fara balẹ fun ankọọbu. Wọn ko le rin taara, niṣe ni wọn n kasẹ iyawo, nitori ọkọọkan ni wọn le gbe ẹsẹ, ẹni to ba gbiyanju lati gbe ẹsẹ ni meji meji yoo ṣubu ni. Bẹẹ ni wọn wọ turuturu dewaju adajọ, Adajọ Hotonu ati awọn eeyan rẹ. Bi wọn ti n wọle lawọn ero ti wọn wa nibẹ n wo wọn, ṣugbọn ko sẹni to le gbin, ohun gbogbo pa lọlọ ni.Alaye ko pọ mọ, nigba ti awọn mẹfẹẹfa kuku ti rojọ tẹlẹ, ti olupẹjọ si ti fi idi ẹjọ tirẹ naa mulẹ, to jẹ ki wọn dajọ nikan lo ku fun wọn. Nelson Diefor ti i ṣe olori wọn duro, o dorikodo; Youperre Dakoru to jẹ atamatase wọn naa n wo baibai, okun ti mu aparo lẹsẹ poo. William Ogbolu to jẹ lebura mọ pe oun naa ti taja oun debi to lapẹẹrẹ, bẹẹ si ni Johnson Ibekwe to jẹ kuku ati iranṣẹ nileeṣe Boulos ti wọn ti ji wọn lowo yii mọ pe oun ti ṣe iṣẹ iranṣẹ daran, ko si jọ pe oun yoo tun ṣe iṣẹ iranṣẹ fẹnikan ni ileeṣẹ gidi kan ni Naijiria yii mọ. Ọlọpaa Mopol to wa laarin wọn, Lawrence Edemirukevu, lo n jẹka, abi kin ni ọlọpaa Moba n wa laarin awọn adigunjale, nigba to ni iṣẹ rẹ to n ṣe lọwọ. Oun naa dorikodo ni o, to n ṣẹju pako bii maalu rọbẹ, oun ati William Douglas, toun naa ni oniṣowo worobo loun, ọja pẹẹpẹẹpẹ lo n ta.Olupẹjọ ijọba, Adekunle Ilọri, to fidi ẹjọ gbogbo mulẹ wa nibẹ nigba ti Adajọ Hotonu bẹrẹ idajọ rẹ, ohun to si kọkọ ṣe ni lati ṣalaye awọn eeyan meji kan ninu awọn adigunjale naa, o ni awọn gan-an leṣu beleke, awọn ni wọn wa nidii ohun gbogbo. Ẹni akọkọ ni Nelson Diefor, ẹni ti oun funra ẹ ti jẹwọ pe oun lolori wọn. Adajọ ni ọrọ rẹ dun oun gan-an, nitori ki i ṣe oun lo yẹ ki wọn ba ni iru ipo bẹẹ, bẹẹ ni ko gbọdọ jẹ oun ni wọn yoo ka awọn iwa buruku bẹẹ mọ lọwọ. Idi ni pe Katikiisi ni baba Nelson yii. Ni ipinlẹ Rivers, ni Kamabim, ni wọn ti bi i. O kawe nibẹ, o kawe nilẹ Ibo, l’Owerri, ko too waa maa kawe ni Onikẹẹ, Yabba, l’Ekoo. Iwe mẹsan-an lo kawe ẹ de to fi ni oun o ka mọ lọdun 1966, lo ba wọṣẹ nileeṣẹ Port Authority, bi ogun abẹle si ti fẹẹ bẹrẹ lo gba ṣọja lọ, wọn si jọ jagun abẹle ni, afi bo ṣe yi biri to waa pada di adigunjale.Adajọ sọrọ Youpelle Dakoru naa, o ni ọdaju apaayan gan-an ni, oun ko si ri iru ẹni bẹẹ ri. O ni tirẹ naa buru nitori ọmọ ọlọpaa loun, ọga ọlọpaa ni baba rẹ, ohun to si jẹ ko jẹ ọgba awọn ọlọpaa ni Ọbalende, l’Ekoo, ni wọn bi i si niyẹn, bo tilẹ jẹ ni Yenagoa, nipinlẹ Rivers, lawọn naa ti wa. O kawe l’Ekoo, Ibadan lo si ti kawe mẹwaa jade ki ogun abẹle too de, toun naa si kọri si ṣọja. Oun naa ba wọn jagun abẹle, afi bo ṣe kuro loju ogun to n waa paayan kiri igboro lati gba owo ọwọ wọn. Ibinu eyi ni adajọ ko ṣe wo wọn loju, afi lẹẹkan naa to kọju si wọn, gbolohun kan naa lo si wi jade, o ni, ‘Wọn yoo yinbọn pa yin ni, afi ẹni kan ṣoṣo ninu yin ni yoo ṣẹwọn ọdun mẹẹẹdogun!’ Ọlọpaa moba yẹn nikan ni wọn ni yoo ṣẹwọn, idi si ni pe ko ba wọn lọ soko ole naa, wọn ni ọta ibọn lo fun wọn, ko si mọ ohun ti wọn fẹẹ fi i ṣe.Bayii ni wọn dajọ iku awọn marun-un, ti wọn si ni ki wọn tete yinbọn pa gbogbo wọn. Aye ijọba ologun igba naa ko si ni sunmẹ-sunmẹ ninu, paapaapa ni wọn yoo ṣe gbogbo ohun ti wọn ba fẹẹ ṣe. Iyẹn lo ṣe jẹ pe ọjọ kẹrin ti wọn dajọ iku yii naa ni wọn ti mu wọn lọọ pa, ọjọ Satide to tẹle e ni, ọjọ kọkandinlogun, oṣu karun-un, ọdun 1979. Bawọn ero ṣe mọ pe wọn yoo pa wọn lọjọ naa ko yeeyan, nitori pitimu ni wọn pe seti okun. Koda, awọn eeyan wa lati awọn ipinlẹ mi-in ti wọn waa woran awọn adigunjale ti okiki wọn lalu ja. Bo tilẹ jẹ pe aago mẹsan-an aarọ ni wọn fi pipa wọn si, lati bii aago meje lawọn eeyan ti kunbẹ, ero ko si dakẹ titi ti wọn fi ko awọn ole naa de, ti wọn de wọn mọ agba, ti wọn si kẹyin wọn sokun. Lẹyin naa ni awọn ṣọja to lọwọọwọ, ti wọn feesi awọn adigunjale naa nikọọkan.N lọga wọn ba peṣẹ fun wọn, ‘fayaaa!’ Bẹẹ ni ina ibọn dahun lọ ‘karakaka’, n lawọn adigunjale naa ba dorikodo, ọta ibọn fa wọn ya pẹrẹpẹrẹ. Bẹẹ lopin de sawọn adigunjale to ja ọgọrin ẹgbẹrun gba lẹẹkan, ko si tun si ẹjọ ole ti wọn ṣe lasiko naa, lati igba ti wọn ti ṣe ẹjọ Oyenusi, to tun la ariwo lọ ju ẹjọ awọn Dakoru yii lọ. Ọkan awọn ijọba Ọbasanjọ pada balẹ, awọn oloṣelu naa fi ẹdọ lori oronro, wọn si n ba kanmpeeni wọn lọ, wọn n wa oloṣelu ti yoo gbajọba lọwọ Ọbasanjọ nibẹrẹ oṣu kẹwaa, 1979."},{"question":"તમારી સોસાયટીમાં નિયમિત સફાઈ થતી નથી તે અંગેની ફરિયાદ યોગ્ય અધિકારીને કરો.","answer":"[તમારું નામ][તમારું સરનામું][શહેર, રાજ્ય, પિન કોડ][ઈ - મેઈલ સરનામું][ફોન નંબર][તારીખ]પ્રતિ,અધ્યક્ષશ્રી,શહેર નગરપાલિકા.વિષય: નિયમિત સફાઈ કરાવવા બાબતસાહેબશ્રી,જયભારત સાથે જણાવવાનું કે અમારા વિસ્તાર ના સ્વચ્છતા સંબંધિત પ્રશ્નનો ઉકેલ ન લાવવા બદલ અમારા મ્યુનિસિપલ કોર્પોરેશનોની બેદરકારી તરફ હું તમારું ધ્યાન દોરું છું.અમે ઘણા દિવસોથી આ સમસ્યાનો સામનો કરી રહ્યા છીએ. ગયા વર્ષે શેરીની યોગ્ય રીતે સફાઈ કરવામાં આવી હતી. પરંતુ છેલ્લા કેટલાક મહિનાઓથી તેની સફાઈ કરવામાં આવી નથી. ભંગારવાળાઓ અહીં અને ત્યાં રસ્તા પર વિખરાયેલા છે. જે ખૂબ જ ગંદુ લાગે છે. તે આપણા પર્યાવરણને પ્રદૂષિત કરે છે. ડ્રેનેજ સિસ્ટમ ખૂબ જ ખરાબ છે. ગંદા પાણી અને સ્વચ્છતાના પાણીનો યોગ્ય નિકાલ થતો નથી. જેના કારણે આપણા વિસ્તારમાં દુર્ગંધ ફેલાઈ રહી છે. મચ્છર અને માખીઓ ના કારણે મેલેરિયા, ડેન્ગ્યુ અને અન્ય રોગોનો મોટો ખતરો છે. છેલ્લા કેટલાક મહિનાઓથી સફાઈ કર્મચારીઓ તેમની ફરજ બજાવતા ન હોવાથી સ્ટ્રીટ ડસ્ટ ડબ્બાની સફાઈ કરવામાં આવી નથી.વધુ મા, છેલ્લા બે માસથી અમારી સોસાયટીમાં સફાઈ કરવા આવનાર સફાઈ કામદાર ખૂબ જ અનિયમિત છે. દરરોજ સવારે સફાઈ કરવાની હોય છે, પરંતુ તે અઠવાડિયામાં ભાગ્યે જ બે દિવસ આવે છે. રસ્તા બરાબર વળાતા નથી. કચરાના ઢગલા નિયમિત ભરાતા નથી. પરિણામે દુર્ગધ અને માખીઓનો ત્રાસ અસહ્ય થઈ પડ્યો છે. તેમાં વળી ઢોરનાં મળમૂત્ર ભળે છે. સોસાયટીમાંથી નીકળતાં નાક દબાવીને નીકળવું પડે તેવી સ્થિતિ છે. સોસાયટીના ઘણા રહીશો બીમાર થઈ ગયા છે. સફાઈ કામદારને સફાઈ કરવા જણાવીએ છીએ, પરંતુ તે એક કાનેથી સાંભળી બીજા કાનેથી કાઢી નાખે છે.આપશ્રીને નમ્ર વિનંતી કે આપશ્રી આ અંગે જરૂરી તપાસ કરી તાત્કાલિક સફાઈ કરાવવાની વ્યવસ્થા કરશોજી.આભાર સહ.આપનો વિશ્વાસુ[તમારું નામ]"},{"question":"別名をしろがねと言い、熱と電気をよく通す金属と言えば？","answer":"銀です。"},{"question":"സസ്തനികളിലെ ഏത് ജൈവ പ്രക്രിയയാണ് കൂടുതലും കോശവിഭജനം മൂലം സംഭവിക്കുന്നത്? ഇനി പറയുന്നവയാണ് ഓപ്ഷനുകൾ: [ഐ] രോഗശാന്തി; [II] ശ്വസനം [III] വിഘടനം [IV] പ്രകാശസംശ്ലേഷണം നിങ്ങളുടെ ഉത്തരം:","answer":"രോഗശാന്തി"},{"question":"పల్లెటూళ్ళకు వెళితే మనం ఏ ఏ విషయాలు తెలుసు కోవచ్చు?","answer":"మానవత్వం తెలుస్తుంది. స్నేహం విలువ తెలుస్తుంది. కలసిమెలసి ఉండడమెలాగో తెలుస్తుంది. పక్షుల కిలకిలలు, జంతువుల కలకలలు తెలుస్తాయి. పచ్చటి ప్రకృతికి దగ్గరగా ఉండవచ్చు. హాయిగా ఉండవచ్చు. కలుషితం కాని స్వచ్చమైన వాతావరణంలో జీవించ వచ్చు. ఒక్కమాటలో చెప్పాలంటే, అమ్మ చేతి గోరు ముద్దలు తిన్నట్లు ఉంటుంది. అమ్మ జోలపాట వింటున్నట్లుంటుంది. తాత చెప్పే కథల మాధుర్యం తెలుస్తుంది. నాన్న తోడులోని భరోసా తెలుస్తుంది."},{"question":"काठमाडौं उपत्यकाको लागि पहुँच/आवास के हो।","answer":"काठमाडौं उपत्यकाको त्रिभुवन अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय विमानस्थलमा सिधै उडान गर्न सकिन्छ। सीमावर्ती सहर र देशका अन्य भागबाट काठमाडौं जान वा बस चढ्न सकिन्छ। काठमाडौं उपत्यका र वरपरका आधुनिक सुविधासहितका पाँचतारे होटल, रिसोर्टहरू छन्।"},{"question":"Sọ fúnmi nípa Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó.","answer":"Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó jẹ́ ìpínlẹ̀ kan ní gúúsù ìwọ̀-oòrùn Nàìjíríà. Láàárin àwọn Ìpínlẹ̀ mẹ́rìndìnlógójì náà, ó pọ̀ níye, ó sì kéré ní ààyè. Ó sopọ̀ mọ́ gúúsù nípasẹ̀ àwọn ìgbèríko Benin àti sí ìwọ̀-oòrùn nípasẹ̀ ààlà òkèèrè pẹ̀lu Ìlu Benin, Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó ń pín àwọn ààlà pẹ̀lú Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn sí ìlà-oòrùn àti àríwá ní èyí tí ó mu jé ìpínlẹ̀ kan ṣoṣo ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà tí ó pín ààlà pẹ̀lú ìpínlẹ̀ kan péré. Ìlú tí ó pọ̀ jùlọ ní ilẹ̀ adúláwọ̀ ni ìlú Èkó; wọ́n dá ìpínlẹ̀ náà látara agbègbè Ìwọ̀-Oòrùn tí ó sì jẹ́ olú-ìlú tẹ́lèrí ní ọjọ́ kẹ́tadínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù Èbìbí, ọdún 1967. Gégẹ́ bí ìtọ́ka agbègbè, Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó jẹ́ ilẹ̀ omi tí ìdá-mẹ́rin rẹ̀ dín ní díẹ̀ kúnfún òsà àti àwọn odò. Èyí tí ó fẹ̀ jù nínú àwọn omi wọ̀nyí ni ọ̀sà Èkó àti Lekki nínú ìpínlẹ̀ náà pẹ̀lú odò Ògùn àti Ọ̀sun tí ó ń sàn wọnú wọn. Àwọn omi yòó kù jẹ́ ìṣàn-omi tí ó ń sàn kiri ìpínlẹ̀ náà tí wọ́n sì jẹ́ ọ̀nà ìrìnàjò pàtàkì fún àwọn èèyàn àti ọjà. Ìpínlẹ̀ yìí bákan náà ṣàkóónú àwọn onírúnrú ohun ọ̀gbìn, ẹranko àti ẹranmi gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹjá ṣe wà náà ni àwọn ẹranmi ilẹ̀ adúláwọ̀ àti àwọn ọ̀ọ̀nì.Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó ti jé ibùgbé fún ọdún tó ti pẹ́ nípasẹ̀ àwon ọ̀wọ́ onírúurú ẹ̀yà onílùú, ní pàtàkì awọn ọmọ Yorùbá ni wọ́n ń gbé káàkiri ìpínlẹ̀ náà àmọ́ àwọn èèyan Ewe àti Ogu náà ń gbé ibi tí o nasẹ̀ lápá Ìwọ̀-Oòrùn.Gẹ́gẹ́ bí àbáyọrí ṣíṣí lọ láti orílẹ̀-èdè kan sí òmíràn láti bíi ọ̀rúndún sẹ́yìn, ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó pẹ̀lú ti ní èrò tó pọ̀ tí wọn kìí ṣe àwọn ọ̀wọ́ ẹ̀yà orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà pẹ̀lú Edo, Fulani, Hausa, Igbo, Ijaw, Ibibio, àti èèyàn Nupe láàárin àwọn ọ̀wọ́ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà yòókù. Àwọn ọ̀wọ́ mìíràn wá látìta tí wọn wá láti àwọn ìlú tí ó pín ààlà orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà pèlú Saro (Sierra Leonean) àti Amaro (Brazilian) gẹ́gẹ́ bí àwọn ọ̀wọ́ tí wọn ṣẹ̀ wá tí wọ́n kó lẹru tẹ́lẹ̀rị́ tí wọ́n padà sílẹ̀ adúláwọ̀ ní àwọn ọdún 1800 pẹ̀lú àwọn àwùjọ àárín ìlà-oòrùn orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà tí wọ́n ti wà ti pẹ́ (pàápàá Syrian àti Lebanese orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà) pẹ̀lú di èrò ní apákan gbòógì ní ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó pẹ̀lú àwọn tí wọ́n ṣí wá láìpẹ́ láti ìlu Benin, China, Ghana, India, Togo, àti United Kingdom. Ẹ káàbọ̀ sí Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó."},{"question":"Tweet a dị n'okpuru ọ na-egosipụta mmetụta dị mma, nke na-adịghị mma, ka ọ bụ mmetụta na-anọpụ iche?2020 emeela anyi ihe ọjọọ","answer":"Tweet ahụ na-egosipụta mmetụta na-adịghị mma."},{"question":"Can you describe the craftsmanship behind Sri Lanka's traditional \\"Kandyan Sari,\\" and how does wearing this garment contribute to cultural identity?","answer":"The traditional \\"Kandyan Sari\\" in Sri Lanka is a testament to exquisite craftsmanship and cultural identity. Worn predominantly by women during special occasions, this garment showcases intricate handloom work, elaborate embroidery, and vibrant color combinations. Each sari tells a story through its design, representing aspects of Sri Lankan culture and heritage. The artistry involved in creating a \\"Kandyan Sari\\" is often passed down through generations, emphasizing the cultural continuity. Wearing this garment becomes a source of pride, connecting individuals to their roots, and tourists exploring local markets or attending cultural events can witness firsthand the craftsmanship that goes into creating these elegant saris."},{"question":" Dhig sumadda joogsiga. ","answer":" Sumadda joogsi waa (.)"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada taring\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud berkuasa."},{"question":"Question: Which of the following is not a natural resource?a. Soilb. Waterc. Electricityd. AirAnswer:","answer":"Answer: (c)Electricity is not a natural resource. It is a manmade resource i.e., a form of energy that is not found in nature but can be produced artificially, by man. Whereas air, soil and water are all natural resources."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa nabigii laga soo saaray waddan Afrikaan ah?","answer":"Nabi Muuse(cs)."},{"question":"21 Kasım 1938 de ne oldu?","answer":"21 Kasım 1938 günü yabancı devletlerden gelenlerin de katıldığı bir cenaze töreni ile Ankara Etnografya Müzesi'ndeki geçici kabrine konuldu ve orada 4 ay katafalkta kaldı. Aynı günün akşamı Cumhurbaşkanı İsmet İnönü, Atatürk üzerine bir radyo konuşması yaptı."},{"question":"「マッチ売りの少女」「親指姫」「裸の王様」といった童話を書いた、デンマークの作家は誰でしょう？","answer":"アンデルセンです。"},{"question":"ලෝක ඒඩ්ස් දිනය ","answer":"ලෝක ඒඩ්ස් දිනය සෑම වසරකම දෙසැම්බර් මස 01 වන දින සමරනු ලැබේ. මෙම දිනය සැමරීමේ අරමුණ වන්නේ එච්.අයි.වී. වෛරස ආසාදනය හේතුකොටගෙන ව්‍යාප්ත වන ඒඩ්ස් වසංගතය පිළිබඳ ප්‍රජාව දැනුවත් කිරීමත්, රෝගය හේතුවෙන් මිය ගිය රෝගීන් සිහි කිරීමත් ය."},{"question":"Maxay tahay waxtarka fitamiin E iyo cunnooyinka hodanka ku ah wax noogga sheeg?","answer":"Fitamiin E waa mid ka mid ah nafaqooyinka aasaasiga ah ee jirku uusan ka maarmi karin. Waa fitamiin ku milma dufanka waana sunsaare awood badan oo unugyada jirka ka ilaaliya sunta jirka ku dhex samaynta, taas oo hadii aan laga hortagin keeni karta cudurro badan sida cudurrada wadnaha ku dhaca iyo kansarka. Fitamiinkani waxa uu xoojiyaa habdhiska difaaca jirka, waxa uu ka qeyb qaataa samaysanka unugyada dhiigga cas, waxaana uu ka hortagaa xinjiroobista dhiigga. Sida oo kale, fitamiin E waxa uu door wayn ka ciyaaraa caafimaadka maqaarka, indhaha iyo maskaxda. Faaidooyinka fitamiin E: Waxaa uu siyaadiyaa aragga, waxaana uu ka hortagaa cilladaha indhaha ku dhaca .Shaqada beerka iyo kilyaha ayuu wanaajiyaa .Xoojinta lafaha ayuu ka qeyb qaataa .Wuxuu sare u qaadaa shaqada maskaxda.Waxa uu awood siyaa difaaca jirka .Waxa uu kobciyaa caafimaadka maqaarka iyo timaha .Waxaa uu kordhiyaa tayada shahwada waxaana uu wanaajinta bacriminta ragga.Cunnooyinka laga helo fitamiin E: Miraha Afakaadhada Lawska Barbarooniga guduudan Saliid saytuunta Saliida gabaldayaha Caleenta broccoli Koostada Cambaha Ukunta Kaluunka Dadka waa waa weyn waxa ay u baahan yihiin 15 mg oo fitamiin E ah maalin kasta. "},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. Cikgu Angeline menyusun __ yang akan disampaikan kepada para pemenang di atas meja. Pilihan:  A) kemas-kemas B) kotak-kotakC) piala-pialaD) hadiah-hadiah ","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C) piala-piala"},{"question":"¿A cuál categoría pertenece la siguiente pregunta?Pregunta: ¿Ha habido algún presidente asiático en los Estados Unidos?","answer":"La categoría a la que pertenece la pregunta es historia."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'harapkan guruh di langit, air di tempayan ditumpahkan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud melakukan pekerjaan yang tergesa-gesa maka rugi akibatnya (kehilangan barang yang sudah dimiliki)"},{"question":"वाकाटक घराण्याचा मूळ संस्थापक कोण होता ?","answer":"विंध्यशक्ती"},{"question":"1924年以降、南アフリカの各地で発見され、ラテン語で「南の猿」という意味の名がつけられた化石人類は何でしょう？","answer":"アウストラロピテクス"},{"question":"Türkiye'nin en uzun tüneli hangi ilde?","answer":"Gebze-Orhangazi-İzmir Otoyolu Projesi kapsamında Samanlı Dağı delinerek, 3 şeritli 2 tüp olarak yapılan Orhangazi Tüneli, 3 bin 590 metreyle Türkiye'nin en uzun otoyol tüneli unvanını taşıyor."},{"question":"Do you remember when we were reading https://te.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E0%B0%93%E0%B0%AC%E0%B1%81%E0%B0%B2%E0%B0%B0%E0%B1%86%E0%B0%A1%E0%B1%8D%E0%B0%A1%E0%B0%BF%E0%B0%AA%E0%B0%B2%E0%B1%8D%E0%B0%B2%E0%B1%86 the other day? It started sth like document_plaintext[:100].. Can you continue it for up to another 1000 characters?","answer":"ంద్రమైన తలుపుల నుండి 10 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన కదిరి నుండి 35 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 893 ఇళ్లతో, 3374 జనాభాతో 1906 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 1695, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 1679. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 257 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 438. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 595222[2].పిన్ కోడ్: 515581.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుగ్రామంలో ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాలలు ఆరు, ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల ఒకటి , ప్రభుత్వ మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల ఒకటి ఉన్నాయి. సమీప బాలబడి, సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల, సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల  ,  తలుపుల లోను, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్ / సైన్స్ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల,  ఉన్నాయి.  పాలీటెక్నిక్, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల‌లు కదిరి లోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల అనంతపురం లోను,వైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యంఓబులరెడ్డిపల్లెలో ఉన్న ఒక ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రంలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ఇద్దరు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు. ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉంది. పశు వైద్యశాల,కలదు. "},{"question":"\\"Bude lagi bali saka toko.\\"Tembung \\"bali\\" krama inggile yaiku...A. WangsulB. TindakC. MlampahJawaban: ","answer":"Jawaban: A. Wangsul"},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase:  A mesquita foi mandada construir pelo sultão em 1501. Foi a segunda grande mesquita imperial a ser construída em Istambul a seguir à","answer":"conquista turca da cidade. As pedras usadas na construção foram trazidas da famosa igreja da Nascente da Vida, que foi destruída pelos turcos."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Harold C. Urey para a química?","answer":"Harold C. Urey, um químico norte-americano, recebeu o Prêmio Nobel de Química em 1934 por sua descoberta do deutério, um isótopo pesado do hidrogênio, contribuindo significativamente para a compreensão da composição isotópica dos elementos."},{"question":"வினா:ஆண்டாளின் கனவுக் காட்சிகளை எழுதுக.","answer":"விடை:திருமாலை வழிபட்டுச் சிறப்புநிலை எய்திய ஆழ்வார்கள் பன்னிருவர் ஆவர்.அவருள் ஆண்டாள் மட்டுமே பெண் ஆவார். இறைவனுக்குப் பாமாலை சூட்டியதோடு தான் அணிந்து மகிழ்ந்த பூமாலையையும் சூட்டியதால், “சூடிக் கொடுத்த சுடர்க்கொடி” என அழைக்கப்பெற்றார்.ஆழ்வார்கள் பாடிய பாடல்களின் தொகுப்பு “நாலாயிர திவ்வியப் பிரபந்தம்” ஆகும். இத்தொகுப்பில் ஆண்டாள் பாடியதாகத் திருப்பாவை, நாச்சியார் திருமொழி என்ற இரு தொகுதிகள் உள்ளன.நாச்சியார்  திருமொழி மொத்தம் 140 பாடல்களைக் கொண்டது.திருப்பாவையில் பாவை நோன்பு மேற்கொண்ட, ஆண்டாள், நாச்சியார் திருமொழியில் பல வகைப் பாடல்களைப் பாடி, கண்ணபிரானை அடைய வழி வகுக்கிறாள். 1. சதிராடும் இளம்பெண்கள், தம் கைகளில் கதிரவன் போன்ற ஒளியையுடைய விளக்கையும் கலசத்தையும் ஏந்தியவாறு வந்து எதிர் கொண்டு அழைக்கிறார்கள்.2. மதுராபுரியை ஆளும் மன்னனாம் கண்ணன், பாதங்களில் பாதுகை அணிந்து கொண்டு புவி அதிர மகிழ்ச்சியுடன் நடந்து வருகிறான்,.3. மத்தளம் முழங்க, வரி சங்கம் ஊத, முத்துக்களையுடைய மாலைகள் தொங்கவிடப்பட்ட பந்தலின் கீழ் அத்தை மகனும், “மது” என்ற அரக்கனை அழித்தவனுமாகிய கண்ணன் என்னைத் திருமணம் செய்து கொள்கிறான் என்று ஆண்டாள் கனவு கண்டதாகக் கூறுகிறாள்."},{"question":"ساینس پوهان ادعا کوي چې د سویلي امریکا او افریقا براعظمونه یو وخت یو واحد ځمکه وه. لاندې ټولې څرګندونې د دې ادعا ملاتړ کوي پرته له یوې؛ لاندې یو غوره کړئ. (a) په لویدیځ کې غرونه د ورته عمر ډبرې لري. (b) دا براعظمونه د معما ټوټې په څیر ښکاري. (c) ورته کبان د دې براعظمونو په ساحلونو کې په سمندرونو کې ژوند کوي. (d) په دې براعظمونو کې ورته فوسیلونه موندل شوي.ځواب دا دی:","answer":"(c) ورته کبان د دې براعظمونو په ساحلونو کې په سمندرونو کې ژوند کوي."},{"question":"අධ්‍යනය කටයුත්තක් සඳහා \\"දෙමළ ගත්තර\\" කුලය ගැන විස්තර අවශ්‍යයි.","answer":"කාලිංග මාඝ රජතුමාට පක්ෂපාතීව වැඩ කළ මාදු ගඟ අසබඩව ජීවත් වූ පිරිසක්.වීදිය බණ්ඩාර කුමාරයා කාලිංග මාඝගේ පිරිවර හඹා යද්දී දිවිතුර ,වල්ලඹගල ,හා මතුගම ප්‍රදේශයන්ට පැමිණ ජීවිතාරක්ෂාව ලබා ගත් අය ලෙසයි ප්‍රසිද්ධ . ඔවුන් දෙමළ ජාතිය හා සම්බන්ධ නොවේ.වාසගම් වලින් බැලූ කළ සලාගම කුලයේ අය බව පෙනී යයි."},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள் - சிப்பாய்1857 சிப்பாய் கிளர்ச்சிக்குப்","answer":"பின் அவத் நவாப்புகள் பிரித்தானிய இந்திய அரசின் கட்டுப்பாட்டின் கீழ் தனியுரிமையின்றி சுதேச சமஸ்தான மன்னர்களாக 1858 வரை ஆண்டனர். பின்னர் அவகாசியிலிக் கொள்கையின் படி, அவத் இராச்சியம் பிரித்தானிய இந்திய அரசுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டது."},{"question":"سه تا سریال کمدی ایرانی را اسم ببر.","answer":"البته که سریال‌های کمدی ایرانی زیادی وجود دارد و انتخاب سه مورد از بین آن‌ها نسبتاً سخت است. ولی سه سریال کمدی معروف ایرانی عبارتند از:1. «پایتخت»2. «شهرزاد» (به وضوح بخش‌های کمدی دارد، اما بیشتر به صورت یک درام تاریخی با المان‌های کمدی معروف است)3. «دورهمی»البته این فهرست کامل نیست و سریال‌های کمدی زیادی دیگر هم در ایران ساخته شده است."},{"question":"Di negeri manakah Hari Raya Gawai diraikan di Malaysia? Pilih jawapan yang betul daripada pilihan berikut.A. TerengganuB. KelantanC. SabahD. Sarawak","answer":"Jawapannya ialah D. Sarawak. Gawai adalah perayaan sempena meraikan tamatnya musim menuai padi yang disambut setiap tahun di negeri Sarawak pada 1 Jun."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'cakap angin'? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud cakap-cakap yang tidak berfaedah. Contoh ayat: Daripada bercakap angin dan melepak di gerai baiklah kita pergi ke perpustakaan."},{"question":"C'est qui Astérix?","answer":"Astérix est un personnage de bande dessinée créé par les auteurs français René Goscinny (scénario) et Albert Uderzo (dessin et co-scénario). La première bande dessinée mettant en scène Astérix, intitulée \\"Astérix le Gaulois\\", est parue en 1961."},{"question":"சரியான சரணங்களில் பிழைகள் இல்லாமல் தமிழ் தாய் வாழ்த்து எழுதவும். பிறகு, ஒரு பத்தியில் அதன் அர்த்தத்தை விளக்க வேண்டும்.","answer":"தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்து என்பது இந்திய மாநில அரசுகளுள் தமிழை ஆட்சி மொழியாய் கொண்டுள்ளவற்றில் பாடப்பெறும் வாழ்த்துப் பாடலாகும். இது தமிழ்த் தாயை வாழ்த்தி வணக்கம் செலுத்துவதாக அமையும். இப்பாடல் அரசு விழாக்கள், பள்ளிகளின் காலை இறைவணக்கக் கூட்டம் முதலான நிகழ்வுகளின் தொடக்கத்தில் பாடப்படுகிறது. இந்திய தேசிய கீதம் இறுதியில் பாடப்படும்.தமிழக அரசால் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்ட தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்துப் பாடலை எழுதியவர் மனோன்மணீயம் பெ. சுந்தரனார் என்பவராவார். இவர் 1891-இல் எழுதி வெளியிட்ட புகழ்பெற்ற நாடக நூலான மனோன்மணீயம் நூலில் உள்ள பாயிரத்தில் தமிழ்த் தெய்வ வணக்கம் எனும் தலைப்பிலுள்ள ஒரு பகுதி இப்பாடலாகும்.வரலாறுதமிழகத்தின் அனைத்து விழாக்களிலும் மனோன்மணீயம் சுந்தனாரின் நீராரும் கடலுடுத்த பாடலைப் பாட வேண்டும் என்ற கோரிக்கை 1913-ஆம் ஆண்டு கரந்தைத் தமிழ்ச் சங்கத்தின் ஆண்டறிக்கையில் இடம்பெற்றது. அதன் தொடர்ச்சியாக 1914 முதல் கரந்தைத் தமிழ் சங்கத்தின் ஆண்டு விழாக்களில் பாடிவந்தனர். அதேபோலப் கரந்தைத் தமிழ்ச் சங்கத்தைத் தாய்சங்கமாக ஏற்று ஆங்காங்கே உருவாக்கப்பட்ட சங்கங்களின் விழாக்களிலும் தொடக்கப் பாடலாக இப்பாடல் பாடப்பட்டு வந்தது. தமிழ்நாடு அரசு இப்பாடலைத் தமிழக அரசின் பாடலாக ஏற்குமாறு கோரிக்கைகள் வைக்கப்பட்டு வந்தன.1967 சென்னை மாநில சட்டமன்றத் தேர்தலில், தி.மு.க வெற்றிபெற்று ஆட்சியமைத்தது. தமிழ்நாட்டின் முதலமைச்சரான கா. ந. அண்ணாதுரை தமிழ் மொழியின் வளர்ச்சிப்போக்கை முன்னெடுக்கும் விதமாகத் தமிழ்நாட்டின் பள்ளி, கல்லூரி விழாக்களில் பாட ஏதுவாகத் தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்தைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்க ஆலோசனை செய்தார். ஆலோசனையின் முடிவில் மனோன்மணீயம் சுந்தரனாரின் நீராரும் கடலுடுத்த பாடலும், கரந்தை கவியரசு இயற்றிய வானார்ந்த பொதியின்மிசை வளர்கின்ற மதியே என்ற பாடலும் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டன. நீராரும் கடலுடுத்த பாடலில் வரும் தெக்கணமும் அதிற்சிறந்த திராவிட நல் திருநாடும் வரிகளில் வரும் திராவிட என்ற சொல் அண்ணாதுரையை ஈர்த்தது.எனவே அப்பாடலையே அரசுபூர்வமாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்து அறிவிக்கவிருந்த நிலையில் 1969-இல் அண்ணா இறந்தார்.இதன்பிறகு மு. கருணாநிதி முதலமைச்சராகத் பொறுப்பேற்றதையடுத்து, ஆரியம் போலத் தமிழ் உலகவழக்கழிந்து சிதையவில்லை என்று கூறும் வரிகள் தள்ளப்பட்டு தமிழ்த்தாயைப் புகழும் வகையில் அமைந்த வரிகள் மட்டும் ஏற்று இப்பாடலை 1970 மார்ச்சு 11 அன்று தமிழக அரசு தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்தாக அறிவித்தது. 2021-ஆம் ஆண்டு திசம்பர் 17-தேதி அன்று மு. க. ஸ்டாலின் தலைமையின் கீழ் செயற்பட்ட தமிழக அரசு தமிழ்நாடு அரசின் மாநிலப் பாடலாகத் தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்தை அறிவித்தது. 2021 திசம்பரில் வெளியிட்ட தமிழ்நாடு அரசாணையில் நீராரும் கடலுடுத்த பாடலைத் தமிழ்நாட்டின் அனைத்துக் கல்வி நிலையங்களிலும், பொதுத்துறை நிறுவனங்களிலும் விழா நிகழ்ச்சிகளின் தொடக்கத்தில் கட்டாயம் பாடவேண்டும். பாடலைப் பாடும்போது அனைவரும் கட்டாயம் எழுந்து நிற்க வேண்டும் (மாற்றுத் திறனாளிகளுக்கு விலக்கு) இப்பாடலை 55 விநாடிகளில் முல்லைப்பாணி எனும் பண்ணில் (மோகனராகம்) மூன்றன் நடையில் (திசுரம்) பாடவேண்டும் என்று குறிப்பிடப்பட்டது.பாடல் வரிகள்“\\tநீராருங் கடலுடுத்த நிலமடந்தைக் கெழிலொழுகும்சீராரும் வதனமெனத் திகழ்பரதக் கண்டமிதில்தெக்கணமும் அதிற்சிறந்த திராவிடநல் திருநாடும்தக்கசிறு பிறைநுதலும் தரித்தநறுந் திலகமுமே!அத்திலக வாசனைபோல் அனைத்துலகும் இன்பமுறஎத்திசையும் புகழ்மணக்க இருந்தபெருந் தமிழணங்கே!தமிழணங்கே!உன் சீரிளமைத் திறம்வியந்து செயல்மறந்து வாழ்த்துதுமே!வாழ்த்துதுமே!வாழ்த்துதுமே!தமிழிசைக் குறிப்பு :- இப்பாடல் முல்லைப்பாணி எனும் பண்ணில் அமைந்துள்ளது. மூன்றன் நடை தாளத்தில் அமைந்துள்ளது. முல்லைப்பாணி, முல்லத்தீம்பாணி, முல்லையந்தீங்குழல் (முல்லை அம் தீம் குழல்), சிறுமுல்லை, சாதாரி, தாரப்பண், காந்தாரப் பண், ஆசான், ஆசான் திறம் என பல்வேறு பெயர்கள் கொண்டுள்ளது. தமிழிசையின் முதல் பெரும்பண் செம்பாலை எனும் முல்லைப்பண் (அரிகாம்போதி). இந்த முல்லைப்பண்ணின் திறப்பண் தான் சிறுமுல்லை (மோகனம்). எனவே இது தமிழிசையின் முதல் சிறுபண். முல்லைப்பண், சிறுமுல்லை இரண்டு பண்களையும் தமிழர்கள் மிக உயர்வான இடத்தில் வைத்துக் கொண்டாடினர் எனும் உண்மையை நாம் தமிழ் இலக்கியங்களில் காணலாம். உலகெங்கிலும் பல நாகரிகங்களிலும், இரண்டாயிரம் ஆண்டுகள் முன்பிருந்து இன்றுவரை இந்த சிறுமுல்லைப்பண் மிகவும் புகழ்பெற்று பயன்பாட்டில் உள்ளது. தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்துக்கு இப்பண்ணைத் தெரிவு செய்தது பாராட்டுக்குரிய செயல். தமிழிசைப் பண்கள் குறித்து இந்தப் பக்கத்தில் பழந்தமிழ் இசை பழந்தமிழிசையில் பண்கள் காணலாம்."},{"question":"\\"R\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ කී වෙනි අකුර ද?","answer":"\\"R\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ දහ අට වන අකුර යි."},{"question":"வினா : அயோடின் நம் உடலில் எந்தெந்த இடத்தில் உள்ளது ?","answer":"விடை : தைராக்ஸின்,"},{"question":"Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ mélòó ni ó wà ní ìpínlẹ̀ Jìgáwá?","answer":"Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ mẹ́tàdínlọ́gbọ̀n ni."},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Ñàkk a xam jubluwaayu sunu teewaay ci kaw suuf rekk a ko waral. sàkkuwunu ñëw ci kaw suuf, xamunu nees lanu fi war a dunde, te bëggunu fi a jugé.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Ñàkk a xàm jubluwaay u sunu teewaay ci kaw sùuf rekk a ko wàral. Sàkkuwu nu ñëw ci kaw sùuf, xàmu nu nees la nu fi wàr a dunde, te bëggu nu fi a jóge."},{"question":"Tsumo inotevera inorevei?Kuwanda huuya, museve wakapotera pamuzukuru.","answer":"Panevakawanda ndima unorereka."},{"question":"A que categoría perteneces la siguiente pregunta: ¿Quién era el cantante de Nirvana nacido en Aberdeen, Washington?.","answer":"La categoría a la que pertenece la pregunta es Música"},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:माझिये अंतरीं भरावें । सर्वकाळ वास्तव्य करावें ।मज वाग्सुंन्यास वदवावें । कृपाकटाक्षेंकरूनी ॥ २॥","answer":"अर्थ:आपण माझे अंतःकरणास व्यापून सर्वकाळ तेथे वास्तव्य करावे आणि आपल्या कृपाकटाक्षाने माझे अज्ञान दूर करून माझ्या मुखाने ग्रंथ वदवून घ्यावा. (२)"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ɗari ɗaya da sittin da biyar a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 165"},{"question":"කමත් බසෙන් ගොම්පස් රාජකාරිය  යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගොම කමතට නොවැටෙන සේ පිදුරු අණ්ඩියට වැටීමට සලස්වා එය කමතෙන් පිටතට ගෙනගොස් දැමීම"},{"question":"What are the titles of the six volumes of Sir Winston Churchill's \\"World War II\\"?","answer":"Sir Winston Churchill's six-volume series on World War II, often regarded as a classic in war literature, has the following titles:The Gathering Storm - This volume covers the pre-war years and the rise of Hitler, focusing on the period from the end of World War I to the early years of World War II.Their Finest Hour - This volume deals with the early part of the war, including the Battle of Britain and the beginning of the Nazi invasion of Western Europe.The Grand Alliance - Here, Churchill discusses the widening of the war and the formation of the alliance between the United Kingdom, the United States, and the Soviet Union.The Hinge of Fate - This volume covers crucial moments such as the turning of the war in favor of the Allies, with events like the battles in North Africa and the invasion of Italy.Closing the Ring - In this part, Churchill narrates the period of the war where the Allies start closing in on Nazi Germany, including the Normandy invasion.Triumph and Tragedy - The final volume describes the conclusion of the war, the post-war negotiations, and the onset of the Cold War.These volumes not only provide a detailed history of the war but also offer insights into Churchill's perspectives and leadership during this critical period."},{"question":"வினா: குறைந்த எலக்ட்ரான் கவர் தன்மையுடைய தனிமம்","answer":"விடை: சீசியம்"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة التي تحدثت عن تقسيم الغنائم؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة الأنفال"},{"question":"Mutiat Adio tun rẹwọn he lẹyin to ti ṣẹwọn lẹẹmeji","answer":"Ẹwọn ọdun mẹta ni wọn tun sọ obinrin kan, Mutiat Adio, ti ile-ẹjọ ti kọkọ sọ sẹwọn lẹẹmeji ọtọọtọ lori oriṣiiriṣii ẹsun ọdaran si.Ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an bayii ni pe o fi iwe sọwe-dowo san miliọnu kan aabọ naira (N1.5m), gẹgẹ biii owo mọto to ra lọwọ Fabunmi Samuel, ṣugbọn ti ko sowo ninu akaunti rẹ.Wọn ni fun nnkan bii oṣu mẹta ni ko fi si owo ninu akaunti ti obinrin yii fun wọn ni iwe sọwe-dowo ẹ yii, bẹẹ igbakeji akọwe agba tẹlẹ ni nile-ẹjọ giga kan nipinlẹ Ọyọ.Ninu ẹsun ti ajọ EFCC, iyẹn ajọ to n gbogun ti iwa ajẹbanu, to fi ilu Ibadan ṣebujokoo fi kan an ni wọn ti fidi ẹ mulẹ pe wọn ti dajọ obinrin yii lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to kọja.Agbẹnusọ fun ajọ naa, Ọgbẹni Wilson Uwujaren, sọ pe ki wọn too gbe idajọ kalẹ lo ti kọkọ sọ pe oun ko jẹbi ẹsun ti wọn ka si i lẹsẹ pe o fi ọgbọn gba owo, o tun fun eeyan ni iwe sọwe-dowo, bẹẹ ni ko si owo ninu akaunti rẹ.Sugbọn lẹyin ti Adio jẹwọ pe oun jẹbi ni wọn sọ ọ sẹwọn ọdun mẹta, bakan naa ni Adajọ Owolabi paṣẹ pe ko san idaji miliọnu naira yooku fun ileeṣẹ Fatai Olanrewaju Motors, to ra mọto Toyota Pathfinder (2000) lọwọ wọn.Ọgbọnjọ, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2018, ni wọn kọkọ gbe e wa sile-ẹjọ, nibi to ti sọ pe oun ko jẹbi ẹsun ti wọn ka si i lẹsẹ yii, ko too yi ọrọ ẹ pada pe loootọ loun jẹbi.Adajọ Owolabi ti sọ pe ko lọọ ṣẹwọn ọdun mẹta, ko si tun da idaji miliuọnu pada fawọn to ra mọto lọwọ wọn, to fun ni sọwedowo ọhun.Ni bayii, wọn lo ti digba mẹta ọtọọtọ ti ile-ẹjọ yoo ran Arabinrin Mutiat Adio yii lẹwọn.Ọdun 2018 ni wọn kọkọ sọ ọ sẹwọn ọdun meje lori ẹsun pe o fọgbọn gba owo miliọnu mẹsan ati ẹgbẹrun lọna igba naira lọwọ ẹnikan to n jẹ Abiọdun Ọlọnade, tiyẹn n gbe lorilẹ-ede Ireland lọhun-un.Lọjọ kẹfa oṣu kẹta ọdun 2020 ni wọn tun ran an lẹwọn ọdun marun-un lori ẹsun pe o ji owo to le ni miliọnu mejilelogun (N22,375,913) ni banki Guaranty Trust Bank Plc."},{"question":"Apakah sinopsis untuk filem Mukhsin yang diarahkan oleh Yasmin Ahmad?","answer":"Orked bukan seperti budak perempuan lain, yang lebih suka bermain masak-masak dan kahwin-kahwin. Dia yang kasar kelakuannya, sukar diterima kanak-kanak lain di kampungnya. Malah, orang kampung memandang aneh keluarga ini seperti ketika Orked dan ibu, Mak Inom bermain hujan sementara ayah, Pak Atan melagukan keroncong.Satu hari, Orked memerhati budak-budak lelaki bermain ‘hantu galah.’ Bila seorang pemainnya terseliuh kaki ada yang mencadangkan Orked menggantinya, tetapi seorang budak lelaki lagak ketua bukan saja enggan, malah membaling bola ke arahnya.Orked diam, tidak mengelak biarpun bola yang dibaling keras terkena badannya. Sedang mereka mentertawakannya, dia membalas dengan membaling bola sama ke arah budak lelaki tadi yang terkena dahinya.Dan, hidup Orked pun berubah.Kehadiran Mukhsin, budak lelaki itu yang datang bercuti di kampungnya membibitkan persahabatan di antara mereka. Orked malah bergaya seperti Mukhsin - baju dan seluar lusuh, serta berkaki ayam, bermain dengan budak lelaki, memanjat pokok dan berbasikal.Tapi, sebagai kanak-kanak yang meningkat remaja, Mukhsin mula menyimpan rasa terhadap Orked, menyebabkan ujud permasalahan antara mereka. Dan, bagaimana perasaan cinta mampu merosakkan sebuah persahabatan.Filem Mukhsin berkisar tentang kasih sayang dan percintaan antara watak Orked, 10, dan Mukhsin, 12. Filem ini memaparkan tentang rasa cinta pertama yang timbul di hati mereka.Bagaimanapun ketika itu masalah yang timbul ialah Orked masih terlalu mentah untuk bercinta, manakala Mukhsin pula sedang melalui zaman peralihan akil baligh.Hingga hari terakhir Mukhsin meninggalkan kampung Orked, dia masih gagal meluahkan rasa cintanya.Lalu Mukhsin pergi meninggalkan satu kenangan cinta indah buat Orked yang turut diminati seorang kanak-kanak Cina di sekolahnya."},{"question":"Inona no tombontsoa azo avy amin’ny fanaovana tambiro?","answer":"Ny tambirô dia soatoavina nampifandray ny mpiara-monina amin’ny alalan’ny asa, ka ny tombontsoa azo avy amin’ny fanaovana azy dia:-Misy ny fiaraha-miasa.-Vita haingana ny asa.-Mihamafy ny fihavanana sy ny firaisankina eo amin’ny mpiara-monina.-Miara-miakatra ny vokatra satria vita iray andro ny asa."},{"question":"A karanta waɗannan labaru, sannan a amsa tambayoyin da suka biyo kowannensu.‘‘Ba neman aure ke da wuya ba, shigaka-fito’’. Ka ga shiga-ka-fito ɗin nan, lallai shiga-ka-fito ɗin ne! Domin aljihu kan jigata kafin a kai ga biki. Tuddan da al’ada ta tanada, waɗanda dole sai an haye su, suna da yawa.Yanzu ɗauki misalin kayan na–gani-inaso, wato ’yan kayan nan da ake shiryawa a kai gidan su yarinya a karon farko. Ma’anar yin haka, wai iyaye su san cewa manemin auren ’yarsu da gaske yake. To, ina dole ga yin haka? Da can da yake zuwa yana zance da ’yarsu yana yi mata hasafi, ba a san da gaske yake ba?Gangaro kan kayan toshi. Nan ma tsabagen kuɗi ake kashewa a sayi suturu da kayan shafe-shafe a kai wa yarinya. Kada fa ka ce zuwa zance da manemi yake yana yi wa yarinya kyauta mako-mako, shi ke nan, ya wadatar. Ina, ko kaɗan!Kada ka mance da kuɗin gaisuwar iyaye da dukiyar aure kafin a yi baiko da sa ranar biki. Kuɗi ne maɗiɗɗiki ake tanada a kai wa iyayen yarinya da niyyar dai wannan abu da aka ambata.Duk bayan wannan, ana sa ranar aure, manemin yarinya ya dosa karakaina ke nan daga wannan gida zuwa wancan, ko ma wannan gari zuwa wancan da sunan gayar da iyaye da kakanninta, wai don su san shi. I, za su san shi mana, tun da ba yana zuwa ne ziƙau ba! Da zarar biki ya kawo jiki kuma, uwa-uba za a shirya kayan lefe na fitar hankali a kai wa yarinya. Nan ma dukiya ake narkawa.Haƙiƙa duk waɗannan abubuwa al’ada ce kawai ta ƙaƙaba wa al’umma. Ai ta fuskar dukiya, muhimmin abu ga aure, sadaki. Amma abin takaici, yanzu an yi masa mahalli a can ƙarshen sahu!Ziƙau a labarin na nufinA) da mummunar kamaB) babu kuɗiC) babu mutunciD) a galabaice","answer":"B) babu kuɗi"},{"question":"කෘතීම බුද්ධියේ පියා ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"ඇමරිකානු ජාතික ජෝන් මැකාති මහතා"},{"question":"31. O que é um intervalo intrajornada e qual é a sua importância na legislação trabalhista?","answer":"O intervalo intrajornada é um período de descanso concedido ao trabalhador durante a jornada de trabalho. Sua importância reside na garantia de pausas para descanso e alimentação, de acordo com a legislação trabalhista brasileira."},{"question":"कॉम्प्युटर.","answer":"कॉम्प्युटर आज आपल्या जीवनाचा एक महत्वपूर्ण भाग बनला आहे. आज प्रत्येक क्षेत्रात कम्प्युटरचा वापर केला जातो. जगातील सर्वात प्रथम कॉम्प्युटर चा उपोयोग \\"चार्ल्स बैबज\\" ह्यांनी १९४६ मधे केला होता, ते कम्प्युटर चे आविष्कारक आहेत. चार्ल्स बैबज ह्यांना \\"फादर ऑफ कम्प्युटर\\" ही उपाधी दिली गेली आहे.जेव्हा पहीला कम्प्युटर बनवला गेला होता तेव्हा तो आकाराने खूप मोठा होता, आणि तेव्हा कम्प्युटर प्रत्येकाच्या घरात ठेवणे शक्य नव्हते. पण वेळेबरोबर कॉम्प्युटर मध्ये फारसे बदल करण्यात आले आणि आज कॉम्प्युटर आकाराने छोटे झाले आहेत, आणि त्याबरोबरच आता ते खूप ऍडव्हान्स झाले आहेत.आज प्रत्येक क्षेत्रामध्ये कम्प्युटरचा वापर केला जातो. म्हणून सांगितले जाते कि आजचे युग हे कॉम्प्युटरचे युग आहे.कम्प्युटरच्या मदतीने कुठलेही काम अगदी जलद करता येते आणि कॉम्प्युटरने केलेले काम अचूक असते. म्हणून कम्प्युटरने प्रत्येक कार्यालयामध्ये आपली जागा बनवली आहे. कम्प्युटर हा आपल्या जीवनाचा महत्वपूर्ण भाग झाला आहे.संगणकाने मानवी जीवन एकदम सोपे करून टाकले आहे, पण कॉम्प्युटरचे फायदे आणि नुकसान देखील आहेत. कॉम्प्युटरचा वापर आपण कसा करून घेतो हे महत्त्वाचे असते कारण मनुष्य सारखे कॉम्प्युटरला चांगले वाईट ह्यामधला फरक कळत नाही, तो केवळ त्याला दिलेल्या सूचना अनुसार चालतो.कम्प्युटरच्या सहाय्याने आज विद्यार्थी शालेय शिक्षण घरी बसल्या मिळवू शकतो. आज कॉम्प्युटर कोणी पण कुठेही घेऊन जाऊ शकते त्यामुळे कामे आपल्या वेळेनुसार करता येतात. आज सर्व डेटा एका छोट्या कॉम्प्युटर मध्ये ठेवला जाऊ शकतो त्यामुळे पूर्वीच्या फाइल्स पासून सुटका झाली आहे. कॉम्प्युटर मध्ये काही शोधायला वेल खुप लागत नाही बटन दाबले की सर्वकाही जागेत बसून डोळ्यासमोर येते. आज तिकीट काढणे, लाईट बिल भरणे आणि अशी कितीतरी कामे किती जलद होतात, हे सर्व कॉम्प्युटर मुळेच शक्य झाले आहे.कॉम्प्युटरचे फायदे तर भरपूर आहेत पण त्याचे काही नुकसान सुद्धा आहेत. संगणकामुळे आज सर्व कामे सोपी झाली आहेत पण त्यामुळे माणसे आळशी होत चालली आहेत, मनुष्य आता कॉम्प्युटर वर अवलंबून राहू लागला आहे. आज कॉम्प्युटर ने सर्वकाही ऑटोमॅटिक झाल्याने कंपनीमध्ये माणसे नव्हे तर रोबोट काम करतात ज्याने लोकांना आता काम मिळत नाही. विद्यार्थी आपला पूर्ण वेळ कम्प्युटर गेम खेळत वाया घालवतात. काही वाईट वृत्तीची लोक कॉम्प्युटर वायरस बनवतात ज्याने ते कॉम्प्युटर मधला महत्वपूर्ण डेटा चोरी करतात ज्याने खूप नुकसान होते. कम्प्युटरचा वापर केल्याने डोळ्याचा आणि कमरेचा त्रास होतो.असा हा कॉम्प्युटर एक बहुपयोगी तंत्र आहे पण त्याचे केवळ फायदे नसून नुकसान देखील आहे. आपण कम्प्युटर चा योग्य वापर केला पाहिजे पण त्यावर पूर्णपणे अवलंबून नाही राहिले पाहिजे."},{"question":"મહારાણા પ્રતાપ વિશે નિબંધ લખો","answer":"હિંદુ પંચાગના મુજબ મહારાણા પ્રતાપનો જન્મ જયેષ્ઠ મહીનાના શુક્લ પક્ષની તૃતીયા તિથિ પર થયો હતો. તેમજ અંગ્રેજી કેલેંડરના મુજબ મહારાણા પ્રતાપનો જન્મ 9 મે 1540માં રાજસ્થાનના કુંભલગઢમાં થયો હતો. મહારાણા પ્રતાપે ઘણીવાર રણભૂમિમાં મુઘલ શાસક ને ટક્કર આપી હતી. રાજસ્થાનમાં મહારાણા પ્રતાપના જન્મોત્સવને ધૂમધામથી ઉજવાય છે. આ વર્ષે 13 જૂન 2021 રવિવારે મહારાણા પ્રતાપનો જન્મોત્સવ ઉજવાશે. આવો જાણીએ તેમના જીવનથી સંકળાયેલી કેટલીક ખાસ વાતોં. મહારાણા પ્રતાપની માતાનું નામ જીવંતાબાઈ અને પત્નીનું નામ અજબદે પવાર હતું.  તેમને સંતાનમાં ત્રણ પુત્રો અને બે પુત્રીઓ હતી. પરંતુ તેઓ માત્ર ત્રીસ વર્ષની ઉંમરે જ મૃત્યુ પામ્યા હતા. પરંતુ કેટલીક જગ્યાઓએ તેમની 11 પત્નીઓ અને 17  સંતાનો હતાં એવો ઉલ્લેખ છે, સત્તર પુત્રો અને પાંચ પુત્રીઓ. તેમનાં સૌથી મોટા પુત્ર અમરસિંહે તેમની રાજગાદી સંભાળી અને તેમનો વંશ આગળ વધાર્યો. તેઓ સીસોદીયા રાજપૂત હતા. તેઓ સીસોદીયા વંશના ચોપનમાં રાજા હતા.  મહારાણા પ્રતાપની ઊંચાઈ 7 ફૂટ 5 ઇંચ જેટલી હતી. મહારાણા પ્રતાપએ તેમની મા પાસેથી યુદ્ધ કૌશલની શિક્ષા ગ્રહણ કરી હતી.  મહારાણા પ્રતાપએ હલ્દીઘાટીના યુદ્દમાં અકબરને પૂર્ણ ટ્ક્કર આપી હતી. જ્યારે મહારાણા પ્રતાપની પાસે માત્ર 20 હજાર સૈનિક હતા અને અકબરની પાસે આશરે 85 હજાર સૈનિકોની સેના હતી. તે છતાં આ યુદ્ધને  અકબર જીતી શક્યો નહોતો. આ યુદ્ધ પછી મુઘલોએ મેવાડ, ચિત્તોડગઢ, કુંભલગઢ, ઉદયપુર અને ગોગુંડા પર કબ્જો મેળવી લીધો હતો. મોટા ભાગના રાજપૂત રાજાઓ મુઘલોની શરણાગતિ સ્વીકારી ચુક્યા હતા, પરંતુ પ્રતાપે ક્યારેય હાર સ્વીકારી ન હતી.અકબરની શરણાગતિ સ્વીકારવી ન હતી એટલે જ્યારે અકબરે કુંભલગઢ જીતી લીધું એમની ગેરહાજરીમાં ત્યારે પણ તેઓ શરણાગત થવાને બદલે અરવલ્લીનાં જંગલોમાં રહેવા લાગ્યા હતા. જંગલોમાં રહીને, અનેક મુસીબતોનો સામનો કરીને તેમનું શરીર ખાસ્સું કસાયેલું હતું. તેમનું વજન લગભગ 110 કિલો હતું. વાત માનવામાં નહીં આવે પણ સત્ય છે.મહારાણા પ્રતાપના ભાલાનુ  વજન 81 કિલો અને છાતીના કવચનુ  વજન 72 કિલો હતુ.મહારાણા પ્રતાપ ક્યારે પણ મુઘલોના સામે નમ્યા નથી. દરેક વાર તેમણે મુઘલોને કરારો જવાબ આપ્યો.  મહારાણા પ્રતાપનો સૌથી પ્રિય ઘોડાનુ  નામ ચેતક હતો. તે ઘોડો પણ બહાદુર હતો. યુદ્ધ દરમિયાન જ્યારે જહાંગીરનો હાથી તેમની એકદમ નજીક આવી ગયેલો ત્યારે તેમનાં ઘોડા ચેતકે હાથી પર પોતાનાં બે પગ ટેકવી દીધેલ, કાઠીયાવાડી કુળનો આ ઘોડો. એક સમયે જ્યારે મુઘલો સામેના યુદ્ધમાં મુઘલ સેના એકલા પ્રતાપની પાછળ પડી હતી ત્યારે ચેતક 22 ફૂટનું નાળુ એક જ છલાંગમાં કુદાવી ગયો હતો.  110 કિલોનાં પ્રતાપ, 208 કિલોનો તેમનો સામાન લઈને 22 ફૂટનું નાળુ કૂદવું કોઈ સામાન્ય બાબત નથી. પ્રતાપને સહી સલામત સ્થળે પહોંચાડી તો દીધા, પરંતુ ચેતક બચી ન શક્યો. તે ત્યાં જ મૃત્યુ પામ્યો. હલ્દી ઘાટીમાં આજે પણ ચેતકની સમાધિ બની છે. વર્ષ 1596 માં, શિકાર રમતી વખતે મહારાણા પ્રતાપને ઈજા થઈ હતી, જેમાંથી તે કદી સાજા થઈ શક્યા નહી. તેમનું ચાવડમાં 19 જાન્યુઆરી 1597 માં માત્ર 57 વર્ષની વયે અવસાન થયું. તે મહારાણા હતા, જેમના ડરથી અકબર તેની રાજધાની લાહોર લઈ ગયો અને મહારાણાના મૃત્યુ પછી તેણે ફરીથી આગ્રાને તેની રાજધાની બનાવી હતી. પોતાના જીવનમાંથી સ્વતંત્રતા શીખવનારા મહારાણા પ્રતાપ દરેક ભારતીય માટે અમર છે અને હંમેશા અમર રહેશે."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk ikan siakap tiga rasa? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan untuk ikan siakap tiga rasa:  1 ekor ikan siakap saiz sederhana, 2 sudu besar cili kisar, 4 biji cili padi, 2 sudu besar sos cili, 1 sudu besar sos tomato, 1 sudu besar sos tiram, 1 sudu kecil kicap manis, 1 sudu kecil cuka, Sedikit nanas, Daun sup / daun bawang, Garam dan gula secukup rasaBahan untuk sapuan: 1 sudu kecil serbuk kunyit, 1 sudu besar tepung jagung, 1 sudu kecil garamBahan kisar: 1 biji bawang besar, 3 biji bawang merah, 3 ulas bawang putih, 1 inci haliaCara penyediaan:1. Bersihkan dan kelar ikan siakap. Kemudian lumurkan ikan luar dan dalam dengan campuran bahan sapuan - serbuk kunyit, garam dan tepung jagung.2. Kisar bawang besar, bawang merah, bawang putih dan halia.3. Potong dadu nanas. Potong daun sup. Potong halus cili padi.Cara memasak:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali sehingga betul-betul panas.2. Goreng ikan siakap dalam minyak banyak (deep fry) sehingga garing. Angkat dan tuskan, kemudian dan letak di dalam pinggan hidangan.3. Di dalam kuali yang berasingan, tumis bahan-bahan yang telah dikisar sehingga naik bau.4. Kemudian masukkan cili kisar dan tumiskan sehingga pecah minyak.5. Masukkan semua sos, cili padi, cuka dan kiub nenas. Masukkan sedikit air jika kuah terlalu pekat. Kacau sehingga semuanya sebati.6. Perasakan dengan garam dan gula, kacau kemudian angkat.7. Bila nak makan, tuangkan kuah dan taburkan daun sup ke atas ikan."},{"question":"‘नेपाल पिक’ कुन जिल्लामा पर्छ?","answer":"नेपाल पिक ताप्लेजुङ जिल्लामा पर्छ।"},{"question":"Кыргыз Республикасынын биринчи премьер-министри ким болгон?","answer":"Кыргыз Республикасынын биринчи премьер-министри - Насирдин Исанов болгон."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा   चालत्या गाडीला खीळ","answer":"व्यवस्थीत चालणार्‍या कार्यात अडचण निर्माण होणे."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：在21世纪初，哪位英国首相领导了对伊拉克的军事行动？","answer":"答案：托尼·布莱尔是在21世纪初领导了对伊拉克的军事行动的英国首相。"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన వ్యాక్యంలో తప్పు ఉంటె సరిచేసి రాయండి:  కిరణజన్య సంయోగక్రియలో ఒక కార్బోహైడ్రేట్ అణువు ఏర్పడటంతో పాటుగా ఒక నీటి అణువు, ఒక అణువు కార్బన్ డై ఆక్సైడ్ కూడా ఉత్పన్నమవుతాయి.","answer":"కిరణజన్య సంయోగక్రియలో ఒక కార్బోహైడ్రేట్ అణువు ఏర్పడటంతో పాటుగా ఒక నీటి అణువు, ఒక అణువు ఆక్సిజన్ కూడా ఉత్పన్నమవుతాయి."},{"question":"Content: Ninu fidio kan to lu ori ayelujara pa lọsan ọjọ Ẹti ni Bobrisky ti kede bẹẹ fun araye nipa isẹ abẹ to fẹ ṣe naa amọ o ni aya oun n ja.Isẹ abẹ naa ti wọn n pe ni Brazilian butt lift, ni wọn ti maa bu ọra kuro ni awọn ẹya ara kan, bii itan, ikun, isalẹ ẹyin ati gegeru.Awọn ọra yii ni wọn yoo si ko lọ sinu idi lati jẹ ko tobi si, ti irisi rẹ yoo si tun yatọ lai jẹ pe wọn ri ounkohun sinu rẹ.  Ninu fidio naa ni Bobrisky ti n sọ fun awọn ololufẹ rẹ pe aya n ja, ẹru si n ba oun nipa isẹ naa to ku ọjọ mẹta pere.\\"Ẹru n ba mi pupọ nipa isẹ abẹ to ku dẹdẹ ki n se naa nitori irora ti maa jẹ fun ọsẹ melo kan, irora yii le to bẹẹ gẹẹ, ti ko si se fi ẹnu sọ.Maa ni irora nibi ọmu ati ni gbogbo ara kaakiri amọ mo ti setan lati tẹsiwaju pẹlu isẹ abẹ naa. Maa se e nitori mo ti san gbogbo owo to yẹ fun isẹ abẹ naa.Àwọn iròyin tì ẹ leè ní ìfẹ̀ síí:Mo gbọdọ se ni, maa wọ inu yara isẹ abẹ lọ, ki n si jade pẹlu ara to rẹwa, ọjọ Kọkanlelọgbọn osu Kẹjọ ni ọjọ ibi mi, irisi mi gbọdọ le koko ni.\\"Bobrisky tẹ siwaju pe, lati ọdun diẹ sẹyin ni oun ti n ro lati se isẹ abẹ naa, ti oun si se asaro pupọ lori rẹ, ki oun to pinnu pe oun yoo se isẹ abẹ yii.King Sunny Ade's son: Ohùn orin bàbá mi nìkan kọ ni l’Ọlọrun fún mi, ijó bíi kòkòrò ni ṣááO ni oun ni owo to towo lati sisẹ abẹ naa, amọ ni kete ti wọn ba ti sisẹ abẹ si igegeru oun, ko le pada si bo se wa tẹlẹ mọ laelae.O ni idi ree ti oun se n ronu lẹẹmeji nipa isẹ abẹ ọhun amọ lọwọ lọwọ bayii, ko si iyemeji mọ, oun ti pinnu lati se isẹ abẹ naa lọjọ mẹrin oni.nThe previous content can be summarized as follows:","answer":"Gbajúgbajà ọkùnrin to maa n múra bí abo, Idris Okunneye, ti ọ̀pọ̀ èyàn mọ si Bobrisky ti n kọminú lórí isẹ́ abẹ to fẹ́ se láti mú ki ìdí rẹ tobi, ko si dúró re nilẹ."},{"question":"Bathi ukuthula uBheki esadla amathambo ekhanda.'Ake ngihambe ngihogela le ndaba nami mama. Uma ngephuza ukubuya uvalemama.''Uyiphathe ngesinono le ndaba Bheki. Uma izigebengu zingathola ukuthi uyaseshazingakwenzakalisa mntanami.'Avalelise uBheki. Aqonde kuTholakele. Sekumnyama impela. Acabange ukuthiuyobe ufile uma efice umlungu kaTholi. Ahambe asheshe. Sekuvaliwe emnyangokaTholakele. Angqongqoze. Avule uTholi. Angene uBheki.'Bengithi usungilahlile mntakwethu,' kusho uTholakele. Asho maqede agaxe uBhekiamphose endlini. Babambane bemile bangane isikhathi eside'Yini le ekade isha lapha endlini?''Kusho ukuthi kukulezi zindlu engakhelene nazo.'Aqalaze indlu yonke uBheki. Abone amakopi otshwala engasenalutho.'Ubani obephuza lapha?''Abanye nje abangani bami. Uzohamba noma uyalala?''Angihambi Tholakele.''Kwangcono. Ngingakwenzela ukudla?''Kungcono into ephuzwayo.' Nempela asukume uTholi enze isiphuzo.1. Yikuphi okufakazela ukuthi umama kaBhekani wayengumuntu onothandolwengane yakhe?","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo:• Wayengathandi ukuthi ingane yakhe ibe sehlazweni lokuthandananomfelokazi osazilile.• Wayefuna ukuthi ingane yakhe ishade nomuntu ofundile futhi osezingenilayo.• Wayemxwayisa ngengozi engamvelela uma engalandeli imiyalelo kababawakhe osewashona."},{"question":"በውሃ ላይ የሚሰራ ብስክሌት ያስተዋወቀው ማንታ 5 ኩባንያ የየት ሀገር ድርጅት ነው?","answer":"የኒውዝላንድ"},{"question":"යශෝදරාවත, තුන්සරණ කවිපොත, මහබිනික්මන් කවි යන කෘතීන් ලියැවී ඇති සාහිත්‍ය යුගය කුමක්ද?","answer":"මෙම කෘතීන් මහනුවර යුගයේ ලියැවී ඇත."},{"question":"自民党のリーダーは総裁、社民党のリーダーは党首といいますが、共産党のリーダーを何というでしょう？","answer":"委員長です。"},{"question":"ਔਰਤ ਆਪਣੀ ਅਲਮਾਰੀ ਦੇ ਕਮਰੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਭੱਜੀ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸਨੇ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਰੱਖਣ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡੀ ਸਾਰੀ ਅਲਮਾਰੀ ਲਈ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਫੋਲਡ ਕੀਤੇ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸਨੇ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਰੱਖਣ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡੀ ਸਾਰੀ ਅਲਮਾਰੀ ਲਈ।"},{"question":"Mercedes McCambridge","answer":"Mercedes McCambridge ni à bini ọjọ kẹfadinlógun óṣu March, ọdun 1916 ti ó si ku ni ọdun 2004 jẹ óṣèrè lóbinrin ti Radio, Stage, Film ati Television ilẹ America to gba Ebun Akademi bi Obinrin osere keji to dara ju lo.McCambridge ni a bini Jolliet, Illinois fun Marie ati John Patrick (Agbẹ). Awọn óbi óṣèrè lóbinrin naa jẹ ijọ catholic ati Iran Irish-American. Óṣèrè lobinrin naa bẹrẹ irin ajo iṣẹ rẹ gẹgẹ̀bi óṣèrè ti radio ati ṣiṣè èrè ni Broadway ni ọdun 1930s.McCambridge fẹ ọkọ rẹ akọkọ William Fifield ni ọdun 1939 ti wọn si bi ọmọ ọkunrin John Lawrence Fifield ni óṣu December, ọdun 1941. Tọkọ taya naa pinya ni ọdun 1946 leyin igbeyawó ọdun mèjè. Ni ọdun 1950, Óṣèrè lobinrin naa fẹ óṣèrè/producer/oludari Fletcher Markle. Tọkọ taya naa pinya ni ọdun 1962 lẹyin Igbeyawó ọdun mèjila. McCambridge ku ni óṣu March ni ọdun 2004 ni La Jolla, San Diego, California.Mercedes jade lati collegi ti Mundelein ni ilù Chicago.Latari ipa óṣèrè lóbinrin naa ni television ati aworan Motion ti Industry ni a fun ni irawọ mèji lori Hollywood Walk of Fame."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Футбол тарыхындагы эң ири эсеп - 149: 0 Тарыхтагы эң кыйратуучу эсеп менен аяктаган беттеш Мадагаскарда өттү.Мадагаскар футболдук чемпиону А.С.Адема өлкөнүн жогорку лигасынын беттешинде Олимпик Л'Эмирн стадионун жеңип алды.  Эсеп 149: 0.Ушундай кызыктай дүйнөлүк рекордду орнотууга жеңилгендер өздөрү жардам беришкен.  Олимпиадалык калыстын адилетсиз чечимине нааразы болуп, алар өз дарбазасына өздөрү топ киргизе башташкан.  Беттештин аягына чейин алар 149 упай топтой алышты. Муну менен алар тарыхта калышты."},{"question":"Title: ఆమె చిన్న పిల్ల కాదు.. అన్ని రోజులు వేధిస్తుంటే చూస్తూ ఎలా ఉంటారు? నన్ను కావాలనే ఇరికిస్తున్నారు : బిషప్ ఫ్రాంకోnGiven the above title of an imaginary article, imagine the article.n","answer":"నిరసనల్లో పాల్గొన్న నన్స్కానీ, బిషప్ ఫ్రాంకో ఈ ఆరోపణలను ఖండిస్తున్నారు. ‘అవి ఒట్టి అబద్దాలు, కట్టు కథలు. ఫిర్యాదు చేసిన మహిళ చిన్న పిల్ల కాదు. అన్ని రోజులు పాటు వేధిస్తుంటే ఆమె చూస్తూ ఎలా ఉంటారు?’ అని బీబీసీతో మాట్లాడుతూ ఆయన చెప్పారు. పంజాబ్‌లోని జలంధర్ డైసిస్‌కు ఆయన బిషప్‌గా ఉన్నారు. చర్చిల్లో బిషప్‌ది చాలా ఉన్నత స్థానం. దేశంలో మొత్తం 144 డైసిస్‌లకు గాను 145 మంది బిషప్‌లు ఉన్నారు. ఆ నన్‌పైన ఉన్న వేరే ఫిర్యాదుపై తాను విచారణ చేస్తున్నందుకే తనను లక్ష్యంగా చేసుకున్నారని బిషప్ ఫ్రాంకో పేర్కొన్నారు. మరోపక్క ఈ కేసు విషయంలో పోలీసులు స్పందించట్లేదని ఆరోపిస్తూ కేరళలో కొందరు నన్స్ నిరసన కార్యక్రమాలు నిర్వహిస్తున్నారు. వారికి క్యాథలిక్ లాటిన్ చర్చితో పాటు స్థానికులు కూడా మద్దతు తెలుపుతున్నారు. కానీ, జలంధర్‌కు చెందిన ‘మిషనరీస్ ఆఫ్ జీసస్’ ఆ నన్స్‌ను నిరసనల్లో పాల్గొనద్దని కోరింది. పోలీసులకు ఫిర్యాదు చేయడానికి ముందు బిషప్ ఫ్రాంకో తనను రేప్ చేశారని ఆరోపిస్తూ ఆ నన్ చర్చి అధికారులకు ఫిర్యాదు చేశారు. కానీ ఎవరూ తనను పట్టించుకోలేదని ఆమె చెప్పారు.బహిరంగంగా నిరసనలు ప్రారంభించడానికి ముందు ఆమె ఈ ఏడాది జనవరి, జూన్, సెప్టెంబర్ నెలల్లో దిల్లీలోని పోప్ ప్రతినిధులకు లేఖ రాసినట్లు వివరించారు. పోలీసులు ఎలాంటి చర్యలు తీసుకోకపోవడాన్ని ప్రశ్నిస్తూ జార్జ్ జోసెఫ్ అనే వ్యక్తి కేరళ హైకోర్టులో పిటిషన్ వేశారు. ‘బిషప్‌ను వెంటనే అరెస్టు చేయాలి. హైకోర్టు పర్యవేక్షణలో విచారణ జరగాలి. ఆ బిషప్ దేశం వదిలి వెళ్లకుండా చూడాలి’ అని ఆయన  పిటిషన్‌లో పేర్కొన్నారు. తాము నిందితుడి విషయంలో ఆధారాలు సేకరించామని, కానీ ఈ కేసులో ఆచితూచి అడుగేయమని కోర్టు తమకు సూచించిందని పోలీసులు కేరళ హైకోర్టుకు తెలిపారు. మరోపక్క బిషప్ మాట్లాడుతూ... ‘ఆ నన్‌‌కు మరో వ్యక్తితో సంబంధాలున్నట్లు ఆరోపణలు వచ్చాయి. దానిపైన నేను విచారణ జరుపుతున్నా. తన కేసు నుంచి దృష్టి మరల్చేందుకే ఆమె అర్థం లేని ఆరోపణలు చేస్తున్నారు’ అని అన్నారు. ఈ వ్యాఖ్యలకు స్పందిస్తూ... ‘బాధితురాలిపై చేస్తున్న అసత్య ఆరోపణలు ఇవి. ఒకవేళ తన కుటుంబ జీవితం బాలేకపోతే, ఆమె ఇంకా ఎందుకు కుటుంబంతోనే ఉంటుంది?’ అని కేరళలో నిరసనలకు నాయకత్వం వహిస్తున్న అనుపమ చెప్పారు‘నిందితుడిని పోలీసులు అరెస్టు చేయక తప్పదు. హైకోర్టుకు సమర్పించిన అఫిడవిట్‌లో కూడా బిషప్‌కు వ్యతిరేకంగా ఆధారాలు దొరికాయని పోలీసులు పేర్కొన్నారు’ "},{"question":"پوښتنه څه ده: \\"فیلان د سویلي افریقا په دښته کې او په سویلي او سویل ختیځ آسیا کې خپریږي؟\\"؟ موضوع یو فیل دی.","answer":"\\"هلته چې فیلونه ژوند کوي؟\\""},{"question":"Tambaya: Mi ake nufi da \\"banana\\" da Hausa?","answer":" Amsa: tana nufin \\"aiba\\"\\t\\t\\t\\t\\t"},{"question":"మతరాజ్యం అంటే ఏమిటి ? ","answer":"మతరాజ్యం అంటే రాజ్యానికి ఒక అధికార మతం ఉంటుంది. సాధారణంగా అధికార మతం ఉన్న మతరాజ్యాలలో ఇతర మతాల నిషేధం ఉంటుంది. లేదా ఇతర మతాల కార్యకలాపాలపై చాలా నియంత్రణ ఉంటుంది. మత రాజ్యాలలో దేశంలోని అన్ని కీలక పదవులకు అధికార మతస్థులనే నియమించడం గానీ లేదా ఎన్నుకోవడానికి గాని అర్హత కలిగి ఉంటారు. రాజ్యం మత కార్యకలాపాలలో అధికారికంగా పాల్గొంటుంది. మత | వ్యాప్తికి, పునరుద్ధరణకు, ప్రార్థనాలయాల నిర్మాణానికి రాజ్యం నిధులు సమకూరుస్తుంది. మతసహనం, సహజీవనం ఈ రాజ్యాలలో చాలా తక్కువగా ఉంటుంది. రాజ్యకార్యకలాపాలలో మతపెద్దల, మతాచారాలకు అగ్రతాంబూలం ఉంటుంది. మతపరమైన న్యాయం, చట్టాలలో, ప్రజల జీవనవిధానంలో ప్రముఖంగా కన్పిస్తుంది. ప్రజల జీవన విధానం, వేషధారణ, ఆహారపు అలవాట్లలో కూడా మత ప్రాధాన్యత ఈ రాజ్యాలలో స్పష్టంగా కనిపిస్తుంది."},{"question":"ماهو اليوم الذي يتبع يوم الأحد؟","answer":" يوم الآثنين يلي يوم الأحد."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity : \\" Ny lesoka lesona, _\\"","answer":"\\" Ny lesoka lesona, fa sao ianao miesona.\\" "},{"question":"इ.स. 8 व्या शतकात जगप्रसिध्द विक्रमशिला विद्यापीठाची स्थापना कोणी  केली ?","answer":"राजा धर्मपालने"},{"question":"مراحل تولید فرش دستباف ایرانی از ابتدا تا پایان چیست؟","answer":"ابتدا هنرمند طراح نقشه فرش را می‌کشد. سپس پشم با توجه به رنگ‌های آمده در نقشه رنگ می‌شود. دار قالیبافی تقریباً شبیه چنگ است، به جز آن که شکل V شکل چنگ را ندارد و چهارگوش است، همچنین از بالا تا پایین دار رشته‌های متعدد نخی کشیده می‌شود که به آنها تار می‌گویند. قالیباف پشم رنگی را مطابق نقشه دور این تارها گره می‌زند تا سطح نرم و رنگارنگ فرش به تدریج شکل بگیرد و بافته شود. قالیباف پس از آن که یک رج کامل را گره‌زنی کرد، رشته‌ نخ‌هایی از جنس پنبه یا پشم، به نام پود را روی رج بافته شده قرار می‌دهد و با شانه یا دفّه قالیبافی محکم روی پود می‌کوبد. سپس بافت رج جدید را شروع می‌کند و این فرایند را آن‌قدر ادامه می‌دهد تا فرش کامل شود. فرش دستباف ایرانی از هزاران گره تشکیل می‌شود و بافت آن معمولاً به چندین ماه کار پرزحمت و دقیق نیاز دارد."},{"question":"එක්සත් රාජධානියේ මුදල් ඒකකය කුමක් ද?","answer":"ස්ටර්ලින් පවුම එක්සත් රාජධානියේ මුදල් ඒකකයයි. එය \\"£\\" ​හෝ \\"GBP\\" මගින් සංකේතවත් වේ."},{"question":"Em que clube o jogador de futebol Vini Jr. foi revelado?","answer":"O jogador Vini Jr. foi revelado no Flamengo."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：在1100-1200年间，中国是哪一个朝代？","answer":"答案：在1100-1200年间，中国的朝代是辽和金。"},{"question":"Калвендин отчету 1962-жылга чейин чыгарылганбы же 1980-жылга чейин чыгарылганбы?","answer":"1962-жылы студенттер президент Жорж Бидлдин кеңсесин басып алып, университеттин кампустан тышкаркы ижарага берүү саясатына нааразылык билдиришкен. 1967 - жылы университеттин комитети Калвендин отчету деп белгилүү болгон документти чыгарган. Университеттин \\"социалдык жана саясий иш-аракеттери\\" жөнүндөгү эки беттүү билдирүүсүндө: \\"Коомдогу миссиясын аткаруу үчүн университет изилдөө эркиндигинин өзгөчө чөйрөсүн сактап, саясий модалардан, кумарлардан жана кысымдардан көз карандысыз болушу керек\\" деп айтылган. Андан бери бул билдирүү университеттин 1980-жылдары Түштүк Африкадан жана 2000-жылдардын аягында Дарфурдан инвестиция алуудан баш тартышы сыяктуу чечимдерди негиздөө үчүн колдонулган."},{"question":"Laravel ကဘာလဲ","answer":"Laravel ဟာ php ecosystem ထဲမှာ အတော်လေး လူသိများတဲ့ framework တခုဖြစ်ပြီးတော့ Laravel သာ မရှိခဲ့ရင် php ကို ဒိုင်နိုဆောတွေနဲ့ တန်းတူ ပြတိုက်မှာပဲ ကြည့်လို့ရတော့မယ်လို့တောင် ဆိုကြပါတယ်။ Python ရဲ့ Django နဲ့ Ruby ရဲ့ ROR တို့လို battery-included framework တခုဖြစ်ပြီး Laravel မှာ တိကျတဲ့ file structure နဲ့ web application တခုရဲ့ အသုံးအများဆုံး feature တွေက အသင့်ပါဝင်ပြီးသား ဖြစ်တယ်။ opinionated framework တခုဖြစ်တဲ့ Laravel က Architecture မှာ ဘယ်လောက် အတိုင်းအတာထိ စွက်ဖက်ထားသလဲ နားလည်ဖို့ လုပ်ကြပါမယ်။"},{"question":"\\"Адам өзүнөн кийинкилерди...\\"  деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакап мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Адам өзүнөн кийинкилерди көрүп картаят.\\""},{"question":" ‘సభరనమయవ’ గణాలు ఏ పద్యానికి చెందినవి?A) ఉత్పలమాలB) మత్తేభముC) శార్దూలముD) చంపకమాల","answer":"B) మత్తేభము"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Aza atao toy ny fanjaibe hazo ny fitiavana, _\\"","answer":"\\"Aza atao toy ny fanjaibe hazo ny fitiavana, very tsy mampamoifo, hita tsy mahafaly\\""},{"question":"క్రింది ప్రశ్నకి ఒక్కమాటలో జవాబునివ్వండి.  హిమాద్రి శ్రేణి సరాసరి ఎత్తు ఎంత?","answer":"6100"},{"question":"Huraikan pendapat anda tentang kepentingan pengangkutan moden di negara kita. ","answer":"Mengurangkan kesesakan lalu lintasMenjimatkan masaMemberikan keselesaan kepadapenumpang"},{"question":"වස්තුවක ස්කන්ධය මනිනු ලබන ජාත්‍යන්තර ඒකකය කුමක්ද?","answer":"වස්තුවක ස්කන්ධය මනිනු ලබන ජාත්‍යන්තර ඒකකය කිලෝග්‍රෑම් (kg) වේ."},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. Robert jalan __ kerana takut ketinggalan komuter. Pilihan:  A) panjang-panjangB) rapat-rapatC) laju-lajuD) cergas-cergas","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C) laju-laju"},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકનુ એક લેખન નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે. આજ રીતની \\"માથાફોડ\\" પર આવુ જ બીજુ લેખન લખો.\\"ચંપા અને હીરા એકવાર શાક લેવાં ગયાં. હીરાએ એક શેર રીંગણાં લીધાં ને ચંપાએ પણ શેર લીધાં. ધેર આણીને રીંગણાં મુક્યાં ત્યાં તો હીરાનાં રીંગણા વધારે ​લાગ્યાં. બન્ને રીંગણા તોળી જોયાં તો ચંપાનાં એક શેર ને હીરાનાં સવાશેર ને નવટાંક ! હીરાની મા કહે: “એ તો હીરાને શાક લેતા સારું આવડે છે.” હીરા કહે: “તો આવડે ના ? કાછિયાનું ધ્યાન ન હતું એટલામાં મેં એક રીંગણું ઉપાડી લીધું “ ચંપા કહે: “એવું મફતનું રીંગણું શું કામ લઈએ ?” ચંપાની બા કહે: “આ મારી ચંપા, છે જરા યે હોશિયાર ?”⁠ચંપા હોશિયાર છે ખરી ?\\"","answer":"ચંપા અને એની બેનપણીઓ દર્શન કરવા ગઈ હતી. મંદીરમાં એક છોકરી રડતી હતી. એની બા દર્શન કરીને ઘેર ગયેલી ને પાછળ છોકરી રહી ગયેલી. ચંપા કહે: “ચાલોને આપણે એને ઘેર મૂકી આવીએ. “બીજી કહે: “ના, બાપુ, અમારાં માબાપ વઢે. “ચંપા મૂકવા ગઈ, છોકરીઓ ઘેર ગઈને ચંપાની બાને વાત કરી. અમથી ની ​બા ઊભાં હતાં: “જુઓ છોને ? આ ચંપા તો એવી ને એવી રહી ! અત્યારે મૂકવા ગયા વિના શું રહી જતું હતું ? લઈ જાત એની બા, એને ગરજ હોત તો.”⁠ચંપાની એવી ને એવી જ રહી છે કે ?"},{"question":"வணக்கம்... இந்த சொல்லைப் பயன்படுத்தி, ஏதாவது எழுதுக?","answer":"வணக்கம். நான் உங்களுக்கு எப்படி உதவி செய்ய வேண்டும்?                                                                                                    வணக்கம் ( (About this soundகேட்க)) என்பது தமிழ் கலாச்சாரத்தில் மரபாகும். இது வணங்குதல், தொழுதல், அன்பொழுகல், போற்றுதல், வாழ்த்துதல், வரவேற்றல், நன்றி உரைத்தல் போன்ற பல பொருள்களைக் கொண்டு காணப்படுகிறது.[1]இது இடத்துக்கு இடம், வணக்கம் பெறும் நபர் என்பதைப் பொறுத்து மாறுபட்டுக் காணப்படும். இறை வணக்கம் என்பது இறைவனை வழிபடுதலை அல்லது இறைவனை வணங்குதலைக் குறிக்கும்.[2]திருக்குறளில் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ள ஒரு வணக்கம்:கோளில் பொறியின் குணமிலவே எண்குணத்தான்தாளை வணங்காத் தலை. (திருக்குறள் 9)                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           "},{"question":"“不以规矩,不成方圆”这句话是什么意思呢？","answer":"\\"规\\"是指圆规，而\\"矩\\"是指曲尺。这句谚语比喻做事要遵循一定的法则。"},{"question":"Oṣere ilẹ wa, Racheal Oniga, wọ kaa ilẹ lọ tilu-tifọn","answer":"Pẹlu bawọn mọlẹbi ṣe lawọn o fẹ ero nibi isinku ẹni wọn, Oloogbe Racheal Oniga, sibẹ ọgọọrọ eeyan lo pesẹ sibi ayẹyẹ isinku ti wọn ṣe fobinrin naa lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii, nigba ti wọn gbe oku rẹ rele ikẹyin.Ṣaaju isinku naa ni eto ijọsin ati iwaasu ti kọkọ waye ile-ijọsin Catholic Church of Ressurrection, to wa l’Ekoo, nibẹ ni Rẹfurẹndi agba, Raphael Adebayọ ti sọrọ iwuri nipa ọkan lara awọn irawọ oṣere ilẹ wa to doloogbe lẹni ọdun mẹrinlelọgbọn yii.Ojiṣẹ Ọlọrun naa ni loootọ ni iku jẹ nnkan ibanujẹ nla, sibẹ o ni gbese nla kan ti gbogbo eeyan ni lati san ni, “Racheal Oniga ti san tirẹ, bo ṣe san an la fi n royin rẹ yii, gbogbo wa si gbọdọ ronu lori ohun tawọn eeyan yoo sọ nigba to ba kan kaluku wa”.Oniwaasu naa tun rọ awọn mọlẹbi ati ọmọ oloogbe lati ma ṣe bara jẹ pupọ, ki wọn ṣe ara wọn lọkan, ki wọn si maa ranti ipa rere ti oloogbe naa ni laye ati nigbesi aye wọn.Lẹyin iwaasu yii ni wọn gbe posi funfun to n dan bii digi, ninu eyi ti wọn ṣe oku Racheal Oniga lọjọ si. Itẹkuu to wa ni Omega Funeral Homes, lagbegbe Ojodu, l’Ekoo, ni wọn gbe oku naa lọ.Lẹyin iwaasu ṣoki leti saare, ti wọn si kọrin idagbere ni ilana ẹsin Katoliiki, wọn rọ posi naa sisalẹ, awọn ọmọ oku feeru fun eeru, wọn fi yeepẹ fun yeepẹ pẹlu omije, lawọn alaayan-oku ba rọ yeepẹ bo oloogbe naa mọlẹ.Ọpọ awọn oṣere tiata ni wọn pesẹ sibi eto isinku naa. Ṣe ṣaaju ọjọ yii lawọn oṣere tiata ẹlẹgbẹ rẹ ti peju sibi eto aisun to waye l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ni ile oloogbe ọhun to wa ni Magodo. Lara wọn ni Ọmọọba Jide Kosọkọ, Bọlaji Amuṣan (Mista Latin), Fẹmi Adebayọ, Iyabọ Ojo, Muyiwa Ademọla, Kunle Afọlayan, Desmond Elliot atawọn oṣere mi-in.Ọpọ awọn oṣere naa ni wọn sọrọ nipa Racheal Oniga bii eeyan atata, wọn lo kopa rere laye ati lawujọ, wọn si ṣadura fun un.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọgbọnjọ, oṣu keje, ni Abilekọ Racheal Oniga ku lojiji, l’Ekoo, lẹyin aisan ranpẹ kan. Ọpọ ọmọ ati ọmọọmọ lo gbẹyin rẹ."},{"question":"வினா : மருத்துவத்தின் தந்தை?","answer":"விடை : ஹிப்போகிறேட்டஸ்"},{"question":"参考下面的段落,然后以相同的语言回答后面的问题:  1955年4月2日举行的立法议会选举是一场激动人心和激烈的斗争,有几个新的政党加入了这场斗争. 投票者自动登记, 选举人数扩大到30万左右. 党在选举中惨败,仅获得四个席位. 新成立的左翼劳工阵线以10个席位获得最大的胜利,并与UMNO-MCA联盟组成联盟政府, 另一个新政党人民行动党 (PAP) 赢得了三席.  问题:1955年选民的数量有多大?","answer":"30万左右"},{"question":"फोटोमिटर","answer":"बज एलड्रिन"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Magaca Jaziirada Afrika Ugu Weyn?","answer":"Jawaab: Waa Jaziirada Loo-Yaqaano Madagaskar."},{"question":"¿Cuál es el tema principal de esta pregunta?: ¿Quién fue el presidente más pequeño?","answer":"El tema principal de la pregunta anterior es: Política. "},{"question":"É verdade que a operária de abelha africanizada morre depois de ferroar uma vítima?","answer":" É verdade que a operária de abelha africanizada morre depois de ferroar uma vítima. Isso ocorre porque o ferrão da abelha é em forma de serra, após penetrar na pele, fica preso. Quando a abelha voa tem seus órgãos abdominais danificados, pois parte do aparelho digestivo fica junto ao ferrão e ao saco de veneno, causando a sua morte na sequência. É uma pena que as abelhas não possam sobreviver após ferroar uma vítima, mas é importante lembrar que elas só atacam quando se sentem ameaçadas. Portanto, é melhor manter uma distância segura das abelhas e evitar perturbá-las."},{"question":"இந்தியாவில் எத்தனை மாநிலங்கள் உள்ளன?","answer":"இந்தியாவில் 28 மாநிலங்களும், தில்லி தேசிய தலைநகரப் பகுதி உள்ளிட்ட 8 நடுவண் அரசின் ஆட்சிப்பகுதிகளும் உள்ளன. அனைத்து மாநிலங்களிலும் மற்றும் ஒன்றியப் பகுதிகளில் பாண்டிச்சேரி, சம்மு காசுமீர், தில்லி தலைநகரப் பகுதி ஆகியவற்றிலும் மக்களால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படும் அரசுகள் உள்ளன. ஏனைய ஒன்றியப் பகுதிகள் இந்திய அரசால் நியமிக்கப்படும் ஆளுநர்களைக் கொண்ட, குடியரசுத் தலைவரின் நேரடி ஆட்சிக்கு உட்பட்ட பகுதிகளாகும். 1956 ஆம் ஆண்டில், மாநிலங்கள் மீளமைப்புச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் மொழிவாரி மாநிலங்கள் உருவாக்கப்பட்டன. அதன் பின்னர், வட இந்தியப் பகுதிகளில் சில புதிய மாநிலங்கள் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. மாநிலங்களும், ஒன்றியப் பகுதிகளும், மாவட்டங்கள் என்ற சிறிய நிருவாக அலகுகளாகப் பிரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன."},{"question":"ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාව(accessibility) යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාව යනු ආබාධ සහිත පුද්ගලයන්ට භාවිත කළ හැකි නිෂ්පාදන, උපාංග, සේවා  හෝ  පරිසරයන් සැලසුම් කිරීමයි. මෙයින් අදහස් කරන්නේ ආබාධ සහිත පුද්ගලයින්ට අන් සියල්ලන්ටම සමාන තොරතුරු සහ සම්පත් වෙත ප්‍රවේශ වීමට සහ භාවිතා  කිරීමට හැකි බව සහතික කිරීමයි.ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාවයේ ප්‍රධාන අංශ කිහිපයක් මෙන්න:1. භෞතික ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාව: මෙයට ගොඩනැගිලි, ප්‍රවාහනය සහ වෙනත් භෞතික අවකාශයන් ආබාධිත පුද්ගලයන්ට භාවිත කළ හැකි බවට පත් කිරීම ඇතුළත් වේ. එයට රෝද පුටු බෑවුම්, බ්‍රේල් සංඥා සහ ගොඩනැගිලිවල සෝපාන වැනි විශේෂාංග ඇතුළත් වේ.2. ඩිජිටල් ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාව: මෙමගින් වෙබ් අඩවි, මෘදුකාංග සහ ඩිජිටල් මෙවලම් පුළුල් පරාසයක හැකියාවන් ඇති පුද්ගලයන්ට භාවිත කළ හැකි බවට පත් කිරීම කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කරයි. දෘශ්‍යාබාධිත පරිශීලකයින් සඳහා තිර කියවනය, බිහිරි හෝ ශ්‍රවණාබාධ සහිත පරිශීලකයින් සඳහා සිරස්තල සහ විවිධ ශාරීරික ආබාධවලට ඉඩ සලසන අතුරු මුහුණත් මෙයට ඇතුළත් වේ.3. නිර්මාණයේ ඇතුළත් වීම: ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාව ඇතුළත් සැලසුම් මූලධර්ම අවධාරණය කරයි, එනම් නිෂ්පාදන සහ සේවා හැකිතාක් පිරිසකට භාවිත කළ හැකි වන පරිදි නිර්මාණය කර ඇති අතර, බොහෝ විට ආබාධ සහිත අයට පමණක් නොව සැමට ප්‍රතිලාභ සැලසේ.4. නීති අනුකූලතාව: බොහෝ රටවල පොදු අවකාශයන්, ඩිජිටල් සේවා සහ සේවා ස්ථානවල ප්‍රවේශය සහතික කිරීම සඳහා නීති සහ රෙගුලාසි ඇත. උදාහරණයක් ලෙස, එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ආබාධ සහිත ඇමරිකානුවන්ගේ පනත (ADA) විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍රවල ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාව නියම කරයි.5. සදාචාරාත්මක සහ සමාජ වගකීම: නෛතික අනුකූලතාවයෙන් ඔබ්බට, ප්‍රවේශ්‍යතාව ඔවුන්ගේ ශාරීරික හෝ සංජානන හැකියාවන් නොසලකා සියලු පුද්ගලයන්ට සමාන අවස්ථා සහ සහභාගීත්වය සහතික කිරීම සඳහා සදාචාරාත්මක සහ සමාජ වගකීමක් ලෙස සලකනු ලැබේ."},{"question":"6. Quais são os ritos processuais aplicáveis ao processo trabalhista contencioso?","answer":"Os ritos processuais aplicáveis são o rito ordinário e o rito sumaríssimo, dependendo do valor da causa e da natureza das partes envolvidas."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦\\"ታላቁ\\" እና \\"የሕዝብ ሻምፒዮን\\" በመባል የሚታወቀው የትኛው ቦክሰኛ ነው? መልስ፦ ","answer":"ሙሀመድ አሊ"},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে নিচের অনুচ্ছেদটি পড়ুন এবং পরবর্তী প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিন |অনুচ্ছেদ :(রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুর (৭ই মে, ১৮৬১ - ৭ই আগস্ট, ১৯৪১)[1] (২৫শে বৈশাখ, ১২৬৮ - ২২শে শ্রাবণ, ১৩৪৮ বঙ্গাব্দ)[1] ছিলেন অগ্রণী বাঙালি কবি, ঔপন্যাসিক, সংগীতস্রষ্টা, নাট্যকার, চিত্রকর, ছোটগল্পকার, প্রাবন্ধিক, অভিনেতা, কণ্ঠশিল্পী ও দার্শনিক।[2] তাঁকে বাংলা ভাষার সর্বশ্রেষ্ঠ সাহিত্যিক মনে করা হয়।[3] রবীন্দ্রনাথকে গুরুদেব, কবিগুরু ও বিশ্বকবি অভিধায় ভূষিত করা হয়।[4] রবীন্দ্রনাথের ৫২টি কাব্যগ্রন্থ,[5] ৩৮টি নাটক,[6] ১৩টি উপন্যাস[7] ও ৩৬টি প্রবন্ধ ও অন্যান্য গদ্যসংকলন[8] তাঁর জীবদ্দশায় বা মৃত্যুর অব্যবহিত পরে প্রকাশিত হয়। তাঁর সর্বমোট ৯৫টি ছোটগল্প[9] ও ১৯১৫টি গান[10] যথাক্রমে গল্পগুচ্ছ ও গীতবিতান সংকলনের অন্তর্ভুক্ত হয়েছে। রবীন্দ্রনাথের যাবতীয় প্রকাশিত ও গ্রন্থাকারে অপ্রকাশিত রচনা ৩২ খণ্ডে রবীন্দ্র রচনাবলী নামে প্রকাশিত হয়েছে।[11] রবীন্দ্রনাথের যাবতীয় পত্রসাহিত্য উনিশ খণ্ডে চিঠিপত্র ও চারটি পৃথক গ্রন্থে প্রকাশিত।[12] এছাড়া তিনি প্রায় দুই হাজার ছবি এঁকেছিলেন।[13] রবীন্দ্রনাথের রচনা বিশ্বের বিভিন্ন ভাষায় অনূদিত হয়েছে। ১৯১৩ সালে গীতাঞ্জলি কাব্যগ্রন্থের ইংরেজি অনুবাদের জন্য তিনি সাহিত্যে নোবেল পুরস্কার লাভ করেন।প্রশ্ন :রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুর কত সালে নোবেল পুরস্কার পান ?","answer":"১৯১৩"},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ilay mpanamboatra fiara Japoney malaza izay iray amin'ireo mpanamboatra fiara lehibe indrindra eran-tany, fantatra amin'ny modely toa ny Camry sy Prius?a) Hondab) Nissanc) Subarud) Toyota","answer":"Valiny: d) Toyota - Toyota dia iray amin'ireo mpitarika manerantany amin'ny indostrian'ny fiara ary malaza amin'ny fahatokisana sy fanoloran-tena amin'ny fiara hybrid."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 日本のJAXAは7日の朝、ロケットの「H2A」を打ち上げました。H2Aは、月を調べる探査機「SLIM」を高さ約620kmまで運んで、軌道に入れました。宇宙を調べる人工衛星「XRISM」も軌道に入れて、打ち上げは成功しました。JAXAは今年3月、新しいロケット「H3」の打ち上げに失敗しました。このため、H2Aが成功するかどうか、多くの人が注目していました。H2Aが運んだSLIMは、3か月か4か月あとに月を回る軌道に入って、来年1月か2月ごろ月に下りることを計画しています。日本の探査機はまだ月に下りたことがありません。SLIMが調べるデータは、アメリカの「アルテミス計画」で人が月に行って調べることにも役に立てる予定です。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。- ロケット: 1）筒の中に入れた火薬などを爆発させ、後ろへふき出すガスの勢いの反動で、飛ぶ仕かけ。また、それを装置した飛行物体。- 打ち上げ: 1）（勢いよく）物を空中に上げる。2）波が物を陸に運び上げる。3）（仕事などを）すっかり終える。- 探査: 1）探して調べること。- 機: 1）仕かけ。仕組み。2）とき。きっかけ。3）心の動き。4）はたらき。5）だいじな点。6）飛行機。また、飛行機を数える言葉。- 約: 1）ちかう。取り決める。2）縮める。省く。簡単にする。3）おおよそ。ほぼ。だいたい。- 軌道: 1）電車や汽車の走る線路。レール。2）月や星などの天体が動く、決まった道筋。- 宇宙: 1）地球・太陽・星などのある、果てしなく広い空間のこと。地球は太陽を中心にして銀河系宇宙にあり、この銀河系宇宙のようなものがたくさん集まって宇宙を作っている。- 人工衛星: 1）ロケットで打ち上げ、地球の周りを回るようにした、人間の作った衛星。宇宙のようすや気象などを調べたり、通信や放送などの電波の中継に役立てたりする。- 成功: 1）ものごとが思いどおりにうまくいくこと。2）高い地位や財産を得ること。- 注目: 1）注意してよく見ること。- データ: 1）考えるもとになる材料や事実。2）コンピューターで使えるように、数字や記号に置きかえられた資料。"},{"question":"Макал","answer":"Ага — тууган кимде жок, сыйлашпаса жатча жок. "},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\" Aleo very tsikalakalam-_ toy izay very tsikalakalam-_\\".","answer":"Rehefa feno ny banga dia mahazo hoe: \\"Aleo very tsikalakalam-bola toy izay very tsikalakalam-pihavanana\\"."},{"question":" एक देशभक्त नेता की कहानी लिखें, जो अपने देश के लिए समर्पित था।","answer":"इस नेता ने न केवल देश की स्वतंत्रता के लिए संघर्ष किया, बल्कि वह आज भी लोगों को एक सशक्त और सशक्तिशाली देश बनाने के लिए प्रेरित करते हैं।"},{"question":"Who is an animal found only in Sri Lanka?","answer":"I understand the confusion caused by the phrasing in the question. If you're asking about an animal species that is found only in Sri Lanka, one example is the Purple-faced langur (*Semnopithecus vetulus*). This primate is endemic to Sri Lanka and is known for its distinctive facial features and coloration."},{"question":"Di mana terletaknya Kundasang? Apakah sumber pendapatan penduduk di Kundasang?","answer":"Kundasang, atau kadangkala dikenali sebagai Pekan Kundasang, merupakan sebuah pekan kecil yang paling hampir dengan Gunung Kinabalu dan berjiran dengan Pekan Nabalu. Ia terletak hanya 6 km dari Taman Negara Kinabalu. Cuaca yang segar serta pemandangan yang indah menjadi alasan utama ramai pelancong datang berkunjung ke Kundasang.Pertanian merupakan sumber pendapatan yang utama kepada penduduk di sini. Jadi tidak hairanlah Kundasang merupakan pusat membeli belah sayur-sayuran yang sangat terkenal di daerah ini. Manakala pelancongan juga menjadi sumber pendapatan kedua terpenting bagi penduduk di Kundasang."},{"question":"* ما إسم ذكر البط؟","answer":"علجوم"},{"question":"बायनरी स्टार सिस्टम्स काय आहेत?","answer":"बायनरी स्टार सिस्टीम ही तारकीय व्यवस्थेचा एक प्रकार आहे ज्यामध्ये दोन तारे गुरुत्वाकर्षणाने बांधलेले असतात आणि वस्तुमानाच्या सामान्य केंद्राभोवती फिरतात. दुस-या शब्दात सांगायचे तर, त्यामध्ये दोन तारे असतात जे एकमेकांच्या अगदी जवळ असतात आणि परस्पर गुरुत्वाकर्षणाच्या आकर्षणामुळे एकमेकांभोवती फिरतात. बायनरी तारा प्रणाली या विश्वामध्ये सामान्य आहेत आणि तारकीय उत्क्रांती, गतिशीलता आणि खगोल भौतिकशास्त्राच्या विविध पैलूंमध्ये मौल्यवान अंतर्दृष्टी प्रदान करतात.बायनरी स्टार सिस्टीम वैशिष्ट्यांची विस्तृत श्रेणी प्रदर्शित करू शकतात, यासह:1. कक्षीय कालावधी: दोन ताऱ्यांना त्यांच्या वस्तुमानाच्या सामान्य केंद्राभोवती एक पूर्ण कक्षा पूर्ण करण्यासाठी लागणारा वेळ काही तासांपासून ते हजारो वर्षांपर्यंत मोठ्या प्रमाणात बदलू शकतो.2. पृथक्करण: दोन ताऱ्यांमधील अंतर देखील लक्षणीयरीत्या बदलू शकते. काही बायनरी सिस्टीममध्ये तारे असतात जे एकमेकांच्या अगदी जवळ असतात (बायनरी जवळ असतात), तर इतरांमध्ये जास्त अंतर असलेले तारे असतात (विस्तृत बायनरी).3. वस्तुमान गुणोत्तर: बायनरी प्रणालीतील दोन ताऱ्यांचे वस्तुमान समान (समान-वस्तुमान बायनरी) किंवा लक्षणीय भिन्न (असमान-वस्तुमान बायनरी) असू शकतात.4. विक्षिप्तता: परिभ्रमण मार्गाचा आकार अधिक गोलाकार (कमी विक्षिप्तता) किंवा अधिक लंबवर्तुळाकार (उच्च विलक्षणता) असू शकतो.5. संवाद: बायनरी तारे एकमेकांशी विविध प्रकारे संवाद साधू शकतात, त्यांच्या उत्क्रांतीवर परिणाम करतात. उदाहरणार्थ, \\"मास ट्रान्सफर\\" म्हणून ओळखल्या जाणार्‍या तार्‍यांमध्ये सामग्रीचे हस्तांतरण केले जाऊ शकते.बायनरी स्टार सिस्टम्सचे त्यांच्या निरीक्षण करण्यायोग्य गुणधर्म आणि वर्तनांवर आधारित अनेक श्रेणींमध्ये वर्गीकरण केले जाते:1. व्हिज्युअल बायनरी: या बायनरी सिस्टीम आहेत ज्यामध्ये दुर्बिणीद्वारे वैयक्तिक ताऱ्यांचे निराकरण केले जाऊ शकते आणि स्वतंत्र वस्तू म्हणून त्यांचे निरीक्षण केले जाऊ शकते.2. स्पेक्ट्रोस्कोपिक बायनरीज: या प्रणालींमध्ये, तारे दृष्यदृष्ट्या निराकरण करण्यासाठी एकमेकांच्या खूप जवळ असतात, परंतु त्यांच्या वर्णक्रमीय रेषा त्यांच्या परिभ्रमण गतीमुळे पृथ्वीच्या दिशेने किंवा दूर जात असताना वेळोवेळी बदल दर्शवितात.3. एक्लिप्सिंग बायनरीज: या प्रणालींमध्ये एक तारा दुसऱ्याच्या समोरून गेल्याने ग्रहण होत असताना ब्राइटनेसमध्ये नियतकालिक बदल दिसून येतात. हे खगोलशास्त्रज्ञांना ताऱ्यांचे आकार आणि वस्तुमान निर्धारित करण्यास अनुमती देते.बायनरी स्टार सिस्टम तारकीय गुणधर्मांचे विविध पैलू जसे की वस्तुमान निर्धारण, तारकीय उत्क्रांती आणि भरती-ओहोटीचे परिणाम समजून घेण्यासाठी महत्त्वपूर्ण डेटा प्रदान करतात. त्यांच्याकडे व्यावहारिक अनुप्रयोग देखील आहेत, जसे की खगोलशास्त्रातील अंतर निर्देशक म्हणून काम करणे आणि गुरुत्वाकर्षण सिद्धांतांची चाचणी करणे. बायनरी स्टार सिस्टीमच्या अभ्यासाने आपल्या विश्वाबद्दल आणि वेगवेगळ्या संदर्भात ताऱ्यांचे वर्तन समजून घेण्यात खूप योगदान दिले आहे."},{"question":"لدينا السؤال التالي: كم يبلغ متوسط دقات قلب الإنسان في الدقيقة ؟ ، أجب عليه بطريقة مختصرة.","answer":"حسناً، متوسطة دقات قلب الإنسان حوالي 72 - 80 دقة في الدقيقة."},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ કહે છે: \\"આશ્રમવૃક્ષો પછી આ વનવૃક્ષો છે. મનુષ્યજીવન અને વનસ્પતિજીવન એકબીજાનાં કેવી રીતે સહાયક છે અને કુદરતનું ડહાપણ કેવું અદ્‌ભૂત છે એની ખબર કુદરતના અભ્યાસમાંથી પડે છે. વનવૃક્ષો માત્ર વૃક્ષોની યાદી નથી કે તેનાં વર્ણનો નથી. પક્ષીઓ પેઠે વૃક્ષો પણ અભ્યાસ કરવા યોગ્ય છે, અને એ રસિક અભ્યાસની દિશા ઉઘાડવા માટે આવાં પુસ્તકોની યોજના છે.\\"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાએ \\"બીલી\\" વિષે વર્ણન કરતા નીચે મુજબ ની વાતો કહી છે:\\"દેવોને જેમ જાતજાતનાં ફૂલોનો શોખ છે તેમ જ તેમને પાંદડાઓનો પણ શોખ છે. શંકરનું પ્રિય પાંદડું બીલીપત્ર છે.બ્રાહ્મણો બહુ ભાવથી ભોલાનાથ ઉપર બીલીનાં પાંદડાં ચઢાવે છે. બીલીના પત્રોનો અભિષેક થાય છે; એક મંત્ર બોલાય અને એક પાંદડું ચડાવાય. શંકરે તેને પોતાનું કર્યું તેથી બીલીનું ઝાડ પવિત્ર મનાય છે.બીલીનાં પાંદડાં અજાણપણે પણ શંકર ઉપર પડી જાય તોપણ જેનાથી તે પડે તેને અભિષેકનું પુણ્ય મળે છે. પુરાણમાં વ્યાધ અને હરણાંની કથામાં બીલીના અભિષેકનો મહિમા છે.મેં અને મારા મિત્રોએ શંકરબાપા ઉપર બીલીના પાંદડાં ઠીકઠીક ચડાવ્યાં છે. બીલીના પાંદડાં તીરખીએ ત્રણ ઝૂમખે થાય છે, અને તે ઉપરથી જ તે ઓળખાય છે. કોઈક જ વાર બીલીપત્ર પાંચ પાંદડે મળે છે, બે બાજુએ બે અને વચ્ચે એક. એનો મહિમા વળી વધારે છે.\\"તેમનું આગળ \\"બીલી\\" વિષે નું વર્ણન શું હશે?","answer":"આપણે કહી શકીએ કે બીલીના પાંદડાંની ગોઠવણ કલાયુક્ત છે.બીલીનું ઝાડ સાધારણ રીતે રાયણ જેવડું થાય છે. તેનો છાંયો શીળો અને ઘટ્ટ હોય છે. બીલીના વૃક્ષ નીચે બિરાજતા શંકરને બીલેશ્વર કહે છે.બીલીના ફળને બીલાં કહે છે. બીલાંથી છોકરાઓ રમે છે અને તેને પથરા ઉપર પછાડીને ફોડવામાં આનંદ લે છે. પાકેલા બીલાંનો સ્વાદ ગળચટ્ટો લાગે છે. ગામડાંના છોકરાઓ તે ખાય છે.બીલીનો ગર્ભ વૈદલોકો ઝાડા ઉપર ઔષધ તરીકે વાપરે છે.બીલી વિષે વધારે માહિતી લેખકને નથી; પણ જો વધારે મળશે તો બીજી આવૃત્તિમાં તે ખુશીથી લખશે."},{"question":"Manomeza ohatra amin'ny literatiora am-bava sy literatiora an-tsoratra.","answer":"Ireto misy ohatra amin'ireo karazana literatiora.- Literatiora am-bava : kabary, ankifidy, ankamantatra, angano, ohabolana, oha-pitenenana (...).- Literatiora an-tsoratra: tononkalo, sombin-tantara, tantara foronina, tantara tsangana (...)."},{"question":"Generate a headline for the following text: Intwazana yaseMdantsane iphumelele ukhuphiswano lweTruTalent Search lonyaka ka2021. Olu khuphiswano, oluqhutywa sisikhululo seSABC, iTruFM, likhangela italente kusasazo neyooDJ abakwaziyo ukuxuba iingoma ngobuchule. UHlumela Qabo ophumeleleyo, ebengenele kwicandelo lezosasazo. Iindaba zokuphumelela kwakhe zibhengezwe liBambela Manejala kwiTruFM, uMasi Mdingane, kwinkqubo iDrive 326 ebhexeshwa nguSlujah Bunu noBabalwa G. UQabo, uphumelela emva kweeveki eziliqela zokuvan’ amandla noompondo zihlanjiwe kwiqonga losasazo. Eli nenekazi lohlule uSima Fiyo ebelikhuphisana naye kwiTop 2. UFiyo, ebefudula engumsasazi we5FM emva kokungena apho ngokuphumelela ukhuphiswano lokukhangela umsasazi. UQabo kulindeleke asasaze inkqubo engachazwanga ukususela kunyakamali omtsha, oqala ngomhla wokuqala kuTshazimpuzi 2021. Eli gqiyazana khange likwazi ukuzibamba luvuyo ngethuba litsalelwa umnxeba emoyeni, lixelelwa iindaba ezimnandi. Ukanti ophumelele kwicandelo looDJ nguSinovuyo Chula owaziwa njengoMtizo Da DJ. Halala!!!","answer":"Sure, here's a headline for the given text - OwaseMdantsane ngumsasazi omtsha wetrufm."},{"question":"请解释“不以一眚掩大德”的意思。","answer":"\\"眚\\"的意思是过失,错误，而\\"掩\\"是指遮蔽,遮盖；\\"德\\"指的是德行。这句谚语形容不因为一个人有个别的错误而抹杀他的大功绩。"},{"question":"Mutsara 1: Makore maviri gare gare, Gulam Ali, saGavhuna weKashmir, akaisa kupandukira kwaHari Singh Nalwa, mukuru mukuru weKhakha. Mutsara 2: Makore maviri gare gare, saGavhuna weKashmir, Hari Singh Nalwa akaisa kupandukira kwomukuru weKhakha ainetsa zvikuru, Gulam Ali. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hongu kana kuti kwete?","answer":"Kwete"},{"question":"القصيدة: \\"تَذكر بِالحِما إِذ شامَ بَرقاً # زَمان اللَهو مُنتَسق النِظام\\"\\tالبحر: ","answer":"الوافر"},{"question":"ਨਕਸ਼ਬੰਦੀ ਲਹਿਰ ਦਾ ਨੇਤਾ ਕੌਣ ਸੀ ?","answer":"ਸ਼ੇਖ ਅਹਿਮਦ ਸਰਹੰਦੀ ।"},{"question":"Berikan resepi membuat Apam Balik Rangup dan langkah-langkap untuk menyediakannya.","answer":"Apam Balik Rangup ialah sejenis kuih tradisional yang popular di Malaysia dan mempunyai tekstur yang lebih nipis dan renyah berbanding dengan Apam Balik Tebal. Bahan-2 cawan tepung gandum-1 sudu besar susu pekat-1/4 cawan gula-1 sudu kecil yis-1/2 cawan air suam-2 sudu besar minyak masak-1 sudu kecik soda bikarbonat-Sedikit garam-1 biji telur saiz kecil-1 cawan susu segar (kalau takda boleh je letak air kosong)Bahan Topping :-Jagung-Kacang tanah disangai dan ditumbuk kasar-Gula-Sedikit marjerin utk disapu pada permukaan apam balik setelah masakCara-cara:1. Bahan bertanda gula, yis dan air suam di campur dalam satu cawan, tutup permukaan cawan dan biarkan 5 minit dah naik berbuih boleh dicampur dalam adunan tepung nanti.2. Pecahkan telur kacau dengan whisk hingga berbuih, campur semua bahan2 di atas, kacau hingga sebati, tuang campuran yis tadi dan sekali lagi kacau hingga sebati.3. Biarkan dalam 30 minit dan boleh dioles pada permukaan pan nonstick (tak perlu sapu minyak ya) dalam 1 senduk atau lebih sikit.4. Api dapur hanya guna api perlahan saja ye utk elakkan ia hangus, bila nampak dah separuh kering bolehla tabur gula, jagung dan kacang tanah. Dah masak lipat dua.5. Dah siap masak boleh sapu sikit marjerin pada kulit apam balik."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిఆర్గాన్ రెండు ఉపయోగాలు వ్రాయండి.","answer":"Ar ఉపయోగాలు :1. ఆర్గానన్ను ప్రధానంగా అధిక ఉష్ణోగ్రతా లోహ సంగ్రహణ ప్రక్రియలలో జడ రసాయనిక వాతావరణాన్ని కల్పించటానికి ఉపయోగిస్తారు.2. ఆర్గాన న్ను విద్యుత్ బలను నింపడానికి ఉపయోగిస్తారు."},{"question":"لدينا المقال التالي: اهتم باختيار جامعة معتمدة من قبل الرابطة القومية أو الدولية لجامعات علم النفس أو واحدة من الجامعات ذات التقييمات العليا على المستوى الأكاديمي. عادة ما يتطلب العمل كأخصائي نفسي مدرسي أن تُتم ثلاثة سنوات من الدراسات العليا بعد الحصول على البكالوريوس. بينما يعتمد احتياجك للحصول مستويات أعلى من الدراسة؛ الماجستير أو درجة تخصص تعليمي أو الدكتوراه في علم النفس المدرسي، على مستوى أهدافك المهنية المستقبلية.   درجة الدكتوراه تكون مطلوبة من أجل فتح عيادة خاصة وعادة ما تتضمن على 5-7 سنوات من الدراسات العليا والعمل بعد الجامعي وما يقارب 1500 ساعة من التدريب وإعداد الرسالة العلمية. العديد من الجامعات تجمع بين درجة الماجستير وشهادة التخصص التربوي. قم بزيارة المواقع الإلكترونية الخاصة بالمدارس التي ترغب في العمل بها. اطلع على السير الذاتية الخاصة بالأخصائيين النفسيين العاملين بها وحاول أن تتعرف على نوعية الدرجات العلمية التي حصلوا عليها بشكل أهلهم للانضمام إلى فريق عمل هذه المدرسة. اطلع على الإحصائيات الإلكترونية المتاحة حول بعض الجامعات المقترح إكمال دراستك العليا من خلالها. كم عدد الطلاب الخريجين الذين نجحوا في الحصول على وظائف في خلال سنتين أو أقل من التخرج؟ وما هي أماكن عملهم؟ بالنسبة لدرجة الماجستير أو التخصص التربوي؛ فالعام الأول سوف يتضمن مجموعة من البرامج الدراسية الأساسية، العام الثاني سوف يشتمل على دورات دراسية وعملية، العام الثالث سوف يكون عبارة عن فترة تدريب تحت الإشراف بدوام كامل لمدة 1200 ساعة بشرط أن تقوم بإتمام 600 ساعة منهم بداخل الجامعة.  إذا قررت أنك على الأغلب سوف تلتحق بالعمل في محافظة أو بلد أخرى، فحاول الاستفسار من منظمي برنامجك الدراسي عن فرص إتمام التدريب في ذلك المكان المستهدف أو خوض تجربة التدرب في أي مكان خارجي. بعد الحصول على الدرجة العلمية سوف تكون الخطوة التالية هي الإيفاء بشروط الالتحاق بالعمل في دولة أو مدينة معينة. يختلف هذا الأمر من بلد لأخرى. حاول البحث عبر الإنترنت لمعرفة الشروط والمتطلبات الأساسية للبلد التي ترغب بالعمل بها.  بعض الجهات المحلية المسؤولة عن التعيين تطلب حصولك على شهادة معتمدة ومقبولة من الجهات الحكومية، بينما تقوم مدن ودول أخرى بتنظيم اختبارات خاصة لمنحك ترخيص العمل. سوف تكون بحاجة للحصول على شهادة معتمدة من الرابطة القومية للأخصائيين النفسيين في حالة اشترطت المدرسة أو الجهة الرقابية المسؤولة عن التعيين هذا الأمر. غالبًا ما تحتاج من أجل الحصول على هذه الشهادة إلى النقاط التالية: إتمام فترة تدريب موثقة، الانتهاء من البرنامج المعتمد من قبل الرابطة، اجتياز اختبارات علم النفس المدرسي والقدرات التربوية والمهارات والمعرفة التعليمية.  يمكنك الاستعداد للحصول على هذه الشهادة عن طريق قراءة الدلائل التعليمية وشراء نماذج المحاكاة والتمرن والبحث عبر الإنترنت من أجل الاطلاع على خبرات الأفراد الذين سبق لهم اجتياز هذا النوع من الاختبارات.. قم بتلخيصة!","answer":"هذا تلخيص للمقال السابق: اختر الجامعة المناسبة لإتمام دراستك العليا. قم بإتمام الحصول على الدرجة العلمية. قم بتلبية شروط الحصول على ترخيص العمل الخاصة بالمدينة أو الدولة. احصل على شهادة معتمدة من النقابة أو الهيئة القومية الخاصة بالأخصائيين النفسيين في المدارس."},{"question":"ما اسم أم مصعب بن عمير ؟","answer":"خناس بنت مالك"},{"question":"Người vợ chính thức của thần biển cả Poseidon là ai?","answer":"Người vợ chính thức mà Poseidon yêu say đắm là nàng Amphitrite. Amphitrie vốn là một trong 12 con gái của Titan Oceanus và Thetis. Vốn xuất thân từ biển, Amphitrie có vẻ đẹp mặn mà, thanh thoát."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي نواقض الوضوء؟","answer":"الإجابة: الخارج من السبيلين ، زوال العقل، أكل لحم الإبل"},{"question":"Uma milha é igual a quantos metros?","answer":"Uma milha equivale a aproximadamente 1,609.34 metros. Para transformar milhas em metros basta multiplicar o valor em milhas por 1,609.34."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഭാഗം വായിച്ച് ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക. ഖണ്ഡിക: \\"പതിനെട്ടാം നൂറ്റാണ്ടിൽ, ജ്ഞാനോദയ യുഗം ബൗദ്ധിക ചിന്തയിൽ കാര്യമായ മാറ്റം വരുത്തി. ജ്ഞാനോദയ ചിന്തകർ യുക്തി, വ്യക്തിവാദം, പരമ്പരാഗത അധികാരത്തിന്റെ സന്ദേഹവാദം എന്നിവയെ പിന്തുണച്ചു. വോൾട്ടയർ, റൂസോ, ലോക്കെ തുടങ്ങിയ പ്രമുഖർ സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യത്തിനും സമത്വത്തിനും മതേതര സമൂഹത്തിനും വേണ്ടി വാദിച്ചു. കാലഹരണപ്പെട്ട വിശ്വാസങ്ങളെ വെല്ലുവിളിക്കാനും മനുഷ്യാവകാശങ്ങൾ പ്രോത്സാഹിപ്പിക്കാനും ലക്ഷ്യമിട്ട് ശാസ്ത്രം, വിദ്യാഭ്യാസം, സാമൂഹിക പരിഷ്കരണം എന്നിവയിലൂടെ അവർ പുരോഗതിയിൽ വിശ്വസിച്ചു.\\"ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: പതിനെട്ടാം നൂറ്റാണ്ടിലെ ജ്ഞാനോദയ കാലഘട്ടത്തെ കുറിച്ച് ഈ ഭാഗം ചർച്ച ചെയ്യുകയും അതിന്റെ പ്രധാന സവിശേഷതകൾ, സ്വാധീനമുള്ള വ്യക്തികൾ, ദാർശനിക തത്വങ്ങൾ എന്നിവ എടുത്തുകാണിക്കുകയും ചെയ്യുന്നു."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Caroline Flack. ","answer":"Ba láithreoir Sasanach í Caroline Flack (a rugadh ar 9 Samhain, 1979). Ba láithreoir Love Island agus iar-láithreoir The X Factor agus The Xtra Factor le Olly Murs í. Bhuaigh sí an dara sraith déag Strictly Come Dancing sa bhliain 2014. Fuair sí bás ar 15 Feabhra 2020."},{"question":"Ìpè pàjáwìrì sí BBC dóòlà ẹ̀mí obìnrin mẹ́fà tó há sínú ọkọ̀ yìnyín","answer":"Olupẹjọ ọmọ orilẹede Faranse fidi rẹ mulẹ pe awakọ akẹru naa ti kọkọ duro lọna nibi ti o ti pe ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa nigba lẹyin to gbọ ohun awọn eeyan.Olupẹjọ ni awakọ naa ko mọ bo ya oun ti ṣe ohun to lodi si ofin.Ileeṣẹ ti awakọ naa ba a ṣiṣẹ ti sọ fun wa pe awakọ naa ṣe iranwọ fawọn ọlọpaa pẹlu bi o ṣe dahun awọn ibeere wọn ti o si tun fi ohun silẹ.Wọn fi awakọ naa silẹ lai fi ẹsun kankan kan an, o si tẹsiwaju irinajo rẹ.Awọn obinrin mẹfa kan ti bọ lọwọ iku ojiji lẹyin ti ileeṣẹ iroyin BBC ṣagbateru bi awọn ọlọpaa ṣe ṣawari ọkọ onifiiriiji ti wọn wa ninu rẹ lorilẹ ede Faranse.Awọn obinrin naa ti mẹrin ninu wọn jẹ ọmọ orilẹ ede Vietnam ti awọn meji to ku Si wa lati Iraq lo ha sinu ẹrọ amunkan tutu to wa lẹyin ọkọ akẹru kan nibi ti wọn ko ti mi daadaa mọ.Ọkan lara wọn lo pe BBC lori ago lati inu ọkọ ọhun.Lẹyin naa ni BBC sọ fawọn ọlọpaa ti awọn ọlọpaa si ṣe awari ọkọ naa.Agbẹnusọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa orilẹede Faranse sọ fun BBC pe awọn ti fọrọ wa awakọ naa lẹnu wo.Ipe pajawiri\\"Ni ọsan Ọjọru ni atẹjiṣẹ kan wọle sori foonu mi eyi to sọ pe \\" awọn eeyan kan ti gbá ibo orilẹ ede Faranse kọja sí ilẹ Gẹẹsi pẹlú ọkọ amunkan tutu.Ko pẹ rẹ ni mo gba ipe kan eyi ti ẹni to pe n beere pe ṣe mo wa ni ilẹ Yuroopu?Ẹni to pe mi naa bẹbẹ lohun rara pe ki n ṣe iranwọ fun oun ni kiakia.Bayii ni mo rántí bi oru ṣe pa awọn ọmọ orilẹ ede Vietnam mọkandinlogoji ṣe ku sẹyin ọkọ tirela kan lọdun 2019 ni EssexAwọn eeyan kan lo fẹ fi wọn ṣe owo.Mi gbiyanju lati béèrè ibeere kan tabi méjì lọwọ ẹni to pe mi naa.Ohun ti mo ṣa gbọ ni pe awọn eeyan mẹfa kan há sinu fìrííjìì lẹyin ọkọ akẹru.Ko sí ẹni to mọ nọmba ọkọ naa, ibi to wa ati ibi to n lọ.Ọdọbínrin kan tẹ atẹjiṣẹ sí mi lati inu ọkọ naa to ko ọgẹdẹ.O ni irin nla ni wọn fi ti ilẹkùn ọkọ naa pa.Fidio awọn obinrin to ha sinu fìrííjìì ọkọ akẹruFidio kan ṣafihan inu ọkọ akẹru ti ẹru kun inu rẹ, ati aye diẹ tàwọn to wa ninu rẹ jokoo sí.Níbẹ ni ọkan lara wọn ti wukọ, o ni oun ko le mi daadaa mọ ni ede Oyinbo.Obìnrin naa sọ fun mi pe awọn ti lo bíi wakati mẹwaa lẹyin ọkọ naa, ati pe ẹru bẹrẹ sí ni ba awọn lẹyin ti wọn ri pe awakọ naa ti morile ọna ibo miiran.Lọgan ni kan sí awọn akẹgbẹ mi ni BBC ti wọn n gbe ni orilẹ ede Faranse ati akoroyin iwe iroyin Le Monde niluu London eleyii to sọ fun akẹgbẹ tiẹ naa niluu Paris eyi to mọ nipa wiwọle ati jijade awọn eeyan lati orilẹ ede kan sí omiiran.Bí a ṣe ṣ'awari ọkọ naaObìnrin to bá mi sọrọ lanfaani lati sọ fun pẹlu ẹrọ GPS to wa lori foonu rẹ ibi ti wọn wa gan an eleyii to jẹ ki n ri ọkọ naa loju popo E15 lẹba Dracé ni ariwa ilu Lyon.Bayii ni mo sọ fun akẹgbẹ mi lorilẹ ede Faranse pe ki a kan sí agọ olopaa to sun mọ ibi ti ọkọ naa wa.Ṣadeedee ni a o mọ ibi ti wọn wa mọṢadeedee ni n ko ri ọkọ naa mọ lori foonu miSugbọn obinrin yii sí n ti atẹjiṣẹ ranṣẹ sí mi.O sọ pe wọn ti pa ẹrọ amule tutu, eleyii to jẹ ko nira lati mi.Mo gbiyanju lati rọ wọn pe ki wọn sí máa rọju pe awọn ọlọpaa maa to de ibi ti wọn wa.Lẹyin ti a tí jọ sọrọ diẹ, mẹta ninu awọn obinrin naa kọ lati wa pẹlu rẹ, mi o mọ idi ti wọn fi ṣe bẹẹ.Amọ, wọn ya fọto nọmba ọkọ akẹru naa.Bayii ni mo tun ṣe bẹrẹ sí ni ri ibi ti ọkọ naa wa.Awọn ọlọpaa to wa ni ẹkun Rhone sọ fun wa pe awọn ti mọ ibi ti ọkọ naa wa, awọn si ti n fọrọ wa awakọ naa lẹnu wo.Awọn obinrin mẹrin orilẹ ede Vietnam to wa ninu ọkọ naa jẹwọ pe awọn eeyan kan ṣèlérí lati gbe awọn lọ sí ilẹ Gẹẹsi ni.Ọkan ti temi balẹ pe nkan kan kó le ṣe wọn.Lẹyin naa iwadii fihan pe lati orilẹ ede Lithuania ni ọkọ naa ti n bọ.Amọ, mi o le sọ pato ohun to sí n mu mi ranti iṣẹlẹ awọn eeyan mọkandinlogoji to ku sẹyin tirela nigba ti wọn n kọja ni ibode."},{"question":"Атомдун түзүлүшү","answer":"Атом протондор менен нейтрондорду камтыган ядродон турат, орбитальдардагы же энергетикалык деңгээлдердеги электрондор менен курчалган."},{"question":"Senaraikan jenis-jenis mi goreng. ","answer":"Terdapat beberapa jenis mi goreng, antaranya adalah seperti berikut:-1. Mi hailam2. Mi goreng mamak3. Mi goreng jawa4. Mi goreng basah"},{"question":"Вакциналар кантип иштейт?","answer":"Вакциналар иммундук системаны ооруну пайда кылбастан, иммундук жооп жаратууга стимулдайт, организмге келечектеги инфекциялар менен күрөшүүгө жардам берет."},{"question":"Before tomorrow 11:00 PMis there any grammar issues?","answer":"The phrase \\"Before tomorrow 11:00 PM\\" does not have any glaring grammar issues, but it can benefit from a slight adjustment for clarity and completeness:\\"Before tomorrow at 11:00 PM.\\"By adding \\"at\\" before 11:00 PM, it becomes a more grammatically complete and precise statement."},{"question":"قم بتلخيص المقال التالي: تكثف السلطات عمليات البحث عن المختفين وقالت المتحدثة باسم الخارجية التشيكية إن الرعايا الخمسة اختفوا في منطقة القاع بصحبة سائقهم اللبناني. وكان مصدر عسكري لبناني قد أعلن ان السلطات بدأت بحثا مكثفا عن 5 من رعايا جمهورية التشيك يعتقد أنهم تعرضوا للاختطاف في منطقة البقاع الغربي. واختفى الأشخاص الخمسة أثناء جولة لهم في المنطقة الجمعة دون أن يعثر لهم على أثر. وقال المصدر العسكري \\"نعتقد انهم تعرضوا للاختطاف حيث وجدنا متعلقاتهم ووثائق سفرهم جميعا في السيارة التى كانت تقلهم. مواضيع قد تهمك نهاية ويعتبر الاختطاف عملا غير شائع في لبنان منذ الحرب الاهلية التى استمرت بين عامي 1975 و 1990 حيث تعرض نحو 100 أجنبي أغلبهم من الرعايا الأمريكيين أو من أوروبا الغربية للاختطاف. ويعد الغرض الشائع لعمليات الاختطاف القليلة في لبنان مؤخرا هو الفدية. وخلال عام 2011 تعرض 7 أجانب من إستونيا للاختطاف في منطقة سهل البقاع في لبنان واطلق سراحهم بعد نحو 4 أشهر. وترددت انباء غير مؤكدة حينها أن الاجانب السبعة قد أطلق سراحهم بعدما تلقى خاطفوهم فدية لكنه أمر لم يتم تأكيده..","answer":"هذا تلخيص للمقال: أكدت الخارجية التشيكية اختفاء 5 من رعاياها في لبنان في منطقة القاع."},{"question":"1975 yılında 1 dolar kaç lira?","answer":"Ancak, 1970'li yılların sonundan itibaren Türk Lirası'nın dolar karşısındaki değer kaybı hızlandı. Merkez Bankası'nın döviz satış rakamlarına göre, 1975'de 15.30 lira olan dolar, 1976'da 16.83 liraya, 1977 yılında 19.64 liraya, 1978 yılında 25.50 liraya, 1979 yılında 35.70 liraya çıktı."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Kepentingan Sektor Pertanian kepada Negara dan Masyarakat.","answer":"Mendepani era modenisasi dan globalisasi telah membuatkan kita alpa dan leka mengejar kemajuan teknologi dan membina bandar serta pencakar langit yang tidak memberikan impak begitu signifikan kepada negara. Mungkin ada sebahagian individu yang melihat bahawa kemajuan adalah apabila kita mempunyai bandar yang tersergam indah dan masyarakat hidup dikelilingi gajet berteknologi tinggi. Sebaliknya, keseimbangan dalam pelbagai industri akan membuatkan negara kita maju dan dipandang tinggi oleh negara-negara lain. Misalnya di negara Jepun dan Korea Selatan, setiap industri seperti teknologi, pertanian, perindustrian dan pelancongan dibangunkan bersama-sama. Oleh itu, barisan pimpinan negara perlu mengubah dasar dan polisi negara supaya tidak kekal ditakuk lama. Salah satu sektor yang berpotensi besar dalam meningkatkan kemajuan dan ekonomi negara adalah sektor pertanian. Sektor yang sebelum ini dipandang enteng dan kurang diberi perhatian sebenarnya mempunyai kepentingan yang memberikan manfaat bukan sahaja kepada negara malah kepada masyarakat tempatan dan juga alam sekitar.Antara kepentingan untuk negara sektor ini adalah ia dapat membantu kita memanfaatkan sumber yang dimiliki oleh negara. Umum mengetahui bahawa Malaysia merupakan negara yang dikelilingi dan kaya dengan sumber alam seperti lautan, sungai, tanah tinggi dan juga iklim yang kondusif. Justeru itu, kita seharusnya menggunakan sumber tersebut dengan baik supaya memberikan manfaat kepada negara dan juga bangsa. Sebagai contoh, penerokaan tanah untuk penanaman kelapa sawit oleh Perdana Menteri Kedua Malaysia, Tun Abdul Razak berjaya memberikan hasil yang baik kepada negara dan juga masyarakat tempatan. Tetapi usaha tersebut haruslah diteruskan dengan tabdir urus yang cekap serta amanah. Apabila mendapat saingan daripada negara jiran seperti Indonesia, kita seharusnya meningkatkan kualiti dan menjadi pengeluar utama kelapa sawit dalam pasaran antarabangsa. Selain dapat memberikan hasil yang bernilai, pertanian juga dapat memelihara alam sekitar daripada menjadi mangsa pembangunan dan perindustrian. Secara tidak langsung, pemeliharaan sumber alam dan ekologi akan menjadi seimbang dan dapat berkekalan untuk generasi akan datang menerima manfaat daripadanya.Apabila sektor pertanian diperluaskan dan menjadi agenda utama kerajaan, ia dapat mewujudkan peluang pekerjaan kepada masyarakat tempatan terutamanya golongan luar bandar. Wawasan untuk merapatkan jurang pendapatan penduduk bandar dan luar bandar dapat direalisasikan dengan merencana program pertanian yang efisien. Dari segi infrasturktur dan bantuan, kita sudah pun mempunyai pelbagai jabatan dan agensi kerajaan yang bertanggungjawab membimbing para petani untuk menghasilkan produk pertanian yang berkualiti serta memberi pulangan yang berganda. Sekiranya setiap agensi kerajaan dan organisasi swasta yang terlibat dalam pertanian mempunyai sinergi dan iltizam yang sama pasti ramai petani-petani berjaya dapat dihasilkan. Malahan, terdapat bekas graduan jurutera yang beralih bidang kerjaya ke bidang pertanian dan berjaya. Beliau yang menjadi peserta di Taman Kekal Pengeluaran Makanan (TKPM) Peradong, Terengganu, berjaya memperoleh hasil tuaian Melon Manis Terengganu sehingga RM 30,000 semusim. Graduan tersebut yang meninggalkan bidang carigali minyak dan gas dan meraih pendapatan bulanan sebanyak RM8,000 sebulan dengan bertani menjadi bukti sektor ini mampu menghasilkan kerjaya yang baik. Persis kata Peribahasa, hujan emas di negeri orang, hujan batu di negeri sendiri, lebih baik negeri sendiri.Sebagai masyarakat berminda kelas pertama, sektor pertanian adalah penting bagi mewujudkan keberdikarian bekalan makanan negara. Maksud kepada keberdikarian bekalan makanan adalah negara menghasilkan dan membekalkan bekalan makanan tempatan secara domestik dan tidak bergantung kepada industri import. Menurut laporan buletin suku tahunan terkini (Suku Ketiga, 2019) oleh Bank Negara Malaysia, negara kekal sebagai pengimport makanan dengan sekurang-kurangnya seperempat daripada jumlah keseluruhan bekalan makanan iaitu 24 peratus diimport. Ini bermakna Malaysia masih lagi tidak mencapai tahap keberdikarian dalam bekalan makanan. Jika berlaku bencana atau pandemik seperti COVID-19 dan rantaian import eksport terpaks diputuskan maka kita tidak mampu untuk membekalkan makanan kepada rakyat kita sendiri. Justeru, agenda ini adalah penting bagi mengelakkan kita menghadapi kekurangan bekalan makanan pada masa kini dan akan datang. Pihak berkuasa perlu menyusun strategi dan bertindak sekarang dalam merencana kebergantungan bekalan makanan tempatan terhadap sektor pertanian domestik. Bak kata peribahasa sediakan payung sebelum hujan. Dengan matlamat yang jelas serta pelaksanaan tadbir urus yang cekap dan amanah, wawasan ini pasti dapat dihasilkan bagi manfaat bersama.Sekiranya kita berjaya membentuk bekalan makanan atau sumber pertanian yang cukup untuk permintaan domestik, kita pasti dapat mengeluarkan hasil untuk pasaran antarabangsa. Dengan meningkatkan sektor pertanian, negara dapat meningkatkan pendapatan eksport serta menyumbang kepada pendapatan negara. Perkara ini telah pun dibuktikan dengan pengkomersialan tanaman kelapa sawit dan getah di mana Malaysia menjadi antara pengeluar utama di dunia. Baru-baru ini tanaman buluh pula mendapat perhatian pemimpin negara kerana mampu memberikan hasil pulangan yang lumayan. Sebanarnya pelbagai lagi potensi yang dimiliki oleh negara dibawah sektor pertanian seperti ternakan ikan, ternakan poultri dan juga tanaman sayur-sayuran serta buah-buahan. Raja buah di hutan kita iaitu buah durian juga semakin mendapat permintaan tinggi untuk dieksport ke negara luar. Dengan sumber yang banyak dan disokong oleh infrastruktur yang baik seperti lapangan terbang serta pelabuhan, pengeksportan hasil pertanian pastinya dapat dipertingkatkan. Namun, usaha ini memerlukan perancangan yang teliti dan kesabaran dalam mengecapi kejayaan yang boleh dibanggakan. Kita perlu elak daripada bersikap seperti mendengar guruh di langit, air di tempayan dicurahkan. Izharnya, dengan hasil tani tempatan yang berkualiti, ia mampu dijual di peringkat antarabangsa dan meningkatkan kadar eksport negara.Konklusinya, pelbagai kepentingan sektor pertanian yang menyumbang kepada negara dan juga nusa bangsa. Masyarakat harus membuang stigma lama bahawa bertani hanya untuk orang kampung dan tidak mampu menjadi kerjaya yang stabil. Kita hanya memerlukan pentadbiran yang efisien dan proaktif yang mampu mengumpulkan tenaga kerja serta pakar untuk membentuk ekosistem pertanian domestik yang unggul. Senario ini persis dengan peribahasa Melayu, yakni hanya jauhari mengenal manikam. Teknokrat dan golongan professional seharusnya menjadi pemacu setiap industri dalam negara bukannya golongan eksekutif yang tidak serba tahu-menahu dan hanya mengejar kepentingan sendiri atau jangka masa pendek. Golongan professional dan teknokrat ini lebih layak kerana mereka mempunyai pengalaman dan pengetahuan yang mendalam. Malahan mereka telah mendedikasikan hidup mereka ke dalam bidang yang mereka ceburi. Di mana ada kemahuan, di situ pasti ada jalan. Semoga setiap golongan membuka mata dan menyedari potensi sektor pertanian dalam negara serta mengambil serius dalam menjaga kepentingan sektor tersebut untuk kemaslahatan bersama."},{"question":"Напиши продолжение:  После завершения Советско-финской войны","answer":"1941—1944 годов, согласно заключённому Московскому перемирию, было восстановлено действие Московского договора 1940 года: к СССР отошла прежняя территория Выборгской губернии, определённая Московским договором 1940 года. В середине лета 1944 года началась вторая эвакуация финнов из Каухаве. Судебный процесс по исключению Харлу из состава муниципалитетов Финляндии состоялся в Йювяскюля 11 декабря 1948 года в 17 часов."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bongkok kail nak mengena'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tipu muslihat itu ialah untuk mencari keuntungan bagi diri sendiri"},{"question":"Inona no fiantsoan'ny Ntaolo ny amin'ny 04 ora  maraina fahiny ?","answer":"Ny fiantsoan'ny Ntaolo ny amin'ny 04 ora  maraina  fahiny dia : \\"Mazava ratsy \\". "},{"question":"Inona ny foto-tsakafon'ny Malagasy ? ","answer":"Vary no foto-tsakafon'ny Malagasy . "},{"question":"வினா:உம், ஓ, ஏ, தான், மட்டும், ஆவது, கூட, ஆ, ஆம், ஆகிய இடைச்சொற்களைப் பயன்படுத்திச் சொற்றொடர்களை உருவாக்குக.","answer":"விடை :1. உம் – தலைவர்களும் போற்றும் தலைவர் காமராஜர்2. ஓ – அவனோ இவனோ இதைச் செய்தது3. ஏ – அவன் படித்தே முன்னேறினான்4. தான் – அவன் தான் பார்த்தான்5. மட்டும் – உங்களில் ஒருவர் மட்டும் முன்னால் வாருங்கள்6. ஆவது – என்றைக்காவது நூலகம் போயிருக்கிறாயா?7. கூட – ஒருவர் கூட சாட்சி சொல்லவில்லை8. ஆ – அவன் படித்தானா?9. ஆம் – தலைமை ஆசிரியர் உள்ளே வரலாம் என்றார்10. ஆகிய – தேனாகிய அமுது மொழி தமிழ்மனிதனை விலங்கிலிருந்து வேறுபடுத்துவது மொழி ஆகும். சொல் என்பது ஏதோனுமொன்றைச் சுருக்கமாய்க் குறிக்கும் அடிப்படை மொழிக்கூறு ஆகும்.பொருளை அறிந்து கொள்வதற்குக் கருவியாக இருக்கும் ஒலியே சொல் என்று பொதுவாகக் கூறலாம்.சொல்லானது பெயர்ச்சொல், வினைச்சொல், இடைச்சொல், உரிச்சொல் என்று நான்கு வகைப்படும். இதில் உரிச்சொல் என்றால் என்ன அதன் வகைகள் பற்றி இக்கட்டுரையில் காண்போம்.உரிச்சொல் என்பது, ஒன்றுக்கு ஒன்று உரிமை உடையதாகத் திகழும் சொல் ஆகும். பெயர்ச் சொல்லாகவோ, வினைச் சொல்லாகவோ, பெயருக்கு அடைமொழியாகவோ, வினைக்கு அடைமொழியாகவோ, பெயருக்கும் வினைக்கும் பொதுவானதாகவோ இருக்கும்.“உரி” என்னும் அடைமொழியை “சொல்” என்பதனோடு சேர்த்து “உரிச்சொல்” எனப்படுகின்றது. உரிச்சொல் தமிழில் உரிச்சொல்லானது முழுச்சொல்லாகவும், குறைச்சொல்லாகவும் வரும்.உரிச்சொல்லின் வகைகள்உரிச்சொல்லானது இரு வகைப்படும்.ஒரு பொருட்குறித்த பலசொல்பலபொருட்குறித்த ஒருசொல்ஒரு பொருட்குறித்த பலசொல் எடுத்துக்காட்டுஒரு பொருள் குறித்த பல சொல்லிற்கு உதாரணமாகசாலப்பேசினான்உறுபுகழ்தவஉயர்ந்தனநனிதின்றான்இதில் உள்ள சால, உறு, தவ, நனி போன்றவை மிகுதி என்னும் ஒரே பொருளைத் தருகின்றது.பலபொருட்குறித்த ஒருசொல் எடுத்துக்காட்டுபலபொருட்குறித்த ஒருசொல்லிற்கு உதாரணமாககடிமனை – காவல்கடிவாள் – கூர்மைகடிமிளகு – கரிப்புகடிமலர் – சிறப்புஇச்சொற்களில் வரும் கடி என்னும் உரிச்சொல் ஆனது பல பொருட்களை குறித்து நிற்கின்றன.அதாவது கடிமனை என்பது காவல் என்ற பொருளையும், கடிவாள் என்பது கூர்மை என்ற பொருளையும், கடிமிளகு என்பது கரிப்பு என்ற பொருளையும், கடிமலர் என்பது சிறப்பு என்ற பொருளையும் குறித்து நிற்கின்றது.உரிச்சொல்லின் மேலும் சில வகைகள்இசை குறித்த உரிச்சொற்கள் (உதாரணம் – கொழுமூதூர்)பண்பு குறித்த உரிச்சொற்கள் (உதாரணம் – கடிமாலை – மணம்மிக்க மாலை)குறிப்புணர்த்திய உரிச்சொற்கள் (உதாரணம் – நனி வருந்தினை – மிகவும் வருந்தி)உரிச்சொல் உணர்த்தும் பண்புகள்உரிச்சொல்லானது பொதுவாக குணப்பண்பு, தொழிற்பண்பு என இருவகைப் பண்புகளை உணர்த்துகின்றது.குணப்பண்பானது பொருளின் பண்புகளை உணர்த்தும்.உதாரணம் – மாதர் வாள் முகம். இங்கு மாதர் எனும் உரிச்சொல்லானது விருப்பு எனும் குணத்தை உணர்த்தி நிற்கின்றது.உடம்போடு கூடிய உயிர்களின் குணங்கள் 32 என்று கூறுகின்றார் நன்னூலார். அவையாவன,அறிவுஅருள்ஆசைஅச்சம்மானம்நிறைவுபொறை (பொறுமை)ஓர்ப்பு (தெளிவு)கடைப்பிடிமையல் (மயக்கம்)நினைவுவெறுப்புஉவப்பு (மகிழ்வு)இரக்கம்நாண்வெகுளி (கோபம்)துணிவுஅழுக்காறு (பொறாமை)அன்புஎளிமைஎய்த்தல் (சோர்வு)துன்பம்இன்பம்இளமைமூப்புஇகல் (பகை),வென்றி (வெற்றி)பொச்சாப்பு (பொல்லாங்கு)ஊக்கம்மறம்மதம் (வெறி)மறவி (மறதி)அஃறிணைப் பண்புகள்வடிவங்கள்வட்டம்இருகோணம்முக்கோணம்சதுரம் முதலிய பலவகைளும்நாற்றங்கள்நறுநாற்றம்துர்நாற்றம்வண்ணங்கள்வெண்மைசெம்மை (சிவப்பு)கருமைபொன்மை (மஞ்சள்)பசுமைசுவைகள்கைப்பு (கசப்பு)புளிப்புதுவர்ப்புஉவர்ப்புகார்ப்பு (காரம்)இனிப்புதொடு உணர்வுகள்வெம்மை (வெப்பம்)தண்மை (குளிர்ச்சி)மென்மை, வன்மைநொய்மை (நைதல்)திண்மைஇழுமெனல் (வழவழப்பு)சருச்சரை (சொரசொரப்பு)இரண்டிற்கும் பொதுவான பண்புகள்தோன்றல்மறைதல்வளர்தல்சுருங்கல்நீங்கல்அடைதல்நடுங்கல்இசைத்தல்ஈதல்"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ਘਰੁ ੪ ॥ਏਕਾ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੇਤੇ ਹੈ ਜੀਅ ॥ਸੁਰਤਿ ਵਿਹੂਣਾ ਕੋਇ ਨ ਕੀਅ ॥ਜੇਹੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਤੇਹਾ ਤਿਨ ਰਾਹੁ ॥ਲੇਖਾ ਇਕੋ ਆਵਹੁ ਜਾਹੁ ॥੧॥ਕਾਹੇ ਜੀਅ ਕਰਹਿ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ॥ਲੇਵੈ ਦੇਵੈ ਢਿਲ ਨ ਪਾਈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤੇਰੇ ਜੀਅ ਜੀਆ ਕਾ ਤੋਹਿ ॥ਕਿਤ ਕਉ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਆਵਹਿ ਰੋਹਿ ॥ਜੇ ਤੂ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਆਵਹਿ ਰੋਹਿ ॥ਤੂ ਓਨਾ ਕਾ ਤੇਰੇ ਓਹਿ ॥੨॥ਅਸੀ ਬੋਲਵਿਗਾੜ ਵਿਗਾੜਹ ਬੋਲ ॥ਤੂ ਨਦਰੀ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਤੋਲਹਿ ਤੋਲ ॥ਜਹ ਕਰਣੀ ਤਹ ਪੂਰੀ ਮਤਿ ॥ਕਰਣੀ ਬਾਝਹੁ ਘਟੇ ਘਟਿ ॥੩॥ਪ੍ਰਣਵਤਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਗਿਆਨੀ ਕੈਸਾ ਹੋਇ ॥ਆਪੁ ਪਛਾਣੈ ਬੂਝੈ ਸੋਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦਿ ਕਰੇ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ਸੋ ਗਿਆਨੀ ਦਰਗਹ ਪਰਵਾਣੁ ॥੪॥੩੦॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 24 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਤਨੇ ਭੀ ਜੀਵ ਹਨ (ਇਹਨਾਂ ਸਭਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ੀ ਹੋਈ ਸੂਝ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ) ਕੋਈ ਭੀ ਐਸਾ ਜੀਵ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੂਝ ਤੋਂ ਵਿਰਵਾ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੋਵੇ ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਸੂਝ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਜੀਵਨ-ਰਸਤਾ ਉਹ ਫੜ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਉਸੇ ਮਿਲੀ ਸੂਝ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ) ਜੀਵ (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਆਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ (ਇੱਥੋਂ) ਚਲੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਹ ਮਰਯਾਦਾ ਤੋਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਹੈ ।੧। ਹੇ ਜੀਵ ! ਤੂੰ (ਆਪਣੀ ਚੰਗੀ ਸੂਝ-ਅਕਲ ਵਿਖਾਣ ਲਈ) ਕਿਉਂ ਚਲਾਕੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ? ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੂਝ) ਦੇਂਦਾ ਭੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਲੈ ਭੀ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਰਤਾ ਚਿਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਾਂਦਾ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। ਹੇ ਮਾਲਕ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰੇ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ, ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਖਸਮ ਹੈ। (ਜੇ ਜੀਵ ਤੈਥੋਂ ਮਿਲੀ ਸੂਝ-ਅਕਲ ਦਾ ਮਾਣ ਭੀ ਕਰਨ, ਤਾਂ ਭੀ) ਤੂੰ ਗੁੱਸੇ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦਾ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਆਖ਼ਰ ਇਹ ਜੀਵ ਸਾਰੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਹੀ ਹਨ) ਹੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਗੁੱਸੇ ਵਿਚ ਆਵੇਂ (ਤਾਂ ਕਿਸ ਉੱਤੇ ਆਵੇਂ ?) ਤੂੰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈਂ ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਹੀ ਬਣਾਏ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ ।੨। (ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਅਸੀ ਜੀਵ ਬੜਬੋਲੇ ਹਾਂ, ਅਸੀ (ਤੈਥੋਂ ਮਿਲੀ ਸੂਝ-ਅਕਲ ਉਤੇ ਮਾਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਵਾਰੀ) ਫਿੱਕੇ ਬੋਲ ਬੋਲ ਦੇਂਦੇ ਹਾਂਪਰ ਤੂੰ (ਸਾਡੇ ਕੁਬੋਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਖਦਾ ਹੈ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦੱਸੇ ਰਾਹ ਉੱਤੇ ਤੁਰ ਕੇ) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਉੱਚਾ ਆਚਰਨ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸੂਝ-ਅਕਲ ਭੀ ਗੰਭੀਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਉਹ ਬੜਬੋਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਦਾ) (ਉੱਚੇ) ਆਚਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਸੂਝ ਬੂਝ ਭੀ ਨੀਵੀਂ ਹੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।੩। ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—ਅਸਲ ਗਿਆਨਵਾਨ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਹ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਆਪਣੇ ਅਸਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਪਛਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ (ਅਕਲ-ਦਾਤਾ) ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈਜੋ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ (ਆਪਣੀ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਅਕਲ-ਦਾਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ) ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਜੇਹਾ ਗਿਆਨਵਾਨ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਕਬੂਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੩੦।\\""},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. Petani itu meletakkan __ di sawahnya untuk menakut-nakutkan burung. Pilihan:  A) bunga-bungaB) kayu-kayuC) orang-orangD) para-para","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C) orang-orang"},{"question":"Sheeg masaajidka ugu faca-weyn ee ku yaala degmada C/Casiis ee magalada Moqdisho sanadkii ladhisay?","answer":"Waxaa ladhisay 1070kii, Hadana Wuxuu Dhisan Yahay 939 Sano."},{"question":"電子計算機發明於哪一年？","answer":"1946年"},{"question":"නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය ජයග්‍රහණය කළ පළමු කාන්තාව කවුද?","answer":"මාරි කියුරි"},{"question":"Dídá àásó ewà sí wópò láàrin àwon","answer":"Òdókùnrin"},{"question":"Иерархия деген эмне ?","answer":"Иерархия - (гр. hieros ыйык, arche бийлик) 1) бүтүндүн бөлүктөрүнүн же элементтеринин жогортон төмөн карай удаалаштык тартипте жайгашуусу; 2) социалдык иерархия коомдун, бюрократиянын социалдык структурасы; 3) кызматтык иерархия кызматтык наамдардын, чиндердин баш ийүү тартиби боюнча төмөндөн жогору карай ырааттуу жайгашуусу; 4) чиркөө иерархиясы православие, католик чиркөөлөрүнүн дин кызматкерлерине баш ийүүсү менен мүнөздөлгөн уюмдашуу принциби; ишкананын ичинде чарбалык ишмердикти уюштуруу. Чарбалык бүтүмдү аткарууну фирманын ички башкаруу бөлүмү ишке ашыргандыктан, анын натыйжасында башкаруунун рыноктук түрү алмашылган учурда орун алат. Ошентип, экон. координациядагы рыноктук жана иерархиялык мамилелер бардык эле экономикалык системада бирин-бири толуктап турат, айырмасы чарбалык ишмердиктеги макулдашуунун биринде рыноктук, экинчисинде иерархиялык ыкма үстөмдүк кылат."},{"question":"Ducada xirashada dharka manoo sheegi kartaa.","answer":"Alxamdulillaahi lladii kasaanii haadaa, {al-thawba} wa rasaqaniihi min qayri xawlin minnii walaa quwwah.Mahad waxaa leh allihii ii xidhay maradan, iguna arsaaqay iyadoon jirin, xeelad iyo awood ka ahaatay dhankayga."},{"question":"ලෝකයේ වැඩිම දූපත් ප්‍රමාණයක් ඇති සාගරය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ලෝකයේ වැඩිම දූපත් ප්‍රමාණයක් ඇති සාගරය පැසිෆික් සාගරයයි."},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:وترى هونكه أن ثمة حاجات دينية ودنيوية دفعت المسلمين إلى اقتحام علم الفلك، وهضم كل المعارف الفلكية السابقة الواصلة إليهم من الهنود والفُرس والإغريق؛ \\"فلما كان العربي يسعى دوما إلى ربح مكسب مادي (= فائدة عملية) لتحقيقاته العلمية أولا بأول: كالقيام بالصلاة في","answer":"سماء المملكة العربية السعودية، وهي أمور تستدعي المعرفة بحركة الشمس والقمر والكواكب. وفي نفس الوقت، كانوا يسعون لتحقيق الربح المعنوي والديني من خلال فهم دقيق للأوقات الدينية مثل أوقات الصلاة وبداية شهور الهجري."},{"question":"Inona ny fomba atao hampirindra ny fianakaviana?","answer":"Mba hisian’ny fiainana milamina sy mirindra eo amin’ny fiainam-pianakaviana dia ilaina ny fisian’ny: fifankatiavana, fifanajana, fifandeferana, fifanampiana, fifampitsimbinana, fifampitokisana, …"},{"question":"Apakah maksud peribahasa 'harapkan guruh di langit, air di tempayan ditumpahkan'?","answer":"Ianya bermaksud terlalu mengharapkan keuntungan yang belum pasti, yang sudah ada ditangan disia-siakan, akhirnya yang manapun tidak dapat."},{"question":"Ọga ọlọpaa patapata ti gbẹsẹ le SARS jake-jado Naijiria, o ni eegun wọn ko gbọdọ ṣẹ mọ","answer":"Ọga ọlọpaa patapata nilẹ wa, Muhammed Adamu, ti gbẹsẹ le ẹka ileesẹ ọlọpaa ti wọn gbe kalẹ lati maa gbogun ti idigunjale ti wọn n pe ni SARS kaakiri gbogbo ipinlẹ to wa ni Naijiria. O ni eegun wọn ko gbọdọ ṣẹ mọ. Ninu atẹjade to fi sita llọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii lo ti kede ọrọ yii."},{"question":"Qual foi o primeiro país a permitir o voto feminino?","answer":"Em 1893, a Nova Zelândia se tornou o primeiro país a garantir o sufrágio feminino."},{"question":"Klimada uyku modu neye yarar?","answer":"SLEEP (Uyku) Modu:Klimanın bulunduğu odada yatanlar bu özellik sayesinde oda sıcaklığının artması ve hava akımının düzenlenmesiyle rahat bir uyku uyurlar. Uyku modu açık olan bir klima yaklaşık 6 saat sonra otomatik olarak kapanacaktır. Cihaz kapatıldıktan sonra uyku fonksiyonu iptal olur."},{"question":"Raha manampa-kevitra ny hilatsaka ho fidina ny filoham-pirenena dia tsy maintsy mametra-pialana 30 andro alohan'ny fifidianana izy, ka tsy maintsy misy filoha vonjimaika misolo azy, iza no afaka misolo azy arakan'ny lalàm-panorenana ?Valiny 1 : - Ny filohan'ny antenimieram-pirenenaValiny 2: - Ny filohan'ny antenimieran-doholonaValiny 3: - Ny praiminisitra ","answer":"Valiny 2 : -Ny filohan'ny antenimieran-doholona no mpisolo-toerana vonjimaika raha toa ka milatsaka ho fidina ny filoha"},{"question":"Dukkan Sahabbai sun kasance suna tambayar Manzon Allah Sallallahu Alaihi Wa Sallama akan alherai amma ban da ----- shi ya kasance yana tambayar sa ne game da sharri, yace yana yin irin wannan tambayar ne gudun kar ya afka cikin sharri","answer":" (a) Abdullahi dan Mas'ud (b) Huzaifa dan Yamani (c) Jabir dan Abdullahi"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday, iyo sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Halgame xalane magaciisa oo saddexan waa \\"Maxamed Cabdulle Xalane\\", waxa uu ku geeriyooday tog-wajaalle oo ku taalla xuduudka waqooyi-soomaaliya iyo itoobiya, waxaa uunna geeriyooday sannadka marka uu ahaa 1964."},{"question":"Fifa mú orílẹ̀èdè mẹ́jọ lorílẹ̀ mẹ́ta láti gbàlejò ìdíje àgbáyé ọdún 2030","answer":"Orilẹ agbaye mẹta ọtọọtọ ni idije ife ẹyẹ bọọlu lagbaye yoo ti waye lọdun 2030.Ajọ to n mojuto ọrọ bọọlu lagbaye iyẹn Fifa lo fidi ọrọ yi mulẹ pe orileede mẹfa ni yoo gbalejo idije yi.Spain Portugal ati Morocco ni wọn kede pe yoo jijọ gbalejo idije naa.Awọn ifẹsẹwọnsẹ mẹta akọkọ yoo waye ni Uruguay,Argentina ati Paraguay.Awọn idije mẹta yi la gbọ pe wọn fẹ fi ṣe ayajọ ọgọrun ọdun ti idije naa bẹrẹ ni Montevideo.Ipade igbimọ alaṣẹ Fifa yoo buwọlu ipinnu yi lọdun to n bọ.Bẹẹ naa ni Fifa fidi rẹ mulẹ pe awọn gba iwe mo ṣetan lati gbalejo idije naa lati ọdọ awọn ẹka igbimọ ere bọọlu Asia ati ipe awọn yoo ṣagbeyẹwọ Oceania fun gbigba alejo idije ọdun 2034.Lẹyin ikede yi ni Saudi naa kede pe awọn yoo fi orukọ silẹ lati du ipo gbigbalejo idije ọdun 2034 fun igba akọkọ.Ọjọ kọkanlelọgbọn ni gbedeke fifi erongba silẹ lati gbalejo idije yi yoo wa sopin.Awọn kan bẹnu atẹ lu ikede Fifa lati gbe igbalejo idije yi lọ si ọpọ orilẹ.Ọkan lara awọn ẹgbẹ alatilẹyin ere bọọlu sọ pe ''Fifa n gbe igbesẹ lati pa ere idaraya to lamilaaka julọ lagbaye run''Ẹgbẹ alatilẹyin Yuroopu sọ pe ''ohun ti ko bojumu ni fawọn alatilẹyin ere bọọlu ni bi Fifa ṣe fẹ faaye gba orilẹẹde ti ko lorukọ gidi nidi ifaaye gba ẹtọmọniyan ko loun fẹ gbalejo idije ọdun 2034.''Amọ Aarẹ Fifa Gianni Infantino sọ pe ''nile aye ti ipinya pọ yi, Fifa ati ere bọọlu lo n mu isọkan wa''O tẹsiwaju pe ''Igbimọ Fifa to n ṣoju ere bọọlu lagbaye panupọ lati ṣe ajọyọ ajọdun ọgọrun idije World Cup ti wọn gbalejo rẹ ni Uruguay lọdun 1930 lọna to bojumu julọ''''Ni 2030 ọna mẹta ni ao ti ri ipasẹ idije yi-Afrika,Yuroopu ati South Amẹrika-orileede mẹfa Argentina,Morocco,Paraguay,Portugal,Spain ati Uruguay ni yoo gbalejo agbaye lati se ayẹyẹ ọgọrun ọdun idije World Cup lọna ara to yatọ''Montevideo ni Uruguay to jẹ ibi ti idije akọkọ ti waye yoo gbalejo ifẹsẹwọnsẹ iṣide naa ni ọdun 2030 ti wọn yoo si gba awọn ifẹsẹwọnsẹ mii ni Argentina ati Paraguay.Eyi to ku ninu idije olorileede mejidinlaadọta yi yoo tẹsiwaju ni ariwa Africa ati Yuroopu.Iyipada orilẹ yi tunmọ si pe ikọ to n kopa le kopa ni ayika meji ọtọọtọ ninu idije kan ṣoṣo.Ninu aba ọdun 2030 yi, Morocco yoo jẹ orileede keji ti yoo gbalejo idije yi fun igba akọkọ lati ilẹ Afrika lẹyin South Africa to gbalejo rẹ lọdun 2010.Wọn kede Spain naa pe wọn yoo jumọ gbalejo idije naa.Ikede yi waye lẹyin ọsẹ meloo kan ti adari ere bọọlu Spain kọwe fipo silẹ lori ẹsun pe o fẹnuko obinrin agbabọọlu Jenni Hermoso lẹnu lasiko idije ere bọọlu agbaye awọn obinrin..Ọdun 1982 ni wọn gbalejo idije yi kẹyin ti Italy ṣi pegede ninu idije ọhun pẹlu bi wọn ṣe gbe ife ẹyẹ agbaye ni igba ẹkẹẹta.Gbogbo awọn to n gbalejo idije yi ni yoo lanfaani lati kopa iyẹn Uruguay, Argentina, Paraguay, Spain, Portugal ati Morocco.Ọrọ ifarajin Fifa lori ọrọ iyipada oju ọjọ naa tun jẹyọ pẹlu ikede yiIpinnu Fifa lati gbalejo idije lọpọ orilẹ n waye lẹyin ti wọn ko sọ ootọ nipa mimu adinku ba ipa ti idije agbaye yoo ni lori ayika wa ni paapa idije Qatar.Fifa sọ nigba naa pe idije yi yoo yatọ nipa mimu adinku ba iye afẹfẹ gaasi to le ṣe ipalara fun ayika amọ wọn o fi ẹri kankan pẹlu ọrọ wọn.Losu Kọkanla ọdun ni BBC gbe iroyin tawọn onimọ nipa ayika ti sọ pe ọrọ to le si araalu lọna ni Fifa sọ ti wọn si kilo pe o ṣeeṣe ki ipalara ti idije yi mu ba ayika ṣẹlẹ ni ilọpo mẹta.Freddie Daley oniwadii ni Global Economy Policy ti Fasiti Sussex, sọ pe ipinnu lati gbalejo idije yi lorilẹ mẹta yoo ni ipalara tori awọn agbagbọọlu,alatilẹyin ati ololufẹ ere bọọlu yoo rinrinajo lorilẹ mẹta dipo ẹyọkan.O ni ''Mo gbagbọ pe igbesẹ Fifa fi han pe wọn ko jẹ olootọ nipa nkan ti wọn pinnu lati ṣe lori ọrọ iyipada oju ọjọ ati gbigbe igbesẹ lori rẹ.''O tẹsiwaju pe Fifa lojuṣe lati se idanilẹkọ fawọn eeyan ki wọn si ri pe wọn jẹ ki wọn kopa nibi irinajo idije yi pẹlu ipalara to kere julọ fayika wa.Saudi Arabia fẹ gbalejo idije ọdun 2034Ọrọ Saudi to fẹ gbalejo idije ọdun 2034 wa ni ibamu pẹlu ipinnu rẹ lati lewaju nibi ere idaraya lagbaye.Bi wọn ṣe n ṣagbatẹru idije ere bọọlu ni wọn n ṣe ti Formula 1,Golf ati ẹsẹ jija.Amọ awọn alatako sọ pe niṣe ni Saudi n fi owo rẹ ati ere idaraya ṣe afọmọ lati wa ojurere lagbaye.Ninu ifọrọwanilẹnuwo kan to waye laipẹ yi pẹlu ileeṣẹ iroyi Fox News, ọmọ ọba Saudi Mohammed bin Salman sọ pe ko si ohun to kan oun pẹlu gbogbo ẹsun wọnyi.O ni ti ''lilo ere idaraya lati ṣe afọmo yoo mu ki owo taa n pa wọle le kun si a o ni jawọ lati maa ṣe lilo ere idaraya lati ṣe afọmọ ara wa''Olori igbimọ to n risi ọrọ idije Olympic ati Olympic awọn to ni ipenija kan tabi omirna Ọmọ ọba Abdulaziz bin Turki bin Faisal sọ pe ''idije bọọlu agbaye jẹ afojusun pataki ninu irinajo Saudi gẹgẹ bi orileede to nifẹ si ere bọọlu.''Australia, tohun ti pe igbimọ ere bọọlu Asian Football Confederation (AFC) jẹjẹ atilẹyin fun Saudi sọ pe awọn naa yoo sagbeyẹwo bi awọn yoo ṣe gbalejo idije 2034."},{"question":"Kíni ìjì ní ède Gẹ̀ẹ́sì?","answer":"Wind."},{"question":"බ්‍රහස්පති ග්‍රහයාගේ ප්‍රමාණය පෘථිවිය හා සැසඳෙන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"බ්‍රහස්පති ග්‍රහලෝකය අනෙකුත් සියලුම ග්‍රහලෝක එකතු වී මෙන් දෙගුණයකටත් වඩා විශාල වන අතර පෘථිවියට වඩා සැලකිය යුතු තරම් විශාලය."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو اسم زوجة فرعون التي آمنت؟","answer":"الإجابة: آسيا"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Individuellt är den största meriten guldet på 400 meter från EM 1969. Han","answer":"hade även Europarekordet på 200 meter under några månader 1967."},{"question":"යුනෙස්කෝ  සංවිධානයේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය පිහිටා  ඇත්තේ කොහේද?","answer":"යුනෙස්කෝ  (UNESCO : United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ අධ්‍යාපනික, විද්‍යාත්මක සහ සංස්කෘතික සංවිධානය) මූලස්ථානය ප්‍රංශයේ පැරිස් නුවර පිහිටා  ඇත. මෙම ස්ථානය ලොව පුරා  අධ්‍යාපනය, විද්‍යාව, සංස්කෘතිය සහ සන්නිවේදනය ප්‍රවර්ධනය කිරීම ඇතුළත් යුනෙස්කෝ  ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සඳහා  කේන්ද්‍රීය කේන්ද්‍රස්ථානය ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරයි."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి భావం రాయండి:ఆ.వె. చదువు జీర్ణమైన స్వాంతంబు పండునుతిండి జీర్ణమైన నిండు బలముచెఱుపు గూర్చు రెండు జీర్ణముల్ గాకున్నవిశ్వహితచరిత్ర వినర మిత్ర","answer":"లోకక్షేమాన్ని కోరే మిత్రమా ! ఒక మాట విను. చదివిన చదువును జీర్ణించుకుంటే మనస్సు పరిపక్వమవుతుంది. తిన్న తిండి జీర్ణమైతే బలం కలుగుతుంది. ఆ రెండూ జీర్ణం కాకపోతే చెరుపు చేస్తాయి."},{"question":"Quem inventou o telefone?","answer":"O telefone foi inventado independentemente por Elisha Gray e Alexander Graham Bell."},{"question":"Mene ne amfanin Kartaji a Jima?","answer":"Shi ne abin da ake tuje gashi da kuma nama daga jikin fata."},{"question":"Tiirka koowaad ee arkaanul- iimaanka oo ah; \\"In Ilaahay la rumeeyo\\" iyo tiirka koowaad ee arkaanul-islaamka qaybtiisa hore oo ah \\"Laa Ilaaha illa laahu\\" maxay ku kala duwan yihiin?","answer":"\\"In Ilaahay la rumeeyo\\" iyo Laa ilaaha Illa laahu\\", way isa soo dhex gelayaan, laakiin \\"Laa Ilaah illa Laahu\\" oo ah kelmaddii tawxiidka, ayaa ujeeddada islaamka sii caddaynaysa."},{"question":"Ungkapan menarik:","answer":"i. melentur buluh biar dari rebungnyaii. Bapa borek anak rintikiii. Alah bisa tegal biasaiv. di mana ada kemahuan, di situ ada jalanv. yang bulat tidak datang bergolek, yang pipih tidak datang melayang"},{"question":"Apakah soalan kepada: \\"Ia ditubuhkan pada Februari 2004 oleh Mark Zuckerberg dengan rakan sebiliknya di kolej serta rakan sekelas Universiti Harvard Eduardo Saverin, Andrew McCollum, Dustin Moskovitz dan Chris Hughes.\\"? Topiknya ialah Facebook.","answer":"\\"Siapakah yang mencipta Facebook?\\""},{"question":"Mengapakah konflik kemanusiaan masih berlaku pada masa ini? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 130 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Punca utamanya konflik kemanusiaan ialah tiada jaminan keselamatan kepada penduduk di negara yang berkonflik. Ketamakan kuasa politik dan ekonomi serta ketiadaan ketegasan dalam kalangan pemimpin dunia juga merupakan salah satu punca. Badan dunia seperti Pertubuhan Bangsa-bangsa Bersatu (PBB) tidak memberi perhatian kepada negara ditindas dan mengambil sikap membisu kuasa besar dalam menangani konflik, ini menyebabkan perebutan kawasan dalam sesebuah negara tidak terkawal. Terdapat perbahasan yang tidak mencapai kata putus dalam isu kemanusian yang melanda sesebuah negara, apabila kuasa besar mencabuli hak negara-negara miskin atau tertindas, suara negara bergolak tidak didengari oleh pemimpin badan dunia. Ini menyebabkan ketiadaan semangat kemanusiaan yang tinggi dalam kalangan negara di dunia. Ketiadaan kerjasama ahli gabungan dalam pertubuhan antarabangsa menyebabkan negara maju lebih mementingkan kuasa politik."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي تزوج اثنتين من بنات الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"الإجابة: عثمان بن عفان"},{"question":"Iza no namorona ilay boky hoe \\"Les lois du succès\\"? ","answer":"Ny namorona ilay boky hoe \\"Les lois du succès\\" dia i Napoléon Hill. "},{"question":"Inona no fiteny ofisialy ao amin'ny faritanin'i Québec any Kanada?1- Anglisy2- Frantsay3- Sinoa","answer":"Safidy 2- Frantsay no fiteny ofisialy ao amin'ny faritanin'i Québec any Kanada."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Picit perut, keluar benda yang untuk memputihkan gigi anda, apa tu?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah ubat gigi. Ubat gigi digunakan untuk mengosok gigi. Pembungkusan produk ini biasanya memerlukan pengguna memicit tiub ubat gigi untuk mengeluarkannya. "},{"question":"Quelle couleur est souvent associée à la croissance, à la nature et à la santé ?un noira) Blancb) Vertc) Rose","answer":"Réponse: b. Le vert est la couleur la plus souvent associée à la croissance, à la nature et à la santé. Biologiquement, le vert est la couleur d’une vie végétale saine, symbolisant la vitalité et la croissance. La psychologie évolutionniste suggère que le lien entre la couleur et les paysages fertiles et les besoins de survie aurait pu conduire les humains à l'associer à l'abondance et au bien-être. Culturellement, le symbolisme du renouveau du vert, observé lors de la renaissance du printemps, s'aligne sur les concepts de santé. Cependant, les interprétations des couleurs peuvent varier en raison des nuances culturelles et des préférences individuelles."},{"question":"Firy ny 3^2?","answer":"Ny 3^2 dia manome 9."},{"question":"Senator Demokrat, Chuck Schumer (kiri) dan Senator Republik, Mitch McConnell (kanan) menjadi pemain kunci dalam sidang pemakzulan Presiden Trump di Senat.Ketika sidang pemakzulan dimulai, Trump berada di Davos menghadiri Forum Ekonomi Dunia di Davos, Swiss. Tim kuasa hukum Trump menyebut dakwaan pemakzulan tersebut sebagai \\"serangan berbahaya\\" terhadap demokrasi.Secara teori, sidang dapat memuluskan jalan bagi pelengseran Trump dari kursi presiden. Jika pelengseran benar terjadi maka itu akan sangat mengejutkan, tetapi yang jelas sebelum hasilnya diketahui nanti, kenyataan bahwa seorang presiden sedang menjalani sidang pemakzulan sudah signifikan.1. Tuduhan seperti apa yang dihadapi Trump?Presiden Trump menghadapi dua pasal pemakzulan, atau dakwaan.Pertama, ia dituduh mencari bantuan dari pemerintah Ukraina untuk memuluskan upaya memenangkan pemilihan presiden untuk periode kedua pada bulan November nanti.Trump menghadari Forum Ekonomi Dunia di Davos bersamaan dengan pe... Lanjutkan artikel dengan total karakter maksimal 4000:","answer":"mbukaan sidang pemakzulannya di Senat AS.Ia dituduh menangguhkan bantuan militer bernilai jutaan dolar kepada Ukraina dan menunda pertemuan presiden Ukraina di Gedung Putih padahal sebelumnya sudah diagendakan. Keduanya digunakan sebagai posisi tawar menawar. Kedua, setelah Gedung Putih menolak mengizinkan staf memberikan kesaksian dalam sidang pemakzulan fase pertama tahun lalu, kubu Demokrat menuduh Trump menghalang-halangi Kongres. 2. Mengapa sidang pemakzulan digelar?Inilah kronologinya:Agustus 2019: Seorang pembocor informasi mengeluarkan tuduhan terhadap Presiden TrumpOktober - Desember: Penyelidikan digelar, sidang diadakan di tingkat DPR Desember: Anggota DPR AS dari partai Demokrat memilih untuk memakzulkan TrumpJanuari 2020: Kasus ini dilimpahkan ke Senat (yang dikuasai oleh Partai Republik yang mendukung Trump). Di Senat inilah sidang pemakzulan dilangsungkan3. Apa yang dicakup dalam sidang Senat?Konstitusi AS tidak begitu tegas dalam menjabarkan pemakzulan. Namun terdapat aturan umum yang dibuat berdasarkan pemakzulan Presiden Andrew Johnson pada tahun 1868. Dalam kasus itu, presiden tidak sampai kehilangan posisinya.Presiden lain yang menjalani sidang pemakzulan adalah Bill Clinton pada tahun 1999. Clinton juga selamat.Sekelompok warga AS menggelar demonstrasi mendukung pemakzulan Presiden Trump.Dua sosok punya tanggung jawab memutuskan bagaimana sidang dijalankan: Mitch McConnell, pemimpin kubu Republik di Senat, dan Chuck Schumer, pemimpin Demokrat di Senat.McConnell mengupayakan agar sidang berlangsung singkat dan Trump dibebaskan dari dakwaan. Ia juga menghendaki diadakan pemungutan suara tentang apakah bukti-bukti terhadap Trump perlu dibeberkan dalam sidang.Mengenai hal ini, Schumer mengatakan McConnell berusaha mencegah bukti dibeberkan dalam sidang, dan mengatakan \\"rakyat Amerika Serikat akan melihat sendiri apa adanya\\".Setidaknya dua pertiga dari seluruh anggota Senat harus mendukung pemberhentian presiden - jadi 67 dari 100 orang senator. Namun karena..."},{"question":"تلخيص المقال:  طيارين طائرة دلتا اللي انزلقت من المدرج في مطار لاغوارديا الأسبوع الماضي خلال عاصفة ثلجية قالوا للمحققين إن الأنظمة الأوتوماتيكية المصممة لإبطاء الطائرة ما كانتش تعمل بشكل صحيح. قالوا إن المكابح الأوتوماتيكية للطائرة كانت مرتبة على \\"أقصى سرعة\\" ، لكنهم لم يشعروا بأي تباطؤ بينما انحرفت الطائرة باتجاه خليج فلاشينج ، وفقًا لمجلس سلامة النقل الوطني. قال طاقم الطيران بردو إن المدرج بدى \\"أبيض بالكامل\\" - مغطى بالثلوج - لما خرجوا من السماء المغطاة بالغيوم وشاهدوها لحظات قبل الهبوط. اقرع للأسفل عشان الفيديو. خلل؟ طيارين رحلة دلتا اللي انزلقت من المدرج في لاغوارديا خلال عاصفة ثلجية الاسبوع الماضي (في الصورة) قالوا للمحققين ان الكوابح مش بتشتغل. لم يتم نشر المدافع الأوتوماتيكية للطائرة - المفتاحات الموجودة فوق الأجنحة التي تقلل من الارتفاع وتبطئ الطائرة - لكن الضابط الأول نشرها يدويًا. كابتن الطائرة كمان قال انه مش قادر يمنع الطائرة من الانجراف لليسار. المحققين قالوا إن الطائرة كانت تحلق على الطيار الآلي لحد ما كانت على ارتفاع 230 قدم عن الأرض، واللي بيدل على هبوط روتيني إلى حد ما حتى النهاية. كانت رحلة دلتا 1086 من أتلانتا تحمل 127 راكب، بمن فيهم طفلين في الحضانة، بالإضافة إلى خمسة من أفراد الطاقم، لما زالت عن المدرج يوم الخميس وتزحلت حوالي 2000 قدم على طول منطقة عشبية عادةً بجانب المدرج المغطى بالثلوج. قريباً: قال طاقم الطيران أيضًا إن المدرج بدى \\"أبيض بالكامل\\" - مغطى بالثلوج - لما خرجوا من السماء المغطاة بالغيوم وشاهدوه قبل لحظات من الهبوط. وجه الطيارة خلص فوق الماء. في آخر 940 من الأقدام دي، الجناح الأيسر للطائرة كان يقطع ويدمر سياج محيط المطار، حسبما قال المحققين. الطائرة اتت لترتاح مع أنفها المتكئ خطيرًا على حافة تفرق بين المدرج و خليج فلاشينج الجليدي. عانت الطائرة من أضرار في الجناح الأيسر، بما في ذلك خزان الوقود المتثقب الذي تسبب في تسرب من بطن الطائرة.","answer":"الطيارين قالوا لهيئة سلامة النقل الوطنية ان المكابح اتعملت على \\"المكس\\" ومع كده مش حاسسوا أي تباطؤ لما طائرة فقدت السيطرة. الظاهر ان الضابط الأول لازم ينشر المفاجئات الأوتوماتيكية بنفسه. اتجه نحو خليج فلاشينج و أنفه معلق فوق الماء. كان هناك 127 راكب، بمن فيهم طفلين، على متن الطائرة في الوقت ده."},{"question":"السؤال: لأيّ نبيٍّ من الأنبياء انشقّ البحر؟","answer":"الجواب: نبيّ الله موسى عليه السلام."},{"question":"A cidade de Uberlândia pertence a qual estado?","answer":"Uberlândia pertence ao estado de Minas Gerais."},{"question":" Sheeg isha ugu muhiimsan ileyska (Iftiinka)?","answer":"Isha ugu muhiimsan ileyska (Iftiinka) waa Qoraxda."},{"question":"කරත්ත කවියක් සඳහා  උදාහරණයක් දෙන්න. ","answer":"තණ්ඩලේ දෙන්නා දෙපොලේ        දක්කනවාකටු කැලේ ගාලේ නොලිහා වද      දෙනවාහපුතලේ කන්ද දැකලා බඩ            දනවාපවු කල ගොනෝ ඇදපන් හපුතල්  යනවා"},{"question":"తనను రక్షించేవారు లేరని బాధపడుతున్న సీతాదేవిని హనుమంతుడు ఏమని ఓదార్చాడు","answer":"శ్రేష్ఠుడైన శ్రీరాముడు సీతాదేవిని రక్షించడానికి ఉన్నాడు. వానరులతో కలిసి వస్తాడు. తప్పనిసరిగా ఆమెను తీసుకొని వెడతాడు. అది నిజమని సీతాదేవిని హనుమంతుడు ఓదార్చాడు."},{"question":"من هو القائد الذي نشر في ربوع فلسطين السلام والإسلام ؟","answer":"عمرو بن العاص"},{"question":"Cúentame sobre la segunda guerra mundial y el holocausto. Usa como máximo 2000 caracteres.","answer":"La Segunda Guerra Mundial, que tuvo lugar entre 1939 y 1945, fue un conflicto global que involucró a la mayoría de las naciones del mundo. Fue desencadenada por la invasión de Polonia por parte de Alemania en 1939 y resultó en una serie de alianzas militares y enfrentamientos en diferentes frentes.Uno de los aspectos más oscuros de la Segunda Guerra Mundial fue el Holocausto, que fue el genocidio sistemático llevado a cabo por el régimen nazi liderado por Adolf Hitler. Durante este período, aproximadamente seis millones de judíos, junto con otros grupos como gitanos, discapacitados y otras minorías étnicas, fueron perseguidos y asesinados en campos de concentración y exterminio.El Holocausto fue un evento sin precedentes en la historia, donde la maquinaria del Estado se utilizó para llevar a cabo el exterminio sistemático de millones de personas. Los campos de concentración como Auschwitz, Treblinka y Sobibor se convirtieron en símbolos de este horror inimaginable.La Segunda Guerra Mundial y el Holocausto dejaron una profunda marca en la historia y en la conciencia global. Sirven como recordatorio de los horrores extremos que puede llevar a cabo el odio y la intolerancia, y han motivado esfuerzos para prevenir futuros conflictos y genocidios a través de la promoción de la paz, la tolerancia y los derechos humanos. "},{"question":"Nye edemede a isiokwu nke dabara ọfụma: Nwaanyị a ma ama na-eme ihe nkiri bụ Rachal Oniga anwụọla dịka ọ gbachara afọ iri isii na anọ. Onyeisi otu ndị na-eme ihe nkiri na Naịjirịa bụ Actors Guild of Nigeria (AGN) bụ Emeka Rollas sị na nwa nwaanyị ahụ gwara odeakwụkwọ ya na ọ bụ eziokwu. \\"Nwa ya gwara odeakwụkwọ na nne ya nwụrụ n'ihe dịka elekere iri nke abalị 30 Julayị, 2021. Emeka sị na ha amatabeghi ihe butere ọnwụ nwaanyị ahụ.  Ihe ndị mmadụ na-ekwu maka ọnwụ Rachel:Onyeisi otu na-eme ihe onyonyo na obom bụ Jide Kosoko sị ya \\"laa n'udo.\\" Hilda Dokubo tinyekwara ọnụ sị na ọ na-akpọkarị ya \\"Nne m, nne m\\". Ọ sị na eluigwe nwere anyaukwu mgbe ụfọdụ maka ọnwụ Rachel.","answer":"Nsogbu adịghị, nke a bụ isi okwu maka ederede enyere - Rachel Oniga: Ihe i kwesịrị ịma maka nwaanyị ọma a larala mmụọ"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH de Granada?","answer":"0,795."},{"question":"Gwam ọ gazuru ụwa n'otu ụbọchị ","answer":"Anyanwu "},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"சுயமரியாதை இயக்கம் 1925 இல் இராமசாமியால் தோற்றுவிக்கப்பட்டது. இதன் முக்கிய கொள்கைப் பரப்புரையாக, சமுதாயத்தின் ஏளனத்திற்கு உரிய மூடப் பழக்க வழக்கங்களையும், பரம்பரை வழக்கங்களையும் பின்பற்றப்படுவதைத் தொடர்ந்து எதிர்க்கும் நிலையை எடுத்தது. மக்களை அறிவின்மையினிருந்து மீட்டெடுக்கவும், தெளிவுடையவர்களாக மாற்றவும் இதன் கொள்கைகள் வழிவகை செய்தன. பகுத்தறிவுச் சிந்தனையுடன் மக்களின் செயல்பாடுகள் இருக்க வலியுறுத்தின. பகுத்தறிவாளர்கள் பின்பற்றப்படவேண்டிய கடமைகளாகப் பலவற்றை இவ்வியக்கம் வலியுறுத்தியது.கற்பு என்ற சொல், பெண் ஓர் அடிமை; சீவனற்ற ஒரு பொருள் என்று காட்டவே ஆகும்-ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி"},{"question":"英格蘭足球超級聯賽有多少觀眾？","answer":"英超是全世界最多人觀看的體育聯賽。在全球各地，212個地區有電視轉播英超賽事，潛在觀眾約有47億人。"},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para esse parágrafo - Em 1816, Simón Bolívar, com a ajuda dos generais Urdaneta, Piar, Páez, Mariño, Nariño, entre outros, obtêm uma série de vitórias sobre os monarquistas. Depois de libertar Guiana e Nova Granada, proclamou em 17 de dezembro de 1819, em Angostura (hoje Ciudad Bolívar) sua fundação. As últimas tropas realistas na Venezuela foram derrotados na histórica Batalha de Carabobo","answer":"em 24 de junho de 1821. Em 28 de novembro de 1821 se dá a Independência do Panamá e voluntariamente se une ao sonho de Bolívar assinado com a Espanha de um pacto de não agressão."},{"question":"Sheeg yaa ugu horeyey muslimiinta qof Maka ka haajiro oo u haajiro madiina?","answer":"Wuxu ahaa abuu salaama Rc."},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Сен менин эң чыныгы, эң сүйүктүү досум болдуң. Сендей дос кымбат эмес, баа жеткис! Сизге каалоо-тилек а сонун туулган!"},{"question":"താഴെപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക:  ഹയർ കമാണ്ട് കോഴ്സ് വിജയിച്ചതിനുശേഷം മിലിട്ടറി ഓപ്പറേഷൻസ് ഡയറക്ടറേറ്റിൽ ഡയറക്ടറായി അദ്ദേഹം സേവനമാരംഭിച്ചു. ഈ സമയത്ത് നടന്ന","answer":"കാർഗിൽ യുദ്ധത്തിൽ ഇന്ത്യൻ ആർമിയുടെ മാധ്യമ വക്താവായും അദ്ദേഹം സേവനം ചെയ്തു."},{"question":"Quem inventou a lata para conservar alimentos em 1810?","answer":"Pedro Durand."},{"question":"What is the meaning of concentration camps?","answer":"Concentration camps are prisons where people are detained and tortured without due process of law."},{"question":"Abusho lutho ubuncane bukaDumisani. Into enkulu ukuthi angimfuni.Ngicabanga nokuthi nalo lelo siko ngeke lisebenze uthando lungekho.Sengathi ijulile inkulumo yakho makoti. Kokunye nathi besinake isikonje kanti kukhona lapho siphaphalaza khona.Ngisuswe yilokho phansi mina Manzini. Ngicabanga ukuthi isikolisebenza kahle uma kukhona ukuzwana. Angiboni ukuthilingaphoqelelwa ngenkani.Sengathi kuzofuneka sihlangane nomndeni wakini; kuboniswanengale ndaba.Engikucelayo ukubuyela ekhaya, kuphela nje. (Kufike uMaMbatha)Sanibona bantabami!Yebo mama!Ulandwe uwe yini umlobokazi baba?Cha nkosikazi ngibabone sebengena nodadewabo. Phela minabengizovuka ekuseni ngiyofuna.(Ebheke kuThenjiwe) Kanti uma umuntu evakashele udadewaboakabe esasho?Cha mama ubengeke asho ngoba uhambe kungekuhle uThenji.Uthi bekwenziwa yini kungabi kuhle?Ngiyaxolisa mama ngesenzo sami. Inkinga yami ukuthi angizimiseleukulandela leli siko enilishoyo, ngicela ukuya ekhaya.Kusho ukuthi ufuna ukuhamba ngenkani?Yikho lokhu okungisuse phansi mama. Yiso leso sizathu futhi esenzeukuba ngimbuyise lapha ekhaya uThenji. Ngeke alungelwe yiluthouma ezokwenza izinto ngenkani. Kodwa-ke nami ngicela nimvumeleabuyele ekhaya.(Ahwaqe) Uyabona wena awufanele ukuzokhuluma izindaba zakulomuzi.1. Uma unikwa ithuba lokweluleka uMaMbatha ngokuphoqelela isikolokungenwa kuThenjiwe, wawungameluleka uthini? Sekela impendulo yakhongamaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Ngangingameluleka ngokuthi sesiphila esikhathini samalungelo laphowonke umuntu enamalungelo okumele ahlonishwe.  Idokwe lidliwa inhliziyo, umuntu akakhethelwa ukuthi kumele athandebani.  Sekunezifo eziningi esikhathini samanje ngakho-ke abanye abantubesifazane ngeke bavume ukungenwa besaba ukuthi bazothola izifo.  Kumele ahloniphe uThenjiwe yize emncane kunaye, isiko likhuthazaukuthi omncane ahloniphe omdala kanti nomdala kumele ahlonipheomncane.  Isiko lokungena aliphoqelelwa kodwa kumele umuntu alilandelengokuthanda kwakhe. (Nokunye okunembayo okuyoshiwo umfundi.)"},{"question":"Акыр-аягы кайсы улуттун өкүлдөрү жөнүндө айтылат? ","answer":"Немис Ренессансы шаарга белгилүү бир имараттарды калтырган (айрыкча азыркы Chambre de commerce et d'industrie, мурунку мэрия, Гутенберг аянтында), ошондой эле француз бароккосу жана классицизми бир нече hôtels particuliers (б.а. сарайлар), алардын арасында Palais Rohan (1742, азыр үч музей жайгашкан) эң көрүнүктүү. Башка имараттар \\"Hôtel de Hanau\\" (1736, азыркы мэрия), Hôtel de Klinglin (1736, азыркы префекттин резиденциясы), Hôtel des Deux-Ponts (1755, азыркы аскердик губернатордун резиденциясы), Hôtel d'Andlau-Klinglin (1725, азыркы Страсбург автономдук портунун администрациясынын орун басары) ж.б. Ал эми француз неоклассицизмине келсек, бул стилдеги эң көрүнүктүү имарат - Брожье аянтындагы опера театры."},{"question":"\\"Ny Bokin'ny Eksodosy ao amin'ny Testamenta Taloha dia mitantara ny fanafahana ny Isiraelita tamin'ny fanandevozana tany Ejipta.\\"Inona ny fanontaniana azo tsogaina amin'io andian-teny io?","answer":"Fanontaniana: Inona no boky ao amin'ny Testamenta Taloha mirakitra ny fanafahana ny Isiraelita tamin'ny fanandevozana tany Egypta?"},{"question":"Soalan : Tuliskan sebuah karangan yang bertajuk ‘Aku Sebuah Basikal’. Pastikan karangan anda tidak melebihi 100 patah perkataan.","answer":"Aku berasal dari ‘Negara Matahari Terbit’ - Jepun. Aku sebuah basikal yang dihasilkan di sebuah kilang besi waja yang kecil. Badanku diperbuat daripada besi waja, getah asli, kaca dan plastik.Aku dan kawan-kawanku yang lain dihantarkan ke pameran basikal setelah dihasilkan. Banyak orang datang melawat pameran basikal itu. Segelintir kawan-kawan saya telah dibeli oleh orang ramai. Tidak lama kemudian, saya juga dibeli oleh seorang lelaki sebagai hadiah hari jadi anaknya.Pemilik saya ialah seorang kanak-kanak lelaki yang bernama Will. Will sangat gembira apabila mendapat saya. Pada mula-mulanya, Will tidak pandai menunggang basikal pada mula-mulanya. Setiap pagi, Will gigih berbasikal di taman kediaman sekitarnya. Will manjadi pandai berkayuh saya setelah latihan selama 2 minggu. Saya sangat bangga karana pemilik saya cepat belajar.  Will selalu membawa saya ke mana-mana sahaja pada masa lapangnya. Will sangat menyayangi saya.  Kadang-kala, Will juga mempinjamkan saya kepada adiknya. Saya berasa sangat bersyukur kerana dapat berbakti kepada Will dan keluarganya. "},{"question":"\\"1\\" อ่านว่าอะไร","answer":"\\"1\\" อ่านว่า \\"หนึ่ง\\""},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe « arrêt cardiaque » na fijanonan’ny fo tampoka ?","answer":"Sokajiana ho fahafatesana voajanahary ny fijanonan’ny fo tampoka na arrêt cardiaque."},{"question":"өмүр башаты деген эмне?","answer":"өмүр башаты – өмүрдүн башталышы"},{"question":"Siapakah Patrick Teoh? Terangkan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 800 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Patrick Teoh (nama asal: Teoh Kah Yong (Bahasa Cina: 张家扬), lahir 16 Oktober 1947) ialah seorang pelakon dan juruhebah radio terkenal di Malaysia. Kerjaya beliau dalam persada radio, TV, pentas dan filem selama lebih tiga dekad telah memberi Teoh gelaran \\"Voice Of Malaysia\\", oleh peminat beliau dan media massa.Patrick Teoh lahir di Ipoh, Perak, Malaysia. Beliau memasuki St. Michael's Institution sehinggalah Tingkatan 5. Sewaktu kecil, ibunya mengharapkan anaknya itu menjadi peguam kerana kepetahan bercakap.Pada masa itu pilihan hiburan amat sedikit. Oleh itu, bapa Patrick membawanya dan ibunya sekali menonton wayang setiap hari untuk tayangan 9.15 malam, sungguhpun si bapa bukanlah seorang peminat filem. Daripada rutin harian menonton sebuah filem setiap hari, Patrick belajar bertutur dalam bahasa Inggeris dengan menonton aksi pelakon seperti John Wayne, Randolph Scott, Henry Fonda dan James Stewart. Tabiat melawat pawagam setiap hari kekal dengan Patrick sehingga mencecah usia 24 tahun. Rekod peribadi beliau iaitu menonton 6 buah filem dalam satu hari.Selepas menamatkan sekolah menengah, Patrick menetap di Ipoh dan menjadi jurujual insuran nyawa dan ensiklopedia selama 1½ tahun. Akhirnya bapa beliau menggesa anaknya mencari \\"pekerjaan yang sebenar.\\" Maka bermulalah pencarian kerjaya Patrick; pada satu masa beliau memohon pekerjaan sebagai atendan penerbangan carter. Suatu hari pada tahun 1966, beliau bermakan malam di rumah apabila terdengar pengumuman Rediffusion, sebuah stesen radio kabel, mengenai kekosongan jawatan juruhebah radio. Maka Patrick memohon jawatan tersebut, lalu menjalani temuduga dan lulus. Ketika itu beliau berusia 19 tahun.Pada tahun 1966, Teoh menyertai Rediffusion sebagai seorang \\"Juruhebah Rancangan Bahasa Inggeris gred 3\\" yang memperoleh gaji M150 sebulan. Bagi tiga bulan pertama, beliau tidak dibenarkan memasuki studio. Sebaliknya, beliau menulis skrip dan memilih lagu untuk Lunch Time Melodies, semata-mata untuk ditolak dan digesa buat semula oleh penyelia beliau. Selepas tiga bulan itu, beliau dibenarkan untuk bertugas di studio ketika waktu puncak, yang mana tugas utama beliau adalah untuk menekan butang untuk memainkan rancangan yang dirakam terlebih dahulu. Selepas enam bulan, beliau dibernarkan berhebah menurut skrip yang diluluskan terlebih dahulu. Dalam masa 2 tahun, Teoh dinaikkan pangkat kepada Pembantu Pengurus Rancangan dan setahun selepas itu, belaiu menyandang jawatan Pengurus Rancangan untuk Rediffusion. Kenangan terpenting dalam kerjaya beliau dalam Jabatan Rancangan Bahasa Inggeris Rediffusion adalah apabila Teoh diberitahu oleh Penyelia Jabatan ketika itu bahawa beliau tidak akan banyak menyumbang kepada industri kerana kecacatan fizikalnya (Teoh mengidap polio pada usia 7 tahun). Namun begitu, Teoh menggantikan penyelia itu sebagai Penyelia Rancangan Bahasa Inggeris.Pada tahun-tahun terakhir Teoh bersama Rediffusion, Malaysia sedang mengalami pemesatan dalam industri pengiklanan. Ekonomi tempatan kian mantap, dan kerajaan pula memperkenalkan peraturan 'Buatan Malaysia', iaitu sekurang-kurangnya 65% daripada unsur-unsur dalam iklan yang disiarkan melalui media elektronik mestilah berbangsa Malaysia atau buatan Malaysian. Maka Teoh sering kali diminta untuk kerja suara latar, sampaikan pada satu detik dalam kerjaya beliau, sehingga 99% iklan berbahasa Inggeris yang tersiar dalam media elektronik disuarakan beliau sendiri. Maka inilah bagaimana beliau bergelar \\"Voice of Malaysia\\".Teoh juga dihargai sebagai pelopor mobile disco di Malaysia. Pada pertengahan 1970-an, terletusnya era disko di negara. Pada masa itu, Patrick kerap diambil untuk bekerja sebagai DJ untuk parti persendirian dan majlis seumpamanya. Ketika satu majlis tahunan bagi industri pengiklanan, beliau dibawa masuk sebagai 'sokongan' untuk kugiran yang membuat persembahan. Hadirin memberi reaksi positif kepada irama disko yang diputarkan beliau, lalu beliau diminta untuk membuat persembahan untuk saki-baki malam itu. Setelah majlis itu tamat, beliau dijemput untuk membuat persembahan di majlis untuk memutarkan banyak lagi lagu disko. Setelah melihat kelarisan 'mobile disco', Teoh membuka sebuah syarikat bernama \\"The Music Machine\\" khususnya untuk tujuan itu.Pada Jun 1984, TV3 memulakan penyiaran di Lembah Klang. Patrick, bersama-sama Mahadzir Lokman, Wan Zaleha Radzi, Robert Lam, dand Caryn Lim diambil untuk menjadi pemberita untuk stesen ini. Pada tahun 1994, stesen radio 24 jam yang baru Time Highway Radio membuktikan dirinya sebagai pesaing hebat kepada stesen radio RTM. Maka RTM memutuskan untuk menjenamakan semula Radio 4, dan mengambil DJ baru seperti Teoh dan Yasmin Yusoff. Slot rancangan temu bual Teoh ketika itu berkumandang dari 9 pagi hingga 12 tengahari setiap Isnin, Selasa dan Rabu. Apabila Radio 4 mula disiarkan selama 24 ham, Teoh turut mengcarakan satu rancangan pada slot 12 tengah malam hingg atill 3 pagi berjudul Midnight Magic. Dalam Midnight Magic, Teoh menjemput para pendengar untuk memanggil stesen dan menceritakan cerita hantu dalam satu langkah yang nyata popular di kalangan pendengar.Pada akhir 1980-an, Joe Hasham dan Faridah Merican mendirikan The Actors Studio. Salah satu projek terulung mereka ialah kursus lakonan yang mana mereka menjemput Teoh untuk menyertainya. Selepas menjalankan kursus, The Actors Studio mementaskan \\"A Man For All Seasons\\" di mana Patrick diberi peranan sampingan sebagai Kardinal Wolsey. Inilah kemunculan pertama teoh di pentas Malaysia. Kini Teoh seorang pelakon sepenuh masa dan seorang ahli Instant Café Theatre Company yang aktif."},{"question":"Kí ni a ń pe Friday ní èdè Yorùbá?","answer":"Ẹtì ni."},{"question":"ਅਲਿੰਗੀ ਪ੍ਰਜਣਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਕਰੋ । ਹਰੇਕ ਦੀ ਉਦਾਹਰਨ ਦਿਉ ।","answer":"    - ਬਡਿੰਗ,    - ਖੰਡਨ,    - ਬੀਜਾਣੁ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ    - ਕਾਇਆ ਵਰਧਨ ।(i) ਬਡੂੰਗ-ਸਪੰਜ ਅਤੇ ਹਾਈਡਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ ਇਹੀ ਜਣਨ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਨਕ ਪੌਦੇ ਤੇ ਇਕ ਨਵਾਂ ਪੌਦਾ ਵਿਕਸਿਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਕੁੱਝ ਸਮੇਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਜਨਕ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਕਾ ਤੋਂ ਅਲੱਗ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਵਾਧਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ii) ਖੰਡਨ-ਜਦੋਂ ਸ਼ੈਵਾਲ, ਫੀਤਾ ਕਿਰਮ, ਐਨੀਲਿਡਜ਼ ਅਤੇ ਚਪਟੇ ਕਿਰਮ ਦੋ ਜਾਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਖੰਡਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਹਰੇਕ ਖੰਡ ਨਵੇਂ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਧਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਖੰਡਣ ਅਖਵਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।(iii) ਬੀਜਾਣੂ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ-ਕਾਈ, ਮਿਉਕਰ ਆਦਿ ਬੀਜਾਣੂ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜੋ ਉੱਚ ਤਾਪ ਅਤੇ ਘੱਟ ਨਮੀਂ ਵਰਗੀਆਂ ਹਾਲਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਕਠੋਰ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆਤਮਕ ਪਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਢੱਕੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਢੁੱਕਵੀਆਂ ਹਾਲਤਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਵੇਂ ਜੀਵ ਵਿਕਸਿਤ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।(iv) ਕਾਇਆ ਪ੍ਰਵਰਧਨ-ਪੌਦੇ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਗ ਜੋ ਜਣਨ ਅੰਗ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ, ਨਵੇਂ ਪੌਦੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਕਸਿਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਾਂ ਇਸ ਵਿਧੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਇਆ ਪ੍ਰਵਰਧਨ ਆਖਦੇ ਹਨ । ਜਿਵੇਂ, ਗੁਲਾਬ ਦੀ ਕਲਮ ਨਵੇਂ ਪੌਦੇ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"வினா:(அ ) மனோன்மணீயம் சுந்தரனாரின் தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்துப் பாடலையும், பெருஞ்சித்திரனாரின் தமிழ் வாழ்த்தையும் ஒப்பிட்டு மேடைப்பேச்சு ஒன்றை உருவாக்குக.","answer":"விடை:தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்து:தமிழ்த்தாயை சுந்தரனார் அவர்கள் தமிழ்த்தாய் வாழ்த்துப் பாடலில், நீரலைகள் எழுந்து ஆர்ப்பரிக்கின்ற கடலைத் தன் ஆடையாய் உடுத்திக் கொண்டுள்ள நிலமாகிய பெண்ணுக்கு அழகிய முகமாகத் திகழ்வது பாரத கண்டம். அம்முகத்திற்கு அழகிய பிறை போன்ற நெற்றியாகத் திகழ்வது. தெற்குப்பகுதி, அந்நெற்றியில் இட்டுக்கொண்ட குங்குமம் போல புகழ் ஒளி வீசித் திகழ்வது திராவிட நாடு. அக்குங்குமத்தின் வாசனையைப் போல் அனைத்துப் பகுதி மக்களும் இன்பம் அடையும்படி எட்டுத் திசைகளிலும் பரவி வாழ்கின்ற தமிழ் என்னும் தெய்வமே தொன்று தொட்டு வாழ்ந்தாய் என்றாலும் உன் பெருவாழ்வு புதுமைக்குப் புதுமையாய் இன்றும் இளமையாய் விளங்குகிறது. தமிழ்த்தாயே உன் பேராற்றலை வியந்து செய்வதறியாது மெய்மறந்து வாழ்த்துகின்றோம் என வாழ்த்துகின்றார்.பெருஞ்சித்திரனாரின் தமிழ் வாழ்த்து:அழகாய் அமைந்த செந்தமிழே! அன்னை மொழியே! பழமைக்குப் பழமையாய்த் தோன்றிய நறுங்கனியே! கடல் கொண்ட குமரிக் கண்டத்தில் நிலைத்து அரசாண்ட மண்ணுலகப் பேரரசே பாண்டிய மன்னனின் மகளே ! திருக்குறளின் பெருமைக்குரியவளே! பத்துப்பாட்டே! எட்டுத்தொகையே பதினெண்கீழ்க்கணக்கே! நிலைத்த சிலப்பதிகாரமே! அழகான மணிமேகலையே! பொங்கியெழும் நினைவுகளால் உன்னைத் தலை பணிந்து வாழ்த்துகின்றோம் என பெருஞ்சித்திரனார் தமிழ்த்தாயை வாழ்த்துகின்றார்."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: \\"Khó đạt mục tiêu đón 5 triệu khách quốc tế Ngành du lịch đặt mục tiêu năm 2022 đón khoảng 65 triệu lượt khách, trong đó có 60 triệu lượt khách nội địa và 5 triệu lượt khách quốc tế. Tin vui cho ngành du lịch là đến tháng 7.2022, thị trường nội địa đã đón 71,8 triệu lượt khách, vượt chỉ tiêu đề ra cho cả năm. Tuy nhiên, thị trường quốc tế chỉ mới qua gần 1/5 chặng đường dẫn tới mục tiêu 5 triệu lượt khách. Theo số liệu Tổng cục Thống kê công bố ngày 29.7, tính chung 7 tháng năm 2022, khách quốc tế đến Việt Nam đạt 954.600 lượt, gấp 10 lần so với cùng kỳ năm ngoái nhưng vẫn giảm 90,3% so với cùng kỳ 2019, năm chưa xảy ra dịch COVID-19. Như vậy trong 5 tháng còn lại của 2022, Việt Nam cần đón hơn 4 triệu lượt khách, trung bình mỗi tháng gần 810.000 lượt. Tại buổi họp báo thường kỳ quý II/2022 của Bộ VHTTDL, Phó Tổng Cục trưởng Tổng cục Du lịch Phạm Văn Thủy nhấn mạnh, thường mùa cao điểm khách quốc tế đến Việt Nam bắt đầu từ tháng 9 năm nay đến khoảng tháng 4 của năm sau. Ông Thủy cho rằng, để thực hiện mục tiêu đón 5 triệu lượt khách quốc tế, thời gian tới, ngành du lịch sẽ tiếp tục phối hợp với các đối tác liên quan, các cơ quan đại diện Việt Nam, Trung tâm Văn hóa Việt Nam ở nước ngoài để thực hiện các hoạt động quảng bá, xúc tiến để thu hút du khách quốc tế đến Việt Nam… Nhận định về tình hình khách quốc tế đến Việt Nam, ông Nguyễn Công Hoan - Tổng Giám đốc Flamingo Redtours, cho rằng, mục tiêu 5 triệu lượt khách là một chỉ tiêu khó với ngành du lịch trong năm nay. Tuy nhiên, lượng khách đến nay chưa như kỳ vọng do một số yếu tố tác động. Đầu tiên là tác động từ hàng không, bởi các đường bay quốc tế chưa mở lại toàn bộ. Thứ hai là chính sách nhập cảnh chưa thực sự thông thoáng, vẫn còn những điều kiện khó khăn so với trước đại dịch. Theo ông Hoan, một yếu tố quan trọng khiến thị trường khách quốc tế đến Việt Nam chưa thể hồi phục nhanh chóng chính là thời điểm. Bởi mùa hè là khoảng thời gian khách du lịch Trung Quốc, Hàn Quốc, Nhật Bản và Đài Loan (Trung Quốc) đến Việt Nam đông nhất. Đến nay những thị trường này chưa mở cửa lại hoàn toàn.\\"","answer":"Những tín hiệu tích cực Dù vậy, ông Hoan đánh giá tương lai gần vẫn có những tín hiệu tích cực với thị trường quốc tế. Các quốc gia trong khu vực Đông Nam Á mở cửa dần, gỡ bỏ thêm rào cản về những quy định liên quan đến phòng chống COVID-19 như cách ly, xét nghiệm, giấy chứng nhận tiêm chủng... Nếu công tác xúc tiến, quảng bá hiệu quả, ngành du lịch có thể đặt hy vọng vào thị trường Châu Âu, Mỹ, Australia. Bởi tháng 10 mới bắt đầu mùa du lịch của khách từ những thị trường này. Theo công cụ theo dõi xu hướng thị trường Destination Insights của Google. Cụ thể, lượng tìm kiếm về hàng không đến Việt Nam từ Ấn Độ bùng nổ với lượng tìm kiếm tăng hàng trăm phần trăm vào tháng 4 so với cùng kỳ năm ngoái và tăng trên 3.000% vào một tháng sau đó. Trong tháng 7, lượng tìm kiếm tăng cao đến 1.900% vào ngày 10.7. Thị trường này được kỳ vọng tăng trưởng mạnh mẽ khi các hãng hàng không Vietnam Airlines, Vietjet Air nối lại và mở thêm hàng loạt đường bay thẳng đến Ấn Độ trong tháng 6, tháng 7. Bên cạnh đó, thị trường Hàn Quốc cũng đang có những dấu hiệu hồi phục khả quan khi trong 7 tháng đầu năm Việt Nam đón hơn 196.000 lượt khách đến từ xứ sở kim chi - chiếm khoảng 20% trong tổng lượng khách quốc tế đến (954.600 lượt). Đặc biệt, lượng khách Hàn Quốc đến vào tháng 7 đạt hơn 88.300 lượt, gấp 1,7 lần so với tháng 6 (51.300 lượt) và gấp hơn 3 lần so với tháng 5 (27.800 lượt). Ông Hoàng Nhân Chính - Trưởng Ban Thư ký Hội đồng Tư vấn Du lịch (TAB) còn cho rằng ngành du lịch cần cân nhắc cơ hội thu hút những thị trường khách chi trả cao hơn. Điều này hoàn toàn hợp lý trong bối cảnh đại dịch chưa chấm dứt hoàn toàn, không có gì đảm bảo chắc chắn khách du lịch sẽ ồ ạt trở lại trong những tháng cuối năm. Ông Chính nhận định nếu ngành du lịch Việt Nam chỉ đón 4 triệu lượt khách, nhưng doanh thu bằng với mức 5 triệu khách là tín hiệu tích cực. Theo ông Chính, khi thu được nhiều tiền hơn từ lượng khách ít hơn, ngành du lịch không bị quá tải mà vẫn đưa ra những dịch vụ tốt hơn. Từ đó, thay đổi suy nghĩ của khách du lịch quốc tế, rằng du lịch Việt Nam có xu hướng nâng cao chất lượng và trở thành điểm đến ngày càng sang trọng. Định hướng phát triển hướng đến những thị trường chất lượng cao hơn sẽ giúp ngành du lịch có thể trở thành ngành kinh tế mũi nhọn. \\"Nếu không thay đổi cơ cấu thị trường và chất lượng của khách du lịch, ngành du lịch sẽ vẫn theo tư duy cũ, khó phát triển một cách bền vững\\"."},{"question":"Hindi ya kupika ndizi na nyama","answer":"Naosha nyama naweka jikoni ikichemka ikiiva naandaa ndizi nazimenya naosha vizuri. Naandaa viungo vyangu hoho, karoti, nyanya, vitunguu. Naweka ndizi ndani ya sufuria nyama na viungo vyangu katikati na nyama ndizi zingine juu natia na mafuta nafunika zinachemka zikiiva nazigeuza naongeza mchuzi zinachemka kidogo zikiiva naipua tayari."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਃ ੧ ॥ਸਿਦਕੁ ਸਬੂਰੀ ਸਾਦਿਕਾ ਸਬਰੁ ਤੋਸਾ ਮਲਾਇਕਾਂ ॥ਦੀਦਾਰੁ ਪੂਰੇ ਪਾਇਸਾ ਥਾਉ ਨਾਹੀ ਖਾਇਕਾ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 83 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸਿਦਕੀਆਂ ਕੋਲ ਭਰੋਸੇ ਤੇ ਸ਼ੁਕਰ ਦੀ, ਅਤੇ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਾਂ ਪਾਸ ਸਬਰ (ਸੰਤੋਖ) ਦੀ ਰਾਸਿ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, (ਇਸ ਕਰਕੇ) ਉਹ ਪੂਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ । (ਪਰ) ਨਿਰੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਥਾਉਂ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦੀ ।੨।\\""},{"question":"Pindura mubvunzo unotevera. mapeji mangani ari mubhuku racho ari kumashure nekunze","answer":"mapegi 263"},{"question":"漢字で「鬼の灯」と書くナス科の植物で、毎年７月に浅草の浅草寺で行われる市で知られるのは何でしょう？","answer":"ほおずきです。"},{"question":"Ayat 1: Pada tahun 2005, penerbitan Retro Gamer dikreditkan pasukan Elite dalam Jilid 2-Issue 1 sebagai Richard Benton, Matthew Hyden dan Steve Wilcox. Pada tahun 2005, Retro Gamer mengeluarkan kumpulan elit dalam jilid 2 edisi 1 sebagai Richard Benton, Matthew Hyden dan Steve Wilcox dikreditkan. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Ya."},{"question":"नेपाली भाषाको पहिलो पत्रिका कुन हो ?","answer":"नेपाली भाषाको पहिलो पत्रिका गोर्खा इन्डिया लाइफ हो।"},{"question":"प्रश्नः कौन जेन से जेन वर्जिन मैरी ?","answer":"माइकल कोर्डेरो"},{"question":"जीवाश्महरू के हुन् र तिनीहरू कसरी बन्छन्?","answer":"जीवाश्महरू पुरातन जीवहरूको संरक्षित अवशेष वा निशानहरू हुन्। तिनीहरू बन्छन् जब जीवहरू गाडिन्छन् र समयसँगै खनिज हुन्छन्।"},{"question":"Taariikhda fanaankii Digfeer Ilaahay ha u naxariisto qalbigiisana ha u waasiciyo Yaasiin Axmed Goox Digfeer.","answer":"Taariikhda fanaankii Digfeer Ilaahay ha u naxariisto qalbigiisana ha u waasiciyo Yaasiin Axmed Goox Digfeer.Axmed yasiin Goox Digfeer wuxuu ku dhashay gobolka Qorraxay ee dhulka SoomaaliGalbeed dabayqaadii dagaalkii labaad ee Adduunka, xili qiyaastii ku beegan sanadihii 1947 ilaa 1950kii qarnigiii Labaatanaad. Burburkii Soomaaliya kaddib, Digfeer waxa uu inta badan ku noolaa magaalooyinka Jigjiga iyo Jabuuti. Wuxuu ku geeriyooday magaalada Hargeysa sanadkii 2002-dii. Alle ha u naxariisto. Abwaanku beel ahaan wuxuu kasoo jeede beesha madhibaan gaar ahaan reer horoglewuxuu ahaa markii koowaad Yaasiin Axmed Digfeer uu ka soo muuqdo riwaayaddii' Ugub Jacayl Iyo Af Kala Qaad' ee uu alifay nin caan ku ahaa magaca Ina Baaruud. Waxay soo gaadhay Yaasiin Digfeer, waxa uu qaaday heestii' Kaalay Kaalay Kol li Imo, dadkii goobta joogay oo ka badnaa 300 oo qof way diideen in Digfeer Kabanka wareejiyo , sidii ayaanu saddex heesood oo kale ku qaaday. Waxyaabaha gaarka u ahaa Yaasiin Digfeer waxa ka mid ahaa in uu kaalinta koowaad kaga jiray Billadda Tumista Heesaha Fudud ( Saambo / Jaas) waxaana la sheegaa inaanu jirin qof sidiisa u tumay inta la ogyahay Fanka Soomaaliyeed.Heeesihi Ahmed yaasiin Digfeer Waxa ka mid ahaa kuwan hoota ku qoran.Dayaxa iyo cadceeda Bidhaantaada inanyahay Guyaal badan Nin Ku Gaya Ayaankagu Daranaa Nimcooy Dhulka Ina Cabday Labaleey Gacalo Canab Qarni Geeriyoda kuwa ugu danbeeyay Jeeb maran Sagal Taariikhda Garab Haygu nicin hanti laaan Isku Aayni Sacab Beena Bidhaan Hooto Saxiibku waa beer Beyo Cashqeeygii Qarni Geeriyoda Jaceelkeenii shaafoow Boqorqdii Hablah Nabsi Masikow Saaxib Waan ka Xaumahay Gar baan kuu dhiganayaa Barigii horeetaba.Bilawgii sanadkii 1970 - kii, Soomaaliya waxaa ka bilawday Kacdoon Faneed, waxaa aasaasantay Kooxdii Hobolada ee Waaberi ka dibna , sanadkii 1973 waxa la saasay kooxaha Onkod iyo Horseed oo kala hoostagi jiray Milatariga iyo Asluubta Soomaaliyeed. Axmed lidow Abtiile ( Axmed Nuur Jaangoo ) oo xiliyadaasi ka mid ah Fanaaniinta."},{"question":"Ọpẹ o, ijọba ti ṣi gbogbo ileewe pada nipinlẹ Eko","answer":"Idunnu ti ṣubu lu ayọ fun gbogbo akẹkọọ atawọn obi nipinlẹ Eko bayii pẹlu bi ijọba ipinlẹ naa ṣe paṣẹ pe ki gbogbo awọn akẹkọọ pata lai yọ ẹkan kankan silẹ pada sẹnu ẹkọ wọn.Ọjọ kọkandinlogun, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii, iyẹn ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, to n bọ ni gbogbo ileewe pata, yala ti aladaani tabi ti ijọba yoo pada, ti awọn kilaasi kan tijọba ni ki wọn ṣi duro sile tẹlẹ naa yoo darapọ mọ awọn ẹlẹgbẹ wọn lati bẹrẹ si i gba ẹkọ pada nileewe kaluku wọn.Ni nnkan bii oṣu mẹfa sẹyin ni ijọba paṣẹ pe ki gbogbo ileewe di titi pa ni kete ti ajakelẹ arun Koronafairọọsi gbode agbaye kan, ti kinni naa si n burẹkẹ nipinlẹ Eko, ati lawọn ipinlẹ mi-in nilẹ wa.Ohun ti ijọba sọ ni pe, ileewe ti oun ni ki wọn ṣi pada yii, gbogbo ọmọ pata lo kan, paapaa awọn jẹle-o-sinmi (Daycare ati kindergarten)Kọmiṣanna fun ọrọ ẹkọ l’Ekoo, Arabinrin Fọlaṣade Adefisayọ, sọ pe lẹyin ti ijọba ti wo ṣaakun eto imurasilẹ daadaa, ti asọyepọ to munadoko si ti waye laarin ijọba atawọn ti ọrọ kan, paapaa nidii ọrọ ẹkọ ati aabo lo fa a ti igbesẹ ọhun fi waye bayii.O ti waa rọ gbogbo awọn ọga agba nileewe, paapaa lawọn ile ẹkọ aladaani lati pa gbogbo ofin ti ijọba ti la kalẹ mọ lori itankalẹ arun Koronafairọọsi, ki wọn si mu eto aabo wọn le dan-in-dan-in.Adefisayọ fi kun un pe ijọba yoo tubọ maa mojuto eto igbaradi kaluku, ati pe ọfiisi naa ni yoo maa fun awọn to ba yege ni iwe-ẹri pe wọn ti yege.Bijọba ti ṣe waa ni ki awọn ọmọleewe pada sẹnu ẹkọ wọn, bẹẹ lo rọ awọn adari ileewe, paapaa awọn ileewe aladaani lati ri i pe ki wọn gba iwe-ẹri ‘mo yege’ lati ṣi ileewe pada lọdọ ajọ eto ẹkọ, ki eto gbogbo le lọ gẹgẹ bii erongba ijọba."},{"question":"కింది సామాన్య వాక్యాల్ని సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యాలుగా మార్చి రాయండి.అ) విమల వంట చేస్తుంది. విమల పాటలు వింటుంది.ఆ) అమ్మ నిద్రలేచింది. అమ్మ ముఖం కడుక్కుంది.ఇ) రవి ఊరికి వెళ్ళాడు. రవి మామిడిపండ్లు తెచ్చాడు.","answer":"అ) విమల వంట చేస్తుంది. విమల పాటలు వింటుంది.జవాబు:విమల వంట చేస్తూ, పాటలు వింటుంది.ఆ) అమ్మ నిద్రలేచింది. అమ్మ ముఖం కడుక్కుంది.జవాబు:అమ్మ నిద్రలేచి, ముఖం కడుక్కుంది.ఇ) రవి ఊరికి వెళ్ళాడు. రవి మామిడిపండ్లు తెచ్చాడు.జవాబు:రవి ఊరికి వెళ్ళి, మామిడిపండ్లు తెచ్చాడు."},{"question":"“Peasant's cabbage” was an early term used for what cruciferous plant spiked in popularity in the 2000s?","answer":"Kale"},{"question":"ನಾನು ಮಸಾಲೆ ದೋಸೆ ಅಥವಾ ರವಾ ಇಡ್ಲಿಯನ್ನು ಆರಿಸಬೇಕೇ? ನಿನ್ನ ಅಭಿಪ್ರಾಯವೇನು?","answer":"ನನಗೆ ವೈಯಕ್ತಿಕ ಅಭಿಪ್ರಾಯಗಳಿಲ್ಲ, ಆದರೆ ನಾನು ಮಾಹಿತಿಯನ್ನು ನೀಡಬಲ್ಲೆ. ಮಸಾಲಾ ದೋಸೆ ಮತ್ತು ರವಾ ಇಡ್ಲಿಗಳೆರಡೂ ದಕ್ಷಿಣ ಭಾರತದ ಜನಪ್ರಿಯ ಭಕ್ಷ್ಯಗಳಾಗಿವೆ, ಪ್ರತಿಯೊಂದೂ ತನ್ನದೇ ಆದ ವಿಶಿಷ್ಟ ರುಚಿ ಮತ್ತು ವಿನ್ಯಾಸವನ್ನು ಹೊಂದಿದೆ. ಮಸಾಲೆಯುಕ್ತ ಆಲೂಗಡ್ಡೆ ತುಂಬುವಿಕೆಯೊಂದಿಗೆ ನೀವು ಗರಿಗರಿಯಾದ ಏನನ್ನಾದರೂ ಆನಂದಿಸಿದರೆ, ಮಸಾಲಾ ದೋಸೆಗೆ ಹೋಗಿ. ನೀವು ವಿಶಿಷ್ಟವಾದ ವಿನ್ಯಾಸದೊಂದಿಗೆ ಹಗುರವಾದ ಆಯ್ಕೆಯನ್ನು ಹುಡುಕುತ್ತಿದ್ದರೆ, ರವಾ ಇಡ್ಲಿಯನ್ನು ಆರಿಸಿಕೊಳ್ಳಿ. ಇದು ಅಂತಿಮವಾಗಿ ನಿಮ್ಮ ಆದ್ಯತೆಗಳನ್ನು ಅವಲಂಬಿಸಿರುತ್ತದೆ!"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jikalau beranak ikut kata bidan'?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah kita hendaklah turut apa yang dikatakann oleh seseorang sekiranya kita berkehendak sesuatu daripadanya."},{"question":"Ònye bụ Onyeisiala Gambia?","answer":"Ònye ísì àlà Gambia bụ Adama Barrow"},{"question":"Dada as seguintes datas de nascimento, indique qual o signo de cada uma:- 18/04/2000- 25/02/1995-25/02/2010","answer":"Segue a lista de datas de nascimento com seus respectivos signos:- 18/04/2000: Áries- 25/02/1995: Peixes-25/02/2010: Peixes"},{"question":"次の段落の内容を書き続けてください： 秋田県では10月4日までに、熊が襲ってきて30人がけがをしました。今まででいちばん多くなっています。北海道や東北、北陸などでは、警報や注意報を出して熊に気をつけるように言っています。 熊の専門家は「熊が食べるどんぐりが、今年はとても少なくて、人が生活している所まで、食べ物を探しに来ています」と言っています。","answer":"専門家は、熊が近くに来ないようにするスプレーや、鈴など音が鳴るものを持ったほうがいいと言っています。山には1人で入らないほうがいいです。人が話す声が熊に聞こえると、熊が近くに来なくなります。そして、もし事故があった場合に連絡ができます。 熊の被害が多い岩手県は、熊が襲ってきたときは、両方の腕で顔や頭を守って、体を丸くして地面の近くまで低くしたほうがいいと言っています。"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Fihavanana tsy tiko ho rava ............................................................ \\"","answer":"\\"  Fihavanana tsy tiko ho rava no tsy anaovako trosa aminao \\""},{"question":"السؤال: في أي عام وشهر كان فتح مكة؟","answer":"الإجابة: في شهر رمضان في العام الثامن للهجرة"},{"question":"ગુજરાતના પ્રાચીન હિંદુ મંદિરોના સ્થાપત્ય અજાયબીઓ અને ઐતિહાસિક અને ધાર્મિક સંદર્ભમાં તેમના મહત્વ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"ગુજરાતના પ્રાચીન હિંદુ મંદિરો આર્કિટેક્ચરલ અજાયબીઓ તરીકે ઊભા છે, જે તેમના બિલ્ડરોની ગહન કારીગરી અને આધ્યાત્મિક ઉત્સાહને પ્રતિબિંબિત કરે છે. મોઢેરાના સૂર્ય મંદિરની જટિલતાઓથી લઈને સોમનાથ મંદિરની ભવ્યતા સુધી, દરેક ઈમારત ભક્તિ, સાંસ્કૃતિક સંશ્લેષણ અને ઐતિહાસિક મહત્વની વાર્તા કહે છે.મંદિરો, ઘણીવાર ઉત્કૃષ્ટ કોતરણી અને શિલ્પોથી શણગારવામાં આવે છે, તે માત્ર પૂજા સ્થાનો તરીકે જ નહીં પરંતુ સાંસ્કૃતિક અને શૈક્ષણિક કેન્દ્રો તરીકે પણ સેવા આપે છે. અડાલજ અને રાણી કી વાવ જેવા આ બાંધકામોની સ્થાપત્યની દીપ્તિ, પ્રાચીન ગુજરાતમાં ઈજનેરી અને સૌંદર્ય શાસ્ત્રની નિપુણતા દર્શાવે છે.આ મંદિરોનો અભ્યાસ ગુજરાતના ઇતિહાસની લાક્ષણિકતા ધરાવતા સામાજિક-ધાર્મિક ગતિશીલતા, વેપાર જોડાણો અને કલાત્મક સિદ્ધિઓની સમજ આપે છે. આ મંદિરો હિંદુ સંસ્કૃતિની શાશ્વત ભાવના અને આ પ્રદેશના વિવિધ સાંસ્કૃતિક પ્રવાહો સાથે તેની જટિલ આંતરક્રિયાના જીવંત પુરાવા તરીકે રહે છે."},{"question":"1999年にモービルと合併し、世界最大の石油会社を誕生させたアメリカの企業はどこでしょう？","answer":"エクソン"},{"question":"Originally, Amazon only sold what kind of product?","answer":"When Jeff Bezos launched Amazon in 1994, the company's primary focus was selling books online. When it first started out, Amazon was primarily an online book seller.But as the firm developed and thrived, it soon diversified into offering a variety of goods, such as toys, apparel, electronics, and more. Amazon has expanded from its original concentration on books to become a global e-commerce behemoth, providing a wide range of products and services."},{"question":"टेलिव्हिजनचा शोध कोणी लावला?","answer":"उत्तर : जॉन लोगी बेअर्ड"},{"question":"Among eukaryotes, replication of DNA takes place in :(1) M phase (2) S phase(3) G1","answer":"Replication of DNA takes place in S-phase of cell cycle in eukaryotes. Most of the cell organellesduplicate in G1phase."},{"question":"Tuliskan sebuah karangan yang bertajuk \\"Peranan ibu bapa membentuk masyarakat penyayang\\".","answer":"Dewasa ini, semakin hari, semangat sayang-menyayangi dalam masyarakat semakin terhakis ditelan arus pemodenan dan kemajuan negara. Hal ini terbukti apabila saban hari kita dihidangkan dengan pelbagai kejadian jenayah seperti kes pembunuhan, ragut, rogol serta kes pembuangan bayi yang tidak berdosa. Kejadian-kejadian tersebut sekali gus memadamkan semangat sayang-menyayangi dalam masyarakat antaranya sikap mengambil berat, prihatin dan saling-menghormati dalam masyarakat. Hal ini demikian kerana masyarakat penyayang hanya dapat dibentuk melalui persaan saling-menyayangi dan menghormati sesama ahli keluarga yang merupakan asas kepada pembentukan masyarakat. Ibu bapa mempunyai peranan besar dalam melahirkan individu yang penyayang sekali gus mewujudkan masyarakat yang penyayang di nusa tercinta ini.            Ibu bapa berperanan memberikan kasih sayang yang secukupnya kepada anak-anak. Kehidupan anak-anak harus diisi dengan kasih sayang oleh ibu bapa dengan menyemai sikap penyayang dalam diri anak-anak sejak kecil lagi seperti kata peribahasa melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Sifat kasih sayang yang dipupuk sejak kecil akan lebih mudah terlaksana malah akan terus sebati dalam diri anak-anak apabila mereka dewasa. Dalam hal ini, kehadiran ibu bapa amat penting dalam tempoh anak-anak membesar. Sebagai contoh, ibu bapa harus sentiasa berada di samping anak-anak semasa mereka dalam kekecewaan seperti  gagal dalam peperiksaan untuk menenangkan hati dan sanubari mereka. Sekiranya, hal ini diberikan perhatian oleh ibu bapa maka anak-anak akan berasa dihargai dan masalah yang mereka alami akan dapat diselesaikan melalui pertolongan ahli keluarga. Tegasnya, ibu bapa harus sedia melapangkan waktu untuk mencurahkan kasih sayang kepada anak kerana ibu bapa merupakan insan terhampir dengan diri anak-anak.            Selain itu, didikan agama juga perlu untuk melahirkan masyarakat yang penyayang di negara kita. Hal ini demikian kerana tidak ada agama yang diturunkan oleh Allah s.w.t yang mengajar penganutnya bersikap kasar dan ganas kepada individu lain apatah lagi dalam kalangan ahli keluarga sendiri. Sehubungan dengan itu, ibu bapa seharusnya mengajar anak-anak mereka mendalami ilmu agama dan mendekatkan diri kepada Tuhan. Contoh amalan yang boleh diajar kepada anak-anak adalah menunaikan solat fardhu, membaca Al-Quran dan berzikir. Bagi penganut-penganut agama lain, ibu bapa perlu selalu mengajak anak-anak mereka ke rumah ibadat. Ibu bapa juga boleh menceritakan pada anak-anak, kisah teladan akan kebaikan mengamalkan nilai kasih sayang dalam kehidupan hatta bersikap kasih sayang kepada binatang.  Amalan-amalan ini akan melembutkan hati dan mententeramkan jiwa serta melahirkan anak-anak yang bersahsiah mulia. Sifat ini akan menjadi darah daging dalam diri anak-anak dan mendorong mereka untuk berperi laku baik seterusnya sentiasa menyayangi keluarga. Oleh itu, tidak dapat dinafikan lagi didikan agama yang secukupnya amat penting dalam melahirkan individu penyayang.            Di samping itu, ibu bapa juga haruslah menunjukkan nilai-nilai yang baik kepada anak-anak mereka. Ibu bapa mestilah menjadi suri teladan kepada anak-anak mereka dan tidak bersikap seperti ketam mengajar anaknya berjalan betul. Hal ini demikian menunjukkan keperibadian anak-anak mencerminkan perwatakan ibu bapa mereka. Banyak nilai baik yang boleh ditunjukkan kepada anak-anak. Sebagai contohnya, ibu bapa mengamalkan semangat kejiranan yang tinggi. Antaranya, mereka perlu melibatkan diri dalam aktiviti gotong-royong, menziarahi jiran yang sakit serta dilanda musibah. Ibu bapa janganlah sekali-kali menunjukkkan sikap zalim dan menindas atau menipu orang lain khususnya di hadapan anak-anak.  Nilai-nilai baik ini akan menjadi ikutan kepada anak-anak. Jelas bahawa, semangat hormat-menghormati, bekerjasama dan saling-membantu dalam masyarakat  akhirnya membentuk sifat penyayang dalam diri anak-anak yang juga merupakan ahli masyarakat.            Seterusnya, keadaan keluarga yang stabil dari segi fizikal dan rohani juga amat perlu bagi melahirkan individu dan masyarakat yang penyayang. Ibu bapa mempunyai peranan besar dalam membentuk keluarga yang stabil. Keluarga yang stabil dari segi fizikal ialah keluarga cukup dari segi kewangan serta mampu menyediakan segala kemudahan dan keperluan hidup berumah tangga. Manakala keluarga yang stabil dari segi rohani ialah keluarga yang saling-menyayangi , hormat-menghormati serta saling-membantu. Sekiranya kedua-duanya dapat dipenuhi oleh ibu bapa maka anak-anak akan hidup dalam keadaan tenang dan harmonis tanpa mengalami sebarang tekanan. Mereka akan lebih terpaut hati untuk berkongsi masalah dengan ibu bapa berbanding menceritakan masalah yang dihadapi dengan rakan yang kurang dikenali hati budinya. Di samping itu juga, ibu bapa harus memastikan hubungan kekeluargaan sesama ahli keluarga erat bagi melahirkan keluarga yang penyayang. Hubungan yang renggang dalam kalangan ahli keluarga menyebabkan anak-anak akan mencari ‘kasih sayang’ di luar rumah yang akhirnya akan menjahanam dan memusnahkan kehidupan mereka.            Masyarakat  penyayang juga dapat dilahirkan melalui hubungan baik dengan masyarakat sekeliling. Ibu bapa harus mendekatkan anak-anak dengan masyarakat setempat bagi mewujudkan hubungan baik dengan masyarakat. Sebagai contoh, ibu bapa boleh mengajak anak-anak untuk menyertai gotong-royong di kawasan tempat tinggal atau solat berjemaah di surau atau masjid. Ibu bapa juga perlu memberikan kesedaran kepada anak-anak mereka akan peri pentingnya nilai kasih sayang dalam kehidupan khususnya semasa berinteraksi dengan masyarakat pelbagai kaum. Dengan menjadikan negara-negara lain sebagai contoh dan teladan seperti perang saudara yang berlaku di Somalia ditambah lagi dengan kebuluran yang berlaku, anak-anak dapat diajar tentang kepentingan amalan kasih sayang. Melalui kasih sayanglah pelbagai bantuan dihulurkan oleh masyarakat antarabangsa kepada negara-negara yang ditimpa bencana seperti bencana Tsunami yang berlaku di Jepun baru-baru ini. Jelas bahawa, hubungan silaturahim yang erat dapat melahirkan individu dan masyarakat yang penyayang.            Konklusinya, ibu bapa berperanan besar dalam melahirkan individu dan sekali gus masyarakat yang penyayang di negara kita. Oleh itu, ibu bapa harus meningkatkan  peranan mereka semaksimum mungkin, namun dalam masa yang sama tidak mengamalkan sikap pilih bulu antara anak-anak. Apa yang diharapkan oleh semua orang ialah amalan kasih sayang yang berjaya dipraktikkkan  akan mampu mewujudkan masyarakat yang sejahtera. Ingatlah!, individu yang penyayang akan mewujudkan keluarga cemerlang seterusnya melahirkan masyarakat serta bangsa yang terbilang."},{"question":"Umhlaba ungumhlaba ngokuhlabaUwuhloniphe uwukhonze uyakuhloniphaUbazonda kabi abazazi ukuhlakanipha.Lunye kuwo uhamboImpinda ayikho.Sinye kuwo isikhathiSifushane aseneleUbupigogo nobusakabuli buyaqedwaBushazwe yizangqotho nemishazo yomhlabaOmahlalothini abantengenyekayo ntengentengeBawe bhu bahuhuluze okwamahoboshaAbaqhwaklazela phezul' onontandakubukwaBaphenduk’izinqibi kugayingane imilomoOsemuva limshwibe shwi limbeke phambiliNgentobeko yobuphansi okwentuthaneUbe phansi nangenzolo ezothile yobuntu.Bhala elinye igama ongalisebenzisa esikhundleni saleli elibhalwengokugqamile kulo musho olandelayo:Abaqhwaklazela phezul' onontandakubukwa","answer":"Abashayela. / abahambela "},{"question":"Sheeg gobolka galgaduud magaalo madaxdiisa ?","answer":"Magaalo madaxdiisu waa dhuusomareeb "},{"question":"Abdulrazaq ladari APC ni Kwara, ariwo lasan ni Lai Muhammed n pa – Awọn Sẹnetọ","answer":"Ọjọ keji ti Minisita fun ibanisọrọ ati aṣa nilẹ yii, Lai Muhammed, pe Gomina ipinlẹ Kwara, Abdulrahman Abdulrasaq, ni ‘one chance’ ni awọn eekan ninu ẹgbẹ APC nipinlẹ naa ti n jade, ti wọn si n sọ ogulutu ọrọ si Lai Muhammed, eyi lo mu ki awọn Sẹnetọ lẹkun mẹtẹẹta ipinlẹ Kwara, Sẹnetọ Lọla Ashiru (Guusu Kwara), Ibrahim Oloriẹgbẹ (Arin Gbungbun Kwara) ati Umar Sadiq (Ariwa Kwara) ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọṣẹ yii, ti wọn si ni gomina Abdulrazaq ni awọn mọ gẹgẹ bii adari ẹgbẹ oṣẹlu Onitẹsiwaju, APC, nipinlẹ Kwara, wọn ni ariwo lasan ni Lai n pa.Wọn jẹ ko di mimọ pe, gbogbo owo ti awọn ri lasiko ìpolongo idibo ọdun 2019, ni awọn na bo ti tọ ati bo ti yẹ, labẹ idari Gomina Abdulrazaq to n dije dupo gẹgẹ bii gomina nigba naa lọhun-un.Ashiru ni ipa malegbagbe ni gomina ṣi n ko lọwọlọwọ bayii nipa idagbasoke ilu pẹlu awọn ohun amayedẹrun to ti ṣe. Ṣugbọn oun ko ni i sọrọ lori nnkan ti Lai Muhammed sọ lori owo ipolongo idibo ọdun 2019, tori pe o ti di ọrọ ọdun meji sẹyin, igba yẹn ti re kọja, igba ọtun si ni awọn wa bayii.Oloriẹgbẹ ni tiẹ so pe awọn ti gbaju mọ akọmọna “O TO GẸ” ti awọn fi dori ipo, bakan naa lawọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ pọ ni, awọn o ya ara awọn lọtọọtọ, o fi kun un pe eto iforukọ ọmọ ẹgbẹ silẹ yoo bẹrẹ pada ni ọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu keje ti a wa yii.Sodiq ni ko ni bojumu ki ẹgbẹ pin yẹlẹyẹlẹ, lẹyin ti ẹgbẹ APC ja ija ominira tan, ti wọn gba agbara."},{"question":"السؤال: من هي التي تزوجها النبي وجعل مهرها عتقها؟","answer":"الإجابة: صفية بنت حيي بن الأخطب"},{"question":"شنوهي اشهر سفينه مذكوره في القرآن ؟","answer":" هي سفينه سيدنا نوح عليه السلام ومذكوره فالقران على انها الفلك وهي اللي حمل فيها سيدنا نوح الكائنات الحيه والمؤمنين اللي امنوا به باش يهربوا من العاصفه والغرق اللي مس المكان اللي كانوا فيه واللي كان غادي يهلك الكفار"},{"question":"Can money buy happiness?","answer":"Whether money can buy happiness is a complex question with no easy answer. Research offers nuanced perspectives on the relationship between wealth and well-being, suggesting it's not quite as simple as a direct purchase. Here's a breakdown of different viewpoints:Arguments for:Meeting basic needs: Having enough money to cover necessities like food, shelter, and healthcare significantly reduces stress and anxiety, laying the foundation for happiness.Increased options and autonomy: Financial security allows for greater control over life choices, including pursuing passions, living in desirable locations, and accessing quality healthcare or education.Experiences and positive emotions: Money can enable us to experience new things, travel, and engage in activities that bring joy and fulfillment, contributing to overall happiness.Studies: Some recent research suggests that income, up to a certain point, can positively correlate with happiness. One study even found the relationship continuing beyond 100,000 for certain groups.Arguments against:Diminishing returns: While money can improve well-being, the impact tends to plateau after basic needs are met. Focusing solely on wealth can lead to neglecting other important aspects of life like relationships and personal growth.Materialism and comparison: Chasing wealth can lead to a focus on possessions and social comparison, breeding dissatisfaction and envy, ultimately hindering happiness.Stress and pressure: Financial pressures and the constant pursuit of more can create stress and anxiety, negating any potential happiness gained from wealth.Individual differences: The relationship between money and happiness varies greatly between individuals. Some find greater fulfillment in meaningful experiences or personal connections, regardless of wealth.The truth likely lies somewhere in the middle. While money can certainly play a role in enhancing well-being, it's not a guaranteed path to happiness. Focusing on fostering strong relationships, pursuing meaningful goals, and cultivating gratitude are equally important for a fulfilling life. Ultimately, the key to happiness lies in finding a balance between financial security, personal fulfillment, and strong social connections."},{"question":"Awọn ọmọ iya meji ti wọn fẹẹ ṣ’oogun owo n’Ijẹbu ti pa iya arugbo o","answer":"Ni Ijẹbu Muṣin lo ti ṣẹlẹ. Awọn ọmọ iya kan naa, Akinọla Akeem ati Muyiwa Akeem fẹẹ lowo ni gbogbo ọna, ni wọn ba lọọ ba oniṣegun kan, Moses Ọduntan ti wọn tun n pe ni Koba, pe ko ṣoogun owo fawọn. Niyẹn ba ni ki wọn mu ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un Naira wa, oogun owo yoo jẹ ṣiṣe. Owo ti oniṣegun fẹẹ gba ti wọn n wa ni wọn ṣe lọọ digunjale, nibẹ ni wọn ti pa iya agbalagba, Christiana, ẹni ọdun mejilelaaadọrin (72).Baba arugbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Ọlatokunbọ lo n fọnnu lọdọ awọn ọrẹ rẹ nile ẹmu pe oun ni owo to to ẹgbẹrun lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹta ataabọ Naira (N550,000) nile oun, oun ko si mọ pe ni  gbogbo igba ti oun n tu aṣiri ara oun yii, Muyiwa Akeem to fẹẹ ṣe oogun owo pẹlu ẹgbọn rẹ wa nibẹ to n gbọ. Kia lo lọọ sọ fun ẹgbọn rẹ, ni wọn ba pada sọdọ Koba, oniṣegun wọn. NI iyẹn ba ṣe oogun fun wọn pe ki wọn lọọ fi ji owo naa wa. Lawọn ọmọ baba kan naa yii ba gba ile Baba Ọlatokunbọ lọ. Bi iyawo rẹ ti ri wọn to si ri i pe ole ni wọn lo fẹẹ pariwo, ni Akinọla ba gba a ̀orun mu, t ofọọ di i lẹnu, lo ba wọ ọ wọ inu yara kan, o si yi i lọrun pa. Niya ba ku.Baba yii ti kọkọ fun wọn ni ẹgbẹrun mẹẹdogun, to ni gbogbo owo to wa lọwo oun niyẹn, ṣugbọn igba to ri i pe wọn fẹẹ pa oun loootọ, o lọọ gbe owo naa jade fun wọn, ẹgbẹrun lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹta ataabọ. Bi wọn ti gba owo naa ni wọn pada wa lati pa baba, oun naa yaa ṣe bi ẹni to ti ku. Wọn ro pe o ti ku ni wọn ṣe fi i silẹ ti wọn lọ. Ni wọn ba gbe owo ti wọn ja gba, o dile Koba. Ni Koba ba fun Akinọla ni ọgọta ẹgbẹrun (N60,000), o fun Muyiwa ni aadọta (N50,000) O ni oun yoo fi eyi to ku ṣe oogun owo fun wọn ni. O ṣe oogun ka fun wọn loootọ, ṣugbọn oogun naa ko ti i di owo lati inu oṣu kẹta ọdun yii ti wọn ti ṣe e, titi ti ọwọ awọn ọlọpaa fi tẹ wọn yii o. Wọn kan pa iya arugbo naa danu lasan ni."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--भीक नको पण कुत्रा आवर","answer":"एखाद्याच्या मनात नसले तर त्याने मदत करू नये परंतु निदान आपल्या कार्यात अडथळा आणू नये अशी स्थिती"},{"question":"O que foi a Política do café com leite? Explique de forma simples!","answer":"A política do café com leite foi uma forma de dividir o poder entre duas regiões importantes do Brasil: São Paulo, que era conhecido por produzir muito café, e Minas Gerais, que era conhecido por produzir muito leite.Essa política do café com leite durou por um bom tempo no Brasil, e foi uma forma de equilibrar o poder entre essas duas regiões importantes.Então, resumindo, a política do café com leite foi um acordo onde São Paulo e Minas Gerais se revezavam no poder para garantir que ambos tivessem uma chance de governar o país."},{"question":"Milazalazà momba ny Festival Angaredona .","answer":"Ny hetsika lehibe Angaredona dia hetsika ara-mozika eto Madagasikara, nisy nanomboka ny taona 2004. Manome sehatra ny karazana mozika sy gadona velona rehetra eto Madagasikara io hetsika io.Hetsika noforonin’i Rajery, ny tanjona mandritra ny Angaredona dia haneho ny lanjan’ny karazana mozika misy eto Madagasikara ( ny lanjany, ny heriny ary ny akony)."},{"question":" صالحیت او د صالحیت د تفویض په برخه کې وضاحت ورکړي؟","answer":"ځواب: صالحیت د مادي او معنوي قدرت او اختیاراتو څخه عبارت دی چې حدود قانون ټاکلي دي او د آمر نه مادون ته د واک انتقالته صالحیت تفویض ګڼل کیږي چې دوه معیاره لري قانوني صالحیت او اداري صالحیت."},{"question":"السؤال: شحال كان عمر علي بن أبي طالب رضي الله عنه لما استشهد ؟","answer":"الإجابة :٦٣ سنة"},{"question":" අප්‍රාණවත් යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"අප්‍රාණවත් යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය ප්‍රාණවත් වේ. "},{"question":"प्रश्न – नारळाचे पाणी कोणता रोग कमी करते?उत्तर – ","answer":"नारळाचे पाणी रक्तदाब कमी करते."},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de pergunta da categoria Música","answer":"Em que ano Khelani lançou seu primeiro álbum de estúdio? 2017"},{"question":"你有没有看过一句自己特别喜欢的话 ？","answer":"1.  世上只有一种英雄主义，就是在认清生活真相之后依然热爱生活。                                                      —罗曼·罗兰2.  人生当苦无妨,良人当归即好。                                                 —《雪中悍刀行》3. 善人宜宽，待恶人当严，待庸众之人宜宽严互存。                                                      —《菜根谭》4. 孤独这两个字拆开来看，有孩童，有瓜果，有小犬，有蚊蝇，足以撑起一个盛夏傍晚间的巷子口，人情味十足。稚儿擎瓜柳棚下，细犬逐蝶窄巷中，人间繁华多笑语，惟我空余两鬓风。孩童水果猫狗飞蝇当然热闹，可都和你无关，这就叫孤独。                                                            —林语堂"},{"question":"உலக நீர் நாள் எப்போது கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது?","answer":"உலக நீர் நாள், ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் அவையின் தீர்மானத்துக்கு இணங்க ஆண்டு தோறும் மார்ச் 22 ஆம் நாள் உலகெங்கும் கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது.1992 ஆம் ஆண்டில் பிரேசிலில் ரியோ டி ஜனெய்ரோ நகரில் இடம்பெற்ற சுற்றுச்சூழல் மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி குறித்து நடைபெற்ற ஐநா பேரவைக் கூட்டத் தொடரில் வைக்கப்பட்ட 21ம் நூற்றாண்டின் செயல் திட்டத்தின்படி 1993, ஜனவரி 18 ஆம் நாள் 47வது ஐ.நா பேரவை கூட்டத் தொடர் 193ம் தீர்மானத்தை நிறைவேற்றியது. அத்துடன் 1993ம் ஆண்டு முதல் ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டின் மார்ச் 22ம் நாளும் உலக நீர் வள நாளாக கொண்டாடத் தீர்மானிக்கப்பட்டது. நீர் வளத்தின் ஒட்டுமொத்தத் திட்டத்தையும் நிர்வாகத்தையும் மேம்படுத்தி நீர் வள பாதுகாப்பை வலுப்படுத்தி நாள்தோறும் கடுமையாகியுள்ள நீர் பற்றாக்குறை பிரச்சினையை தீர்ப்பது என்பது தீர்மானம் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டதன் நோக்கமாகும். அதேவேளையில் மக்களிடையே விரிவாக பிரச்சாரம் செய்து மக்களிடையே அந்தந்த நாட்டின் நீர் வளப் பாதுகாப்பு பற்றி விழிப்புணர்வு வளர்த்தி ஏற்படுத்தவும் கேட்டுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டது."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.වැල් වැල් දිග ඇති - මල් මල් රුව ඇතිරාජ වංහ ඇති - කෑවොත් පණ නැති  ","answer":"නියඟලා"},{"question":"வினா :இந்தியாவின் மிகப்பெரிய காற்றாலை சக்தி அமைந்துள்ள இடம்A. கயத்தாறுB. நான்குநேரிC. செட்டிக்குளம்D. பனங்குடி","answer":"விடை : C. செட்டிக்குளம்"},{"question":"Paragrafın devamını tamamla: İklim değişikliği ile mücadele amacıyla uluslararası düzeyde birçok anlaşma ve protokol kabul edilmiştir. Bunlardan en bilineni 2015 ","answer":"Paris Anlaşması'dır. Bu anlaşma ile ülkeler sera gazı emisyonlarını azaltma taahhütlerinde bulunmuşlardır."},{"question":"ਨਦੀਆਂ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੀ ਆਰਥਿਕਤਾ ਲਈ ਮਹੱਤਵਪੂਰਨ ਕਿਉਂ ਹਨ?","answer":"ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਬੁਨਿਆਦੀ ਮਹੱਤਵ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਦਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਇੱਕ ਬੁਨਿਆਦੀ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਰੋਤ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਗਤੀਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਲਈ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਲਈ, ਨਦੀ ਦੇ ਕਿਨਾਰਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਵਸਨੀਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਕਰਸ਼ਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ. ਇਹ ਬਸਤੀਆਂ ਹੁਣ ਵੱਡੇ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਬਣ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ। ਆਪਣੇ ਰਾਜ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਹਿਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੂਚੀ ਬਣਾਓ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਨਦੀ ਦੇ ਕੰਢੇ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ। ਸਿੰਚਾਈ, ਨੈਵੀਗੇਸ਼ਨ, ਪਣ-ਬਿਜਲੀ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਲਈ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕਰਨਾ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਮਹੱਤਵ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ - ਖਾਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਰਗੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਲਈ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਖੇਤੀਬਾੜੀ ਇਸਦੀ ਬਹੁਗਿਣਤੀ ਆਬਾਦੀ ਦੀ ਰੋਜ਼ੀ-ਰੋਟੀ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਸਰੋਤ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Quelles sont les caractéristiques et les impacts de la révolution numérique sur la société moderne ?","answer":"La révolution numérique est caractérisée par l'utilisation généralisée de la technologie informatique, d'Internet et des dispositifs électroniques. Elle a transformé la communication, l'accès à l'information, les modèles d'affaires, et les emplois. Ses impacts incluent la mondialisation, l'émergence de nouvelles industries, et des préoccupations sur la vie privée et la sécurité des données."},{"question":"Were bimọ sita gbangba l’Ọrẹ, oun lo gbẹbi ara ẹ","answer":"Were bimọ sita gbangba l’Ọrẹ, oun lo gbẹbi ara ẹ Oluṣẹyẹ Iyiade, AkurẹGbogbo awọn to n gbe lagbegbe kootu Majisireeti to wa niluu Ọrẹ, nijọba ibilẹ Odigbo, lẹnu ya pupọ nigba ti wọn ji laaarọ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ to kọja yii, ti wọn si ri were kan ti wọn mọ daadaa lagbegbe ọhun to ti bimọ ọkunrin lantilanti funra rẹ ki ilẹ too mọ.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, aarin oru lọmọ bẹrẹ si i mu obinrin were ọhun, funra rẹ lo da ọmọ naa bi nigba ti ko rẹni gbẹbi fun un.Nigba to bímọ ọhun tan, funra rẹ lo ge iwọ rẹ kuro lara olubi, o fi lara akisa to di mọra nu ẹjẹ ara rẹ, bẹẹ lo tun fi nu ẹjẹ ọmọ to bi.Lẹyin eyi lo ṣẹṣẹ waa fi akisa naa we ọmọ tuntun naa nitori otutu, to si tẹ ẹ sita gbangba nibi tawọn ọlọkada kan ti ba a nigba tilẹ mọ.Awọn alaaanu kan ni wọn pada gbe obinrin alaaganna ọhun ati ọmọ rẹ lọ sile-iwosan ijọba to wa niluu Ọrẹ fun itọju, nibẹ lo si wa titi di asiko ta a fi n kọ iroyin yii lọwọ."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Ny fahafinaretana no tiana ho azo, \\"","answer":"\\" Ny fahafinaretana no tiana ho azo, ka izay nasaina atao lazaina fa mety. \\""},{"question":"In 1948 kreeg de Zwitserse chemicus Hermann Muller de Nobelprijs geneeskunde voor zijn ontdekking van een zeer efficiënte insecticide. Deze werd eerder al gebruikt als geneesmiddel tegen malaria. Goede twintig jaar later werd het product wereldwijd verboden vanwege zeer giftig en uiterst vervuilend. Geef de verkorte naam van deze insecticide.","answer":"DDT "},{"question":"Quand est-ce que le masque à gaz a t-il été inventé ?","answer":"Le masque a gaz a été inventé par un écossais se nommant John Stenhouse en 1854. Ce masque à gaz était déjà capable de filtrer les gaz toxiques à l'homme qui circulaient dans l'air. John Stenhouse, s'est rendu compte à l'époque que certains charbons de bois arrivaient à stopper les particules nocives. Il inventa alors un masque aux formes étranges qui contenait des filtres faits de petits bouts de charbon de bois. Son efficacité fut prouvée et les usines se mirent à en acquérir pour protéger les ouvriers des émanation toxiques et ils n'inhalèrent plus de gaz."},{"question":"ප්‍රථම ලාංකික පුරාවිද්‍යා කොමසාරිස්වරයා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"ප්‍රථම ලාංකික පුරාවිද්‍යා කොමසාරිස්වරයා වූයේ මහාචාර්ය සෙනරත් පරණවිතාන මහතාය."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਥਿਤਿ ਵਾਰੁ ਨਾ ਜੋਗੀ ਜਾਣੈ ਰੁਤਿ ਮਾਹੁ ਨਾ ਕੋਈ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 4 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਕਿਹੜੀ ਥਿੱਤ ਸੀ, (ਕਿਹੜਾ) ਵਾਰ ਸੀ, ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਕੋਈ ਜੋਗੀ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਣਦਾ। ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨਹੀਂ (ਦੱਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ) ਕਿ ਤਦੋਂ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਰੱੁਤ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਕਿਹੜਾ ਮਹੀਨਾ ਸੀ। \\""},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් ප්‍රථම ශතකය වාර්තා කළ ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"සිදත් වෙත්තමුණි"},{"question":"வினா:மரவள்ளிக்கிழங்கு பணியாரம் செய்வது எப்படி?","answer":"விடை:தேவையானவை: மரவள்ளிக் கிழங்கு துருவல் - 3 கப், தோசை மாவு - ஒரு கப், தேங்காய் துருவல் - ஒரு கப், காய்ந்த மிளகாய் - 8, பெருஞ்சீரகம் - ஒரு டீஸ்பூன், எண் ணெய், உப்பு - தேவையான அளவு.செய்முறை: தேங்காய் துருவலுடன் காய்ந்த மிளகாய், பெருஞ்சீரகம் சேர்த்து நீர் விடாமல் நைஸாக அரைக் கவும். இதனுடன் மரவள்ளிக்கிழங்கு துருவல், உப்பு சேர்த்து மேலும் இரண்டு சுற்று சுற்றி எடுக்கவும். தோசை மாவை இதில் சேர்த்து நன்கு கலக்கவும்.குழிப்பணியாரக் கல்லை சூடாக்கி, எண்ணெய் தடவி, காய்ந்ததும் மாவை ஊற்றவும். அடுப்பை 'சிம்’மில் வைத்து, பணியாரங்களைத் திருப்பிப் போட்டு வேகவிட்டு எடுக்கவும்."},{"question":"What is \\"quantum entanglement,\\" and how does it challenge our classical understanding of physics?","answer":"Quantum entanglement is a quantum physics phenomenon where two or more particles become correlated in such a way that their properties are interdependent. It challenges classical physics concepts like locality and realism."},{"question":"Quels sont les principaux défis environnementaux auxquels le monde est confronté aujourd'hui?","answer":"Le monde est confronté à de nombreux défis environnementaux, tels que le changement climatique, la perte de biodiversité, la pollution de l'air et de l'eau, la déforestation, et l'épuisement des ressources naturelles. Ces problèmes ont des conséquences graves pour la planète et exigent des actions concertées à l'échelle mondiale."},{"question":"Paragrafın geri kalanını tamamla: Mobil hizmetler, zaman içinde büyük bir evrim geçirdi. İlk mobil telefonlar sadece ses iletişimini desteklerken, günümüzdeki akıllı telefonlar bir dizi karmaşık hizmeti destekleyebilir. Mobil hizmetlerin hızlı gelişimi, kullanıcıların daha bağlantılı ve bilgiye daha erişilebilir hale gelmelerini sağlamıştır. Mobil hizmetlerin geleceği, 5G teknolojisinin daha ","answer":"yaygın hale gelmesi, Nesnelerin İnterneti (IoT) entegrasyonu ve yapay zeka gibi gelişmelerle şekillenebilir. Bu, daha hızlı veri iletimi, daha akıllı cihazlar ve daha fazla bağlantılı uygulama anlamına gelebilir."},{"question":"Ndeipi mhosva yechipiri inowanikwa pasi rose?","answer":"Mhosva yechipiri yepasi rose mushure mekutengesa zvinodhaka ndeyekutengesa kwevanhu. Kutengeswa kwevanhu kunosanganisira kupinza vanhu basa, kutakura, kuchengetedza, kana kugamuchira vanhu kuburikidza nechisimba, chitsotsi, kana kumanikidza nechinangwa chekushandisa. Kubiridzira uku kunogona kutora nzira dzakasiyana siyana, kusanganisira kumanikidzwa kushanda, kubata pabonde, uye kutengeswa kwenhengo dzemuviri.Kutengeswa kwevanhu kutyora kwakanyanya kwekodzero dzevanhu uye kunoonekwa senyaya yakakosha pasi rose. Nhamburiko dzekurwisa kubiwa kwevanhu dzinosanganisira kudyidzana nedzimwe nyika, mitemo, mishandirapamwe yekuzivisa vanhu, nerutsigiro kune vakabatwa."},{"question":"કયા પાત્રની સૌથી યાદગાર એક્ઝિટ છે?","answer":"જ્યોર્જ ઓ'મેલી, જેનું સિઝન 5 માં દુ:ખદ અવસાન એ શ્રેણી માટે એક મોટો વળાંક હતો"},{"question":"Tambaya: Wanene ya taka Spock a cikin sabon fina-finan Star Trek?","answer":"Zachary John Quinto."},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、最大500語の段落を書いてください： 妊娠しないようにする薬を薬局で売るテストを始める","answer":"「緊急避妊薬」は、妊娠しないようにする薬です。性交してから72時間以内にこの薬を飲んだ場合、妊娠しない割合は80%以上です。薬を飲んだあと、子宮から血が出たり頭が痛くなったりすることがありますが、大きな問題はないと言われています。厚生労働省によると、外国では約90の国や地域で、医者の処方箋がなくてもこの薬を買うことができます。薬を買うときに必要なお金は、イギリスやアメリカなどでは約6000円以下で、日本では1万5000円ぐらいです。日本では医者の処方箋が必要です。夜や日曜日などは病院に行くことができないため、薬局で売ってほしいという意見がありました。厚生労働省は26日、処方箋がない人にこの薬を薬局で売るテストをすると言いました。研修を受けた薬剤師がいて、今までにこの薬を売ったことがある薬局で売ります。早い場合は今年の夏に始めて、来年の3月まで処方箋がなくても問題がないかどうか調べます。"},{"question":"Teknoloji ve tasarım denge ne demek?","answer":"4 – Denge. Denge, hem renklerin, hem görsellerin, hem de yazıların eşit dağılımını ifade eder. Bu denge, göz yormayan bir tasarımı ifade eder ve tasarım ilkeleri arasında önemli bir tanesidir."},{"question":"اعتراض تي مبني پروگرامنگ (OOP) جي پويان اصول ڇا آهي؟","answer":"Object-oriented programming (OOP) ھڪڙو نمونو آھي جيڪو \\"Objects\\" تي ٻڌل آھي، جيڪي ڪلاس جا مثال آھن. ڪلاس ڊيٽا ۽ طريقن کي گڏ ڪن ٿا جيڪي ڊيٽا تي ڪم ڪن ٿا. OOP جي بنيادي اصولن ۾ شامل آهن encapsulation، وراثت، پوليمورفيزم، ۽ تجريد. اهي اصول ماڊلر ۽ منظم ڪوڊ جي اجازت ڏين ٿا، ڪوڊ ٻيهر استعمال ڪرڻ ۽ آسان سار سنڀال کي وڌائڻ."},{"question":"පහත කවිය කුමන වර්ගයේ කවියක්ද?තණ්ඩලේ දෙන්නා දෙපොලේ        දක්කනවාකටු කැලේ ගාලේ නොලිහා වද      දෙනවාහපුතලේ කන්ද දැකලා බඩ            දනවාපවු කල ගොනෝ ඇදපන් හපුතල්  යනවා","answer":"මෙම කවිය කරත්ත කවියකි."},{"question":"Qual è la risposta corretta alla seguente domanda?\\"Chi ha vinto più palloni d'oro, Messi o Ronaldo?\\"","answer":"Tra Messi e Ronaldo, Messi ha vinto più palloni d'oro."},{"question":"මරණිය පාප හත නම් කුමක්ද?","answer":"මරණීය පාප හත නම් මුල් කිතුනු ඉගැන්වීම් හා අනුගාමිකයන්ට උපදෙස් දී ඇත වැටුනාවූ මනුෂ්‍යාගේ පාපයට වහල්වීම (නැඹුරුකම) පිළිබඳව මූලික ලැයිස්තුවක් වේ. මේ මරණීය පාප පිළිබඳව වැරදි වැටහීමක් නම් මේ “මරණීය” පාප නම් දෙවියන් වහන්සේ සමාව නොදෙන පාප ලෙසට. බයිබලයේ පැහැදිලිව පවසනවා දෙවියන් වහන්සේ සමාව නොදෙන පාපය නම් දිගටම පවත්වාගෙන යන මිථ්‍යාදෘෂ්ටිය වේ. මන්ද එය යේසුස් වහන්සේගේ කුරුසියේ මරණය හා යේසුස් වහන්සේ තුළින් ලැබෙන සමාව එපා කරන නිසා. මරණීය පාප හත බයිබලානුකුලද? ඔව් හා නැත. හිතෝපදේශ 6:16-19 පවසනවා “ස්වාමින් වහන්සේ ද්වේෂ (වෛර) කරන කාරණා හයක් ඇත, උන් වහන්සේ පිළිකුල් කරන කාරණා හතක් තිබේ: 1) උඩඟු ඇස් 2) බොරුකාර දිව 3) නිර්දෝෂ ලේ වගුරුවන අත් 4) දුෂ්ඨ උපා යොදන සිත 5) නපුරට දුවන්ට ඉක්මන් වෙන පාද 6) මුසා බස් නික්මවන බොරු සාක්‍ෂිකාරයා හා 7) සහෝදරයන් අතරේ භේද පතුරවන්නා.” කෙසේ වෙතත්, බොහෝ මනුෂ්‍යන් මේ ලැයිස්තුව මරණීය පාප ලෙසට තේරුම් නොගත්තෝය."},{"question":"Aşağıdaki cümlenin daha karmaşık bir versiyonunu oluşturun:Jake Nava'nın yönettiği bir müzik videosu da yapım aşamasında.","answer":"Tabii ki, cümlenin daha karmaşık bir versiyonu \\"Jake Nava tarafından yönetilen ve 15 Aralık 2009'da MySpace'te prömiyerini yapan bir müzik videosu\\"."},{"question":"Quem são os Navajos?","answer":"Navajo é um povo indígena da America do Norte, que vive, principalmente, nos Estados do Arizona, Utah e Novo México nos Estados Unidos da América. Estima-se que 399.494 pessoas vivam na Reserva Navajo e eles são falantes de \\"Diné bizaad,\\" cujo significado é “A linguagem do povo”. A Nação Navajo é a maior tribo, federalmente, reconhecida pelo Governo dos Estados Unidos da América."},{"question":"Sử dụng các từ “chia hết cho”, \\"bội\\", “ước” thích hợp (?):a) – 16 (?) – 2;b) – 18 là (?) của – 6;c) 3 là (?) của – 27.","answer":"Lời giải:a) Vì – 16 = (– 2) . 8 Nên số – 16 chia hết cho số – 2Vậy từ thích hợp điền vào dấu (?) là \\"chia hết cho\\".b) Vì – 18 = (– 6) . 3 Nên – 18 là bội của – 6Vậy từ thích hợp điền vào dấu (?) là \\"bội\\".c) Vì – 27 = 3 . (– 9) Nên 3 là ước của – 27Vậy từ thích hợp điền vào dấu (?) là \\"ước\\". "},{"question":"የእቴጌ ጣይቱ እናት ማን ይባላሉ?","answer":"ወይዘሮ የውብ ዳር"},{"question":"Ερώτηση: Ποιά είναι η σημασία της ψυχολογίας στην ευημερία του ατόμου;","answer":"Απάντηση: Η ψυχολογία παίζει σημαντικό ρόλο στην ευημερία του ατόμου. Βοηθά στην κατανόηση των συναισθημάτων, την αντιμετώπιση του στρες, την προαγωγή της αυτοεκτίμησης και την ανάπτυξη θετικών σχέσεων."},{"question":" Cho tập hợp A = {1; 2; 3; 4} và tập hợp B = {3; 4; 5}. Trong những câu sau, câu nào nói đúng về một tập hợp C gồm các  phần tử thuộc tập A nhưng không thuộc tập hợp B?A. C = {5}     B. C = {1; 2; 5}     C. C = {1; 2}     D. C = {2; 4}","answer":"Các phần tử thuộc tập hợp A mà không thuộc tập hợp B là 1; 2Nên tập hợp cần tìm là C = {1; 2}.Chọn đáp án C."},{"question":"සාල්ලෙක ලාලා පාතට බානා කෙනෙක්කියන්නේ මොකද්ද?මල්ලක දමා පහතට දමන අර්ථය නම් ඇයි කෙනෙක් කියලා දාලා තියෙන්නේ ?","answer":"\\"සාල්ලෙකැ ලාලා පාතට බාන කෙනෙකුන් මෙන්\\"(සාල්ලෙකැ = උඩහල්ලෙකැ / පැසෙකැ/උරයෙකැ)(කිසියම්) කෙනෙකුන් උරයෙකැ ලා පාතට බානවා වගේ, කේවට්ට බමුණාගේ හිසෙහි අසුචි ( වසුරු/ වර්චස්) පිඬක් ( පිණ්ඩයක්/ගුළියක්) හෙළා ( පහතට දමා)...කිසියම් කෙනෙකු උරයෙක දමා/බහා පහතට බාන්නාක් මෙන් (ගිරා පණ්ඩිතයා ද) බමුණාගේ හිස මතට අසුචි/ වසුරු පිඬක් හෙළා...උරයෙක දමා පහතට බෑමේ දී හරියට ම ඉලක්කය කරා යොමු කිරීමට පුළුවන. එවැනි අවස්ථාවක එය කරන කෙනෙකු ද සිටිය යුතුය. ප්‍රධාන ක්‍රියාව වර්චස් පිඬ එල්ලයට ම යොමු කිරීම යි. එය කළ ආකාරය දැක්වීමට ඉහත කී උපමාව යොදා ගෙන ඇත."},{"question":"ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਵੇਲੇ ਘੋੜਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਵਪਾਰ ਦੇ ਕੋਈ ਦੋ ਲਾਭ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਵੇਲੇ ਘੋੜਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਵਪਾਰ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਲਾਭ ਸਨ –  1.   ਇਸ ਵਪਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸਿੱਖ ਅਮੀਰ ਬਣੇ ਅਤੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਧਨ ਦਾ ਵਾਧਾ ਹੋਇਆ ।  2.  ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਤ-ਪ੍ਰਥਾ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਾਰੀ ਚੋਟ ਲੱਗੀ ।"},{"question":"एक नैतिक गुणों वाले बच्चे की कहानी लिखें, जो अपने नैतिक मूल्यों के साथ अद्भुत काम करते हैं।","answer":"उस बच्चे ने हमेशा सच्चाई, न्याय और सहानुभूति के साथ अपने जीवन का हर काम किया, और उनके नैतिकता ने उन्हें बहुत ऊंचाइयों तक पहुँचाया।"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe andevo teo amin'ny tantaran'ny Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny andevo na ondevo na ndevo dia iray amin' ireo saranga ara-tantara telo lehibe teo amin' ny vahoaka malagasy indrindra teo amin' ny Merina teto Madagasikara, niaraka tamin' ny saranga hafa antsoina hoe andriana sy hova. Ny andevo, miaraka amin' ireo saranga hafa, dia nisy ihany koa tamin' ireo foko malagasy lehibe hafa toa ny Betsileo."},{"question":"Yang mana dari berikut ini terbentuk segera setelah pembuahan? Pilih jawabanmu dari: a. sel telur b. sel sperma c. zigot Jawabannya adalah:","answer":"c. zigot"},{"question":"IPL තර​ග ඉතිහාසයේ පිට පිටම දෙවරක් ශූරතා දිනාගත් පළමුවැනි කණ්ඩායම කුමක්ද?","answer":"IPL තර​ග ඉතිහාසයේ පිට පිටම දෙවරක් ශූරතා දිනාගත් පළමුවැනි කණ්ඩායම චෙන්නායි සුපර් කිංග්ස් (CSK - 2010 - 2011) වේ."},{"question":"Alin sa mga sumusunod na probinsya ang matatagpuan sa Mindanao?Lanao del Sur, Antique, Marinduque, Basilan, Dinagat Islands","answer":"Matatagpuan sa Mindanao ang mga probinsya ng Lanao del Sur, Basilan at Dinagat Islands. Sa Visayas matatagpuan ang Antique habang sa Luzon naman matatagpuan ang Marinduque."},{"question":"Ösym'den en az kaç puan almak gerekir?","answer":"2022-YKS'den itibaren SAY, SÖZ, EA ve DİL puan türlerinde sınav puanı hesaplanması için uygulanan TYT puan türünde 150 puan alma şartı ile yerleştirme puanlarının hesaplanmasında; TYT puan türü için 150, SAY, SÖZ, EA ve DİL puan türleri için 180 olan sınav puanı barajı uygulaması kaldırıldı."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన పదంతో సొంత వాక్యం రాయండి:చిత్తశుద్ధి","answer":"చిత్తశుద్ధితో చేసిన ప్రతి పనిలో విజయం లభిస్తుంది."},{"question":"ਸਾਧੂ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਕੌਣ ਸੀ ?","answer":"ਸਾਧੂ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ, ੩ ਸਤੰਬਰ ੧੮੮੯ ਨੂੰ ਪਟਿਆਲਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੰਮਿਆ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਇਸਾਈ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਦੇ ਹੇਠਲੇ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ੧੯੨੯ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੋਇਆ ਸੀ।== ਆਰੰਭਿਕ ਜੀਵਨ ==ਸਾਧੂ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਇੱਕ ਸਿੱਖ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਟਿਆਲਾ ਰਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਸਾਧੂ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਦੈਵ ਸਾਧੂਆਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿਣ ਲੈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਸੀ, ਜੋ ਵਣਾਂ ਜੰਗਲਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੂੰ ਲੁਧਿਆਣਾ ਦੇ ਇਸਾਈ ਸਕੁਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੰਗਰੇਜੀ ਸਿਖਣ ਲਈ ਭੇਜਿਆ, ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਬਾਈਇਬਲ ਖਰੀਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਇੱਕ ਪੰਨਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਦੇ ਸਹਮਣੇ ਸਾੜ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਤਿੰਨ ਰਾਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ, ਰੇਲ ਪਟਰੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਆਤਮਦਾਹ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਇਸਨਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ, ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹ ਇਸਨਾਨ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ, ਸਾਧੂ ਨੇ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਹਾ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ ਸੱਚਾ ਰੱਬ। ਜੇਕਰ ਰੱਬ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਅਸਤਿਤਵ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਰਾਤ ਨਾ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਅਤਮਦਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ। ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਸਵੇਰਾ ਹੋਣ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੀ ਸਾਧੂ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੂੰ ਈਸਾ ਮਸੀਹ ਦਾ ਉਸਦੇ ਛਿਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਹੱਥਾਂ ਸਹਿਤ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਾਂਤ ਹੋਇਆ।"},{"question":"Sheeg Wabiga Jubba Meesha Uu Ku Dhamaado?","answer":"Wabiga Jubba Wuxu Ku Dhamaadaa Meesha La Yiraahdo Goobwayn."},{"question":"ਲੇਖਾਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਕੰਪਨੀ ਦੇ ਫੰਡਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਹੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇਖ-ਰੇਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅਹੁਦੇ ਤੋਂ ਹਟਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਸੂਤੀ ਛੁੱਟੀ 'ਤੇ ਗਈ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅਹੁਦੇ ਤੋਂ ਹਟਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"О каком важном событии этот текст: В составе партизанских войск Поздерац участвовал в марте 1943 года в битве на Неретве, а в мае — июне того же года сражался на Сутьеске. 8 июня 1943 года на плато Вучево в лесу Поздерац был ранен после авианалёта. Его отправили в госпиталь в Тьентиште, но 12 июня от последствий полученных ранений он скончался в Драгош-Седле.","answer":"сражение на Сутьеске"},{"question":"මිනිස් ස්නායු පද්ධතියේ සැකැස්ම කෙසේද?","answer":"ස්නායු පද්ධතියේ මූලික තැනුම් ඒකකය ස්නායු සෛල හෙවත් නියුරෝන වේ. ස්නායුවක් සැදී ඇත්තේ ස්නායු තන්තු සිලින්ඩරාකාර කළඹක් ලෙස සැකසීමෙනි. මේවා මොළයෙන් හා සුෂුම්නාවෙන් ඇරඹී ශරීරයේ සෑම කොටසකටම සම්බන්ධවීම සඳහා දිගින් දිගටම බෙදෙමින් විහිදී යයි. පැරණි ඊජිප්තු, ග්‍රීක හා රෝම වැසියන්ට පවා හඳුනා ගැනීමට තරම් ස්නායු විශාලයි. නමුත් අන්වීක්ෂය සොයා ගන්න තුරු එහි අභ්‍යන්තර ව්‍යුහය පිලිබඳ සොයා ගැනීමට හැකි නොවුණි."},{"question":"Pergunta: Quem foi o presidente da assembleia constituinte da Índia após sua independência? Resposta:","answer":"O presidente da assembleia constituinte da Índia em 1947 foi o Dr. Rajendra Prasad. Ele foi também o primeiro presidente da Índia, eleito pela assembleia constituinte do país em 1950."},{"question":"卫生间的基本构造是什么？","answer":"答：卫生间的基本构造通常包括马桶、洗手池和淋浴设施。一些更大的卫生间可能还包括浴缸、镜子、储物柜等。"},{"question":"О каком важном событии идет речь: В 1992 году из-за территориальных споров между осетинами и ингушами вспыхнул вооружённый конфликт. По состоянию на 2020 год, конфликт в регионе остается замороженным.","answer":"О ингушско-осетинском конфликте."},{"question":"Rong","answer":"Rong"},{"question":"15. O que é a Súmula de Jurisprudência no âmbito da Justiça do Trabalho?","answer":"A Súmula de Jurisprudência é um documento que reúne o entendimento consolidado dos Tribunais Superiores trabalhistas sobre determinada questão jurídica, servindo como orientação para julgamentos futuros."},{"question":"Recap the article:Reporter with the Associated Press. POSTED: August 4, 2013, at 14:41 EST. UPDATED: August 4, 2013, 14:48 EST. With three million Time Warner Cable subscribers still unable to watch CBS on Sunday, they will be unable to watch Tiger Woods' quest to win the Bridgestone Invitational in New York, Los Angeles, Dallas, and other major cities. Withholding CBS from customers in several cities on Friday, the cable provider claimed the network's retransmission fees were excessive compared to what it pays other broadcasters. CBS claims that it has never before experienced a drop from a cable provider and that it has negotiated agreements with AT&T, Cablevision, Comcast, DirecTV, and Verizon, among others. Blackout on CBS: Time Warner Cable terminated CBS in multiple cities due to a disagreement about the cost of broadcasting. Time Warner spokeswoman Maureen Huff stated on Sunday that \\"talks continue.\\" A CBS spokeswoman declined to provide an update on the negotiations' state. The two New York-based businesses have been using full-page print advertisements in regional newspapers to raise awareness of their claims. Customers of Time Warner Cable were also met this weekend with a notice on a white screen stating that the network had made 'outrageous requests' for payments while watching CBS. The message informed viewers that there were still other options to watch their favorite shows, one of which was 'using an antenna to get CBS free over the air.' Despite the fact that anyone with an antenna may receive CBS's signal for free over the air, 85% of CBS viewers watch TV via a pay TV service. In order to protect itself from fluctuations in advertising revenue, CBS is attempting to generate income via retransmission fees. According to analysts, the network's ability to grow depends on its ability to collect money from paid TV subscribers. Time Warner, on the other hand, claims that caving in to requests for increased fees would send users' costs over the roof. In support of its rival, Time Warner, DirecTV declared that it was \\"fighting back against exorbitant programming cost increases.\\" Three hundred thousand...","answer":"Time Warner Cable shut down the CBS network due to billing problems, and the blackout is in effect for a third day.Consumers no longer have access to CBS programming in Dallas, Los Angeles, or New York.A Time Warner representative stated that \\"talks are continuing.\\" Anyone with an antenna can access CBS for free."},{"question":"Dime a qué categoría corresponde la pregunta: ¿Quién ganó el Óscar a mejor película el 2020?","answer":"La categoría es cine."},{"question":"Apakah maksud dengan peribahasa \\"Indah khabar daripada rupa\\"?","answer":"Maksud nya ialah: Sesuatu berita yang biasanya ditokok tambah daripada keadaan sebenarnya."},{"question":"Zer da balio absolutoa matematikan?","answer":"Zenbaki baten balio absolutua bere balio positiboa edo nulua da, zeinuaren arabera. Hau da, balio absolutua ez da inoiz negatiboa eta zenbaki batek zero puntutik duen distantzia adierazten du. Adibidez, -5 eta 5en balio absolutua biak dira 5."},{"question":" ترجم الجملة التالية إلى اللغة العربية“ everyday Ali eats one apple”","answer":"ترجمة الجملة هي كل يوم يأكل علي تفاحة واحدة"},{"question":"Eeyan mẹrin padanu ẹmi wọn ni marosẹ Eko s’Ibadan","answer":"Aago mẹta oru ku iṣẹju mẹwaa lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ kejila, oṣu kẹwaa yii, asiko naa ni tirela kan to fi oju ọna rẹ silẹ to n gba ọna ọlọna, fori sọ ọkọ akero Mazda to n bọ jẹẹjẹ ẹ, o si sọ eeyan mẹrin di oku ninu awọn mẹfa to wa ninu bọọsi akero naa, lagbegbe afara Ṣapade, ni marosẹ Eko s’Ibadan.Alaye ti ọga FRSC nipinlẹ Ogun, Kọmanda Ahmed Umar, ṣe fawọn akọroyin l’Abẹokuta laaarọ ọjọ iṣẹlẹ naa ni pe tirela ti nọmba ẹ jẹ AGL 813 XX, lo wa iwakuwa pẹlu oju ọna ti ki i ṣe tiẹ to n gba bọ.O ni eyi lo jẹ ko kọlu bọọsi akero ti nọmba tiẹ jẹ FDY 265 XA. Umar fi kun un pe eeyan mẹfa lo wa ninu mọto akero naa, ọkunrin marun-un pẹlu obinrin kan.O ni bi tirela naa ṣe fori sọ ọkọ wọn ni ọkunrin mẹta ku lẹsẹkẹsẹ, obinrin kan ṣoṣo to wa ninu ọkọ naa si dagbere faye pẹlu.Ijamba yii ṣee dena gẹgẹ bi Umar ṣe wi, o ni agbegbe to lewu gan-an nibi to ti ṣẹlẹ, awọn awakọ ti wọn ni oju iwoye si mọ eyi. Ṣugbọn awakọ tirela to wakọ tako ofin irinna yii lo mọ-ọn-mọ da wahala to ṣee koore ẹ silẹ, to fi di pe awọn ẹni ẹlẹni tẹri-gbasọ.Ajọ FRSC ba ẹbi awọn to padanu eeyan wọn kẹdun, wọn si ni ki ẹni to ba n wa eeyan rẹ to rin irin ajo, ti ko si gburoo rẹ mọ lati oru naa, wa si ileeṣẹ FRSC to wa ni Ogere lati mọ si i nipa ijamba yii, ki wọn si waa gba awọn ẹru awọn ẹni to doloogbe ninu ijamba naa.Ile igbokuu-si FOS, n’Ipara, ni wọn ko oku awọn mẹrin naa si, bẹẹ ni FRSC si tun n gba awọn awakọ nimọran pe ki wọn yee da wahala silẹ bii eyi, ki wọn yee gba ọna ti ki i ṣe tiwọn nitori oju to n kan wọn."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : గెలీలియో యొక్క పరిశీలనలు ఏమిటి?","answer":"ఇటలీ దేశానికి చెందిన గెలీలియో అన్న మేధావి దూరదర్శినికి మెరుగులు దిద్దాడు.దీనితో యాభై మైళ్ళ దూరంలో ఉన్న ఓడ అయిదు మైళ్ళు దూరాన ఉన్నంత స్పష్టంగా కనిపించేది. ఈ ఆ పరికరం ఖగోళశాస్త్ర అధ్యయనానికి సైతం తోడ్పడింది.గెలీలియో బాగా రాస్తాడు, చక్కగా ఉపన్యాసాలిస్తాడు. కాబట్టి విస్తృత ప్రజాదరణ పొందాడు.కోపర్నికస్ సిద్ధాంతాలు చర్చిస్తూ జ్యూపిటర్ ఉపగ్రహాలను, ఆ గ్రహ పరిభ్రమణాన్ని తాను స్వయంగా చూసిన విషయం శ్రోతలకు చెప్పేవాడు.లోలకంలోని సిద్ధాంతాలను గెలీలియో కనుగొనటంతో మరింత మెరుగైన గడియారాలు తయారు చేయగలిగారు.పీసాలో వాలి ఉన్న భవన శిఖరం నుంచి చేసిన ప్రయోగంలో బరువైన వస్తువులు, తేలికైన వస్తువులు ఒకే వేగంతో కిందకు పడతాయని అతడు నిరూపించాడు."},{"question":"Wyjaśnij znaczenie powiedzenia: \\"Fortuna kołem się toczy.\\"","answer":"\\"Fortuna kołem się toczy\\" to stare przysłowie, które sięga do mitologii rzymskiej, w której Fortuna była właśnie boginią przeznaczenia. Bardzo często jej postać była przedstawiana właśnie z kołem, które wprawione w ruch toczy się tak długo, aż nie podziałają na niego siły zewnętrzne. Jest to bardzo mądre powiedzenie, które uświadamia nam, że przeznaczenie jest cały czas w „ruchu” i jedyne, czego możemy być pewni, to zmiana. Zatem każdego dnia niezależnie od biegu wydarzeń \\"fortuna kołem się toczy\\"."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'di mana bumi dipijak, di situ langit dijunjung'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud menurut adat atau peraturan di tempat yang kita diami atau tinggal."},{"question":"Pergunta: quando é que \\"We are the world\\" foi lançada?","answer":"7 de Março de 1985"},{"question":" Văn bản Thánh Gióng – tượng đài vĩnh cửu của lòng yêu nước viết về vấn đề gì? Vấn đề ấy được nêu khái quát ở phần nào? Qua văn bản, em hiểu truyền thuyết Thánh Gióng có ý nghĩa như thế nào?","answer":"- Văn bản Thánh Gióng – tượng đài vĩnh cửu của lòng yêu nước viết về vấn đề Thánh Gióng chính là tượng đài vĩnh cửu tượng trưng cho lòng yêu nước dân tộc.- Vấn đề ấy được nêu khái quát ở phần 1.- Qua văn bản, em hiểu truyền thuyết Thánh Gióng có ý nghĩa: Minh chứng cho truyền thống giữ nước của dân tộc có từ rất lâu, từ đó củng cổ lòng yêu nước của mọi người."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Ngày 31/7, tin từ Cục Thuế tỉnh Quảng Ngãi cho biết, đơn vị đã ra quyết định xử phạt hành chính và truy thu tiền liên quan đến lĩnh vực thuế đối với 2 doanh nghiệp là Công ty TNHH Pibaly và Công ty CP kết cấu thép Đại Dũng miền Trung - đều có trụ sở tại phân khu công nghiệp Sài Gòn - Dung Quất (xã Bình Thạnh, huyện Bình Sơn, tỉnh Quảng Ngãi) với tổng số tiền hơn 4 tỷ đồng. Cụ thể, Công ty TNHH Pibaly bị xử phạt số tiền hơn 450 triệu đồng vì đã quyết toán sai chi phí được trừ, thu nhập khác khi tính thuế thu nhập doanh nghiệp; xác định sai điều kiện được hưởng ưu đãi thuế thu nhập doanh nghiệp, dẫn đến thiếu số tiền thuế thu nhập doanh nghiệp phải nộp. Cục Thuế tỉnh Quảng Ngãi còn áp dụng các biện pháp khắc phục hậu quả đối với Công ty TNHH Pibaly, gồm: Buộc phải nộp đủ số tiền thuế thiếu vào ngân sách nhà nước số tiền hơn 2,2 tỷ đồng; tiền chậm nộp tiền thuế được tính đến hết ngày 15/7 là hơn 580 triệu đồng. Tổng cộng, Công ty TNHH Pibaly bị truy thu tiền thuế, tiền chậm nộp và tiền phạt hành chính phải nộp vào ngân sách nhà nước gần 3,3 tỷ đồng. Đối với Công ty CP Kết cấu thép Đại Dũng miền Trung, Cục Thuế tỉnh Quảng Ngãi xác định công ty này có 2 vi phạm, gồm: Kê khai sai dẫn đến thiếu số thuế giá trị gia tăng phải nộp; kê khai sai dẫn đến thiếu số tiền thuế thu nhập doanh nghiệp và thuế thu nhập cá nhân phải nộp. Với 2 vi phạm này, Công ty CP kết cấu thép Đại Dũng miền Trung bị phạt hơn 135 triệu đồng. Bên cạnh đó, công ty này còn bị áp dụng biện pháp khắc phục hậu quả, gồm: Buộc nộp đủ số tiền thuế thu nhập doanh nghiệp, thuế thu nhập cá nhân bị thiếu gần 670 triệu đồng; tiền chậm nộp tiền thuế thu nhập doanh nghiệp, thuế thu nhập cá nhân tính đến hết ngày 20/7 hơn 177 triệu đồng. Tổng cộng số tiền thuế truy thu, tiền phạt và tiền chậm nộp mà Công ty CP kết cấu thép Đại Dũng miền Trung phải nộp là hơn 980 triệu đồng.","answer":"Hai doanh nghiệp bị truy thu và xử phạt hơn 4 tỷ đồng vì vi phạm thuế"},{"question":"A seguinte música pertence a qual banda brasileira? \\"Por Enquanto.\\"","answer":"Cássia Eller."},{"question":"ọmọ mélòó ni Gloria Bamiloye bí?","answer":"mẹ́ta ni."},{"question":"Siapakah orang pertama yang menjejakkan kaki di Bulan?","answer":"Neil Armstrong"},{"question":"Man réew moo njëkk a génn ci mbootaayu UE ?","answer":"Royaume Uni mooy réew mi njëkk a génn ci mbootaayu UE."},{"question":"දුරකථනය සොයාගත්තේ කවුද?","answer":"ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් ග්රැහැම් බෙල්"},{"question":"Atsakykite į šį klausimą. Kur buvo įsteigti pirmieji prekybos rūmai?","answer":"Prancūzijoje pirmieji Prekybos rūmai buvo įsteigti 1599 m. (Marselis); inicijavo prekybininkų luomo atstovai. 1700 ir 1701 m. Prancūzijos Vyriausybė įsteigė nemažai tokių rūmų. Iš Prancūzijos paplito tradicija steigti tokius rūmus daugumoje kitų valstybių."},{"question":"Haz un listado de tres lugares para ir a visitar en Bogotá, Colombia.","answer":"1. Cerro de Monserrate: Una de las mejores actividades por hacer en Bogotá es subir al Cerro de Monserrate y disfrutar de las mejores vistas panorámicas de la ciudad.2. Barrio La Candelaria: La Candelaria, está situado en el centro histórico de la ciudad, es el barrio más reconocido por turistas que visitan Bogotá. Uno de sus atractios es poder perderse por sus calles estrechas empedradas y sentir el peso de la historia observando las casas coloniales, con fachadas de colores vivos, es un auténtico placer para los sentidos.3. Museo del Oro: El Museo del Oro, situado entre los 25 mejores museos del mundo según el portal TripAdvisor, es otro de los lugares para visitar durante un viaje a la ciudad de Bogotá."},{"question":"Кандай жаңылмач билесиң ?","answer":"Мына сизге жаңылмач:Жогор жактан сел келет, Сегиз серке тең келет. Куйругун кумга малып келет, Сакалын сууга салып келет."},{"question":"manomeza teny na andian-teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny hoe poatoizay","answer":"ny teny na andian-teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny hoe poatoizay dia hoe miaraka amin'izay, na hoe vetivety monja."},{"question":"Dame una ejemplo de trivia para la categoría: Política","answer":"¿Quién fue el único presidente de EE. UU. que sirvió en la Corte Suprema? El presidente William Howard Taft. Después de su presidencia, Taft fue nombrado como Juez Jefe de la Corte Suprema de los Estados Unidos y ejerció ese cargo desde 1921 hasta 1930."},{"question":"Owahono ukara ing ngisor iki dadi krama alus:\\"Ibu ora doyan mangan sayur bayem.\\"Jawaban:","answer":"Jawaban: Ibu mboten kersa dahar sayur bayem."},{"question":"Descreva um mercado movimentado numa cidade exótica.","answer":"Barracas coloridas exibiam especiarias, artesanato e delícias locais. Sons de regateio e risadas enchiam o ar, enquanto os visitantes exploravam a rica cultura daquele lugar distante."},{"question":"ගෝලීය උණුසුමට මිනිසා විසින් ඇති කරන ලද හේතු මොනවද?","answer":"වන විනාශයශාක යනු ඔක්සිජන් වල ප්‍රධාන ප්‍රභවයයි. ඔවුන් කාබන් ඩයොක්සයිඩ් අවශෝෂණය කර ඔක්සිජන් මුදා හැරීමෙන් පාරිසරික සමතුලිතතාවය පවත්වා ගනී. බොහෝ ගෘහාශ්‍රිත හා වාණිජ අරමුණු සඳහා වනාන්තර විනාශ වෙමින් පවතන අතර . මෙය පාරිසරික අසමතුලිතතාවයට හේතු වී ඇති අතර එමඟින් ගෝලීය උණුසුමද ඉහළ යයි. යාන වාහන භාවිතයඉතා කෙටි දුරක් සඳහා වුවද වාහන භාවිතා කිරීමෙන් විවිධ වායු විමෝචන ඇතිවේ. වාහන වායුගෝලයට කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ් සහ අනෙකුත් විෂ ද්‍රව්‍ය විශාල ප්‍රමාණයක් විමෝචනය කරන පොසිල ඉන්ධන දහනය කිරීමෙන් උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යයි.ක්ලෝරෝෆ්ලෝරෝ කාබන් (CFC)වායු සමීකරණ සහ ශීතකරණ අධික ලෙස භාවිතා කිරීමත් සමඟ මිනිසුන් වායුගෝලීය ඕසෝන් ස්ථරයට බලපාන CFC පරිසරයට මුදා හරිමින්  ඇත. සූර්යයාගෙන් නිකුත් වන අහිතකර පාරජම්බුල කිරණවලින් පෘථිවි පෘෂ්ඨය ආරක්ෂා කරනු ලබන්නේ ඕසෝන් ස්ථරයි. මෙම CFC මගින් ඕසෝන් ස්ථරය ක්ෂය වීම මෙන්ම පාරජම්බුල කිරණ සඳහාද මග පාදමින් පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ නංවා ඇත.කාර්මික සංවර්ධනයකාර්මීකරණය පැමිණීමත් සමඟ පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් ඉහළ යමින් පවතී. කර්මාන්තශාලා වලින් පිටවන අහිතකර වායුන් විමෝචනය වීම පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමට හේතුවක් වේ.2013 දී දේශගුණික විපර්යාස සඳහා වූ අන්තර් රාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලය වාර්තා කළේ 1880 සහ 2012 අතර ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වයේ වැඩිවීම සෙල්සියස් අංශක 0.9 ක් වූ බවයි. පූර්ව කාර්මික මධ්‍යන්‍ය උෂ්ණත්වය හා සසඳන විට වැඩිවීම සෙල්සියස් අංශක 1.1 කි.කෘෂිකර්මයවිවිධ ගොවිතැන් කටයුතු මගින් කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ් සහ මීතේන් වායුව නිපදවේ. මේවා වායුගෝලයේ ඇති හරිතාගාර වායුවලට එකතු වීමෙන් පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩි කරයි.අධික ලෙස් ජනගහනය වැඩි වීම නිසාද ගෝලීය උණුසුම වැඩිවීමට මූලිකම හේතුවකි.ජනගහනය වැඩි වීමම  මිනිස්සු හුස්ම ගන්නවා යන්නයි. මෙයද වායුගෝලයේ ගෝලීය උණුසුම ඇති කරන ප්‍රාථමික වායුව වන කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ් මට්ටම ඉහළ යාමට හේතුවක් වේ.ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමේ ස්වභාවික හේතුගිනි කඳුගිනිකඳු යනු ගෝලීය උණුසුම ඉහළ යාමට විශාලතම ස්වභාවික දායකත්වය සපයන හේතුවකි. ගිනිකඳු පිපිරීම්වලදී පිටවන අළු සහ දුමාරය වායුගෝලයට යාම දේශගුණය වෙනස් වීමට බලපායි.ජල වාෂ්පජල වාෂ්ප යනු හරිතාගාර වායු වර්ගයකි. පෘථිවි උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම හේතුවෙන් ජල මාර්ග වලින් වැඩි ජලය වාෂ්ප ප්‍රමාණයක් පිට වී වායුගෝලයේ රැඳී සිටීම මගින් ගෝලීය උණුසුම වැඩි කරයි.පර්මාෆ්‍රොස්ට් දියවීමපර්මාෆ්‍රොස්ට් යනු ශීත කළ පසක් වන අතර එය වසර ගණනාවක් තිස්සේ පාරිසරික වායූන් එහි සිරවී ඇති අතර , එය පෘථිවි පෘෂ්ඨයට පහළින් පවතී. එය ග්ලැසියරවල රැදී පවතී. මෙම ග්ලැසියර් දියවන විට එය නැවත වායුගෝලයට මුදා හරින අතර එමගින් පෘථිවි උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩි කරයි.ලැව් ගිනිලැව් ගිනි නිසා කාබන් අඩංගු දුමාර විශාල ප්‍රමාණයක් පිටවේ. මෙම වායූන්ද  වායුගෝලයට මුදා හරින අතර පෘථිවියේ උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස ගෝලීය උණුසුමද ඉහළ යයි.ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමේ බලපෑම්උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාමගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම පෘථිවි උෂ්ණත්වයේ ඇදහිය නොහැකි තරම් ඉහළ යාමට හේතු වී තිබේ. මේ හේතුවෙන් ග්ලැසියර දියවීම ඉහළ ගොස් ඇති අතර එය මුහුදු මට්ටම ඉහළ යාමට හේතු වී තිබේ. මෙය වෙරළබඩ කලාපවලට අහිතකර බලපෑම් ඇති කළ හැකිය.පරිසර පද්ධතියට තර්ජනගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම කොරල්පර වලටද බලපා ඇති අතර එමඟින් කොරල් පර හා මුහුදු සත්ව ජීවිත අහිමි වීමට හේතු විය හැකිය. ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය වැඩිවීම නිසා කොරල්පරවල අස්ථාවරත්වය තවත් නරක අතට හැරී ඇත.දේශගුණික විපර්යාසගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම දේශගුණික තත්ත්වයන් වෙනස් වීමට හේතු වී තිබේ. සමහර ප්‍රදේශයන් වල  නියඟත් සමහර ප්‍රදේශයන්ට ගංවතුරද පරස්පර ලෙසින් බල පවත්වයි . මෙම දේශගුණික අසමතුලිතතාවය ගෝලීය උණුසුම ඉහළ යාමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයකි.රෝග පැතිරීමගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම තාපය හා ආර්ද්‍රතාවයේ රටා වෙනස් වීමට හේතු වේ. මෙමගින් රෝග වාහකයන් වන මදුරුවන් හා කෘමීන මගින්  නොයෙක් රෝග පැතිරවීම සිදු විය හැක. ඉහළ මරණ අනුපාතගංවතුර, සුනාමි සහ වෙනත් ස්වාභාවික විපත් වැඩි වීම මගින්  මරණ සංඛ්‍යාවන් වැඩි විය හැක. එසේම, එවැනි සිදුවීම්ද  මිනිස් ජීවිතයට බාධා කළ හැකි රෝග පැතිරීමට හේතු විය හැක.ස්වභාවික වාසස්ථාන අහිමි වීමදේශගුණයේ ගෝලීය වෙනස් කම් නිසා ශාක හා සතුන්ට ව්‍යාප්තිය හා  වාසස්ථාන අහිමි වීමට හේතු වේ. මෙම අවස්ථාවේ දී, සතුන් ඔවුන්ගේ ස්වභාවික වාසස්ථාන වලින් සංක්‍රමණය  වීම සිදු වීමද , ඔවුන්ගෙන් බොහෝ දෙනෙක් වඳ වීමද සිදු විය හැක. මෙය ජෛව විවිධත්වයට ගෝලීය උෂ්ණත්වය ඉහළ යාම නිසාවෙන් සිදු වන තවත් ප්‍රධාන බලපෑමකි."},{"question":"දේදුන්නක වර්ණ පහක් ඇත.","answer":"අසත්‍ය (දේදුන්නට වර්ණ 7ක් ඇත, VIBGYOR)"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"Ny Alahadin'ny _ no Alahady ankalazana ny fidiran'i Jesosy tamim-boninahitra tao Jerosalema.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Ny Alahadin'ny Sampan-drofia no Alahady ankalazana ny fidiran'i Jesosy tamim-boninahitra tao Jerosalema."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा अचाट खाणे मसणात जाणे","answer":"खाण्यापिण्यात अतिरके झाल्यास परिणाम वाईट होतो."},{"question":"Inona ny sandam-bolan'ny Costa Rica?","answer":"Ny vola ofisialin'ny Costa Rica dia ny \\"colón costaricien\\" (CRC)."},{"question":"O ṣẹlẹ: Buhari ju bọmbu ọrọ̀ padà s’Ọbasanjọ","answer":"Nígbà tí Ààrẹ tẹ́lẹ̀  Olóyè Oluṣẹgun Ọbasanjọ, tí kọkọ sọ òkò ọrọ ránṣẹ sí olórí ìjọba ilẹ wa, Muhammadu Buhari, lọsẹ tó kọjá yìí làwọn èèyàn tí mọ pé kò sí kí ọrọ náà má di ìjà àwọn aloku ṣọja méjì, wọn mọ pé Buhari yóò fèsì padà ṣáà ni. Ní irọlẹ Ọjọ Àìkú, Sannde yìí, ní èsì ọrọ náà jáde. Ṣùgbọ́n kí i ṣe èsì lásán, bombu ọrọ ni. Ileeṣẹ Ààrẹ ní bí àwọn kàn bá wá tí wọ́n fẹ́ pín Nàìjíríà sí wẹwẹ, tàbí tí wọ́n fẹ́ sọ àwọn ọmọ Nàìjíríà di ọta ara wọn, irú àwọn èèyàn bẹẹ kò lè ní olórí tàbí alága méjì ju Oluṣẹgun Ọbasanjọ lọ.Bi ẹ ko ba ti i gbagbe, Ọjọbọ to kọja yii, iyẹn ọjọ Alamisi, ni Ọbasanjọ ju oko ọrọ ranṣe si Buhari, nibi ipade kan ti awọn agbaagba ẹya gbogbo ni Naijiria ṣe ni ilu Abuja. Nibẹ ni Ọbasanjọ ti sọ pe Buhari ati ijọba rẹ lo n sọ awọn ọmọ Naijiria di ọta ara wọn, awọn ni wọn n ṣe ijọba ẹlẹyamẹya, oun ko si ri iru rẹ ri lati ọjọ ti oun ti daye. Ṣugbọn Buhari sọrọ, lati ẹnu agbẹnusọ rẹ, Garba Shehu, o ni nigba ti oun Buhari n wa gbogbo ọna lati mu iṣọkan ba Naijiria, Ọbasanjọ pẹlu awọn kan wa nibi kan ti wọn n fi ọrọ ẹsin ati ẹlẹyamẹya pin Naijiria wẹlẹwẹlẹ.Shehu ni Buhari ti ṣe bẹbẹ, ẹgan ni hẹẹ, ati pe gudugudu meje pẹlu yaayaa mẹfa ti baba naa n ṣe lo jẹ ki awọn eeyan bii Ọbasanjọ maa ṣe ilara ẹ, o ni ko si ohun meji to n da Ọbasanjọ laamu ju owu jijẹ lọ. O ni, “Buhari ti sọ Naijiria di ọrẹ awọn ilu odikeji, o ti mu idagbasoke ba eto ọrọ aje, bẹẹ lo ti ṣe agbekalẹ awọn ohun amayedẹrun gbogbo to ti bajẹ, o si tun ku oriṣiriṣi ti yoo ṣe. Ki waa ni awọn bii Ọbasanjọ ko ni i jowu rẹ si, nigba to jẹ ohun ti awọn ko le ṣe ni Buhari n ṣe!”Buhari gba ẹnu Shehu sọro pe ori oke giga ni Ọbasanjọ wa ti gbogbo eeyan to o si, ṣugbọn o ti ko itiju ba awọn ti wọn fẹran rẹ pẹlu awọn ọrọ to n sọ, nitori wọn ro pe yoo maa pari ija nibi ti nnkan ba ti fẹẹ daru ni, ṣugbọn awọn naa ti ri i pe oun gan-an lo n da rugudu silẹ. Omọ Buhari yii waa ni Ọbasanjọ fẹran lati maa fi ara rẹ han gẹgẹ bi Mesaya ti aye n wi, oun naa si maa n ri ara rẹ bẹẹ pe Mesaya kan loun, eleyii lo si maa n jẹ ko ṣiwa hu, tabi ko ṣi ọrọ sọ, ti yoo si maa ro pe ko sẹni to le ṣe ilu daadaa bii toun. O ni nitori ẹ lo ṣe fẹẹ yi ofin pada nijọsi, ko le lo ju saa meji lọ lori aga ijọba, ko too di pe iyẹn ko ṣee ṣe fun un. O ni ki Ọbasanjọ lọọ jokoo jẹẹ, ko sinmi owu jijẹ ati ilara, ko si yee ro pe mesaya nla kan loun."},{"question":"Нарын облусу тууралуу маалымат!","answer":"Нарын облусу - Кыргызстандын борбордук бөлүгүндө жайгашкан. Өрөөндөр менен Ички Тянь-Шандын эңкейиштерин ээлейт жана өлкөдөгү эң чоң регион болуп саналат.Нарын облусу 5 райондон (Нарын району, Кочкор району, Жумгал району, Ат-Башы району, Ак-Таклаа), 1 шаар, 2 шаар тибиндеги поселоктон жана 61 айыл округунан турат.Жеринин аянты - 45 200 км²Калкынын саны - 287 000 (2019)"},{"question":"Wat maakt een goede foto?","answer":"Er zijn drie belangrijke elementen voor een goede foto: 1. licht, 2. onderwerpen en 3. compositie. Goede foto's zijn scherp, hebben een goede belichting (licht) en compositie. Om de perfecte foto te maken, moet je op de juiste brandpuntsafstand staan, het juiste diafragma instellen voor de onderwerpen in je kader, ervoor zorgen dat de sluitertijd is ingesteld voor de actie die je vastlegt (hogere sluitertijd voor sport, lagere sluitertijd voor portretten) en ervoor zorgen dat de ISO correct is ingesteld om samen te werken met zowel de sluitertijd als het diafragma. Het begrijpen van hoe de ISO, het diafragma en de sluitertijd samenwerken, is essentieel voor het maken van de perfecte foto."},{"question":"බුදුන්වහන්සේ විසින් නම් ගෝත්‍ර වශයෙන් සඳහන් කරමින් දේව ගණයාගේ ගුණ වර්ණනා කරනලද සූත්‍ර දේශනාව කුමක්ද ?","answer":"බුදුන්වහන්සේ විසින් නම් ගෝත්‍ර වශයෙන් සඳහන් කරමින් දේව ගණයාගේ ගුණ වර්ණනා කරනලද සූත්‍ර දේශනාව වන්නෙ මහා සමය සූත්‍රය යි."},{"question":"வினா:தியானத்தின் பலன்கள் என்ன?","answer":"விடை:பொதுவாக ஒவ்வொரு மனிதரும் விரும்புவது ஆரோக்கியத்தையும் அமைதியையும் சந்தோஷத்தையும்தான். ஆரோக்கியம் என்பதை நிச்சயமாக உருவாக்கிக் கொள்ளமுடியும். தியானம் என்ற தன்மை நமக்குள் வந்துவிட்டால், அமைதியும் சந்தோஷமும் இயல்பானவை ஆகிவிடும்.தியானம் என்பது செயல் அல்ல, அது ஒரு நிலை. வாழ்க்கையே தியானநிலையில் இருக்கவேண்டும் என்பது தான் நம் நோக்கம். ஏதோ பத்து நிமிடங்களுக்கு கண்ணை மூடி அமர்வதைப் பற்றி நாம் பேசவில்லை. எதைச் செய்தாலும் தியான நிலையில் செய்வதைப் பற்றி பேசுகிறோம். இந்தத் தன்மையையே நமது வாழ்வில் கொண்டுவர விரும்புகிறோம். அப்படி நடந்தால் ஆரோக்கியமாக இருப்பது, அமைதியாக இருப்பது, ஆனந்தமாய் இருப்பது என்பதெல்லாம் முயற்சியின்றி நடக்கும்.தியானத்தின் தன்மை அப்படிப்பட்டது. ஒரு மனிதன் இப்படி இருந்தால் அவனது உடல், மன செயல்பாடுகள் ஒருமுகப்பட்டும் கூர்மையுடனும் இருக்கும். ஒரு மனிதர் அமைதியாகவும், ஆனந்தமாகவும் இருக்கும் போது மட்டுமே அவரது புத்திசாலித்தனம் சிறந்த முறையில் செயல்படும்."},{"question":"கேள்வி:  உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய பீடபூமி எது?","answer":"பதில்: கிங்காய்-திபெத்திய பீடபூமி உலகின் மிக உயரமான மற்றும் மிகப்பெரிய பீடபூமி ஆகும்.குறிப்பு :நிலவியலில் பீடபூமி  என்பது ஒரு வகையான மேட்டு நிலப்பரப்பைக் குறிக்கும். பொதுவாக கடல் மட்டத்தை விட நன்கு உயரமான சம நிலப்பரப்பு பீடபூமி எனப்படுகிறது.உலகின் மிக உயரத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள திபெத் பீடபூமி \\"உலகின் கூரை\\" என கருதப்படுகிறது. இது 25,00,00 சதுர கிலோ மீட்டர் பரப்பளவும், கடல் மட்டத்திலிருந்து 5000 மீ உயரத்திலும் அமைந்துள்ளது. காலநிலை மாற்றங்கள் பீடபூமியினால் ஏற்படும். உதாரணமாக இந்தியாவின் பருவமழை காலங்களில் வரும் பருவக்காற்றை திசை திருப்பும் அளவிற்கு திபெத் பீடபூமி உயரமானது.வட அமெரிக்காவின் கொலெராடோ பீடபூமியும் (337,000 ச.கி.மீ ) குறிப்பிடத்தகுந்த பீடபூமியாகும்."},{"question":"Ileeṣẹ agunbanirọ fiya jẹ mọkanla ninu wọn to n sa lẹnu iṣẹ","answer":"Yatọ si awọn meji to j’Ọlọrun nipe lasiko ti wọn n ṣiṣẹ sin ilẹ baba wọn lọwọ, mọkanla ninu awọn akẹkọọ-jade nileewe giga ti wọn ṣe ìsìnrúùlú wọn nipinlẹ Ọyọ ni ko le ba awọn ẹgbẹ wọn pari eto naa.Eyi ko ṣẹyin bi awọn NYSC, iyẹn ajọ to n ṣakoso eto ìsìnrúùlú nilẹ yii, ẹka ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ṣe fagi le iṣẹ ti awọn agunbanirọ ọhun ṣe fun odidi ọdun kan ti wọn lo nibi eto ọhun.Pẹlu igbesẹ yii, awọn agunbanirọ mọkọọkanla ọhun ko ni i le pada sile koowa wọn lasiko ti awọn yooku wọn ti pari eto ọlọdun kan ọhun, eyi ti wọn ṣe lati fi ṣiṣẹ sin Naijiria ti i ṣe ilẹ baba wọn.Nigba to n sọrọ nibi ayẹyẹ aṣekagba ìṣí keji, ìsọ̀rí keji awọn agunbanirọ ọdun 2020 yii ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ pari ìsìnrúùlú wọn ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Adari ajọ naa, Abilekọ Grace Ogbuogebe, sọ pe niṣe lawọn mọkọọkanla naa maa tun isinruulu wọn ṣe fun odidi ọdun kan. Idi ni pe wọn n sa lẹnu iṣẹ, bẹẹ ni wọn tapa si awọn ofin ati ilana ajọ NYSC mi-in lasiko ti wọn n ṣiṣẹ sin ilẹ baba wọn lọwọ.Awọn akẹkọọ-jade kaakiri awọn ileewe giga ilẹ yii ti wọn jẹ ẹgbẹrun meji ati ẹẹdẹgbẹrun o le meji (2,892) ni wọn kopa ninu eto yii gẹgẹ bi ọga wọn ṣe fidi ẹ mulẹ.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, ẹẹdẹgbẹjọ ati mẹẹẹdọgbọn (1,525) ninu awọn to ṣẹṣẹ sin ilẹ baba wọn tan yii ni wọn jẹ obinrin. Ogoji (40) ninu wọn lo si ṣeto isinruulu wọn nílànà jẹ̀lẹ́ńkẹ́. Ninu awọn wọnyi  la ti ri awọn  alaboyun, awọn to bimọ lasiko eto ọlọdọọdun to pọn dandan naa.O ni eto ọhun ko la ariya lọ lọtẹ yii nitori ajakalẹ arun Korona to wa nita, eyi to n ba gbogbo aye finra.O waa gba awọn akẹkọọ-gboye naa nimọran lati maa ṣamulo gbogbo ẹkọ iwa ifarada, akinkanju ati iwa ọmọluabi ti wọn kọ lasiko ti wọn fi sin ilẹ baba wọn ọhun."},{"question":"Na podstawie podanych dzielnic odgadnij o jakie miasto chodzi?Bemowo, Wawer, Włochy, Ursynów.","answer":"To dzielnice znajdujące się w Warszawie."},{"question":"இன்றைய சிற்பக்கலை குறித்து எழுதுக?","answer":"• இன்று சுதை சிற்பங்களும், கல்சிற்பங்களும் அமைக்கப்பட்டு வருகின்றன.• செங்கல், பைஞ்சுதை (சிமெண்ட்) ஆகியவற்றைக் கொண்டும் கலைநயமிக்க சிற்பங்களை வடிக்கின்றனர்.• வெண்கலம் மற்றும் செயற்கை இழைகள் மூலமாகவும் உருவங்கள் உருவாக்கப் படுகின்றன.• இன்றைய சிற்பக்கலை கோவில்களைக் கடந்து, பலதுறைகளில் தன் இடத்தை நிறைவு செய்கிறது.அ. தட்சிணாமூர்த்தி \\"தமிழர் நாகரிகமும் பண்பாடும்\\" என்ற நூலில் தமிழர் சிற்பக்கலையின் சிறப்பியல்புகளை விளக்கியிருக்கின்றார். அதற்காக மயிலை சீனி வேங்கடசாமி அவர்களின் பின்வரும் கருத்தை தனது நூலில் தருகின்றார். \\"நமது சிற்பங்கள் அயல்நாட்டுச் சிற்பங்களைப்போன்று, வெறும் அழகிய காட்சிப் பொருள்களாக மட்டும் இல்லாமல், காட்சிக்கும் அப்பால் சென்று கருத்துக்களையும் உணர்ச்சிகளையும் ஊட்டுகின்றன.\\" மேலும் வை. கணபதி அவர்களின் பின்வரும் குறிப்பையும் தருகின்றார். \\"நம் நாட்டுச் சிற்பக்கலை மரபின் சிறப்பியல்புகளில் ஒன்று ஆடற்கலையின் இலக்கணங்களையும் இக்கலையில் புகுத்தியதாகும்.\\""},{"question":"1953 மார்ச் 5 இல், இசுடாலினின் இறப்பு நாட்டில் ஓர் அதிகாரப் போட்டியைத் தூண்டியது, இப்போட்டியில், குருசேவ் கட்சியின் முதல் செயலாளராக தனது அதிகாரத்தைப் பலப்படுத்தி வெற்றி பெற்றார். 1956 பிப்ரவரி 25 அன்று, 20 வது கட்சி மாநாட்டில், அவர் ஓர் \\"இரகசிய உரையை\\" நிகழ்த்தினார், இவ்வுரையில் அவர் இசுடாலினின் அரசியல் எதேச்சாதிகாரத்தைக் கண்டித்தார், சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தில் குறைந்த அடக்குமுறை சகாப்தத்தை இவ்வுரை ஏற்படுத்தியது. சாதாரண குடிமக்களின் வாழ்க்கையை மேம்படுத்துவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்ட அவரது உள்நாட்டுக் கொள்கைகள், குறிப்பாக விவசாயத்தில், பெரும்பாலும் பயனற்றவையாக இருந்தன. இறுதியில் தேசியப் பாதுகாப்புக்காக ஏவுகணைகளை நம்புவார் என்று எதிர்பார்த்திருந்த வேளையில், குருசேவ் தேசியப் பாதுகாப்புப் படைகளில் பல குறைப்புகளை அறிவித்தார். இருந்தபோதிலும், குருசேவின் ஆட்சி பனிப்போரின் மிகவும் பதட்டமான ஆண்டுகளைக் கண்டது, இது கியூபா ஏவுகணை நெருக்கடி","answer":"யின் போது உச்சக்கட்டத்தை அடைந்தது."},{"question":"휴대전화 전자파가 꿀벌을 사라지게 한대. ","answer":"꿀벌이 집단 폐사하는 현상(CCD)이 최근 나타났으며, 일부에서는 휴대전화 전자파가 꿀벌의 비행에 방해를 주거나, 꿀벌이 휴대전화 전자파에 영향을 받아 방향 감각을 상실하여 집을 찾지 못하게 되어, 결국 꿀벌 수가 감소한다는 가설이 제기되었습니다.그러나 이와 관련된 연구결과를 분석해본 결과 실험 환경 조건이 매우 미흡하여 실험 결과를 신뢰할 수 없었고, 꿀벌 수의 급격한 감소와 휴대전화 전자파와의 관련성은 없다는 결론이 나왔습니다."},{"question":"Miten sään ennustaminen muuttuu tulevaisuudessa?","answer":"Viidenkymmenen vuoden aikana sään ennustaminen on edennyt jättimäisesti. Sama kehitys näyttää jatkuvan. Ennusteet paranevat edelleen hitaasti ja tasaisesti. Tässä on kuitenkin rajansa, kovin pitkiä yksityiskohtaisia ennusteita emme pysty koskaan tekemään ja aivan lyhytaikaisissakin ennusteissa voi jatkossakin olla virheitä.Ennusteiden paranemiseen ovat vaikuttaneet koulutus, ilmakehän entistä parempi teoreettinen ymmärrys, uudet havaintojärjestelmät sekä kehittyneet ilmakehämallit. Viimeksi mainituilla on ollut ennusteiden paranemisessa ratkaiseva osuus. Ilmakehämalleissa ilmakehän tila määrätään laskemalla. Laitteissa tärkeintä on ollut tietokoneiden kehittyminen. Mitä tehokkaampia tietokoneet ovat suorituskyvyltään, sitä tarkemmin niillä voidaan malleja laskea.Yhden ennusteen sijaan lasketaan jo nykyään useampia ennusteita ja arvioidaan eri ennusteiden todennäköisyyksiä. Tämä kehitys jatkuu myös lähitulevaisuudessa."},{"question":"(Ukhuluma yedwa) Sengathi ngifike ekugcineni-ke manje. Kokunyenobaba angijikele nje. Sengathi ugogo angeze ayizwa le ndabayokubuya kwami. Angiyikhohlwa indlela ajabula ngayo ngishada.Wayelokhu esho ethi umendo ungicelele emadlozini. Ngiyamethembaubaba. Kodwa naye kwakungumuntu wamasiko. Asikaze kodwasixabane naye. Angiboni kodwa ukuthi angavuma ngiganiselwaumuntu ngenkani. Ungcono umama. Angiphathi-ke njengoba kukhonaigugu lakhe uNondumiso. Kwangiyala ukufa madoda. (Athi ukuthula)Omunye umuntu engisafuna ukumthatha ngodlame uDumisani. Ukuthiushintshe nini angiqondi. Ngizomtshela kube kuncane indawo.(Athikaziswe abangenayo)Noma usulapha ekhaya kanti awukhululeki? Phela akusekhona emzinilapha.Sawubona ndodakazi.(Ngeliphansi) Yebo baba.Udadewenu useke wangithi fahla ngodaba lwakho. Nokho-ke ngithenawe ake uzibekele ngawakho ukuze nami ngizwe kahle.1. UZungu ungumlingiswa oyindilinga kulo mdlalo. Sekela lesi sitatimende.","answer":"Izenzo zikaZungu ziyaguquguquka. Ngasekuqaleni kwendaba uZunguuvumelana noMaMbatha mayelana nokuphoqelela uThenjiwe ngaleli sikolokungena. Ngesikhathi indaba iqhubeka ukhombisa ukuzwelana noThenjiwe.Uyabona futhi ukuthi leli siko lokungena kungenzeka ukuthi seliphelelweisikhathi. Ekugcineni uyaguquka futhi, avumelane noMaMbatha baphoqeleleuThenjiwe ukuba avume ukungenwa nguDumisani. Kungenjalo, uzobhekananecala lokuzama ukubulala uDumisani. (Nokunye okunembayo okuyoshiwo ngumfundi)"},{"question":"சிவயோக சுவாமியின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"மனிதன் நெடுக வேலை செய்துகொண்டிருக்கலாம்; வேலை செய்து முடிந்தால் அதைப்பற்றிப் பிறகு நினைத்துத் தொந்தரவு படக்கூடாது."},{"question":"சுபேதார் மேஜர் யோகேந்திர சிங் யாதவ்(பரம வீர் சக்கர விருதாளர்) 1999-இல் நடைபெற்ற","answer":"கார்கில் போரின் போது, புலி மலையை (Tiger Hill) கைப்பற்றுவதற்கு, பாகிஸ்தான் படைகளுக்கு எதிரான இவரது வீர தீரச் செயல்களை பாரட்டும் விதமாக இந்திய இராணுவத்தின் மிக உயரிய பரம வீர் சக்கர விருது இவருக்கு 1999-இல் வழங்கப்பட்டது."},{"question":"લક્ષ્મી નારાયણ મિત્તલ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"લક્ષ્મી નારાયણ મિત્તલ મૂળ ભારતીય નાગરિક અને વિશ્વની સૌથી મોટી સ્ટીલ ઉત્પાદક કંપની આર્સેલર મિત્તલના ચેરમેન અને ચીફ એક્ઝિક્યુટિવ ઓફિસર છે.જુલાઈ 2010ના અંતે મિત્તલ યુરોપમાં સૌથી વધુ ધનવાન વ્યક્તિ અને વિશ્વની પાંચમાં ક્રમની સૌથી ધનાઢ્ય વ્યક્તિ છે જેમની અંગત સંપત્તિ 28.7 અબજ અમેરિકન ડોલર અથવા 19.3 અબજ પાઉન્ડ છે.ફાઇનાન્શિયલ ટાઇમ્સ એ મિત્તલને 2006માં પર્સન ઓફ ધી યર જાહેર કર્યા હતા. ટાઇમ મેગેઝિને મે 2007માં તેમને “100 સૌથી વધુ પ્રભાવશાળી લોકો”માં સ્થાન આપ્યું હતું.2007ના અંતે 946 અબજોપતિઓમાંથી લક્ષ્મી મિત્તલનો સમાવેશ એવી સાત વ્યક્તિમાં થતો હતો જેમણે અંડર ગ્રેજ્યુએટ બિઝનેસ ડિગ્રી ન હોતી મેળવી અને છતાં અબજોપતિ બન્યા હતા"},{"question":"எந்த இந்திய விமான நிலையம் அதன் செயல்பாடுகளை இயக்க சூரிய சக்தியை மட்டுமே பயன்படுத்துகிறது?","answer":"கொச்சி சர்வதேச விமான நிலையம், உலகின் முதல் முழு சூரிய சக்தியில் இயங்கும் விமான நிலையமாகும்."},{"question":"\\"B\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ කී වෙනි අකුර ද?","answer":"\\"B\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ දෙවෙනි අකුර යි."},{"question":"Mẹta lara awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun Alora ko sọwọ ọlọpaa niluu Ileefẹ","answer":"Lẹyin wahala ti awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ba ara wọn fa a niluu Oṣogbo, ti i ṣe olu-ilu ipinlẹ Ọṣun, ni nnkan bii oṣu kan sẹyin, ọwọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti tẹ mẹta lara awọn ti ẹgbẹ Buccaneer ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Alora, niluu Ileefẹ.Ninu wahala ija agba to waye laaarin awọn ẹgbẹ okunkun Ẹyẹ, Aiye ati Alora, niluu Oṣogbo, ni wọn ti pa Akinwale Rotimi lagbegbe Arikalamu, Ṣogo Owonikoko, lagbegbe Ọbatẹ, ati Daniel, lagbegbe Kọlawọle.Latigba naa, gẹgẹ bi Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, Wale Ọlọkọde, ṣe sọ fawọn oniroyin, o ni awọn ọlọpaa ti n dọdẹ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ yii kaakiri ilu Oṣogbo, Ile-Ifẹ ati Ikire.Ọgbọnjọ, oṣu kẹta, ọdun yii, ni ọwọ ba Akintunde Moses, to jẹ ọmọ ọdun mọkanlelogun, Adedayọ Ọlamilekan to jẹ ọmọ ọdun mejilelogun ati Ayọmipọ Oluyẹmi to jẹ ọmọ ogun ọdun.Ibọn pelebe kan, English Revolver Pistol, ni wọn ri lakata wọn, gẹgẹ bi Ọlọkọde ṣe wi, o ni awọn mẹtẹẹta ni wọn sọ pe akẹkọọ lawọn niluu Ileefẹ, ti wọn si jẹwọ pe loootọ lawọn wa ninu Alora.Ọlọkọde waa kilọ fun awọn obi lati ba awọn ọmọ wọn sọrọ daadaa, pe ki wọn jawọ ninu iwa jagidijagan ati iwa ẹgbẹ okunkun ṣiṣe, ai jẹ bẹẹ, awọn naa yoo kawọ pọnyin sọ idi ti wọn fi n ti awọn ọmọ wọn lẹyin ninu iwa ibi."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Na czym polega efekt Dunninga-Krugera?","answer":"Oto odpowiedź. Efekt Dunninga-Krugera polega na tym, że osoby niewykwalifikowane w jakiejś dziedzinie życia mają tendencję do przeceniania swoich umiejętności w tej dziedzinie, podczas gdy osoby wysoko wykwalifikowane mają tendencję do zaniżania oceny swoich umiejętności["},{"question":"பிரெட்ரிக் எங்கெல்ஸ்சின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"கம்யூனிசம் என்பது பாட்டாளி வர்க்கத்தின் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கான சூழ்நிலைகள் பற்றிய அறிவாகும்."},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 24 ਫਰਵਰੀਭਾਰਤੀ ਦੂਰਸੰਚਾਰ ਰੈਗੂਲੇਟਰੀ ਅਥਾਰਟੀ (ਟਰਾਈ) ਨੇ ਟੈਲੀਵਿਜ਼ਨ ਚੈਨਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਡਿਸਟ੍ਰੀਬਿਊਟਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਯਕੀਨੀ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇੱਕੋ ਜਿਹੇ ਚੈਨਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੱਠਿਆਂ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਜਾਵੇ ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਚੈਨਲ ਇੱਕ ਹੀ ਥਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਦਿਖੇ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਉਸਨੇ ਨਿਯਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਅਥਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਨਾ ਕਰਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਡਿਸਟ੍ਰੀਬਿਊਟਰ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਕਾਰਵਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਵੇਗੀ। ਗਾਹਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਇਤ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਦੂਰਸੰਚਾਰ ਰੈਗੂਲੇਟਰੀ ਅਥਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਹੁਕਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਹੁਕਮ ਗਾਹਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਜ਼ਰੀਏ ਤੋਂ ਮਹੱਤਵਪੂਰਨ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਕੋ ਜਿਹੇ ਚੈਨਲ ਇੱਕ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਨਾ ਰੱਖਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਲੱਭਣ ਵਿਚ ਦਿੱਕਤ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਇੱਕ ਹੀ ਚੈਨਲ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਥਾਵਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਦੇਣ ਨਾਲ ਉਸਦੀ ਰੇਟਿੰਗ ਉੱਤੇ ਵੀ ਫਰਕ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਤਾਜ਼ਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਟੀਵੀ ਚੈਨਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਡਿਸਟ੍ਰੀਬਿਊਟਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਰੀ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿਚ ਡੀਟੀਐਚ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧਕ ਤੇ ਮਲਟੀ ਸਿਸਟਮ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧਕ ਵੀ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ। ਟਰਾਈ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੋ ਜਿਹੇ ਚੈਨਲ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਰੱਖਣ ਤੇ ਇੱਕੋ ਚੈਨਲ ਨੂੰ ਕਈ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਦਿਖਾਉਣ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਇਤਾਂ ਮਿਲੀਆਂ ਸਨ। ਟਰਾਈ ਦੇ ਸਲਾਹਕਾਰ (ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ) ਅਰਵਿੰਦ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਨੇ ਏਜੰਸੀ ਨੂੁੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ,‘ਇਹ ਹੁਕਮ ਤੁਰੰਤ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਨਾਲ ਅਮਲ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਟੀਵੀ ਡਿਸਟ੍ਰੀਬਿਊਟਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਪਾਲਣਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ।’ ਇਹ ਹੁਕਮ ਕਦੋਂ ਲਾਗੂ ਹੋਣਗੇ?","answer":"ਇਹ ਹੁਕਮ ਤੁਰੰਤ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਨਾਲ ਅਮਲ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਟੀਵੀ ਡਿਸਟ੍ਰੀਬਿਊਟਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਪਾਲਣਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"முத்துக்குமாரசுவாமி பிள்ளைத்தமிழ் நூற் குறிப்பு தருக. ","answer":"முத்துக்குமாரசுவாமி பிள்ளைத்தமிழ்பிள்ளைத்தமிழ்:முதல் பிள்ளைத்தமிழ் நூல் = ஒட்டக்கூத்தரின் குலோத்துங்கன் பிள்ளைத்தமிழ்பெரியவர்களை குழந்தையாக பாவித்து பாடுதல் ஆகும்இதனை “பிள்ளை கவி, பிள்ளைப் பாட்டு” எனவும் கூறுவர்இது இரு வகைப்படும் = ஆண் பால் பிள்ளைத்தமிழ், பெண்பால் பிள்ளைத்தமிழ்பிள்ளைத்தமிழ் பாடாமல் விலக்கு அளிக்கப்பட்ட கடவுள் = சிவன்முத்துக்குமாரசுவாமி பிள்ளைத்தமிழ்:இதன் ஆசிரியர் குமரகுருபரர்பெற்றோர் – சண்முகசிகாமணிக் கவிராயர், சிவகாமி சுந்தரியம்மைஊர் – திருவைகுண்டம்இயற்றிய நூல்கள் – கந்தர்கலிவெண்பா, மதுரை மீனாட்சி அம்மை பிள்ளைத்தமிழ், மதுரைக் கலம்பகம், சகலகலாவல்லி மாலை, நீதிநெறி விளக்கம் முதலியன.சிறப்பு – தமிழ், வடமொழி, இந்துஸ்தானி ஆகிய மொழிகளில் புலமை மிக்கவர். திருப்பணந்தாளிலும், காசியிலும் தம்பெயரால் மேடம் நிறுவி உள்ளார்.இறப்பு – காசியில் இறைவனடி சேர்ந்தார்.காலம் – பதினேழாம் நூற்றாண்டு."},{"question":"د اوبو د ککړتيا د سمولو له لارې به د ماشومانو د مړينې کچه څومره ښه شي؟ د پخوانۍ پوښتنې په پام کې نیولو سره ، یو داسې شرایط ولیکئ چې ځواب پکې شامل وي. دا د 1 - 20 جملو څخه کیدی شي. په دې اړه:","answer":"د دې په پام کې نیولو سره چې د اوبو ککړتیا د نس ناستې ناروغۍ د لیږد لویه وسیله ده، د پاکو اوبو رسولو او ښه روغتیا ساتنې هڅې کولی شي د ناروغۍ پیښې په ډراماتیک ډول کم کړي. په حقیقت کې، دا وړاندیز شوی چې موږ کولی شو د اوبو د ښه حفظ الصحې او حفظ الصحې په پایله کې د نس ناستې ناروغۍ څخه د ماشومانو په مړینې کې د 88٪ کمښت تمه وکړو. په ورته ډول، د اوبو رسولو او حفظ الصحې د ښه کولو په اړه د ډیری مطالعاتو میټا تحلیل د ناروغیو په پیښو کې له 22٪ څخه تر 27٪ کمښت، او د نس ناستې ناروغۍ سره د مړینې په کچه کې له 21٪ څخه تر 30٪ کمښت ښودلی."},{"question":"Who was Robespierre? Describe any four steps taken by him to bring equality.","answer":"Maximilian Robespierre was the leader of the Jacobin Club.The period from 1793 to 1794 is referred to as the Reign of Terror. Robespierre followed a policy of severe control and punishment.All those whom he saw as being ‘enemies’ of the republic—ex-nobles and clergy, members of other political parties, even members of his party—who did not agree with his methods were arrested, imprisoned, and then tried by a revolutionary tribunal. If the court found them 'guilty', they were guillotined.Robespierre’s government issued laws placing a maximum ceiling on wages and prices. Meat and bread were rationed. Peasants were forced to transport their grain to the cities and sell it at prices fixed by the government.Churches were shut down, and their buildings were converted into barracks or offices."},{"question":"Faaidooyinka Uu Leeyahay Kaluunka?","answer":"FAAIDOOYINKA KALUUNKA LASOLAY,  7 FAAIDO CAAFIMAAD Waa midkamida cunooyinka dadku aadka ujecelyihiin hadaba maogtahay faaidada cajiiba ee laga helo:1=PROTEIN Kaluunka lasolay waxa uu qani kuyahay protein taas o kasacideysa adkaanshaha murqaha jirkada iyo in aay dib u cusbonadaan unugyadena (cells).2=MIISAANKA (culeeyska)Kaluunka lasolay wuxu uyahay fursad dadka doonaya iney iska ridaan culeyska jirkoda sababtuna waxa kuyar dufanta marka loobar bardhigo qaababka kale ee wax lookariyo. 3=CAAFIMAD KA WADNAHA Kaluunka waa il muhim ah oo laga helo #omega3  omega3 waxey muhiim utahay utahay caafimad ka wadnaha xididada dhiiga waxey dajisaa cadadiska dhiiga waxey mamusha reer kulka jirka  iyo caabuqa.4=VITAMIN DWaa meelaha ugu badan ee laga helo vitamin D. Maalintii 4 jeer qofkii qaato kaluunka wuxu helayaa vitamin D 100%  vitamin D waxey muhim utahy cafimadka lafaha wuxu xoojiya difaaca jirka iyo kbdn 5=CAAFIMAD KA MASKAXDA Dadka cuna kaluunka noocyadiisa kala gadisan waxa aad uyar inuu kudhaco xanuunka loyaqaan (Alzheimer disease)Cudurkaan qof ku kudhaco kama reesto sidokale waxa kalumaya xasuusta iyo fikir ka. Waa cudurka asaasaqa. Kaluunka wuxu uficanyahay caafimad ka maskaxda 6=DIFAACA Maadada omega 3 ee laga helo kaluunka waxey ka ilaalisa qofka inuu difaacisu isweeraro gaar ahaan wuxu yareeya in uu kudhaco caruurta macaanka. Sidokale wuxu yareeya xanuunada kala gooys yada. 7=ADKASHAHA LAFAHA Kaluunka lasolay waxa laga helaa calcium madadan ayaa muhiim u ah dhismaha iyo qaabka lafaha ."},{"question":"Продолжи предложение:  В 2011 году с личным рекордом в 8288 очков стал пятым на международных соревнованиях Hypo-Meeting в Австрии, занял 19-е место на","answer":"молодёжном европейском первенстве в Остраве, был восьмым на чемпионате мира в Тэгу."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berbalik gagang\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berpihak kepada musuh. Contoh ayat: Akibat rasa tidak puas hati terhadap ketuanya, Ahmad telah berbalik gagang dengan membocorkan rahsia syarikatnya."},{"question":"Yaa tiriyey gabeyga orod xoogso?","answer":" Mohamud Mohamed Barre."},{"question":"මීසසෝම යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"මීසසෝම යනු බැක්ටීරියා ප්ලාස්ම පටලයේ ඇති අවතලනය වූ නැමීම්ය. ඒවා ඇති වන්නේ ඉලෙක්ට්‍රෝන අන්වීක්ශීය රූප ලබාගැනීමට පිළියෙල කිරීමේදී සිදුකරන රසායනික තිරකිරීමේ තාක්ෂණික ක්‍රම හේතුවෙනි. එසේ වුවද 1960දී මෙම ව්‍යුහවලට බොහෝ ක්‍රියා යෝජනා කරන ලදි, 1970 පසුව මේවා කෘතීම බව හඳුනාගත් අතර තව දුරටත් බැක්ටීරියා සෛලයේ සාමාන්‍ය ව්‍යුහයක් නොවන බව නිගමනය කරන ලදි."},{"question":"Descubra qual o herói dada as seguintes características: Morcego, detetive, milionário. Dica: é da DC universe","answer":"O herói que você está descrevendo provavelmente é o Batman."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--ढवळ्या शेजारी पवळ्या बांधला वाण नाही, पण गुण लागला","answer":"वाईट गुण मात्र लवकर लागतात म्हणजेच वाईट माणसांच्या संगतीने चांगला माणूसही बिघडतो."},{"question":"Qual a regra que explica o acento na palavra \\"Amável\\"","answer":"A palavra \\"amável\\" possui acento agudo no \\"á\\" (a-má-vel) devido à regra de acentuação das palavras paroxítonas com acento tônico na penúltima sílaba que não terminam em ditongo aberto."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أقصر سورةٍ في القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"الجواب: سورة الكوثر."},{"question":"இந்தியாவில் வருமானவரி எந்த ஆண்டு வந்தது?","answer":"1860"},{"question":"Dit toestel was enkele jaren geleden, voor Waze en andere smarthphone-apps hetzelfde deden, heel populair voor de snelheidsduivels onder ons. Officieel is het een rijhulpsysteem. In de praktijk wordt het vooral gebruikt om leden van de community te waarschuwen voor flitspalen en snelheidscontroles. De ontwikkelaar bestaat nog steeds en heeft uiteraard de functionaliteiten inmiddels overgebracht naar een app. Hoe heet dit bedrijf?","answer":"De naam van het bedrijf is Coyote."},{"question":"Zein izan da irakurri duzun azken liburua eta zer pentsatu duzu hori buruz?","answer":" 'Munduaren Amaieran' irakurri nuen eta oso inspiratzailea eta sakona iruditu zitzaidan."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Szczekociny är en stad i Schlesiens vojvodskap i södra Polen. Staden hade 4 115 invånare år 2004. Nära där staden idag ligger ägde slaget om Szczekociny rum ","answer":"den 6 juni 1794 under Kościuszko-upproret."},{"question":"கேள்வி :புல்லாங்குழலில் எத்தனை துளைகள் உள்ளன?1) 82) 73) 94) 10","answer":"பதில் :3) 9"},{"question":"கேள்வி : வேளாண்மை வரியை விதிப்பது ","answer":"பதில் : மாநில அரசு."},{"question":"Inon avy ireo fomba fiteny mety hita ao anaty angano?","answer":"Matetika ny angano dia miatomboka amin’ny hoe: “Indray andro, hono, …”; “nisy, hono,…”; “fahiny elebe, hono,…”; “fahagolan-tany, hono,…”.Fy fiafaran'ny angano mety ahitana ny hoe : “Izany, hono,,..”; “angano, angano, arira, arira,…”"},{"question":"Qui était la compositrice Amy Beach ?","answer":"Amy Beach, compositrice et pianiste américaine, a été une pionnière dans un domaine dominé par les hommes à la fin du XIXe et au début du XXe siècle. Ses compositions englobent des œuvres symphoniques, de la musique de chambre et des chansons, reflétant à la fois des influences romantiques et impressionnistes."},{"question":"Cé hé Jiří Jarošík? ","answer":"Is imreoir sacair Seiceach é Jiří Jarošík a rugadh in Usti Nad Labem i bPoblacht na Seice ar 27 Deireadh Fómhair 1977. Imríonn sé faoi láthair le Ceiltigh Ghlaschú. D'imir sé roimhe sin le Chelsea FC, CSKA Moscú agus Sparta Prág. "},{"question":"இந்தியாவில் உள்ள பெரும் தொழில்களில் மிக பழமையானது?","answer":"விடை: இந்தியாவில் உள்ள பெரும் தொழில்களில் மிக பழமையானது பருத்தி தொழில் ஆகும்."},{"question":"மாமா போட்ட பந்தல் மறுபடி பிரிச்சா கந்தல் அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை: சிலந்தி வலை"},{"question":"David, Jack and Mark are colleagues in a company. David supervises Jack, and Jack supervises Mark. David gets more salary than Jack. What can be inferred from the above statements?A. Jack gets more salary than Mark.B. David gets the same salary as Mark.C. One employee supervises another who earns more than he does. D. One employee supervises another who earns less than he does. ","answer":"The correct answer is D. One employee (David) supervises another (Jack) who earns less than he does. "},{"question":"问题：三星手机的全球研发中心分布在哪些地方？","answer":"答案：三星手机的全球研发中心分布在韩国、美国、中国和其他许多国家。"},{"question":"බුදු දහමේ එන   ඉන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"ඉන්ද්‍රියත්වයෙන් උපකාරක ධර්මය ඉන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය නම් වේ. ඉන්ද්‍රියත්වය නම් අන්‍ය ධර්මයන් තමාට අනුකූල කරවන බව ය. ඒ අනුකූල කරවීම ඒ ඒ ධර්මය ඉපදීමෙන් පසු කරවන්නක් නොව නූපන් ධර්ම තමාට අනුකූල කොට ඉපද වීමකි. එබැවින් ඉන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ජනක ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෙකි.ඉන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ත්‍රි රාශියසහජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයය, පුරේජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයය, රූප ජීවිතේන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයයි ඉන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය තෙවැදෑරුම් වේ. එයින් සහජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ත්‍රි රාශිය මෙසේය.ජීවිතේන්ද්‍රියය, චෛතසිකයය, චිත්තයය, වේදනාවය, ශ්‍ර‍ද්ධාවය, වීර්‍ය්‍යයය, ස්මෘතියය, ඒකාග්‍ර‍තාවය, ප්‍ර‍ඥාවය, යන නාමේන්ද්‍රිය ධර්මයෝ සහජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ධර්මයෝ ය.එකුන් අනූ චිත්තයය, චෛතසික දෙපනසය, චිත්තජ රූපය, ප්‍ර‍තිසන්ධි කර්මජ රූපය යන මොහු සහජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයාගේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්නයෝ ය.බාහිර රූපය, ආහාරජ රූපය, සෘතුජ රූපය, අසංඥ සත්ත්ව කර්මජ රූපය, ප්‍ර‍වෘත්ති කර්මජ රූඵය යන මොහු සහජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යනීකයෝ ය.පුරේජාතින්ද්‍රිය ත්‍රි රාශියආදිම අතීත භවාංග චිත්තය හා උපදනා මධ්‍යමායුෂ්ක පඤ්ච ප්‍ර‍සාදයෝ පුරේජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ධර්මයෝ ය. ද්විපඤ්ච විඥානය හා සර්ව චිත්ත සාධාරණ චෛතසික සත පුරේජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයාගේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්නයෝ ය.ද්විපඤ්ච විඥානයන් ගෙන් අන්‍ය වූ එකුන් අසූ චිත්තයය, චෛතසික දෙපනසය, චිත්තජ රූපය, ප්‍ර‍තිසන්ධි කර්මජ රූපය, බාහිර රූපය, ආහාරජ රූපය, සෘතුජ රූපය, අසංඥ සත්ත්ව කර්මජ රූපය, ප්‍ර‍වෘත්ති කර්මජ රූපය යන මොහු පුරේජාතින්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යනීක ධර්මයෝ ය.රූප ජීවිතේන්ද්‍රිය ත්‍රි රාශියජීවිතේන්ද්‍රිය රූපය, රූප ජීවිතේන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය නම් වේ. කර්මජ කලාපයන්හි ජීවිතේන්ද්‍රියන් අන්‍ය රූපයෝ රූප ජීවිතේන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්නයේ ය. එකුන් අනූ චිත්තයය, චෛතසික දෙපනසය, චිත්තජ රූපය, බාහිර රූපය, ආහාරජ රූපය, සෘතුජ රූපය, ප්‍ර‍තිසන්ධි කර්මජ අසංඥ සත්ත්ව කර්මජ ප්‍ර‍වෘත්ති කර්මජ රූපයන්හි ඇත්තාවූ ජීවිතේන්ද්‍රිය රූපයෝ ය යන මොහු රූප ජීවිතේන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යනීකයෝ ය.දෙවිසි ඉන්ද්‍රිය ධර්මයන් අතුරෙන් ඉත්ථින්ද්‍රිය පුරිසින්ද්‍රිය දෙක ඉන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වශයෙන් නො ගනු ලැබේ. එයට හේතුව ඒ දෙක්හි ජනකත්වය හෝ උපස්ථම්භකත්වය හෝ අනුපාලකත්වයන් නැති බවය. ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයක් වශයෙන් සලකනු ලබන්නේ ඒ ශක්ති තුනෙන් යම්කිසි ශක්ති විශේෂයක් ඇත්තා වූ ධර්ම පමණෙකි. ස්ත්‍රී පුරුෂ භාව රූප දෙකින් සිදු කරන්නේ කර්මාදි අන්‍ය හේතූන් ගෙන් හට ගන්නා රූපයන්හට ස්ත්‍රී පුරුෂාකාරයන් ගැන්වීම ය. ඒ කෘත්‍ය දෙක්හි භාව රූප දෙක අධිපතිකම කරන බැවින් ඒවාට ඉන්ද්‍රිය නාමය ලැබේ. ජනකත්වාදිය නැති බැවින් ඉන්ද්‍රිය ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය නාමය නො ලැබේ."},{"question":"Ọọni Adeyẹye ranṣẹ ikilọ pataki si Sunday Igboho","answer":"Pẹlu bi nnkan ṣe n lọ yii, Ọọni Ile-Ifẹ, Ọba Adeyẹye Ogunwusi, ti ke si Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Sunday Igboho, lati gba ijọba Makinde laaye ko ṣiṣẹ ẹ gẹgẹ bii olori alaabo nipinlẹ Ọyọ.Ọoni Ifẹ sọ pe lootọ ni Sunday Igboho ti ṣiṣe akikanju nipa bo ṣe dide lati ja fun awọn eeyan ẹ, bẹẹ ni awọn ti awọn jẹ ọba alaye yin in paapaa, ṣugbọn bi ọrọ ṣe n lọ yii, ẹtọ ni ko ṣe pẹlẹpẹlẹ, ko ma sọ ara ẹ di ẹni to ga ju ofin lọ, niwọn igba ti awọn alaṣẹ ṣi wa nipo nipinlẹ naa.O ni, “Gbogbo wa la dunnu lori ohun to o ṣe, ṣugbọn nisinyii ti Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde ti lọọ ri Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari lori ọrọ yii, ojuṣe ẹ ni ko o faaye silẹ fun gomina, ẹni ti i ṣe olori alaabo nipinlẹ Ọyọ lati maa ba iṣẹ ẹ ̀lọ. Ohun to dara ni Sunday Igboho gbe dani, bẹẹ lo gbọdọ ṣọra daadaa ki awọn oloṣelu ma lọọ sọ ọ di nnkan mi-in mọ ọn lọwọ.”Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ọjọ meje pere ni Sunday Igboho fun awọn Fulani darandaran ti wọn wa lagbegbe Ibarapa ki wọn fi kuro nibẹ pẹlu awọn nnkan ọsin wọn.Ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn ni pe bi wọn ṣe n ji awọn eeyan gbe, bẹẹ ni wọn n fipa ba obinrin wọn sun, ti wọn si tun n ba awọn nnkan oko wọn jẹ.Bi ọjọ meje ṣe pe ni Igboho atawọn ọmọlẹyin ẹ ko ija lọọ ba awọn Fulani, ti pupọ ninu wọn si fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ nigba ti wọn gburoo ogun tiyẹn n gbe bọ waa ka wọn mọ."},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :১৯১৪ সালে ইম্পেরিয়াল রাশিয়ান সেনাবাহিনী এ এলাকাটি দখল করে এবং এরপরে ১৯১৫ সালে অটোমান সেনাবাহিনী এটি দখল করেছিল। প্রথম বিশ্বযুদ্ধের সময় ব্রিটিশ বাহিনী উসমানীয়দের বিতাড়নের জন্য সেখানে পৌঁছালে তা সরিয়ে নেওয়া হয়। ইরানী সাংবিধানিক বিপ্লবের সময়, কাজার রাজবংশের এবং সময়ের প্রজাতন্ত্র আন্দোলনে পাহ্লাভি রাজবংশ সময়কালে কেরমানশাহের একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভূমিকা পালন করেছিল। ইরান-ইরাক যুদ্ধের","answer":"সময় শহরটি কঠোরভাবে ক্ষতিগ্রস্ত হয়েছিল এবং পুনর্নির্মাণ করা হলেও এটি এখনও পুরোপুরি পুনরুদ্ধারিত হয়নি।"},{"question":"Tìm vị ngữ là cụm động từ, cụm tính từ trong những câu dưới đây. Xác định từ trung tâm và các thành tố phụ trong mỗi cụm từ đó.a) Đôi cánh tôi, trước kia ngắn hủn hoắn, bây giờ thành cái áo dài kín xuống tận chấm đuôi. (Tô Hoài)b) Dế Choắt trả lời tôi bằng một giọng rất buồn rầu. (Tô Hoài)c) Bác bổ sung một số điểm vào bản thảo “Tuyên ngôn Độc lập”. (Theo Bài Đình Phong)d) Chủ tịch Hồ Chí Minh đọc “Tuyên ngôn Độc lập” tại Quảng trường Ba Đình ngày 2-9-1945. (Theo Bùi Đình Phong)","answer":"a) Vị ngữ: trước kia ngắn hủn hoắn (cụm tính từ) bây giờ thành cái áo dài kín xuống tận chấm đuôi. (cụm động từ)*Cụm tính từ: trước kia ngắn hủn hoắn- Thành phần phụ trước: trước kia- Thành phần trung tâm: ngắn- Thành phần phụ sau: hủn hoắn*Cụm động từ: bây giờ thành cái áo dài kín xuống tận chấm đuôi- Thành phần phụ trước: bây giờ- Thành phần trung tâm: thành- Thành phần phụ sau: cái áo dài kín xuống tận chấm đuôi.b) Vị ngữ: trả lời tôi bằng một giọng rất buồn rầu. (cụm động từ)- Thành phần trung tâm: trả lời- Thành phần phụ sau: tôi, bằng một giọng rất buồn rầuc) Vị ngữ: bổ sung một số điểm vào bản thảo “Tuyên ngôn Độc lập”. (cụm động từ)- Thành phần trung tâm: bổ sung- Thành phần phụ sau: một số điểm, vào bản thảo “Tuyên ngôn Độc lập”d) Vị ngữ: đọc “Tuyên ngôn Độc lập” tại Quảng trường Ba Đình ngày 2-9-1945. (cụm động từ)- Thành phần trung tâm: đọc- Thành phần phụ sau: “Tuyên ngôn Độc lập”, tại Quảng trường Ba Đình ngày 2-9-1945"},{"question":"అడుగు, కడుగు, గొడుగు, బుడుగు పదాలను అంత్యప్రాసగా ఉపయోగించి వామనావతారంపై కవితను రాయండి.","answer":"వామనుడైన బుడుగుచేతబట్టెను గొడుగుబలిని తొక్కిన అడుగురాక్షసత్వాన్ని కడుగు – కంచిభొట్ల ఫణిరామ్"},{"question":"ماذا يقاس بالترمومتر المئوي والترمومتر الفهر نهايتي؟","answer":"درجة حرارة الجسم"},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा उतावळा नवरा गुडघ्याला बाशिंग","answer":"प्रसंगी हास्यास्पद ठरेल आशा प्रकराच्या उतावळेपणा दाखविणे."},{"question":"શેખાદમ આબુવાલા ની \\"હવાની હવેલીમાં\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"હવાની હવેલીમાં મહેકે ચમેલી,કવિ મિત્રને વાત આ બહુ ગમેલી.હતી પ્રીત એ તો અમે જાણી લીધું,બહુ ઉભરાઈને પાછી શમેલી.હવે મોત ક્યાંથી વજનદાર લાગે?અમે જિંદગીને ઘણી છે ખમેલી.હશે નમ્રતા એતો ગંગાની ‘આદમ’,હિમાલયની સામે હતી જે નમેલી."},{"question":"How to merge dictionaries and keep values of common keys in a list?","answer":"def merge_and_combine(dict1, dict2):    merged = defaultdict(list)    for d in [dict1, dict2]:        for key, value in d.items():            merged[key].append(value)    return dict(merged)dict1 = {'a': 1, 'b': 2}dict2 = {'b': 3, 'c': 4}print(merge_and_combine(dict1, dict2))  # Output: {'a': [1], 'b': [2, 3], 'c': [4]}"},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. __ saya dapat menyiapkan karangan ini dalam masa yang ditetapkan. Pilihan:  A) Sungguh-sungguhB) Mudah-mudahC) Harap-harapD) Takut-takut","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C) Harap-harap"},{"question":"Mejuo ahịrị okwu a:Oke soro Ngwere maa mmiri.... ","answer":"Azịza:Ọkọọ ngwere ọ gaghị akọ oke.Nke a pụtara n'iso mmadụ eme ihe o mere, onye ahụ nwere ike lafere ma gịnwa agaghị alafere ya. "},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Nama kami berbeza, iaitu Tiger, Heineken dan Guinness, tetapi peranan kami sama. siapakah kami?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah bir. "},{"question":" Sheeg Gabadhii Ugu Horeesay Ee Islaanimo Ku Shahiida","answer":" Waxay Ahayd Sumeya Rc"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da República Centro-Africana?","answer":"0,404."},{"question":"أجب على السؤال التالي \\"ما هي عملة الإمارات ؟\\"","answer":"عملة الإمارات هي: \\"الدرهم\\""},{"question":"在加拿大，當駛入一個交通號誌不工作及無人指揮交通的交叉路口，你應該？","answer":"參考四面停牌的做法，謹慎通過交叉路口。"},{"question":" 2015 ம் ஆண்டில் பிரதமர் அலுவலகம் பெயரில் போலி வெப்சைட் நடத்தி பணம் வசூலித்த நபர் யார்?","answer":"சுதிப்தா சாட்டர்ஜி, 43. கடந்த மூன்று மாதங்களில் ‘பிரதான் மந்திரி ஆதர்ஷ் கிராம் யோஜனா’ திட்டத்தின் கீழ் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட நான்கு போலி இணையதளங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி, நாடு முழுவதிலும் இருந்து சுமார் 50 பேரிடம் சாட்டர்ஜி சுமார் 1.5 கோடி ரூபாய் மோசடி செய்துள்ளார்."},{"question":" கேள்வி: தமிழின் தொன்மையைக்  குறித்து விளக்குக ?","answer":" தமிழ்மொழியின் தொன்மை:தமிழ்மொழி திராவிட இனத்தின் முதல் மொழி ஆகும்.நமக்குக் கிடைத்துள்ள இலக்கியங்களைக் கொண்டு நோக்கினால், சுமார் கி.மு.300க்கு முன்னரே நல்ல நாகரிகத்துடனும் சிறந்த பண்பாட்டுடனும், இலக்கிய வளத்துடன் விளங்கிய மொழி தமிழ்மொழி என்பது புலனாகும். அம்மொழி தோன்றிய காலத்திலிருந்து இன்றளவும் தொடர்ந்து மக்களால் பேசப்பட்டு வரும் மொழி. அது தோன்றிய காலத்தில் தோன்றியதாகக் கருதப்படும் சமஸ்கிருதம், கிரேக்கம், இலத்தீன் போன்ற மொழிகள் வழக்கில் இருந்து நீங்கின.இத்தகைய பழமை வாய்ந்த மொழியில் பல்வேறு மொழிச்சொற்களும் இலக்கியங்களும் இணைந்திருப்பது காலத்தின் கட்டாயத் தேவை என்பதை மட்டும் நாம் உணர்ந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும்.2.1.1 தமிழும் பிறமொழிகளும்தமிழ்மொழி தொன்மைக் காலத்தில் பழந்திராவிட மொழி என்ற நிலையில் இருந்தது. அந்தப் பழந்திராவிட மொழிக் கூறுகள் பலவற்றை அப்படியே கொண்டுள்ள மொழி தமிழ் மட்டுமே. அப்பழந்திராவிடத் தமிழ்மொழியோடு சமஸ்கிருதம் தொடர்பு கொண்டதால் முதலில் பிரிந்த மொழி கன்னடம், அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து தெலுங்கும் துளுவும் அதனைத் தொடர்ந்து மலையாளம் என இன்றைய அளவில் மொழிகள் பிரிந்தன.இவ்வாறு தமிழிலிருந்து தனித்துப் பிரிந்த மொழிகள் எல்லாம் தமக்கென இலக்கிய இலக்கணங்களை உருவாக்கிக் கொண்டன. துளு மொழிக்கு மட்டும் பிற்காலத்தில் இலக்கணம் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது.தமிழோடு தொடக்கக் காலத்தில் நெருங்கிய தொடர்பு கொண்டிருந்த மொழி சமஸ்கிருத மொழி ஆகும். அதிலிருந்து தமிழில் சொற்கள் பல வழக்கிற்கு வந்தன. பிற்காலத்தில் இலக்கியங்கள் மொழிபெயர்ப்பாகவும் தழுவல்களாகவும் தமிழில் இடம் பெற்றன. தமிழிலிருந்து பிரிந்த மொழிகளான கன்னடம், தெலுங்கு, மலையாளம் ஆகிய மொழிகளிலிருந்தும், இந்தியாவின் வடமாநிலங்களில் வழங்கும் குசராத்தி, இந்தி, வங்க மொழி போன்ற மொழிகளிலிருந்தும் இலக்கியங்கள் தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டு உள்ளன. அம்மொழிகளுக்குத் தமிழிலிருந்தும் இலக்கியங்கள் மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.அயல்நாட்டு மொழிகளான ஆங்கிலம், ஜெர்மன், ரஷ்ய மொழிகளிலிருந்தும் கூட இலக்கியங்கள் மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டதோடு தமிழ் இலக்கியங்களும் அம்மொழிகளுக்குப் பெயர்க்கப்பட்டன.இப்படி இலக்கிய வளங்களைக் கொண்டும் கொடுத்தும் இணைந்தே வளர்ச்சி காண வேண்டிய சூழலில் மொழிகள் உள்ளன. இதற்குப் பெரிதும் பயன்படுவது மொழிபெயர்ப்பு ஒன்றே ஆகும்.• இருவகை எண்ணங்கள்பல்வேறு மொழிகளைக் கொண்ட இந்தியாவில் திராவிட மொழிகளும், திராவிடமொழி அல்லாத அயல்மொழிகளும் உள்ளன. வெளிநாட்டு மொழிகளாக ஆங்கிலம் போன்றவை உள்ளன. தமிழிலிருந்து பிறமொழிக்கும், பிறமொழிகளிலிருந்து தமிழிற்கும் மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்ட இலக்கியங்களின் வரலாற்றை இனிக் காணலாம்.• மொழிபெயர்த்தவைஎவற்றை மொழிபெயர்க்க வேண்டும், எவற்றை மொழிபெயர்க்கக் கூடாது என்று முடிவு செய்வதற்கான வரன்முறை எதுவும் இலக்கிய மொழிபெயர்ப்புக்கு இல்லை. ஒருமொழியில் தோன்றிய சிறந்த இலக்கியம் அம்மொழி பேசும் மக்களால் ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளப்பட்டு, காலம் காலமாக வழக்கில் இருந்தால், அந்த இலக்கியம் சிறந்த இலக்கியமாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது. அதே இலக்கியத்தை இருமொழி அறிந்த அறிஞன் ஒருவன், மற்றமொழி பேசும் மக்களுக்கும் பயன்படும் என்ற நோக்கிலோ அல்லது அந்த இலக்கியம் எழுந்த மொழியின் சமூகப் பண்பாட்டு நிலைகளை மற்ற மொழியினரும் அறிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும் என்ற நோக்கிலோ மொழிபெயர்ப்பது இயல்பாக நடக்க வேண்டிய ஒன்று. இத்தகைய இயல்பான நிகழ்ச்சிதான் மொழிபெயர்ப்புக்கான தூண்டு கருவிகளில் ஒன்றாக அமைகிறது.பழங்கால மொழிபெயர்ப்புகள்மொழிபெயர்க்கின்ற எண்ணம் தமிழைப் பொருத்த வரையில் காலத்தில் முற்பட்டது எனலாம். மொழிபெயர்ப்பு எண்ணம் பற்றிய செய்தியினை ''மா பாரதம் தமிழ்ப்படுத்தும் மதுராபுரிச் சங்கம் வைத்தும்'' பாண்டியர்கள் தமிழ் மொழியைக் காத்தனர் என்ற தகவலைச் சின்னமனூர்ச் செப்பேடு சுட்டுகிறது. அந்த மொழிபெயர்ப்பு நமக்குக் கிடைக்கவில்லை.பண்டைய காலத்திலேயே நன்கு வளர்ச்சி அடைந்த இந்திய மொழிகளுள் தமிழ்மொழி தொன்மையானது மட்டுமன்றி, தொடர்ந்து வளர்ந்து வருவதுமாக உள்ளது. அறிவியல் தொழில்நுட்பம் வளராத காலத்திலேயே தமிழர்கள் இந்தியாவின் பிற பகுதிகளிலும் உலகின் ஏனைய பகுதிகளிலும் வணிகத் தொடர்பும் பண்பாட்டுத் தொடர்பும் கொண்டு இருந்தனர். இதனால் பிறமொழியாளர்களுடன் தொடர்பு கொண்டு தம் கருத்தைப் புரிய வைக்க வேண்டியவர்கள் ஆகிவிட்டனர். தமிழ்நாட்டின் சிறப்புமிகு வணிகத் தலமாகக் காவிரிப் பூம்பட்டினம் விளங்கியது. அதன் கடைத்தெருக்களில், ''பதினெண்பாடை மாக்களும்'' அதாவது பதினெட்டு மொழி பேசும் மக்களும் சுற்றித் திரிந்தார்கள் எனப் பட்டினப்பாலை என்ற சங்க இலக்கியமும் மணிமேகலை என்ற காப்பியமும் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன.அவர்களுடன் சீனர், அரேபியர், யவனர் எனப்படும் கிரேக்க ரோமானியர் என்போரும் தமிழ்நாட்டிற்கு வாணிகத்திற்காக வந்து தங்கியுள்ளனர் எனப் பழங்காலத் தகவல்களைத் தரும் தொல்லியல் ஆய்வு குறிப்பிடுகிறது.இத்தகைய சூழலில் அண்டை அயல்நாட்டவருடன் தொடர்பு கொண்டு தங்கள் கருத்தை எடுத்துரைக்க அம்மொழி தெரிந்தவர்கள் சிலராவது இங்கே இருந்திருக்க வேண்டும் அல்லது அவர்களில் சிலராவது தமிழ் மொழியைக் கற்றிருக்க வேண்டும்.கி.மு.215 அளவில் காஞ்சியிலிருந்து சென்ற தூதுக் குழு ஒன்று, சீனப் பேரரசைச் சந்தித்ததாகச் சீனாவின் காலவழிச் செய்திக்கோவை குறிப்பிடுகிறது.இன்றைய திருப்பதி மலைக்கு வடமேற்குப் பகுதியில் தெலுங்கானா என்ற நிலப்பரப்பைக் கடந்து விட்டாலே மொழிபெயர் தேயம் தொடங்கி விடுகிறது என்று சங்ககாலப் புலவர் மாமூலனார் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். இங்கு ''மொழிபெயர் தேயம்'' என்பது தமிழ் தவிர ஏனைய மொழிகளான தெலுங்கு மொழி, கன்னட மொழி பேசும் பகுதி என்று பொருள்.பனிபடு சோலை வேங்கடத்து உம்பர்மொழிபெயர்தேயத்தர் ஆயினும் நல்குவர்என்ற 211ஆவது அகநானூற்றுப் பாடல் அடியின் அடிப்படையில் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு என்ற சொல் கூட உருவாகி இருக்கலாம்.தொல்காப்பியச் சான்று:மொழிபெயர்ப்பின் தெளிவான அறிவு பண்டைத் தமிழருக்கு இருந்திருக்கிறது என்பதற்குத் தொல்காப்பியம் சான்றாக உள்ளது. அதில் நூல்களை வகைப்படுத்தும்போது முதல் நூல், வழிநூல் எனப் பகுக்கப் பட்டுள்ளது. வழி நூலை விளக்கும் போது தொகைநூல், விரிநூல், தொகைவிரி நூல், மொழிபெயர்ப்பு நூல் என நான்கு வகையாகப் பகுத்துக் காட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது. இதற்கான நூற்பா வருமாறு :தொகுத்தல், விரித்தல், தொகைவிரி, மொழிபெயர்த்துஅதர்ப்பட யாத்தலோடு அனை மரபினவே                           எனவே தொல்காப்பியம் தோன்றியதாகக் கருதப்படும் கி.மு. மூன்றாம் நூற்றாண்டில், வேறு பல மொழிகளிலிருந்து மொழிபெயர்ப்புச் செய்யப்பட்ட நூல்கள் தமிழில் இருந்தன எனலாம்.பழந்தமிழ் இலக்கியங்களில் மொழிபெயர்ப்புபுறநானூறு, கலித்தொகை போன்ற சங்கத் தொகை இலக்கியங்களில் 'தருமபுத்திர' என்ற வட சொல் 'அறவன் மகன்' எனவும், 'ஸ்ரீ' என்ற சிறப்பு அடைச்சொல் 'திரு' எனவும் தமிழாக்கம் பெற்றுள்ளன.‘லக்ஷ்மி’ என்ற வடமொழிப்பெயர் முதன் முதலாக மணிமேகலைக் காப்பியத்தில் இலக்குமி என்ற சொல்லாகத் தமிழாக்கம் பெற்றுள்ளது.வாரணாசி என்ற காசியின் பெயரைக் கலித்தொகைப் பாடலில் வாரணவாசி என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளமை பின்வரும் வரிகளால் விளங்கும்.தெருவின்கண் காரணம் இன்றிக் கலங்குவார் கண்டுநீவாரணவாசிப் பதம் பெயர்த்தல், ஏதிலநீ நின்மேல் கொள்வது;                                யமுனா என்ற வடஇந்திய ஆற்றினைச் சங்கத் தமிழர் ''தொழுனை யாற்றினுள் தூமணி வண்ணனை'' என்ற சிலப்பதிகாரத் தொடரின் வழி குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளதை அறியலாம்.பரிபாடலில் நரசிம்ம அவதாரம் ''நரமடங்கல்'' என்றும் பிரகலாதன் ‘பிருங்கலாதன்’ என்றும் குறிப்பிடப்படுவதைக் காணலாம்.சிலப்பதிகாரம் இயற்றப்பட்ட காலத்தில் வடமொழிக் கலப்பு சங்க இலக்கியத்தைக் காட்டிலும் அதிக அளவில் இருப்பதைக் காணமுடிகிறது. குறிப்பாகக் கண்ணகியும் கோவலனும் புகாரை விட்டு மதுரைக்குச் செல்லும் போது இராமனைப் பிரிந்த அயோத்தி போல என்ற குறிப்பைக் காணலாம்.மணிமேகலையிலும் வடமொழிக் கலப்பு மிகுதியாக உள்ளது. இதில் இராமாயணக் குறிப்புக் கையாளப் பட்டுள்ளமை மூன்று காதைகளின் வழி அறிய முடிகிறது.பல்லவர் காலத்திலும் சோழர் காலத்திலும் நிறைய வடமொழிநூல்களின் அறிமுகம் ஏற்பட்டது. இக்காலத்திலிருந்து தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தின் பல்வேறு துறைகளில் நேரடியான மொழிபெயர்ப்புகளும் தழுவல்களும், மொழியாக்கங்களும், சுருக்கமும் விரிவானதுமான நூல்களும் வெளிவந்துள்ளன.பிற்காலத்தில் தெலுங்கு, கன்னடம் ஆகிய மொழிகளைத் தாய்மொழியாகக் கொண்ட ஆட்சியாளர்கள், உருது மொழியைத் தாய்மொழியாகக் கொண்ட இசுலாமியர், ஆங்கில ஆட்சியாளர்கள், ஆங்கிலத்தை தொடர்புமொழியாகக் கொண்ட பிற ஐரோப்பிய ஆட்சியாளர்கள், வணிகர்கள் அவரவர் மொழியையும், இலக்கியங்களையும் தமிழகப் படிப்பாளிகளுக்கு அறிமுகமாக்கினர், அத்துடன் படைப்பாளிகளாகவும் திகழ்ந்து புதிய இலக்கிய வழியைச் செம்மைப் படுத்தியதுடன் புதிய இலக்கிய வடிவங்களையும் உருவாக்கினர்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"beralih tempat\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berpindah ke tempat lain. Contohnya, Fatimah sudah beralih tempat ke Kuala Lumpur dua tahun yang lalu."},{"question":"බුදුන්වහන්සේ විසින් නම් ගෝත්‍ර වශයෙන් සඳහන් කරමින් , දේව ගණයාගේ ගුණ වර්ණනා කරනලද සූත්‍ර දේශනාව කුමක්ද ?","answer":"බුදුන්වහන්සේ විසින් නම් ගෝත්‍ර වශයෙන් සඳහන් කරමින් , දේව ගණයාගේ ගුණ වර්ණනා කරනලද සූත්‍ර දේශනාව වන්නේ මහා සමය සූත්‍රයයි."},{"question":"Wayne Bennett se hizo cargo de Chris Anderson como entrenador del equipo en marzo de 1999.¿Es una paráfrasis de la siguiente oración?Chris Anderson asumió la sucesión de Wayne Bennett como entrenador de equipo en marzo de 1999?","answer":"Sí, la primera oración es una paráfrasis de la segunda oración. Ambas oraciones hablan del cambio de entrenador del equipo en marzo de 1999, pero utilizan diferentes estructuras y enfoques para expresar la misma idea:1) Wayne Bennett se hizo cargo de Chris Anderson como entrenador del equipo en marzo de 1999.2) Chris Anderson asumió la sucesión de Wayne Bennett como entrenador del equipo en marzo de 1999.En ambas oraciones, se indica que un entrenador (Wayne Bennett) dejó su cargo y fue reemplazado por otro entrenador (Chris Anderson) en marzo de 1999."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Barang ini perlu dipecahkan sebelum dimasakkan. Apakah barang ini?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah telur. "},{"question":" waa maxay Duluc? ","answer":" Duluc waxay ka hadasha waxa laga cabanayo iyo dhibaatada jirta ee Ubaahan in wax laga qabto. "},{"question":"Kuinka pitkälle eteenpäin säätä voidaan ennustaa?","answer":"Sääilmiön koko ja elinikä määrää, kuinka hyvin se voidaan ennustaa. Kooltaan laaja ja pitkäaikainen ilmiö voidaan ennustaa useita päiviä etukäteen, mutta yksittäisen sadekuuron syntypaikkaa ei pystytä ennakoimaan.Koska ilmakehä on kaoottinen, emme voi koskaan laskea ilmakehän tilaa eteenpäin tarkasti. Pienikin virhe alkutilan määrittelyssä voi kasvaa suureksi virheeksi parin päivän päähän. Sääennustusmalliin virhettä tulee alkutilanteen määrityksen epätarkkuudesta ja mallin omasta vajavaisuudesta.Suomi on mantereisen ja mereisen ilmaston välimaastossa, jossa matalapaineita liikkuu runsaasti. Tämä vaikeuttaa nimenomaan Suomessa sään ennustamista."},{"question":"Ahitsio izay diso amin’ny fanambarana manaraka :«  Tovovavy sahy tsy azo vazivazina no fijery azy. Manana ny tsangan-kevin, tsy matahotra ny hiady hevitra, tso-piaina ary mahita lavitra hatrany amin’ny aty f. »","answer":"Ity ilay fanambarana voaisy :«  Tovovavy sahy tsy azo vazivazina no fijery azy. Manana ny tsangan-keviny, tsy matahotra ny hiady hevitra, tso-piaina ary mahita lavitra hatrany amin’ny aty fo. »"},{"question":"UC Merced的教学质量如何？","answer":"答：尽管UC Merced是一所年轻的大学，但其在教学和研究方面都有着不错的表现，特别是在工程和自然科学领域。"},{"question":"සිංහල ජන කතාවක් කියන්න","answer":"ගමරාළ පිට්ටු උයපු හැටිඔන්න එක ගමරාළ කෙනෙක් හේනක් කෙටුවා. හේන වටේ දඬු වැටක් බැඳලා, පැලකුත් හැදුවා. මුං, තල, කුරහන්, වට්ටක්කා, කැකිරි, පුහුල්, බටු, බණ්ඩක්කා, ඉරිඟු වගේ බෝග ජාති ගොඩක් වගා කළා. ගමරාල හුඟක් මහන්සි වෙලා වැඩ කෙරුවා. හේන සරු සාරව තිබුණා. ඔන්න ඉතින් අස්වැන්න නෙළන කාලේ ළං වුණා. දැන් තමයි වැඩියෙන් හේන රැක බලා ගන්න ඕන. මොකද කැලේ ඉන්න මුවෝ, වල් ඌරො වගේ සත්තු හේනට ඇවිත් හැමදේම කාලා විනාශ කරල දාන හින්දා. කැලේ සත්තු හේනට එන්නේ රෑට. ඒ හින්ද හේනෙම නවතින්න ඕන කියලා ගමරාල තීරණය කළා.උදේ වරුවම හේනේ වැඩ කරපු ගමරාල ගෙදර ගියා.\\"මේක කරන්න බෑ. වල් ඌරො රංචු පිටින් හේනට පනිනවා. මම අද ඉදලා පැලේ නවතිනවා. හාමිනේ මට ඔය උයා පිහා ගන්න ඕන අඩුම කුඩුම ටික ලෑස්තිකරලා දුන්නනං.\\"ඔන්න එදා හවස ගමරාල ඕන කරන බඩු මුට්ටු ටිකත් අරගෙන, රෑට කන්න බත් මුලකුත් බැදගෙන හේනට යන්න පිටත් වුණා.කන්න දෙයක් හොයාගෙන ගම කිට්ටුවට ආපු නරිරාලට ගමරාලව මුණගැහුණා.\\"මේ බඩු මුට්ටුත් උස්සගෙන කොහෙද යන්නේ?\\" නරිරාල ඇහුවා.''මම යන්නේ පැලේ නවතින්න, නැවතිලා රෑට පැල් රකින්න. නරිරාලත් කැමතිනං යං. අද රෑට කන්න හොඳ බත් මුලකුත් තියනවා.\\" ගමරාල කිව්වා.කන්න බොන්න තියෙනවනං මටත් හොඳයිනේ කියලා හිතපු නරිරාල හරිම කැමැත්තෙන් ගමරාලත් එක්ක පැලට ගියා. කළුවර වැටීගෙන එනකොට ගමරාල  පැල ඉස්සරහ ලොකු ගිනිමැලයක් ගැහුවා. ගෙනාපු බත් මුල දෙන්නත් එක්ක බෙදාගෙන කාලා පැල් රකින්න පටන්ගත්තා.ගමරාලයි, නරිරාලයි එකතු වෙලා හේනට පනින කැලේ සත්තු පන්නල දැම්මා. ඔහොම ටික දවසක් යනකොට සත්තු හේනට පනින එක අඩුවෙලා ගියා. ගමරාල මහන්සි වෙලා පැල් රැකපු නිසා සත්තු හේනට එන එක නැවතුණා. ඒ හින්දා ගමරලාට දැන් සතුටුයි.ඔන්න එක දවසක් ගමරාලට හිතුණා පිට්ටු ටිකක් කන්න.  \\"නරි රාලේ, අද අපි රෑට පිට්ටු කමු.'' ගමරාල කිව්වා. ''පහුගිය ටිකේම නරි රාලත් හුඟක් මහන්සි වුනානේ. වෙනසකටත් එක්ක අද පිට්ටු කමු.\\"''අදහස නං හොඳයි. එත් ඉතින් පිට්ටු හදන්න ඕන කරන දේවල් අපි ළඟ නෑනේ. ඕක හරියන්නේ නෑ.'' නරියා කිව්වා.''ඒකට මොකද. මං හදන්නන්කො. නරි රාල බලන් ඉන්නකො. අද රෑට අපි පිට්ටු කනවමයි.\\" මෙහෙම කියපු ගමරාල පිට්ටු හදන්න පටන් ගත්තා.පොල් ගාලා, පිටි අනලා, පිට්ටු මිශ්‍රනේ හැදුවා. දැන් මේ මිශ්‍රනේ තම්බන්න ඕන. වතුර මුට්ටියක කටට රෙදි කෑල්ලක් බැඳලා, ඒක උඩට පිටි මිශ්‍රනේ දාලා, වහලා, ලිප උඩ තියලා තම්බගන්න ඕන. දැන් තමයි ප්‍රශ්නේ. මුට්ටියට බඳින්න රෙදි කෑල්ලක් නෑ. ගමරාල ටිකක් කල්පනා කලා.''ඕකනේ, මම කිව්වේ. ඔය වැඩේ හරියන්නේ නෑ.\\" නරියා කිව්වා.ගමරාලට තමන් ඇඳ ගෙන ඉන්න අමුඩ ලේන්සුව මතක් වුණා. ''වැඩේ හරි.'' කියලා ගමරාල, ඇඳ ගෙන ඉන්න අමුඩ ලේන්සුව ඉණේ තියෙද්දීම ලේන්සුවේ ඉස්සරහ කොටස මුට්ටියේ කටට තියල ගැට ගැහුවා.ඊට පස්සේ ඒක උඩට පිටි ටික දාලා, මැටි කෝප්පයකින් වහලා, ලිප උඩින් තිබ්බා. ගමරාලත් ලිප ලඟ දණ ගහගෙන ඉන්නවා. ඇයි, ගමරාල අමුඩය ඇඳ ගෙනනේ ඉන්නේ.\\"ඔය වැඩේ හරියන්නේ නෑ.\\" කියලා නරියා හැම වෙලේම කියව කියව හිටියා. ගමරාල ඒවා ගණන් ගත්තේ නෑ. හොඳට ලිප මොලවලා, ලිප ලඟට වෙලා ඉන්නවා.රස්නෙත් එන්න එන්නම වැඩි වෙන්වෙන්වා. ගමරාල කොහොමහරි ඉවසගෙන හිටියා. දැන්නං වතුර මුට්ටියත් හොඳටම පැහෙනවා. දැන්නං ගමරාලට හරිම අමාරුයි. මුට්ටිය දුම් දාමින් පැහෙනවා. දුමයි, රස්නෙයි හින්ද ගමරාලට ඉබේටම නැගිට්ටවුනා.පැහෙන වතුර මුට්ටියයි, පිට්ටුයි ගමරාලගේ ඇඟේ. ගමරාලගේ ඇඟත් පිච්චිලා. ගමරාල වේදනාවෙන් කෑගැහුවා.''අනේ අපොයි, මේ කැලේ අපිට මොන පිට්ටු ද\\" කියලා නරියා කැලේටම දිව්වා."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：什么是波斯音乐，它的特点是什么？","answer":"答案：波斯音乐是伊朗的传统音乐形式，具有悠久的历史和独特的风格。它的特点包括复杂的旋律模式、微妙的音调变化和注重情感表达。波斯音乐常使用乐器如塔尔、坚果和锣鼓等。"},{"question":"Ilé ẹjọ́ Kòtẹ́milọ́rùn yá, mi ò gba ìdájọ́ 'Tribunal' wọlé - Adebutu","answer":"Olùdíje sípò gómìnà lẹ́gbẹ́ òṣèlú People’s Democratic Party, (PDP) ní ìpínlẹ̀ Ogun, Ladi Adebutu ti ní òun kò gba ìdájọ́ tí ìgbìmọ̀ gbé awuyewuye ìbò ní ìpínlẹ̀ náà gbé kalẹ̀ lórí ètò ìdìbò àwọn.Adebutu ní ìdájọ́ náà banilọ́kàn jẹ́ púpọ̀, tó sì jẹ́ ìdúnkokò ńlá sí ètò ìṣèjọba àwaarawa.Ní ọjọ́ Àbámẹ́ta, ọgbọ́n ọjọ́ oṣù Kẹsàn-án ni ìgbìmọ̀ tó ń gbọ́ ẹ̀hónú ìbò náà da ẹjọ́ tí Adebutu pè tako gómìnà Dapo Abiodun nù pé ẹja náà kò lẹ́sẹ̀ nílẹ̀.Ètò ìdájọ́ náà ló wáyé fún wákàtí mọ́kànlá.Àjọ tó ń rí sí ètò ìdìbò ní Nàìjíríà, INEC kéde Dapo Abiodun ti ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú All Progressives Congress, (APC), gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹni tó jáwé olúborí níbi ètò ìdìbò sípò gómìnà ìpínlẹ̀ náà tó wáyé nínú oṣù Kẹta ọdún 2023 pẹ̀lú ìbò 276,298.Adebutu ti ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú PDP ló tẹ̀lé nígbà tí òun rí ìbò 262,383, TÍ Biyi Otegbeye tẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú African Democratic Congress wà ní ìpò kẹta pẹ̀lú ìbò 94,754.Ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú PDP àti Adebutu nígbà náà ní àwọn kò gba èsì ìbò tí INEC kéde náà wọlé tí wọ́n sì wọ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú APC àti Abiodun lọ síwájú ìgbìmọ̀ tó ń gbọ́ awuyewuye èsì ìbò.Wọ́n fẹ̀sùn kàn pé Abiodun kọ́ ló ní ìbò tó pọ̀ jùlọ àti pé INEC kò tẹ̀lé òfin ètò ìdìbò lásìkò ìbò náà.Bákan náà ni wọ́n tún fẹ̀sùn kàn pé àwọn jàǹdùkú da ètò ìdìbò rú ní àwọn ibùdó ìdìbò tó lé ní 99 tí èyí sì dí àwọn ènìyàn tó lè ní ẹgbẹ̀rún lọ́nà ogójì lọ́wọ́ láti kópa níbi ìdìbò náà.Ki lawọn ẹbẹ ti Ladi Adebutu gbe ka iwaju ile ẹjọ idibo gomina ni Ogun?Ladi Adebutu ní kí ilé ẹjọ́ kéde òun gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹni tó jáwé olúborí níbi ètò ìdìbò gómìnà tó wáyé ní ọjọ́ Kejìdínlógún oṣù Kẹta, kí wọ́n gba ipò náà lọ́wọ́ Dapo Abiodun.Ó ní kí ilé pàṣẹ kí ètò ìdìbò tuntun mìíràn wáyé ní àwọn ibùdó ìdìbò 99 ní wọ́ọ̀dù mọ́kànlélógójì káàkiri ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ mẹ́rìndínlógún tí ètò kò ti wáyé tẹ́lẹ̀ àtàwọn ibi tí wọ́n ti da ètò ìdìbò rú.Àmọ́ àwọn adájọ́ tí wọ́n ń gbọ́ awuyewuye náà ní Adebutu kò fi ẹ̀rí gbe àwọn ẹ̀sùn rẹ̀ lẹ́sẹ̀ pé àwọn kan dí àwọn ènìyàn láti dìbò lásìkò ìbò náà gbe ẹ̀sùn rẹ̀ lẹ́sẹ̀.Wọ́n ní kò sí ẹ̀rí pé ìwà màgòmágó wáyé níbi ètò ìdìbò náà tàbí pé iye ìbò tí wọ́n dì pọ̀ ju àwọn tó yẹ kó dìbò lọ tàbí pé Abiodun kò yẹ láti díje dupò náà gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹ̀sùn tí Adebutu fi kàn.Wọ́n ní nítorí náà ni àwọn ṣe dá ẹjọ́ náà nù pé kò lẹ́sẹ̀ nílẹ̀ rárá.Nígbà tó ń fèsì sí ìdájọ́ náà, Adebutu ní àwọn adájọ́ náà kò ṣe àwọn àgbéyẹ̀wó àwọn ẹ̀rí tí àwọn kó sí iwájú ilé ẹjọ́.Agbẹnusọ Adebutu, Afolabi Orekoya ní ó ti darí àwọn ikọ agbẹjọ́rò rẹ̀ láti gba ilé ẹjọ́ kòtẹ́milọ́rùn lọ nítorí àwọn kò ní sinmi àyàfi tí àwọn bá rí ìdájọ́ òdodo gbà.Ó ní àwọn ní ìgbàgbọ́ nínú ètò ìṣèjọba àwaarawa àti òfin àti pé èyí ló mú àwọn gbé ìgbésẹ̀ òfin láti gba ẹ̀tọ́ àwọn padà.Ó fi kun pé òun ní ìfarajìn láti ri dájú pé ìfẹ́ àwọn ènìyàn wá sí ìmúṣe lórí ètò ìdìbò náà.Ó ṣàlàyé pé àwọn ẹ̀rí tó fìdí múlẹ̀ ni àwọn kó síwájú ìgbìms tó ń gbọ́ ẹ̀hónú ìbò náà, tí àwọn sì ní ìgbàgbọ́ pé tí àwọn bá dé ilé ẹjọ́ Kòtẹ́milọ́rùn, àwọn máa rí ìdájọ́ tó tẹ́ àwọn lọ́rùn gbà.Bákan náà ló ní ó jẹ́ ohun tó kọnilóminú pé ilé ẹjọ́ kìí ṣe ibi tí ènìyàn ti le rí ìdájọ́ òdodo gbà mọ́ lásìkò yìí.Ó wá fi dá àwọn alátìlẹyìn rẹ̀ lójú pé òun kò ní jẹ́ kí ìdájọ́ náà kó àárẹ̀ ọkàn bá òun.Oni ọjọ Abamẹta ni igbimọ adajọ kotẹmilọrun to n ri si ẹjọ ti oludije si ipo gomina fẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP, Ladi Adebutu pe gomina ipinlẹ Ogun, Dapo Abiodun pe ko wọle ibo gomina ipinlẹ naa.Lọjọ kẹrin oṣu Kẹsan an yii ni igbimọ igbẹjọ naa sun idajọ wọn si ọgbọnjọ oṣu Kẹsan an yii.Hamidu Kunaza to jẹ adari awọn adajọ to n ṣe igbẹjọ naa ti sọ ṣaaju fun gbogbo awọn tọrọ kan pe ni ipari oṣu kẹsan an ni iadajọ yoo waye.Akọwe igbimọ igbẹjọ kotẹmilọrun naa, Obioma Ezenta fi lede pe ọjọ Abamẹta yii ni idajọ naa yoo waye.Bakan naa ni oludamọran oludije fun ipo gomina fẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP, Afolabi Orekoya sọ pe igbimọ igbẹjọ ọhun ti sọ fawọn nipa idajọ oni.Ajọ eleto idibo INEC kede pe gomina Abiodun ri ibo 276,298 nigba ti Adebutu ṣe ipo keji pẹlu ibo 262,38 ninu ibo gomina to waye lọjọ kejidinlogun oṣu Kẹta.Adebutu tako esi idibo yii, o si n sọ fun ileẹjọ lati kede oun gẹgẹ bi ẹni to jawe olubori ninu eto idibo naa."},{"question":"உனக்குத் தெரிந்த சித்த மருத்துவ குறிப்புக்கள் சிலவற்றை கூறு.","answer":" சித்த மருத்துவ குறிப்புகள் 1. தலைவலி குணமாக: விரவி மஞ்சளை விளக்கெண்ணையில் ஊறவைத்து  விளக்கில் காட்டி சுட்டு அதன் புகையை மூக்கின் வழியாக சுவாசிக்க  தலைவலி, நெஞ்சுவலி முதலியன அகலும்.2. இருமல் குணமாக: அரசு மரத்துப்பட்டையை காயவைத்து வறுத்து கரியானவுடன் தூளாக்கி 1 டம்ளர் நீரில் 1 கரண்டி போட்டு கொதித்ததும் வடிகட்டி சர்க்கரை பால் சேர்த்து குடிக்க இருமல் குணமாகும்.3. ஜலதோஷம் நீங்க: ஜலதோஷம் காய்ச்சல், தலைவலிக்கு பனங்கிழங்கை அவித்து காயவைத்து இடித்து பொடியாக்கி பனங்கல் கண்டு சேர்த்து சாப்பிட்டால் குணமாகும்."},{"question":"Shin ya halasta mace ta tura wa saurayinta hoton ta amma mai hijabi?","answer":"Toh asali abunda Malamai sukace haramunne mace ta turama wanda ba muharramintaba hoto. Sukace idan yanason ganinta tohseyazo yaganta a zahiri. Amma zance na gaskiya Haramunne mace ta turama saurayinta Hoto koda kuwa ta sanya hijabi. Amma ansamu wasu malamai waɗanda suka halasta hakan amma sedai ba'a karɓan maganarsu. Abunda Sheikh Albani da Malamai na kirki suka tabbatar shine Haramunne turawar."},{"question":" कोणत्या देशामध्ये कोणत्याही प्रकारचे तुरुंग नाही आहे?","answer":"नेदरलँड्समध्ये गुन्हेगारी असली तरी, याचा अर्थ असा नाही की तेथे कोणताही गुन्हा नाही. तथापि, गुन्ह्यासाठी शिक्षा खूप कठोर आहे आणि ज्यांच्यावर आरोप आहेत त्यांनी स्वतःला बदलण्यासाठी आणि भविष्यात अशा प्रकारचे गुन्हे करण्यापासून रोखण्यासाठी मानसिक पुनर्वसन कार्यक्रमात भाग घेतला पाहिजे."},{"question":"“అన్నం మెతుకును చూచి అన్నం ఉడికిందో లేదో చెప్పవచ్చు. అలాగే పుస్తక పరిచయ వ్యాసాన్ని (లేదా) పుస్తక సమీక్షను చదివితే, ఆ పుస్తకం గురించి ఆమూలాగ్రమంగా తెలుసుకోవచ్చు” ఎట్లాగో వ్రాయండి.","answer":"ఒక పుస్తకం యొక్క లక్షణం, శైలి, రచనా విధానం, దాని తత్త్వం, పుస్తకం ద్వారా రచయిత లేక కవి చెప్పదలచిన అంతరార్థం, వాని దృక్పథాన్ని, వానిలో నిబిడీకృతమైయున్న సారాంశాన్ని పుస్తక పరిచయ వ్యాసం ద్వారా పాఠకులకు తెలియజేస్తాడు. దీనికే ముందుమాట, పీఠిక, తొలిపలుకు, ఆముఖం, ప్రస్తావన, మున్నుడి మున్నగు పేర్లు కలవు.ఈ పుస్తకం యొక్క నేపథ్యాన్ని, లక్ష్యాల్ని పుస్తక పరిచయకర్త పాఠకులకు తెలియజేస్తాడు. అంతేకాక ఆ పుస్తకంలో రచయిత లేక కవి వివరించిన తీరు, అందులోని మంచిచెడ్డలు, పుస్తక పరిచయకర్త లేక సమీక్షకుడు తెలియచేస్తాడు.ఉదాహరణకు ‘భూమిక’ అను ప్రస్తుత పాఠాన్ని చదివితే కేశవస్వామి తన కథల్ని రెండు భాగాలుగా 1969, 1981 సంవత్సరాలలో విడుదల చేశాడని తెలుస్తోంది. స్వాతంత్ర్యానికి పూర్వం నుండి, భారత్లో విలీనం అయ్యేవరకు హైదరాబాదు రాజ్యం చరిత్ర, ఈ కథలు తెలుపుతాయని తెలుస్తోంది. హైదరాబాదులోని సామాజిక పరిణామాలు, ఈ పుస్తకంలో ఉన్నట్లు తెలిసింది.కేశవస్వామి రచనల్లో హైదరాబాదు జీవభాషను చిత్రించినట్లు కూడా తెలుస్తోంది. కేశవస్వామి కథలు చదివితే, కేశవస్వామి హృదయం వెల్లడవుతుందని తెలుస్తోంది. కేశవస్వామి కథలలోని సారాంశం, దీనివల్ల టూకీగా తెలుస్తుంది.అందుచేత గూడూరి సీతారాం రాసిన పుస్తక పరిచయాన్ని చదవడం వల్ల, నెల్లూరి కేశవస్వామి గురించి, ఆయన రచనల గురించి, ఆ రచనలలోని కథాంశాల వైవిధ్యం గురించి, రచయిత హృదయాన్ని గురించి మనం తెలుసుకోవచ్చు."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny diso tsipelina ao anatin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Zava-dehibe amin'ny fiarovna ny fahasamihafan'ny biolojika ny fiarovana ireo karazana biby atahorna ho lany tamingana.\\"","answer":"Ity ilay fanambarana miaraka amin'ny tsipelina efa voahitsy \\"Zava-dehibe amin'ny fiarovana ny fahasamihafan'ny biolojika ny fiarovana ireo karazana biby atahorana ho lany tamingana.\\""},{"question":"Qual é o papel de um designer gráfico?","answer":"Um designer gráfico cria elementos visuais, como logotipos e materiais de marketing, para transmitir mensagens visualmente."},{"question":"ጽሑፉን ጠቅለል አድርገህ ተናገር፦  (ሲ ኤን ኤን) -- የቼክ ቴኒስ ደጋፊዎች ከ30 ዓመታት በፊት ከነበረው የቬልቬት አብዮት በፊት ታይቶ የማይታወቅ የሀብት መጨመር እያገኙ ነው። የቼክ ሪፐብሊክ የሴቶች ቡድን እሁድ እለት በተከታታይ ለሁለተኛ ዓመት የፌዴራል ዋንጫን አሸንፏል - በ 1980 ዎቹ በማርቲና ናቭራቲሎቫ የሚመራው የቼኮስሎቫኪያ ቡድን ሁሉን ያሸነፈውን ስኬት በማስታወስ ። ሉሲ ሳፋሮቫ በሴርቢያ ላይ ያሸነፈችውን ነጥብ በማስመዝገብ በፕራግ የቀድሞውን የዓለም ቁጥር 1 ጄሌና ጃንኮቪክን 6-1 6-1 በማሸነፍ በመጨረሻው ጨዋታ ላይ የማይነካ 3-1 መሪነትን አቋቁማለች ። \\"በዚህ አይነት ህዝብ ውስጥ እዚህ ቤት ውስጥ መቆየት በቃላት ሊገለፅ የማይችል ነው ፣ አስገራሚ ስሜት ነው\\" ብለዋል ሳፋሮቫ በዓለም ደረጃ 17 ኛ ደረጃ ላይ የሚገኙት። \\"በጣም ብዙ ስሜቶችና ደስታዎች አሉ - ይህ ደግሞ በየቀኑ የምንለማመደው ስሜት ነው፣ ምንም እንኳን ለመስራት ስሜት ባይኖርህም እንኳ።\\" የፌዴራል ዋንጫ ትኩሳት ፕራጋን ይመታል ። ቼኮቹ ከቅዳሜው የመክፈቻ ግጥሚያ በኋላ 2-0 ሲመሩ ሳለ ሰርቢያውያን ግን ሌላዋ የቀድሞ ቁጥር 1 የሆነችው አና ኢቫኖቪች ባለፈው ዓመት የዊምብሌዶን ሻምፒዮን የነበረችውን ፔትራ ክቪቶቫን 6-3 7-5 በማሸነፍ በጨዋታው ውስጥ ቆይታለች። ባለፈው ወር በኢስታንቡል በተካሄደው የ WTA ሻምፒዮና ላይ የዋንጫዋን መከላከያ ያጠናቀቀ ህመም ቢኖርም ከጃንኮቪች ጋር የመጀመሪያዋን ጨዋታ ያሸነፈችው ክቪቶቫ \\"ብዙ ኃይል አልነበረኝም እናም በፍርድ ቤቱ ላይ ግልፅ ነበር\\" ብላለች። \\"ለጥቂት ጥይቶች ብቻ ለመጫወት ሞክሬ ነበር፤ ረዘም ላለ ጊዜ መጫወት አልቻልኩም፤ ለዚያም ነው ስህተት መሥራቴ የጀመረው።\\" ቼኮች ከጣሊያን (2009-10) እና ከሩሲያ (2007-08) በኋላ ማዕረጉን ለመከላከል ሦስተኛው ተከታታይ ብሔር ሆነዋል ። እስከ 1988 ድረስ በአሮጌዋ ቼኮዝሎቫኪያ የተሸነፉትን አምስት ሲቆጥሩ በአውስትራሊያ የተሸነፉትን ሰባት ጋር ይዛመዳሉ - በአጠቃላይ ሁለተኛ ፣ ግን ከአሜሪካ 10 ዓይናፋር (* ዓይናፋር ሲጥቀም ምን ለማለት ፈልጎ እንደሆነ አላውቅም)። ባለፈው ዓመት የተገኘው ድል ከስሎቫኪያ ጋር በ1993 ከተለያየ ወዲህ የመጀመሪያው ነው። ይህ በእንዲህ እንዳለ ዴቪድ ፌሬር እሁድ እለት በፓሪስ በተደረገው የፍፃሜ ውድድር የጀርዚ ጃኖቪች ግዙፍ ገዳይ ሩጫን ካቆመ በኋላ የመጀመሪያውን የኤቲፒ ማስተርስን ማዕረግ አነሳ ። አምስተኛው ደረጃ ላይ የሚገኘው ስፔናዊው 6-4 6-3 አሸንፎ ከዓለም አራቱ ምርጥ ተጫዋቾች ውጪ ከሮቢን ሶደርሊንግ ወዲህ ከሁለት ዓመት በፊት በተመሳሳይ ውድድር ማስተር 1000 ውድድርን ያሸነፈ የመጀመሪያው ተጫዋች ሆኗል ።","answer":"የቼክ ሪፐብሊክ የሴቶች ቡድን ለሁለተኛ ተከታታይ ዓመት የፌዴራል ዋንጫ ፍፃሜ አሸነፈ። ሉሲ ሳፋሮቫ በአና ኢቫኖቪች አሸናፊነት 3 ለ 1 መሪነትን አገኘች ። የቀድሞዋ ቼኮዝሎቫኪያ እስከ 1988 ድረስ አምስት ጊዜ አሸናፊ ሆናለች ። ዴቪድ ፌደሬር እሁድ እለት በፓሪስ የፍፃሜ ውድድር አሸንፎ የመጀመሪያውን የኤቲፒ ማስተርስ ዋንጫ አሸነፈ።"},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي الدولة اللي فيها أقل عدد ديال السكان فالعالم ؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفاتيكان"},{"question":"There is","answer":"There's a known trend ongoing which have been buttressed with different views and perception. Yes, what was done as stated is practically wrong and inhumane. However, what is essential is to eradicate it before it develop. How can this be achieved? Read this article from @statementsofadmonition and gain more knowledge and awareness about partnership and marriage.https://www.statementsofadmonition.ng/danger-marrying-wrong-spouse-part-1/#statementsofadmonition #motivationalpack #purposefulliving #quoteoftheday #marriage #marriageadvice #relationshipadvice #blogger #courtship #relationshipgoals #marriagetip #family"},{"question":"යකඩ ගැහැනිය නම් අන්වර්ථ නාමයෙන් හැඳින්වූයේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"1979 සිට 1990 දක්වා  එක්සත් රාජධානියේ අගමැතිනිය වූ මාග්‍රට් තැචර්ට \\"යකඩ ගැහැනිය\\" යන අන්වර්ථ නාමයෙන්  ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් විය. ඇයගේ ශක්තිමත් සහ සම්මුති විරහිත නායකත්ව විලාසය සහ ඇයගේ ස්ථාවර දේශපාලන හා  ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිපත්ති හේතුවෙන් ඇය මෙම අන්වර්ථ නාමය ලබා ගත්තාය. තැචර් එක්සත් රාජධානියේ අග්‍රාමාත්‍ය ධුරය දැරූ පළමු කාන්තාව වූ අතර ඇයගේ පාලන සමයේදී බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය සහ ගෝලීය දේශපාලනයේ කැපී පෙනෙන චරිතයක් විය. \\"යකඩ ගැහැනිය\\" යන පදය මුලින් සෝවියට් මාධ්‍යවේදියෙකු විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද අතර එය ඉක්මනින් දේශීය හා ජාත්‍යන්තර වශයෙන් ඇගේ ප්‍රතිරූපය සමඟ සම්බන්ධ විය."},{"question":"Inona no vodiandro amin'ny malagasy?","answer":"Amin'ny malagasy dia ny Alarobia  ny vodiandro ."},{"question":"Ao amin'ny fanangonana biby fiompy dia misy alika, saka ary vorona. Mivovoa avokoa ny alika rehetra, maneno ny saka rehetra, ary mihira ny vorona rehetra.Inona no azontsika tsoahina avy amin’ireo fanambarana etsy ambony ireo?A. Ny saka rehetra dia vorona.B. Ny vorona rehetra dia alika.D. Ny biby sasany mivovo dia alika.E. Tsy misy saka mihira.","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia D. Ny biby sasany mivovo dia alika."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fanahy?","answer":"Ny fanahy, araka ny karazam-pinoana sy fivavahana maro, dia zavatra manan-tsitrapo sy manana fahatsiarovan-tena nefa tsy azo tsapain-tanana, izay mety ho hitan' ny maso indraindray, ka heverina fa manana hery tsy araka ny mahazatra, sady mety hampianjady ny hery sy ny fahefany amin' ny tontolo tsapa. Fanahy, ohatra, ny fanahin' ny olona maty, ny demony, ny andriamanitra, ny matoatoa, ny anjely, sns. Maro ny taranja sy sehatra andinihana sy iresahana ny fanahy, ka isan' izany ny fivavahana, ny teôlôjia, ny finoana, ny angano, ny fedrà, ny fomban-drazana, ary ny fanaovana mazia."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai ayam menang, kampung tergadai\\"?","answer":"Maksud peribahasa ini ialah keberuntungan yang tidak ada faedahnya."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Hon var uttagen till den trupp som representerade Spanien i","answer":"VM i Frankrike år 2019. Hon blev målskytt i 3-1-segern mot Sydafrika i premiärmatchen. Matchen blev historisk som Spaniens första seger i ett världsmästerskap."},{"question":"من هم الضالين؟ ولماذ؟\\t","answer":"النصارى لأنهم حادوا عن الحق جهلاً فكانوا على ضلال بين في شأن عيسى عليه السلام."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਆਖਾ ਜੀਵਾ ਵਿਸਰੈ ਮਰਿ ਜਾਉ ॥ਆਖਣਿ ਅਉਖਾ ਸਾਚਾ ਨਾਉ ॥ਸਾਚੇ ਨਾਮ ਕੀ ਲਾਗੈ ਭੂਖ ॥ਤਿਤੁ ਭੂਖੈ ਖਾਇ ਚਲੀਅਹਿ ਦੂਖ ॥੧॥ਸੋ ਕਿਉ ਵਿਸਰੈ ਮੇਰੀ ਮਾਇ ॥ਸਾਚਾ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਸਾਚੈ ਨਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਾਚੇ ਨਾਮ ਕੀ ਤਿਲੁ ਵਡਿਆਈ ॥ ਆਖਿ ਥਕੇ ਕੀਮਤਿ ਨਹੀ ਪਾਈ ॥ਜੇ ਸਭਿ ਮਿਲਿ ਕੈ ਆਖਣ ਪਾਹਿ ॥ਵਡਾ ਨ ਹੋਵੈ ਘਾਟਿ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥੨॥ਨਾ ਓਹੁ ਮਰੈ ਨ ਹੋਵੈ ਸੋਗੁ ॥ਦੇਂਦਾ ਰਹੈ ਨ ਚੂਕੈ ਭੋਗੁ ॥ਗੁਣੁ ਏਹੋ ਹੋਰੁ ਨਾਹੀ ਕੋਇ ॥ਨਾ ਕੋ ਹੋਆ ਨਾ ਕੋ ਹੋਇ ॥੩॥ਜੇਵਡੁ ਆਪਿ ਤੇਵਡ ਤੇਰੀ ਦਾਤਿ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਦਿਨੁ ਕਰਿ ਕੈ ਕੀਤੀ ਰਾਤਿ ॥ਖਸਮੁ ਵਿਸਾਰਹਿ ਤੇ ਕਮਜਾਤਿ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਵੈ ਬਾਝੁ ਸਨਾਤਿ ॥੪॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 349 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਉਂ ਜਿਉਂ ਮੈਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਉਚਾਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਨਾਮ ਭੁੱਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਮੇਰੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਹੋਣ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ । (ਇਹ ਪਤਾ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਭੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨਾ (ਇਕ) ਔਖਾ ਕੰਮ ਹੈ । (ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਭੁੱਖ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ,  ਇਸ ਭੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ (ਨਾਮ-ਭੋਜਨ) ਖਾ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੁੱਖ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਮਾਂ! (ਅਰਦਾਸ ਕਰ ਕਿ) ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਦੇ ਨ ਭੁੱਲੇ । ਜਿਉਂ ਜਿਉਂ ਉਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰੀਏ, ਤਿਉਂ ਤਿਉਂ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਾਲਕ (ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਰਤਾ ਜਿਤਨੀ ਭੀ ਮਹਿਮਾ (ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ) ਬਿਆਨ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਥੱਕ ਗਏ ਹਨ (ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ) । ਕੋਈ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੱਸ ਸਕਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਦੀ ਕੇਹੜੀ ਹੋਰ ਹਸਤੀ ਹੈ ।ਜੇ (ਜਗਤ ਦੇ) ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਜੀਵ ਰਲ ਕੇ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮਹਿਮਾ) ਬਿਆਨ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਜਤਨ ਕਰਨ,ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅਸਲੇ ਨਾਲੋਂ) ਵੱਡਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ (ਤੇ ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਭੀ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਨਾਹ ਕਰੇ) ਤਾਂ ਉਹ (ਅੱਗੇ ਨਾਲੋਂ) ਘਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਂਦਾ ।੨।ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਕਦੇ ਮਰਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਨਾਹ ਹੀ (ਉਸ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ) ਸੋਗ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਦਾ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਜ਼ਕ) ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ ਦਾਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਤਣਾ ਕਦੇ ਮੁੱਕਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ (ਭਾਵ, ਜੀਵ ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ ਦਾਤਾਂ ਸਦਾ ਵਰਤਦੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਮੁੱਕਦੀਆਂ ਨਹੀਂ) ।ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਵੱਡੀ ਖ਼ੂਬੀ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਉਸ ਵਰਗਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ,(ਉਸ ਵਰਗਾ ਅਜੇ ਤਕ) ਨਾਹ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, ਨਾਹ ਕਦੇ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ!) ਜੇਡਾ (ਬੇਅੰਤ ਤੂੰ) ਆਪ ਹੈਂ, ਉਤਨੀ (ਬੇਅੰਤ) ਤੇਰੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ ਹੈ, (ਤੂੰ ਐਸਾ ਹੈਂ) ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਦਿਨ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਰਾਤ ਬਣਾਈ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਬੰਦੇ ਭੈੜੇ ਅਸਲੇ ਵਾਲੇ (ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੇ) ਹਨ ਜੋ ਐਸੇ ਖਸਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਸਾਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਖੁੰਝੇ ਹੋਏ ਜੀਵ ਨੀਚ ਹਨ ।੪।੨।\\""},{"question":"“பள்ளியைத் தூய்மையாக வைத்திருக்கும்  செயல்திட்ட வரைவு முறை ஒன்றை உருவாக்கித் தலைமை ஆசிரியரின் ஒப்புதலுடன் நடைமுறைப்படுத்துக.","answer":"அனுப்புதல் :             பத்தாம் வகுப்பு மாணவர்கள்,             அரசு உயர்நிலைப்பள்ளி,                     சென்னை – 18.பெறுதல்,                       தலைமையாசிரியர் அவர்கள்,                          அரசு உயர்நிலைப்பள்ளி,                                    சென்னை – 18.மதிப்பிற்குரியஐயா,பொருள்: பள்ளித் தூய்மை குறித்த செயல் திட்ட வரைவு ஒப்புதல் வழங்கி செயல்படுத்தவேண்டுதல் – சார்பாக வேண்டி விண்ணப்பம்: வணக்கம்.                                                                       நாங்கள் நம் பள்ளியில் பத்தாம் வகுப்பு படித்து வருகிறோம். கடந்த 4 ஆண்டுகளாக நம் பள்ளியை நன்கு கவனித்து வருகிறோம். அதன் மூலம் நம் பள்ளி மாணவர்களின் கற்றல் அடைவுகளுக்குத் தடையாக இருக்கும் காரணிகளைப் பற்றி ஆய்வு செய்து வந்தோம். அவற்றை ஒரு செயல்திட்டமாக தயாரித்து தங்கள் பார்வைக்கு அனுப்பி உள்ளோம். அதன் பரிந்துரைகளை ஆராய்ந்து அதற்கு ஒப்புதல் வழங்கி நம் பள்ளியில் செயல்படுத்தி மாணவர்களாகிய எங்கள் கல்வி நலனையும் வருங்கால தலைமுறையினரின் கல்வி நலனையும் காக்குமாறு பணிவுடன் வேண்டுகிறோம்.                                                                     நன்றி!!     இடம் : சென்னை     நாள் : 13.03.2020                                                                                                     இப்படிக்கு,      அரசு உயர்நிலைப்பள்ளி மாணவர்கள்."},{"question":"Mọ mọ ẹni to fẹẹ le mi nipo ọba-Oluwoo","answer":"Bi awọn afọbajẹ ilu Iwo ṣe n bẹ ijọba, ti wọn si n wa gbogbo ọna ti ọba wọn, Oluwoo ti ilu Iwo, Abdul-Rasheed Akanbi, yoo ṣe fi ori apere silẹ, Kabiyesi naa ti sọ pe, oun ti mọ ẹni ti inu oun n bi gidigidi.Ni kete ti iroyin ọhun gbalu kan ni akọwe iroyin fun ọba alaye naa, Alli Ibrahim, ti gbe atẹjade kan sita, eyi ti Oluwoo fọwọ si. Ohun ti Kabiyesi si sọ ni pe, oun ti mọ ẹni to fẹẹ le oun kuro lori ipo, ati pe awọn afọbajẹ ti wọn n tọwọ bọwe kiri, ti wọn n bẹ ijọba Ọṣun ko yọ oun danu yẹn, o lẹnikan to n lo wọn.Oluwoo fi kun un pe ọkunrin kan ti awọn jọ du oye mọ ara awọn lọwọ lasiko tawọn eeyan Iwo n wa Oluwoo tuntun ni ko gba kadara, to n lepa oun kiri lori bi oun yoo ṣe fipo ọhun pitan.Kabiyesi fi kun un pe ariwo ti wọn n pa kiri ko ba oun lẹru, nitori pe gbogbo awọn eeyan Iwo naa lo mọ pe asiko ti oun dori apere awọn baba nla oun yii, ilọsiwaju nla lo ti ba ilu naa. Bakan naa lo sọ pe ẹni to n lo awọn oloye ọhun ko ṣẹṣẹ maa gbiyanju lati ti oun lulẹ, ṣugbọn ti gbogbo akitiyan ẹ n ja sasan.Laipẹ yii lawọn oloye bii mejila kọ lẹta si gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun pe ki gomina rọ Oluwoo loye, nitori itiju nla to n ko ba ilu naa, ati pe ẹlẹwọn eeyan kan bayii ni tẹlẹ lorilẹ-ede Amẹrika lọhun-un, ati ni Canada."},{"question":"Filosofian, nola aztertzen du existentzialismoak gizakiaren askezia, erantzukizuna eta bizitzaren zentzua?","answer":"Existentzialismoak gizakia aztertzen du unibertso indiferente baten aurrean. Gizakia aske da bere bizitzaren zentzua sortzeko, baina erantzukizun handia darama bere erabakiekin."},{"question":"kodi Nyalugwe ndi nyama yotani? ","answer":"Uyu ndi mphaka mmodzi yemwe safuna thandizo lililonse kuti atsike mumtengo. Nyalugwe amakhala womasuka kwambiri moti nthawi zambiri amapeta nyama ndipo amakokeranso zopha zake m’nthambi. Nyalugwe ndi amphaka akuluakulu amphamvu kwambiri omwe ali ofanana kwambiri ndi mikango, ndi akambuku. Amakhala kum'mwera kwa Sahara ku Africa, kumpoto chakum'mawa kwa Africa, Asia, India, ndi China. Komabe, ambiri mwa anthu awo ali pachiwopsezo, makamaka kunja kwa Africa.Mutha kuzindikira anyalugwe ambiri ndi mtundu wawo wopepuka komanso mawanga akuda. Mawangawo amatchedwa rosettes, chifukwa amafanana ndi mawonekedwe a duwa. Mitundu imeneyi imabisa matupi awo pamene akuyenda mu udzu ndi mitengo. Akambuku akuda, omwe amaoneka ngati olimba mumtundu chifukwa chakuti mawanga awo ndi ovuta kusiyanitsa, amatchedwa black panthers.Mosiyana ndi mikango, anyalugwe amangokhala okha. Amuna amakhala okhawokha ndipo zazikazi zimangokhalira kukhala pawekha zikamalera ana. Koma ngati mikango, akambuku amabangula. Akambuku aamuna amateteza gawo lawo pobangula ndi kununkhiza, pamene zazikazi zimagwiritsa ntchito kubangula kwawo kukopa zinzake ndi kuitana ana awo. Kambuku ndi khwangwala, ngati ntchentche yodula nkhuni.Ana a Nyalugwe amabadwa ndi mawanga osawoneka bwino. Mayiyo amabisa ana ake n’kuwasuntha kuchoka pamalo abwino kupita kumalo ena mpaka atakula moti n’kuyamba kusewera ndi kuphunzira kusaka. Ana akamafika zaka ziwiri amakhala okha. Koma maubwenzi a amayi amakhala olimba, ndipo ana nthawi zina amakumananso ndi amayi awo"},{"question":"மக்களுக்கு அழகு சேர்ப்பன……………….ஆகும்.அ) அணிகலன்கள்ஆ) கலைஇ) கல்விஈ) பேச்சுத்திறன்","answer":"மக்களுக்கு அழகு சேர்ப்பன……அ) அணிகலன்கள்………….ஆகும்."},{"question":"什么桥下没水","answer":"答案：立交桥"},{"question":"Inona  amin'ireto no fanambarana tsy marina momba an'i Madagasikara?a) Madagasikara dia nosy any amin'ny ranomasimbe Atlantika.b) Antananarivo no renivohiny.d) Ny fiteny ofisialy dia malagasy.","answer":"Ny Valiny diso dia ny safidy : a) Nosy iray any amin'ny ranomasimbe Atlantika i Madagasikara. (Raha ny tena izy dia nosy iray any amin'ny ranomasimbe Indianina i Madagasikara.)"},{"question":"Qual sentimento expressado no tweet abaixo?Nem acredito que mó brada chorou. 😹🤦🏾‍♂️","answer":"Neutro."},{"question":"apa kejadian penting dalam teks berikut: Rejtan, atau Jatuhnya Polandia adalah lukisan minyak karya seniman Polandia Jan Matejko yang diselesaikan pada tahun 1866. Lukisan ini menggambarkan Tadeusz Rejtan (kanan bawah) yang sedang menentang Pemisahan Polandia Pertama selama Sejm Rozbiorowy pada tahun 1773. Lukisan ini tidak hanya menggambarkan peristiwa sejarah, tetapi juga mengandung alegori sejarah Polandia. Lukisan ini merupakan salah satu karya Matejko yang paling terkenal.","answer":"Rejtan atau jatuhnya polandia"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Henri Verneuil, född som Achod Malakian (), 15 oktober 1920 i Rodosto, Osmanska riket, död 11 januari 2002, var en fransk-armenisk filmregissör och manusförfattare. Han nominerades till Oscar för bästa berättelse vid Oscarsgalan 1956","answer":"för \\"Fåret har 5 fötter\\". Han nominerades till Césarpriset för bästa film och bästa manus 1980 för \\"I... comme Icare\\". År 1996 tilldelades han heders-César."},{"question":"Ọpẹ o, abẹrẹ ajẹsara arun Korona wọ Naijiria latoke-okun","answer":"Ireti awọn ọmọ Naijiria lati ṣẹgun arun buruku Koronafairọọsi ti tubọ fẹsẹ rinlẹ pẹlu bi abẹrẹ ajẹsara to n dena arun naa ti de bayii.Nnkan bii wakati meloo kan sẹyin ni baalu Emirate Airlines kan ko awọn egboogi ti wọn porukọ ẹ ni Oxford-Astrazeneca naa wọle, papakọ ofurufu Nnamdi Azikiwe, l’Abuja, ni baluu naa balẹ si lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii.Eyi ni igba akọkọ ti orilẹ-ede wa maa ri abẹrẹ ajẹsara Korona gba, wọn lontẹ ajọ ilera agbaye, World Health Organisation, wa lara awọn egbogi wọnyi, wọn fọwọ si i fun lilo.Ijọba ti sọ ṣaaju latẹnu Minisita kekere feto ilera, Dokita Ọlọrunnibẹ Mamora, pe apa akọkọ lara awọn egboogi ọhun lo de yii, awọn maa wo bo ṣe ṣiṣẹ si, eyi lawọn fi maa pinnu lati beere fun pupọ si i, tabi kawọn beere fun oriṣii abẹrẹ ajẹsara mi-in.Ko i ti i daju bi wọn ṣe maa ṣeto ati fun awọn araalu labẹrẹ naa, ati bo ṣe maa de awọn ipinlẹ kọọkan, ṣugbọn wọn ni iṣẹ ti n lọ lori eyi."},{"question":"Afaka mahazo sery ve ianao amin'ny alalan'ny vovoka?","answer":"Eny, afaka mahazo sery aminn'y alalann'y vovoka."},{"question":"“God Jul” zvinoreva “Kisimusi inofadza” mumutauro upi?","answer":"\\"Mwari Jul\\" zvinoreva \\"Kisimusi Inofadza\\" muchiSwedish nechiNorwegian. Izwi rinoshandiswa kushuvira mumwe munhu Kisimusi inofadza uye inofadza panguva yezororo. Ndiyo kukwazisa kwezororo muScandinavia uye inowanzoperekedzwa nezvishuwo zvakanaka uye mhemberero panguva yeKrisimasi. Mutsara uyu unoratidza tsika netsika dzechiSweden neNorway tsika, uko Kisimusi izororo rakakosha uye rinokosheswa."},{"question":"සමාස යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"පද කෙටිවීම සමාස ලෙස හැදින්වේ. අර්ථයට අදාල වන ලෙස මනාලෙස ගැලපීම මෙහිදී සිදුවිය යුතුය.ලොකු ද කුඩා ද ළමයි සියල්ලෝම පාන් ද බත් ද කමින් දිවා ආහාරය ගත්හ.ලොකු කුඩා ළමයි සියල්ලෝම බත් පාන් කමින් දිවා ආහාරය ගත්හ.මෙම වාක්‍ය දෙකෙන් ම එකම අර්ථය දෙන අතර දෙවන වාක්‍ය කෙටිය."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هو أول رقم تذكر فالقران الكريم مع ذكر الآية الكريمة؟","answer":"سبع “هُوَ ٱلَّذِى خَلَقَ لَكُم مَّا فِى ٱلْأَرْضِ جَمِيعًا ثُمَّ ٱسْتَوَىٰٓ إِلَى ٱلسَّمَآءِ فَسَوَّىٰهُنَّ سَبْعَ سَمَٰوَٰتٍۢ ۚ وَهُوَ بِكُلِّ شَىْءٍ عَلِيمٌ”. البقرة"},{"question":"Кичинеңизде асманда самалёт учуп баратса жердеги балдардын абалы кандай болгон?","answer":"Абдан кубанчубуз колубузду жайып🧍самалётко окшош анан дагы чуркап ырдачу элек.Самалёт самалёт ✈️Кайда учуп барасыңЧөнтөгүңө салат кетКапитандын баласын. Балалык доор кайра кайтып келсе."},{"question":"Apakah yang terjadi kepada RMS Titanic? Jawapan anda hendaklah tidak melebihi 120 patah perkataan.","answer":"RMS Titanic merupakan yang kedua daripada tiga kapal penumpang yang bertujuan mengawal perniagaan sepanjang perjalanan merentasi Lautan Atlantik. Dimiliki oleh White Star Line dan dibina di limbungan Harland and Wolff, Titanic merupakan kapal wap penumpang terbesar di dunia pada masa pelancarannya. Semasa kapal itu melakukan pelayaran pertamanya, ia berlanggar dengan sebuah aisberg pada jam 11:40 PM (waktu setempat kapal) pada pagi Ahad 14 April 1912, dan tenggelam sepenuhnya dalam tempoh dua jam empat puluh minit kemudian iaitu pada jam 2:20 AM pagi Isnin.Bencana tersebut mengakibatkan kematian lebih 1,500 orang penumpang lalu menjadikannya sebagai bencana laut terburuk semasa zaman aman dalam sejarah dan paling termashyur sehingga kini. Kejadian ini sangat mengejutkan lagi-lagi dengan pengetahuan ramai mengenai kelengkapan Titanic dengan teknologi yang termaju serta anak kapal yang berpengalaman tinggi pada zamannya sehingga ia disangka “tidak mungkin tenggelam”. Keghairahan media awam mengenai mangsa terkenal Titanic, legenda mengenai apa yang berlaku di atas kapal, penukaran undang-undang laut, dan penemuan bangkai kapal pada 1985 oleh pasukan yang diketuai oleh Jean-Louis Michel dan Robert Ballard menjadikan penimpaan terhadap kapal ini kekal masyhur pada tahun-tahun berikutnya."},{"question":"Đề bài:Năm bạn Alice, Beck, Kevin, Danny và Elisa chia một số viên bi với nhau theo cách sau: Alice lấy 1 viên và 1/5 của số bi còn lại, sau đó Beck lấy 1 viên và 1/5 của số bi còn lại. Kevin, Danny và Elisa cũng làm theo như vậy. Hỏi lúc đầu có ít nhất bao nhiêu viên bi?","answer":"Nếu ngay từ đầu trước khi chia bi ta cho thêm vào 4 viên bi thì Alice sẽ lấy đúng 1/5 số tổng số bi, tiếp đó Beck lấy 1/5 số bi còn lại sau Alice , Kevin lấy 1/5 số bi còn lại sau Beck, Danny lấy 1/5 số bi còn lại sau Kevin và Elisa lấy 1/5 số bi còn lại sau Danny.Do có 5 người nên sau khi thêm 4 viên bi thì số bi nhận được lúc đó phải chia hết cho 55 tức là chia hết cho 3125. Vậy lúc đầu số bi ít nhất là 3125 - 4 = 3121 (viên bi)."},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara ny 25 novambra 1992?","answer":"Tamin'ny 25 novambra 1992 dia nisy ny : fihodinana voalohan’ny fifidianana filohan’ny Repoblika, narahin’ny fihodinana faharoa tamin’ny 10 febroary 1993. Voafidy ho filoha i Zafy Albert (66,76%) ary nandray fahefana tamin’ny 27 marsa. "},{"question":"السؤال: من أطول ملوك بريطانيا عمرًا؟","answer":"الإجابة: إليزابيث الثانية"},{"question":"Trên hòn đảo phép thuật có 2021 tắc kè xanh, 2022 tắc kè đỏ và 2023 tắc kè vàng. Biết rằng cứ sau một phút, khi hai con tắc kè khác màu gặp nhau thì chúng sẽ cùng biến đổi sang màu còn lại.Hỏi sau ít nhất bao lâu thì tất cả tắc kè biến đổi thành cùng một màu?","answer":"Ban đầu, số lượng của ba loại tắc kè là ba số tự nhiên liên tiếp, nên khi chia cho 3 có ba số dư là bộ (0, 1, 2).Sau mỗi lần có hai con tắc kè đổi sang màu còn lại thì có hai loại tắc kè giảm 1 và loại tắc kè còn lại tăng 2. Do đó, kết quả số lượng của ba loại tắc kè nhận được vẫn luôn là bộ ba số dư (0, 1, 2) khi chia cho 3.Từ đó suy ra: ở mọi thời điểm, số lượng của mỗi loại tắc kè luôn là bộ ba số chia cho 3 dư (0,1,2) nên không bao giờ có thể biến tất cả các con tắc kè thành cùng một màu vì khi đó số lượng tắc kè sẽ là (0,0, 6066), tức là bộ ba số cùng chia hết cho 3"},{"question":"ทำไมมุสลิมไม่กินหมู","answer":"ตามหลักศาสนาอิสลามคำตอบที่ว่าทำไมมุสลิมไม่กินหมู ก็คือพระเจ้าสั่งห้ามนั่นเอง"},{"question":"வினா : 40 சதவீத பார்மால்டிஹைடின் நீர்க்கரைசலின் பெயர் ","answer":"விடை : பார்மலின்"},{"question":"Escribe código en Python para generar los 10 primeros números de la secuencia de Fibonacci.","answer":"def fibonacci(n):    \\"\\"\\"Genera los primeros n números de la secuencia de Fibonacci\\"\\"\\"    num1, num2 = 0, 1    count = 0        sequence = []    while count < n:        sequence.append(num1)        num1, num2 = num2, num1 + num2        count += 1            return sequence# Llamada a la funciónn = 10result = fibonacci(n)print(result)"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'datar bak lantai papan, licin bak dinding cermin'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sesuatu hukuman yang adil atau fikiran (pertimbangan) yang baik"},{"question":"السؤال: في الحرب العالمية الثانية ، ما هي معدات المشروبات التي يتم توفيرها في دبابات القتال البريطانية؟","answer":"الإجابة: شاي"},{"question":"Kuantum fiziği nedir?","answer":"Kuantum fiziği atomik, moleküler ve atom altı düzeyde madde ya da enerjinin doğasını ve davranışını inceleyen, modern fiziğin oldukça önemli olan bir çalışma alanıdır. 20. yüzyılın başlarından itibaren makroskobik nesnelerin davranışlarını açıklayan yasaların, bu şekilde küçük boyutlarda aynı görevi yapmadığı tespit edilmiştir."},{"question":"Ètò ajé","answer":"Yorùbá tọ̀ wọ́n ní kí la ó jẹ làgba kí la ó ṣe, abálájọ tí ètò ajé fi mumú láyà gbobgo orílẹ̀ èdè àgbáyé tóó bẹ̀. Gbàrà tí ọ̀nà káràkátà oní-pà ṣí pààrọ̀ tayé ọjọ́ tun ti dotun ìgbàgbé ni ètò ajé ti dotun tó gbòòrò síwájú sí. Awọn ènìyàn wáá bẹ̀rẹ̀ síí ní lo àwọn ohun èlò bíi wúrà àti jàdákà láti máa fii se pàṣípààrọ̀ àwọn ohun tí wọ́n nílò. Eléyìí mú kí káràkátà láàrín-ín ìlú àti orílẹ̀ èdè tún gbináyá síi nígbà tí àwọn kù dìẹ̀ ku diẹ tí ń fa ìdílọ́wọ́ nínú káràkátà onípàṣípàrọ̀ ti kúrò ní bẹ̀. Tí abá kọ́kọ́ gbé ètò ayé ní orílẹ̀ èdè aláwọ̀ dúdú yẹ̀ wò fínní fínní, aórìí pe ohun erè oko ló jẹ́ lájorí ọrọ̀ ajé àwọn ènìyàn yìí. Àwọn erè oko wọ̀nyí ni wọ́n si ń fi ń ṣe pàṣípàrọ̀ láti tán àìní ara wọn ṣááju alábàápàbé wọn pẹ̀lú àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun. Ṣíṣa lábàápàdé àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí mú kí àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú ní àǹfàní àti ṣàmúlò àwọn ohun èlò míràn bíi: Jígí ìwojú, Iyọ̀, ọti líle àti àwọn ohun míràn bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ, àti ibí yìí ni wọ́n ti kọ́ àṣà lílo àwọn ohun èlò táati dárúkọ ṣáájú yìí dípò pà sí pààrọ̀ tó mú ọ̀pọ̀ wàhálà lọ́ iwọ́. kẹ̀rẹ̀ kẹ̀rẹ̀, ìlànà àti máa lo owó wá sí ojútáyé, tí ètò ọrọ̀ ajé sì wá búrẹ́kẹ́. Ṣùgbọ́n pẹ̀lú ìbúrẹ́kẹ́ ọrọ̀ ajé yìí, ìyípadà díẹ̀ ló dé bá ipò ò ṣì tí àwọn aláwò dúdú yìí ti wà tẹ́lẹ̀ tẹ́lẹ́rí. Èyí tó pọ̀jù nínú èrè ọrọ̀ ayé ìgbà ló dé yìó lóńlọ sí ọ̀dọ̀ àwọn òyìnbó aláwọ̀ funfun. Kàyéfì ńlá ló jẹ́ pé bí ọ̀rọ̀ àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí tí ń pọ̀ sin i òṣì túbọ̀ ń bá àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú fínra sí. Kàyéfì ọ̀rọ̀ yìí ò sẹ̀yìn ìwà imúni sìn adáni lóró tí àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí fimú àwọn gìrìpá tó yẹ kó fi gbogbo ọpọlọ àti agbára wọn ṣiṣẹ́ láti mú ayé ìrọ̀rùn wáá bá ilẹ̀ wọn àti àwọn ènìyàn wọn. Nígbà tó yẹ kí àwọn gìrìpá aláwọ̀ dúdú máa ṣiṣẹ́ idàgbàsókè ní ìlú ìbílẹ̀ wọn, ìlẹ̀ àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun ni wọ́n wà tí wọ́n ń bá àwọn ènìyàn yìí ṣiṣẹ́ àṣekúdórógbó. Àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí ńlo àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú láti tún orílẹ̀ èdè ti wọn se, àti láti pilẹ̀ ọrọ̀ ajé tó lààmì láka. Gbogbo ìgbà tí ìmúni lẹ́rú yìí n lọ lọ́wọ́, tí ilẹ̀ àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí sì ń tẹ̀ síwájú, kò sí ẹyọ iṣẹ́ ìdàgbàsókè kan ní orílẹ̀ èdè aláwọ̀ dúdú. Ìgbà tí ìmúnilẹ́rú dáwọ́ dúró, lẹ́yìn ìgbà tí àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí ti gòkè àgbà díẹ̀ ń se ni wọ́n tún yára gba ètò ìṣàkóso ìjọba lọ́wọ́ àwọn àláwọ̀ dúdú, tí wọ́n sì sọ pé, ọ̀làjú ni àwọn fẹ́ẹ́ fi wọ àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú yìí tí ẹ̀wù ìdí nìyí tí àwọn fi tẹ wọ́n lóríba tí àwọn sì fi pá gba ijọba wọn. Òtítọ́ tó dájú nip é, àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí ríi pé ilẹ̀ àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú dára fún àwọn iṣé ọ̀gbìn erè oko kan bíi: kòkó rọ́bà, ẹ̀pà, àti kọfí èyí tí ó wúlò lọ́pọ̀lọpọ̀ fún ohun èlò àwọn ilé iṣẹ́ ńláńlá tí wọ́n ti dá sílẹ̀. Wọ́n wá fi tì pá tì kúùkù sọ̀ ilẹ̀ àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú di oko Ọ̀gbìn àwọn ohun èlò tí wọ́n ń lò tí àwọn ilé iṣẹ́ ńláńlá ti wọn. Ipò Ìṣẹ́ àti Ìmúni sìn yìí ni àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú wà tí tí fi di ìgbà tí wọ́n sọ pé àwọn funfun wọn ní òmìnira. Ipò òṣì àti àre tí àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun fi àwọn ènìyàn yìí sí kò jẹ́ kí wọ́n ó lè dá dúró, kí wọ́n sì dáńgbájíá láti máage àwọn ohun ti wọ́n nílò ní ilé iṣẹ́ ìgbàlódé ti wọn fún raa wọn. Àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí ló sì wá ń dá iye owó tí ohun erè oko tó ń wá láti ilè àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú yíò jẹ́, èyí ti ó ń túmọ̀ sí pé, ọwọ́ àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí ni dídọ lọ́rọ̀ àti òdìkejì àwọn ènìyàn aláwọ̀ dúdú wà. Ọwọ́ àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí ni ètò ọrọ̀ ajé àgbáyé wà, tó bá sì ṣe wùn wọ́n ni wọ́n ń lò ó. Abálájọ tó fi jẹ́ owó tí wọ́n ń ná nílùú wọn fińṣe ìdíwọ̀n pàṣípàrọ̀ ọjà ní ọjà àgbàyé. Kódà, àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè kan tó ní àwọn ohun àmúṣọrọ̀ kan tí àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí ò fi bẹ́ẹ̀ ní, bíi epo rọ̀bì ò he è dá ohun kan ṣe lórí ohun àmúṣọrọ̀wọn yìí láì sí ọwọ́ àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun yìí níbẹ̀. Abálájọ tó fi ṣòro láti rí orílẹ̀ èdè aláwọ̀ dúdú kankan nínú àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè tó ti gòkè àgbà. Ọ̀wọ́ àwọn aláwọ̀ funfun ni agbára ètò ọrọ̀ ajẹ́ àgbéyé wà, àwọn ló sì ń pàṣe fún àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè tó kù ní pa ọnà tí wọn yíò gbà ṣe ìjọba àti ọ̀nà tí wọn yíò gbé ọrọ̀ ajé wọn gbà, tí wọ́n bá fẹ́ àjọ ṣepọ̀ dídán mọ́rán pẹ̀lú àwọn."},{"question":"Aiza ny tany tsy mahavokatra indrindra eto madagasikara?","answer":"Ny misy tany tsy mahavokatra indrindra eto Madagasikara dia ny tany any atsimon’ny nosy."},{"question":"රික්තයක් තුළ දී විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංග සියල්ලේම ප්‍රවේගය කොපමණ වේද ?","answer":"රික්තයක් තුළ දී විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංග සියල්ලේම ප්‍රවේගය 3×10^8 m/s වේ."},{"question":"GAN'lar (Generative Adversarial Networks) nasıl çalışır?","answer":"GAN'lar, bir üretken model ve bir ayrımcı model arasında rekabeti temel alır. Üretken model, gerçekçi veri üretmeye çalışırken, ayrımcı model bu verilerin gerçekten üretilip üretilmediğini veya gerçek olup olmadığını ayırt etmeye çalışır."},{"question":"Lẹyin ọdun mẹta lọgba ẹwọn, Ṣeun Ẹgbẹgbẹ tun n bọ nile-ẹjọ o","answer":"Iroyin kan ti wa nita bayii nipa Ṣeun Kareem, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Ẹgbẹgbẹ, wọn lo ṣee ṣe ki igbẹjọ lori ọrọ ẹ tun waye lọjọ kẹfa oṣu kẹwaa ọdun yii, lẹyin to ti lo ọdun mẹta gbako lọgba ẹwọn nibi ti wọn gbagbe ẹ si.Gbajumọ nla ni ọdọmọkunrin yii, lara ohun tawọn eeyan mọ ọn si daadaa ki wahala ẹsun idigunjale ti wọn fi kan an yii too ṣẹlẹ ni ṣiṣe igbelarugẹ fawọn olorin, to si tun maa n gbe sinima Yoruba jade. Oun paapaa ti sọ ọ ri wi pe, oun lawọn mọto akero to maa n pawo wale foun daadaa, bẹẹ loun tun ni ile itura tawọn eeyan ti maa n gbafẹ.Ohun tawọn eeyan mọ mọ Ṣeun Egbẹgbẹ ree o, ki ariwo too gbalu wi pe, ọkunrin naa ni awọn ohun mi-in to n ṣe daadaa ni ikọkọ.Ile-ẹjọ giga (Federal High Court) l’Ekoo lọkunrin yii ti kọkọ foju han niwaju Adajọ Olurẹmi Oguntoyinbo ninu oṣu keji ọdun 2017. Latigba naa lo ti wa lọgba ẹwọn.Ṣeun Ẹgbẹgbẹ atawọn eeyan wọnyi, Oyekan Ayọmide, Lawal Kareem, Ọlalekan Yusuf ati Muyideen Shoyọmbo ni wọn jọ fi ẹsun jibiti ati idigunjale kan. Ẹsun bii ogoji ni wọn si ka si wọn lẹsẹ.Lara ẹsun ti wọn fi kan Ẹgbẹgbẹ atawọn oluku ẹ ni pe wọn lu awọn Hausa ti wọn maa n ṣẹ owo dọla ni jibiti owo to fẹẹ to ogoji miliọnu naira (N39, 098,100), ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọrun owo dọla (90,000) ati owo to fẹẹ to ẹgbẹrun mẹtala owo Euro (£12,550)Wọn ni bo ṣe gba owo yii kaakiri lọwọ awọn Hausa to n ṣẹ owo ilẹ okeere si owo ilẹ wa niyẹn o, ati pe aẁọn Mọla onidọla ọhun to fara gba a, wọn a fẹẹ to bii ọgbọn kaakiri ipinlẹ Eko laarin ọdun 2015 si 2017.Ohun ti a n gbọ bayii ni pe o ṣee ṣe ki igbẹjọ waye lori ẹsun ti wọn fi kan ọkunrin yii lẹyin ọdun mẹta o le to ti wa lọgba ẹwọn. Ọjọ kẹfa oṣu kẹwaa ọdun yii ni wọn sọ pe Ẹgbẹgbẹ yoo tun wa si kootu lẹẹkan si i, lẹyin ọpọlọpọ oṣu to ti wa ni ahamọ ijọba.Ṣe ni nnkan bi ọdun mẹta sẹyin ni wahala ọhun bẹrẹ wẹrẹ ladugbo kan n’Ikeja l’Ekoo nibi ti wọn ti n ta ọpọlọpọ foonu alagbeeka, kọmputa atawọn ẹrọ igbalode mi-in tawọn eeyan n lo. Awọn ọmọ Ibo lo fẹẹ pọju nibi ti a n sọ yii, nibẹ gan-an ni wọn sọ pe Ṣeun Ẹgbẹgbẹ lọ, ko si ohun meji to lọ ṣe nibẹ, wọn ni foonu Iphone olowo nla nla ni ọkunrin yii lọ ji gbe pẹlu awọn eeyan kan ti wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ ibi.Nibẹ gan an lọwọ ti tẹ ẹ, Iphone mẹwaa ni wọn ba lọwọ ẹ pẹlu, tọrọ ọhun si di ti ọlọpaa. Alaye ti Ṣeun Ẹgbẹgbẹ ṣe ni kete to bọ lọwọ awọn ọlọpaa ni pe, oun ko jale o, wọn kan fẹẹ fi iṣẹlẹ ọhun ba oun lorukọ jẹ ni.Ọrọ ọhun fẹẹ ma ti i lọ silẹ, ṣadeede lariwo tun gba ilu laarin ọsẹ meloo kan sira wọn wi pe wọn tun ti mu Ṣeun lagbegbe kan l’Ekoo, ati pe owo dọla ati Euro to fẹẹ ji gbe lọwọ awọn Hausa ti wọn maa n ṣe pasipaarọ owo lo koba a.Nibẹ yẹn gan-an ni wahala buruku ti de ba oun atawọn ẹmẹwaa, n lọrọ ọhun ba dele-ẹjọ ti igbẹjọ si bẹrẹ lojuẹsẹ.Gbogbo akitiyan agbẹjọro ẹ lati wa beeli fun ọkunrin yii lo jasi pabo o, nitori niṣe ni adajọ ni ko lọ wa owo iduro miliọnu marun-un naira wa, bẹẹ lo tun gbọdọ ni oniduro meji ti wọn yoo je ọga patapata lẹnu iṣẹ ijọba. Nibẹ yẹn gan-an ni idaamu buruku yii ti de ba Ṣeun Kareem.Wọn lohun to ṣẹlẹ ni pe, ọkunrin naa ko ri eeyan kan bayii duro fun un nitori ko sẹni to fẹẹ fi iṣẹ ẹ tabi orukọ rere ẹ ṣere. Bi ko ṣe ri oniduro ati owo miliọnu marun-un naira ti won sọ niyen, ti ọrọ ẹ si dabi ẹni ti wọn sọ pe yoo pẹ lẹwọn ju ọbọ lọ.Ni kete ti wahala ọhun ṣẹlẹ, pupọ ninu awọn eeyan ẹ lo sa fun un, koda lagbo awọn oṣere to ti lẹnu daadaa, yẹyẹ ni wọn n fi ọrọ ẹ ṣe, ti ko si si onifuji kan bayii, to tun kọrin ki i mọ.Ọkunrin olorin hip-hop kan tiẹ gbe orin kan jade to pe ni Jẹ ki n fun wọn l’Ẹgbẹgbẹ, eyi to fi ṣalaye bi gbogbo ọrọ ọhun ṣe jẹ pata.Ni bayii, adura tawọn eeyan ẹ n gba bayii ni pe ki Ọlọrun ṣiju aanu wo o, ki ọrọ ẹ yanju lọjọ kẹfa oṣu kẹwaa to n bọ yii nigba ti igbẹjọ yoo tun waye ni kootu."},{"question":"जिम कार्बेटचे जुने नाव काय होते?उत्तर:","answer":"हेली नॅशनल पार्क"},{"question":"Write an answer to the following question: what is a word that means you're able to jump between a lot of things?","answer":"Answer: a word that conveys the ability to jump between a lot of things is \\"versatile.\\" Versatile individuals are adept at adapting and performing well in various tasks, roles, or areas of expertise. They possess a wide range of skills and can easily switch between different activities or subjects."},{"question":"කණ්ඨ තාලුජාක්ෂර යනු මොනවාද ?","answer":"කණ්ඨජ් අක්ෂර යනු උගුර ආශ්‍රිත ව උපන් අක්ෂර වෙ..තාලුජ අක්ෂර යනු තල්ල ආශ්‍රිතව උපන් අක්ෂර වේ එසේනම් කණ්ඨතාලුජ අක්ෂර යනු ඒ දෙකම ආශ්‍රිත ව උපදින අක්ෂර යිඑ, ඒ, ඓ"},{"question":"ನಮ್ಮ ನಾಳಿನ ಪರೀಕ್ಷಾ ವೇಳಾಪಟ್ಟಿಯನ್ನು ಮುಂದಿನ ವಾರಕ್ಕೆ ಮುಂದೂಡುವಂತೆ  ಶಿಕ್ಷಕರಿಗೆ ಸ್ನೇಹಪರ ಇಮೇಲ್ ಬರೆಯಿರಿ ಏಕೆಂದರೆ ನಮ್ಮ ಬ್ಯಾಸ್ಕೆಟ್ಬಾಲ್ ತಂಡವು ಇಂದು ರಾತ್ರಿ ಚಾಂಪಿಯನ್ಷಿಪ್ ಪಂದ್ಯದಲ್ಲಿದೆ ಮತ್ತು ಎಲ್ಲಾ ವಿದ್ಯಾರ್ಥಿಗಳು ತಡವಾಗಿ ನಮ್ಮ ಶಾಲೆಯ ವಿಜಯವನ್ನು ಹೆಮ್ಮೆಯಿಂದ ಆಚರಿಸುತ್ತಾರೆ!","answer":"ಆತ್ಮೀಯ ಶ್ರೀಮತಿ ಜಾನ್ಸನ್,  ನಾಳೆಯ ರಸಾಯನಶಾಸ್ತ್ರದ ಪರೀಕ್ಷೆಯನ್ನು ಮುಂದಿನ ವಾರದ ತರಗತಿಗೆ ವರ್ಗಾಯಿಸುವಂತೆ ಕೋರಿ ಬರೆಯುತ್ತಿದ್ದೇನೆ. ನಿಮಗೆ ತಿಳಿದಂತೆ, ನಮ್ಮ ಶಾಲೆಯ ಬ್ಯಾಸ್ಕೆಟ್ಬಾಲ್ ತಂಡವು ಇಂದು ಸಂಜೆ ಕಾನ್ಫರೆನ್ಸ್ ಚಾಂಪಿಯನ್ಷಿಪ್ನಲ್ಲಿದೆ. ಹೆಚ್ಚಿನ ವಿದ್ಯಾರ್ಥಿಗಳು ಹಾಜರಿರುತ್ತಾರೆ ಅಥವಾ ಟಿ. ವಿ. ಯಲ್ಲಿ (ರಾತ್ರಿಯವರೆಗೂ) ನೋಡುತ್ತಾರೆ. ನಾವು ಗೆಲ್ಲುವ ನಿರೀಕ್ಷೆಯಲ್ಲಿದ್ದೇವೆ ಮತ್ತು ನಮ್ಮ ಅದ್ಭುತ ಶಾಲಾ ಸಾಧನೆಗಳನ್ನು ಆಚರಿಸುತ್ತಿದ್ದೇವೆ. ಇದು ನಮ್ಮ ಶಾಲೆಗೆ ಒಟ್ಟಾಗಿ ಆಚರಿಸಲು ಒಂದು ಉತ್ತಮ ಅವಕಾಶವಾಗಿದೆ ಎಂದು ನೀಡಲಾಗಿದೆ, ನಾನು ಹೆಚ್ಚು ವಿದ್ಯಾರ್ಥಿಗಳು ಹಾಜರಾಗಲು ಎಂದು ಭಾವಿಸುತ್ತೇನೆ ಮತ್ತು ಇದು ಮುಂದೂಡಲಾಗಿದೆ ವೇಳೆ ಪರೀಕ್ಷೆಯಲ್ಲಿ ಉತ್ತಮ.  ಗೌರವಯುತವಾಗಿ, ನಿಮ್ಮ ಅತ್ಯುತ್ತಮ ವಿದ್ಯಾರ್ಥಿ,ಜೋ"},{"question":"(ngezwi elinokuzithoba) Ngiyabonga ukungihlonipha kwenuzivakashi zami nafika lapho ebengicele ukuba niziveze khonangenhloso yokuzoxoxisana ngikhiphe lokhu okungaphakathi kimi.(kanye kanye.) Yebo baba.(athinte kancane isikhwehlela.) Lo mbiko engiqonde ukuwedlulisanamhlanje ngizoqala ngokuwubhekisa kini madodakazi amingomuzwa wokuzisola njengomuntu ozibona enecala phambikwamathongo ami naphambi kukaMvelinqangi ngenxa yesenzosodlame engasenza kini.(kanye kanye.) Yebo baba!(ujabhile.) Lo mbiko engiqonde ukuwedlulisa namhlanje lapha kiniingqikithi yawo isekutheni selokhu ngingenile lapha eselininjengomsolwa otokile osalindele ukuqulwa kwecala lakhe, angikazengikuthole neze ukuphumula emoyeni.Eqinisweni ngihlaselwa amaphupho amabi ephelekezelwa yizithunzizabadala abangamathongo omuzi. Bathi manginilande kuzo zonkeizinkalo enganichithela kuzo, khona lapho ngizicelele uxolo kiningiphinde ngihlawule ngembuzi yokugeza igceke lomuzi wabongenxa yokunihubha kwami ngesikhali emzini wabo. Sengicelaukuzwa kini-ke manje ukuthi ngabe niphawula nithini kuleli lamiloxolo. Ngabe niyangixolela zingane zami kumbe nisangibambeleinhliziyo namagqubu?(Esikhundleni sokuphawula avele abukane emehlweni amadodakaziyimbe.)1. Fingqa ngamaphuzu AMABILI izigameko ezaholela ekuboshwenikukaMdaluli.","answer":"UMdaluli ushaya uMaMlanduli ngoba efuna indabandaba ngenkani,uLondiwe wabiza amaphoyisa waboshwa. Kuthe ngokungawutholi umsebenzi wokwakha umuzi wakwaKhuzwayongenxa yokuthi umsebenzi sewutholwe nguChivenga, umlalelaunyendle ehlathini laseMphekandlubu, uyamshaya amlimazekwaqhamuka iphoyisa uZayeka lambopha."},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut: Apakah konsep kementerian perpaduan?","answer":"Jawapan: Konsep kementerian perpaduan adalah untuk mempromosikan dan memupuk perpaduan di kalangan masyarakat melalui pelbagai inisiatif dan program. Ini termasuk pendidikan dan latihan, aktiviti dan program bersama, promosi dan pembangunan, dan membantu mengatasi masalah yang mungkin menjejaskan perpaduan."},{"question":"एका मादा सिंहीणिचा गर्भकळ किती दिवसांचा असतो?","answer":"उत्तर: १०५ ते ११५ दिवस"},{"question":"Berikan satu contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"ada ubi ada batas, ada budi ada balas\\".","answer":"Mak Cik Limah menjaga rumah Encik Yahya ketika dia ke luar negara. Sebagai balasa, Encik Yahya menghadiahkan sehelai kain kepadanya, ibarat ada ubi ada batas, ada budi ada balas."},{"question":"燕窝中最珍贵的是","answer":" 血燕"},{"question":"पून हिल किन प्रसिद्ध छ?","answer":"पून हिल ट्रेकलाई अन्नपूर्ण सनराइज ट्रेक पनि भनिन्छ र किनभने सबैजना पून हिलको त्यो प्रख्यात स्थानतिर पदयात्रा गरिरहेका छन् जहाँबाट तपाईंले अन्नपूर्ण शृङ्खलामा सूर्योदय देख्न सक्नुहुन्छ, संसारको सबैभन्दा सुन्दर हिमालहरू मध्ये एक।"},{"question":"Kodi tiyi amakula bwino kuti?","answer":"Tiyi amalimidwa makamaka ku Asia, Africa, South America, komanso kuzungulira Nyanja Yakuda ndi Caspian. Maiko anayi akuluakulu omwe amapanga tiyi masiku ano ndi China, India, Sri Lanka ndi Kenya. Onse pamodzi amaimira 75% ya dziko lapansi."},{"question":"முதலில் பதிப்பித்த காப்பியம் எது ?","answer":"முதலில் பதிப்பித்த காப்பியம் சீவக சிந்தாமணி ."},{"question":"కింది పదాల అర్థాలను రాయండి. వీటిని సొంతవాక్యాలలో రాయండి.1. తెల్లముఖం వేయడం2. బుజ్జగించడం3. బిక్కమొఖం వేయడం4. ఎగగొట్టడం5. చీవాట్లు వేయడం","answer":"1. తెల్లముఖం వేయడం అంటే : వెలవెల పోవడం అని అర్థం.వాక్య ప్రయోగం : గురువుగారు అడిగిన ప్రశ్నలకు జవాబు చెప్పలేక, పిల్లలు తెల్లముఖం వేశారు.2. బుజ్జగించడం అంటే : మారాము చేసేవారిని, మంచి మాటలు చెప్పి ఓదార్చి, ఒప్పించడం అని అర్థము.వాక్య ప్రయోగం : కొత్త బట్టలు కావాలని ఏడుస్తున్న తమ్ముణ్ణి మా అమ్మ ఎలాగో బుజ్జగించింది.3. బిక్కమొఖం వేయడం అంటే : భయంతో తెల్లమొగం వేయడం అని అర్థం.వాక్య ప్రయోగం : బడి మాని సినిమాకు వెళ్ళిన తమ్ముణ్ణి, అమ్మ నిలదీసి ప్రశ్నిస్తే, వాడు బిక్కమొఖం వేశాడు.4. ఎగగొట్టడం అంటే : తీర్చవలసిన ఋణం మొదలయిన వాటిని తీర్చకపోడం, చేయవలసిన పనిని మానివేయడం.వాక్య ప్రయోగం :1) రామయ్య బ్యాంకు నుండి తెచ్చుకొన్న ఋణాన్ని ఎగగొట్టాడు.2) నా మిత్రుడు నిన్న బడికి ఎగగొట్టాడు.5. చీవాట్లు వేయడం అంటే : తిట్టడం లేక నిందించడం అని అర్థం.వాక్య ప్రయోగం : నా మీత్రుడు బడికి ఎగగొట్టాడని తెలిసి, వాళ్ళ నాన్నగారు వాడికి చీవాట్లు వేశారు."},{"question":"Inona no atao raha tratra ny sovoka ny vehivavy iray ?","answer":"Mila manantona hopitaly malaky vao ahitana ny iray amin’ireo fambara voalaza ireo ny vehivavy avy niteraka. Ny mpitsabo no mahafantatra ny fitsaboana sahaza rehefa avy manao fizahana ilay marary. Amin’ny ankapobeiny dia esoriny, karoina amin’ny tanana, raha toa ka misy potika ahitra tavela anaty tranon-jaza. Raha avy amin’ny loto kosa dia vonoina amin’ny alalan’ny fanafody ny mikraoba na bakteria fatiditra anaty tranon-jaza. "},{"question":"Isé àwon òbí nínú ètò ìgbéyàwó ni","answer":"ìwádìí"},{"question":"Wat voor belangrijke gebeurtenis beschrijft de volgende tekst: Op 9 november 1997 was het stadion onder de naam Molson Centre de locatie van het professioneel worstel-evenement \\"Survivor Series\\" en de \\"Montreal Screwjob\\", een beruchte gebeurtenis met betrekking op de worstelwereld.","answer":"Het gaat over de Survivor Series."},{"question":"inona ny volana faharoambin'ny folo ao anatin'ny taona?","answer":"ny volana faharoambin'ny folo ao anatin'ny taona dia desambra"},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Nhãn có nguồn gốc từ Đông Nam Á, trồng rộng rãi ở Thái Lan, Việt Nam, Trung Quốc. Cây cho quả vào mùa hè, thường được ăn trực tiếp, cho vào chè tráng miệng. Ngoài ra, y học cổ truyền cũng sử dụng nhãn để chế thuốc. Giá trị dinh dưỡng Theo Healthifyme, 100g nhãn chứa 60 calo, 15g carb, 1,3g protein, 1,1g chất xơ, 0,1g chất béo. Trong nhãn có chứa vitamin C, kali, phốt pho, đồng, mangan, sắt. Tác dụng Cải thiện bộ nhớ Nhãn có chứa các hợp chất tăng cường chức năng nhận thức và trí nhớ. Trong y học cổ truyền, quả nhãn được dùng để điều chế thuốc trị chứng lo âu. Nghiên cứu cho thấy, nhãn có thể có lợi cho não do tác động lên phần cấu trúc não bộ giúp xử lý ký ức. Nhờ đó, ăn loại quả này này thường xuyên giảm nguy cơ mắc bệnh Alzheimer. Làm đẹp da Nhờ hàm lượng vitamin C dồi dào, nhãn có tác dụng đẩy lùi các dấu hiệu lão hóa một cách hiệu quả như cải thiện sắc tố, làm mờ vết thâm, nếp nhăn và vết chân chim. Ngoài ra, trái cây này giúp hình thành collagen, tạo điều kiện sản sinh các tế bào da mới. Vitamin C trong nhãn cũng giảm tác hại của quá trình oxy hóa trên da như giảm thiểu nứt nẻ và bong tróc, giữ lại vẻ tươi trẻ cho làn da. Cải thiện chất lượng giấc ngủ Trong nhịp sống nhanh ngày nay, nhiều người bị mất ngủ hoặc ngủ không sâu. Nhãn có thể là phương thuốc bạn đang tìm kiếm nhờ hoạt tính giải lo âu. Nhãn giảm mức độ của một loại hormone gây căng thẳng. Tăng khả năng miễn dịch Quả nhãn có đặc tính kháng khuẩn mạnh, giúp hệ miễn dịch chống lại nhiễm trùng. Ngoài ra, vitamin C trong nhãn có khả năng giảm tác hại của các gốc tự do. Trà có thành phần chiết xuất từ nhãn ngăn ngừa các vấn đề về đường hô hấp như đau họng, cảm lạnh thông thường và sốt. Chống viêm Một nghiên cứu ghi nhận, nhãn có đặc tính chống viêm nhờ chứa axit ellagic, epicatechin và axit gallic. Tăng ham muốn Quả nhãn được xem là một loại thực phẩm bổ sung truyền thống tăng ham muốn ở cả nam và nữ. Nghiên cứu đã chứng minh vai trò của nhãn trong điều trị rối loạn cương dương và cải thiện quan hệ tình dục. Ngăn ngừa thiếu máu Sản xuất không đủ các tế bào hồng cầu khỏe mạnh có thể dẫn đến thiếu máu. Ăn nhãn sẽ cung cấp sắt cho cơ thể, kích thích sản xuất hồng cầu, cải thiện tuần hoàn. Do đó, bạn sẽ kiểm soát được tình trạng thiếu sắt và nguy cơ thiếu máu. Chống lại các bệnh mạn tính Cơ thể bạn giải phóng các gốc tự do chủ yếu do căng thẳng. Chúng có xu hướng gây tổn thương tế bào ở các mô và cơ quan. Các chất chống oxy hóa trong nhãn có khả năng chống lại một số gốc tự do có hại này. Qua đó, ngăn chặn quá trình tổn thương tế bào bất thường, giảm nguy cơ phát triển các bệnh mạn tính. Tăng cường năng lượng Nếu bạn đang muốn ngưng sử dụng caffeine, nhãn là lựa chọn lý tưởng. Loại trái cây ngon ngọt cung cấp một nguồn năng lượng tức thì nhờ chứa một lượng đường tự nhiên. Rủi ro Hàm lượng đường cao 100g nhãn chứa 65g đường. Do đó, không nên ăn nhãn nếu bạn bị tiểu đường. Hàm lượng đường cao và ít chất xơ làm tăng lượng đường trong máu nhanh chóng. Ngoài ra, 100g trái cây chỉ chứa khoảng 1g chất xơ. So với nhãn tươi, nhãn sấy khô và đóng hộp còn chứa nhiều đường và calo hơn. Vì vậy, nhãn không phải là lựa chọn an toàn cho bệnh nhân tiểu đường. Ngộ độc thuốc trừ sâu Trong quá trình phát triển, nhãn rất dễ bị sâu bệnh. Do đó, một số người nông dân sử dụng thuốc trừ sâu để bảo vệ cây. Nếu liều lượng thuốc vượt quá mức chỉ định, người ăn nhãn có thể đối mặt với nguy cơ ngộ độc thực phẩm. Không an toàn với người đang mang thai Nhãn có thể làm tăng nhiệt độ cơ thể. Mang thai là thời điểm người mẹ dễ gặp phải những cơn bốc hỏa. Do đó, ăn nhãn có thể làm bệnh nặng hơn, dẫn đến khô miệng, táo bón, đau bụng, thậm chí biến chứng thai kỳ.","answer":"Quả nhãn có ảnh hưởng như thế nào tới sức khỏe?"},{"question":"Ka amsa tambayar da ke gaba. A wane bangare na bututun dayake narkewa kuke tsammanin farkon narkewar sitaci","answer":" a bangaren ƙananan glandon salivary"},{"question":"තිපිටක මහාසීව මහතෙර ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"දික්සඟි අටුවාවේ සාමඤ්ඤඵලසුත්තවණ්ණනාවෙහි (141) සම්පජානකාරී යන පදය ගැන ත්‍රිපිටක මහාසීව තෙරුන්ගේ මතයක් දක්වන ලදි. එම අටුවාහිම මහපරිනිබ්බාණසුත්තවණ්ණනාවෙහ (376) මේ නම දීඝභාණක - ත්‍රිපිටක මහාසීවයයි පෙනේ. මැඳුම්සඟි අටුවාහි මහාසච්චකසූත්‍ර‍වණ්ණනාවෙහ (463) මහාසීව නාමය විශේෂණ පදයක් නැතිව පෙනේ. එහිම අච්ඡරිය ධම්මසුත්තවණ්ණනාවෙහ (918) තිපිටකමහාසීව තෙරුන්ගේ මතයක් දක්වා මහාසීව නමැති අන්‍යතෙරනමකගේ මතයක් ද පෙන්වා තිබේ. එබැවින් මහාසීව නමින් ප්‍ර‍කට කීපනමක් සිටියාහයි පිළිගත යුතුය. ඒ අටුවාහිම සතිපට්ඨානවණ්ණනාවෙහි (218) තිපිටකමහාසීව නාමය පෙනේ.අට්ඨසාලින - චිත්තුප්පාදකණ්ඩ - ලොකුත්තරකුසල කථාවෙහි (180) ආජීවපාරිශුද්ධිය ගැන මහාසීවතෙරුන්ගෙ අදහසක් පෙන්වා තිබේ. එහිම විපාක කථාවෙහ (215) මහාසීව තෙරුන්ගේ මතයක් දක්වා එය ප්‍ර‍තික්ෂෙප කොට තිබේ.මහවග අටුවාහ (237) භෙසජ්ජක්‍ඛන්‍ධකවණ්ණනාවෙහි මේ කථාව පෙනේ:- විනයධරයන්ට ප්‍ර‍මුඛ වූ කරවීකතිස්ස ස්ථවිර තෙමේ මහාසීළු තෙරුන් වෙත ගොස් පහන් එළියෙන් ගිතෙල් කළයක් දැක “මේ කුමක්දැ”යි විචාලේ ය. “ගමකින් ගිතෙල් කළයක් ගෙනෙන ලදි. රූක්‍ෂාහාර ලැබුණු විට ගිතෙල් හා අනුභව කිරීම සඳහාය”යි මහාසීවතෙර කීය. “එසේ තැබීම නොවටී”යයි කී විට මහාසීවතෙර එය ඉස්තෝප්පුවෙහි තැබ්බවිය. පසු දිනක ආ තිස්ස තෙර එය දැක නැවත විචාරා සහසෙය්‍යාවට යෝග්‍ය තැනක එය තැබීම නුසුදුසුයයි කීය. මහාසීවතෙරුන් එය ගෙයින් පිට තැබ්බ වූ විට එය සොරු ගෙන ගියහ. ඒ බව තිස්ස තෙරුන්ට දැන් වූ විට “ස්වාමීනි, සාමණෙරයකුට දියයුතු නො වේදැ”යි කීය.විනය අටුවාහි නිස්සග්ගියවණ්ණනායෙහ ද වෙඬරු කෑම ගැන මහාසීවතෙරුන්ගෙ මතයක් දැක්වේ."},{"question":"بطور معمول پرداخت شهریه دانشگاه های اروپایی بصورت یکجا صورت می گیرد یا امکان پرداخت چند مرحله‌ای شهریه وجود دارد؟","answer":"در اکثر دانشگاه هایی که تحصیلات رایگان نیست شهریه بصورت ترمیک پرداخت می شود. اما بسته به کشور و دانشگاه می‌تواند متغیر باشد. از قبل از ورود به دانشگاه برای دریافت ویزا شما باید مبلغی را به عنوان تمکن مالی (حداقل هزینه زندگی و تحصیل برای یکسال) را قبل‌تر در بانک کشور مقصد واریز کنید. این مبلغ بلوکه می شود و مدارک ضمیمه درخواست ویزا به سفارت مربوطه ارائه می‌شود. بعد از ورود شما به مقصد هر ماه بخشی از این هزینه آزاد می‌شود."},{"question":"கரும்பலகைத் திட்டம் எப்போது நடைமுறைப்படுத்தப்பட்டது?","answer":"கரும்பலகைத் திட்டம் என்பது 1986 ஆம் ஆண்டு ராஜீவ் காந்தி தேசியக் கல்விக் கொள்கை வெளியிடப்பட்ட பின்னர், 1987 ஆம் ஆண்டு நேரடியாக நாட்டில் உள்ள அனைத்து தொடக்கப் பள்ளிகளுக்கும் குறைந்த பட்ச முக்கியமான வசதிகளை வழங்குவதற்காக தேசிய அளவில் நிதியுதவி அளிக்கப்பட்ட திட்டமாகும். மாணவர்களின் கல்வியை மேலும் மேம்படுத்த, அவர்களுக்குத் தேவையான கல்வி வளங்கள் மற்றும் நிறுவன வன்பொருள்களுடன் முதன்மை நிறுவனங்களில் மாணவர்களைச் சேர்ப்பதே திட்டத்தின் குறிக்கோள் ஆகும்."},{"question":"人気お笑いタレント・明石家さんまの本名は何というでしょう？","answer":"杉本高文です。"},{"question":"Аллитерация деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"АЛЛИТЕРАЦИЯ ( лат.-кайталоо)- көркөм чыгармалардагы окшош үнсүз тыбыштардын кайталанып келиши.Мисал катары \\"Семетей\\" эпосунан үзүндү:Сарала тулпар ат минген,Сары алтындан тон кийген.Көктеке тулпар ат минген,Көпкөк темир кийинген.Жетик окуп жашынан,Жетимиш эки (72 😲) тил билген."},{"question":"Суроо: Эндоплазмалык тордун клеткалардагы ролу кандай жана ал белок синтезине кандай салым кошот?","answer":"Жооп: Эндоплазмалык ретикулум (ЭР) клеткалардын ичиндеги белоктун синтезине жана липиддердин алмашуусуна катышат. Ал белоктордун бүктөлүшүнө, өзгөрүшүнө жана ташууларына жардам берет."},{"question":"Me Zan Yi Idan Aka Matsa Mini In Yi Zina?","answer":"Ka yi la’akari da sakamakon da wasu matasa suka samu sa’ad da suka yi zina kafin aure."},{"question":"Maji ni nini?","answer":"Maji ni kimiminika. Maji ni muhimu kwa matumizi mbalimbali ya mwanadamu, wanyama na mimea. Maji hutumika katika mazingira ya nyumbani, viwandani, hospitali, gereji na kadhalika. Mwili wa mwanadamu unahitaji maji ili uweze kufanya kazi vizuri, hivyo asilimia sabini na tano za mwili wa mwanadamu ni maji. pia maji hutumika kupozea mashine za viwandani na magari. maji hutumika katika shughuli za kilimo. watu husema kuwa maji ni uhai."},{"question":"உங்கள் குடும்பத்தினருடன் வெளியூர் சென்ற தொடர்வண்டிப் பயணத்திற்கு இணையத்தில் எவ்வாறு முன்பதிவு செய்தீர்கள்? அதன் வழிமுறைகளை அனுபவத்தில் (அ) கேட்டறிந்து வகுப்பறையில் வழங்குக.","answer":"நாங்கள் கடந்தவாரத்தில் கோவையில் இருந்து சென்னைக்கு நீலகிரி விரைவு தொடர்வண்டியில் (வண்டி எண் பன்னிரண்டு ஆயிரம் அறுநூறு எழுபது இரண்டு) இரவு எட்டு முப்பது மணிக்கு முன்பதிவு செய்தோம். இரண்டாம் வகுப்பு (எஸ் – ஆறு, நாற்பத்தி ஐந்து, நாற்பத்தி ஆறு, நாற்பத்தி ஏழு, நாற்பத்தி எட்டு) தூங்கும் வசதி உள்ள பெட்டியில் இரண்டு நடுப்படுக்கை, இரண்டு கீழ்படுக்கை முன்பதிவு செய்து தானியக்கப் பண இயந்திர அட்டை மூலம் பணம் செலுத்தி கைபேசியில் வந்த குறுஞ்செய்தியை பயணச்சீட்டு பரிசோதகரிடம் காண்பித்து சுகமான பயணம் மேற்கொண்டோம்.இணையத்தில் தொடர்வண்டிப் பயணத்திற்கு முன்பதிவு செய்தல்:• மாணவர்களே! நாம் பயணம் செய்ய திட்டமிடும் பொழுதே, பயணத்திற்கான சீட்டை இணையவழியில் பதிவு செய்து கொள்ளலாம்.• இன்றைய காலக்கட்டத்தில் இணையதளத்தில் பயணச் சீட்டை பதிவு செய்வது மிகவும் எளிது. நம் நேரமும், பெருமளவு மிச்சமாகும்.• பயணம் மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டிய ஊருக்கு உங்கள் ஊரில் இருந்து செல்லும் தொடர் வண்டிகளை அறிந்து கொண்டு, அவற்றின் நேரங்களையும் தெளிவாகத் தெரிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும்.• பயணம் செய்ய விரும்பும் நாளில் எந்த தொடர்வண்டியில், எந்த பெட்டியில் இருக்கை வசதி மற்றும் படுக்கை வசதியுடன் இருக்கும் காலியிடங்களை அறிந்து கொள்ள வேண்டும். அவற்றை அறிய முனையும் போதே பயணச் சீட்டுக்கான தொகையும் அறிந்து கொள்ளலாம்.• பின்னர் வங்கி அட்டைகளின் உதவியுடன், பயணச் சீட்டிற்கான தொகையைச் செலுத்தி முன்பதிவு செய்து கொண்டோம் எனில், சற்று நேரத்தில் நமது அலைபேசிக்கு குறுஞ்செய்தியும், அச்செய்தியில் நமக்கான இருக்கை எண், புறப்படும் நேரம் போன்றவை வந்துவிடும்.• மின் அஞ்சலில் பயணச்சீட்டும் வந்துவிடுகிறது. நாம் பயணம் செய்யும் பொழுது, குறுஞ்செய்தியையும், நம்முடைய அடையாள அட்டை ஏதேனும் ஒன்றைக் காட்டி சுகமான பயணத்தை மேற்கொள்ளலாம்.• களைப்பின்றி பயணம் செய்ய இணையவழி பதிவு முறையே சிறந்ததாகும்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai keli dalam lubang\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuk peribahasa itu.","answer":"Ia bermaksud \\"seseorang yang merungut dengan tidak tentu hujung pangkalnya.\\" Rakan-rakan Roslin hairan akan sikapnya yang sering merungut seorang diri bagai keli dalam lubang."},{"question":"Awọn agbofinro ti n mu awọn to ji nnkan ijọba atawọn ileeṣẹ aladaani l’Ọṣun","answer":"Ọwọ awọn oṣiṣẹ alaabo ti n tẹ awọn janduku ti wọn ji awọn nnkan ijọba ati ti ileeṣẹ alaadani kaakiri ipinlẹ naa.Lati ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, lawọn janduku ti bẹrẹ si i lo asiko ifẹhonu han yii digunjale. Lara awọn ibi tawọn janduku ọhun ti ja, ti wọn si ko nnkan olowo iyebiye bii ounjẹ, dukia atawọn ohun eelo inu ile. Bakan naa ni wọn wọ ile Ọnọrebu Rasheed Olalekan Afolabi to wa niluu Ikirun, ti wọn si ko oriṣiiriṣii nnkan lọ nibẹ"},{"question":"関西外国語短期大学時代の同級生で結成した、昨年行われた漫才の「第２回Ｍ１グランプリ」で優勝を果たしたコンビは誰でしょう？","answer":"ますだおかだです。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਸਿਧ ਜਤੀ ਜੋਗੀ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਰਾਜੇ ਰਸ ਭੋਗੀ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਪੰਖੀ ਸਰਪ ਉਪਾਏ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਪਾਥਰ ਬਿਰਖ ਨਿਪਜਾਏ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਪਵਣ ਪਾਣੀ ਬੈਸੰਤਰ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਦੇਸ ਭੂ ਮੰਡਲ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਸਸੀਅਰ ਸੂਰ ਨਖੵਤ੍ਰ ॥ਕਈ ਕੋਟਿ ਦੇਵ ਦਾਨਵ ਇੰਦ੍ਰ ਸਿਰਿ ਛਤ੍ਰ ॥ਸਗਲ ਸਮਗ੍ਰੀ ਅਪਨੈ ਸੂਤਿ ਧਾਰੈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਜਿਸੁ ਜਿਸੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਤਿਸੁ ਤਿਸੁ ਨਿਸਤਾਰੈ ॥੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 275 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਇਸ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਿ-ਰਚਨਾ ਵਿਚ) ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਪੁੱਗੇ ਹੋਏ, ਤੇ ਕਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਸ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਜੋਗੀ ਹਨ, ਅਤੇ ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਹੀ ਮੌਜਾਂ ਮਾਣਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਰਾਜੇ ਹਨ;ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਪੰਛੀ ਤੇ ਸੱਪ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ) ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ,  ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਹੀ ਪੱਥਰ ਤੇ ਰੱੁਖ ਉਗਾਏ ਹਨ;ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਹਵਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਤੇ ਅੱਗਾਂ ਹਨ, ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਦੇਸ ਤੇ ਧਰਤੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਚੱਕ੍ਰ ਹਨ; ਕਈ ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਚੰਦ੍ਰਮਾਂ, ਸੂਰਜ ਤੇ ਤਾਰੇ ਹਨ, ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਦੇਵਤੇ ਤੇ ਇੰਦ੍ਰ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਿਰ ਉਤੇ ਛਤ੍ਰ ਹਨ;(ਇਹਨਾਂ) ਸਾਰੇ (ਜੀਅ ਜੰਤਾਂ ਤੇ) ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ) ਆਪਣੇ (ਹੁਕਮ ਦੇ) ਧਾਗੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਰੋਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜੋ ਜੋ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਤਾਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।\\""},{"question":"س: من هو المالك الحالي للوحة الموناليزا؟أجب عن السؤال السابق بنعم أولا مستعيناً بالنص في الأسفل:الموناليزا (باللُغةِ الفرنسيةِ: Mona Lisa، وباللُغةِ الإيطاليةِ: Monna Lisa) أو الجيوكاندا (باللُغةِ الفرنسية:La Joconde، نقحرة: لا جوكوند، وباللُغةِ الإيطاليةِ:La Gioconda، نقحرة: لا جوكوندا)، هي لوحةٌ فنيةٌ نصفيةٌ تعود للقرن السادس عشر لسيدةٍ يُعتقدُ بِأنها ليزا جوكوندو، بِريشةِ الفنان، والمهندس، والمُهندِس المعماري، والنحّات الإيطالي ليوناردو دا فينشي، حيث رسمها خلال عصر النهضة الإيطالية. استخدم دا فينشي في إنهائها طلاء زيتيا ولوحا خشبيا مِنَ الحور الأسود. تعد هذه اللوحة ملكاً للحكومة الفرنسية حيث تعلق هناك على جدار متحف اللوفر خلف لوح زجاجي مقاوم للرصاص وفي بيئة يتم التحكم بمناخها. لقد وُصِفت هذهِ اللوحة بِأنها \\"أكثر الأعمال الفنية شهرة في تاريخِ الفن، وأكثر عمل فني يتم الكتابة عنه، والتغني به، وزيارته من بينهم\\"، كما وُصفت أيضًا بِأنها \\"أكثر الأعمال الفنيّة التي تمت محاكاتها بشكلٍ ساخر في العالَم\\".يعود أصل تسمية الموناليزا بهذا الاسم إلى مؤرخ الفن جورجيو فاساري عندما كتب: وكلمة (Mona) هي اختصار للكلمة الإيطالية (Ma donna) والتي تعني \\"سيدتي\\" أي أن موناليزا تعني \\"سيدتي ليزا\\"، وليزا هي على الأغلب موضوع اللوحة. وكلمة (Ma donna) كانت تختصر بين عامة الناس في الحديث اليومي إلى (Mona). أما الاسم الإيطالي (La Gioconda) والفرنسي (La Joconde) فأصلهما يعود إلى الكلمة الإيطالية (jocund) والتي تعني \\"سعيد\\" أو \\"مرح\\". كما أن فيها إشارة إلى اسم زوج ليزا الأخير، \\"جوكوندو\\".تعد الموناليزا اليوم -تقريبا- أشهر عمل فني في العالَمِ؛ حيث يصل عدد زوارها إلى الستةِ ملايين زائر خلال السنة الواحدة (80% من زوار متحف اللوفر)، إلا أنَ الموناليزا لم تحظ بهذه الشهرة حتى مطلع القرن العشرين؛ حيث كانت في ذلكَ الوقت مجرد لوحة مِنْ بين اللوحاتِ العديدةِ التي حظيت بِتقديرٍ عالٍ. مع بداية القرن التاسع عشر بدأ الناس يمدحون دا فينشي وساد اعتقاد حينها بأنه عبقري، ومن ثم بدأت شهرة الموناليزا تنمو تدريجياً مع مطلع منتصف القرن التاسع عشر.ويعود سبب شهرتها تلك إلى عدة أسباب مختلفة من أهمها ابتسامتها التي وُصفت بِأنها غامضة ومبهمة؛ حيثُ حيرت العديد مِن الأشخاص مِثل سيجموند فرويد وأساتذة جامعة هارفارد وأعداد لا تحصى مِن المشاهدين.","answer":"السؤال لا يمكن الإجابة عليه بنعم أوﻻ."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සහල් නිෂ්පාදනය කෙසේද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාව තුළ සහල් නිෂ්පාදනය හෝ වී නිෂ්පාදනය (Rice production, Paddy production), ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධානතම නිෂ්පාදනයක් වෙයි. රටෙහි ප්‍රධාන ආහාරය ද සහල් ඇසුරෙන් සාදන බත් වෙයි."},{"question":"Usman Alkali Baba di ọga ọlọpaa patapata nilẹ wa","answer":"Igbimọ to n ṣakoso ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ilẹ wa (Nigeria Police Council), ati Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari ti buwọ lu Usman Alkali Baba lati di ọga ọlọpaa patapata, iyẹn Inspẹkitọ Jẹnẹra (IGP) awọn ọlọpaa ilẹ wa.Owurọ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii, ni Buhari ṣepade pẹlu igbimọ ọhun nile ijọba l’Abuja, lati fẹnu ko lori iyansipo Usman Baba, eyi ti Buhari ṣe lọjọ kẹfa, oṣu kẹrin, ọdun yii.Minisita to n ri si ọrọ awọn ọlọpaa, Alaaji Maigari Dingyadi, jabọ fawọn oniroyin lẹyin ipade naa pe Aarẹ Buhari ati ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa fimọ ṣọkan lori iyansipo naa, wọn si ti sọ Usman Baba di IG, o ti kuro nipo adele ọga agba to ti wa latigba ti wọn ti kọkọ yan an sipo.Usman Baba, ẹni ti wọn bi lọjọ kẹfa, oṣu kẹta, ọdun 1966, niluu Geidam, nipinlẹ Yobe, lo bọ sipo ọga agba patapata ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa lẹyin ti Mohammed Adamu fẹyinti nipo ọhun loṣu keji, ọdun yii, ki Aarẹ too fa akoko ifẹyinti rẹ gun siwaju di ọjọ karun-un, oṣu kẹrin.Ọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu kẹta, ọdun 1988, lo wọṣẹ ọlọpaa, oun si ni ẹni kọkandinlogun ọmọ Naijiria ti yoo di ọga agba ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa latigba ti orileede wa ti gba ominira."},{"question":"Iza no mpanoratra frantsay nanoratra ny \\"Les Misérables\\"?","answer":"I Victor Hugo no nanoratra ny \\"Les Miserables\\"."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన పదాలకి సమాసాలు రాయండి:1. మనోజ్ఞభావి2. శబ్దధాటి3. అజ్ఞానం","answer":"1. మనోజ్ఞభావి :మనోజ్ఞమైన భావి – విశేషణ పూర్వపద కర్మధారయము2. శబ్దధాటి:శబ్దము యొక్క ధాటి – విశేషణ పూర్వపద కర్మధారయము3. అజ్ఞానం :జ్ఞానము కానిది – నైత్పురుష సమాసము"},{"question":"问题：朝鲜的国家象征是什么？","answer":"答案：朝鲜的国家象征是国旗和国徽。"},{"question":"Ngiqinisile, ngadonsa fifteen years wonke, kodwa lo doti ujika uyangi …(Ekhuluma uMthofi engakaqedi ukukhuluma.)Usenikhokhele ngokubulala umyeni wakhe?(Enxapha) Lutho, kangithi yikho nje silapha? Sizofuna imali ye …Kulungile-ke madoda senisebenzile nasinciphisela umsebenzi.Sengiyanithatha-ke ngihamba nani.Uhamba nathi uyaphi?Ngiyanibopha. Seniyochaza phambili.Hawu madoda, kalula kangaka pho! Waze wangenza lo doti wesigangimadoda! (Abafake izinsimbi uNhleko abavalele evenini. Angqongqozeendlini kungavuli muntu, aphenduke angene evenini, ayidumise ihambe.)(Ekhuluma yedwa eshayela.) Kodwa kade ngangisola ukuthi lo Sontounesandla ekufeni kukankosikazi kaMbhele. Sesinabo nobufakazi,okusele ukuthi simbophe. Usezobhekana namacala amabili okubulala.Nginamanga, mathathu amacala okubulala azobhekana nawo ngobanampa oMthofi bavumile ukuthi babulala uMbhele ngoba bethunywe yisolesi sikhohlakali. Sekumphelele ngempela manje. Ingabe useyephiebusuku kangaka ngoba ngabe uyaboshwa kwamanje? Kodwa kufanelesingamtatazeleli.1. Lokhu okwenziwa nguNhleko ngesikhathi uSonto efuna ukubona uMfundisiesibhedlela kuyinto ekholekayo nengenzeka empilweni yangempela. Sekelalesi sitatimende ngephuzu ELILODWA.","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo: Kungenzeka empilweni yangempela ngoba amaphoyisa ayazigadaiziguli esibhedlela. Kungaba ubulima obukhulu ukuthi amaphoyisaavumele umsolwa ukuba azobona isiguli esibhedlela ngoba lokhokungenza ukuthi sibe nokwesaba sigcine sinqikaza ukwethulaubufakazi enkantolo.  Amaphoyisa awabavumeli abazobona iziguli eziqashwe ngamaphoyisauma sekukhishwe loyo mthetho. (Nokunye okunembayo okuyoshiwo umfundi)"},{"question":"Was ist der Unterschied zwischen Ober-/Unterhitze und Umluft beim Backofen?","answer":"Ober- und Unterhitze bzw. Umluft unterscheiden sich dadurch, wie genau geheizt wird. Bei Ober- und Unterhitze sind es Heizelemente (meist spiralförmig), die in der Decke bzw. dem Boden des Ofens verbaut sind und Wärme in die Backkammer übertragen. Bei Umluft ist es ein Ventilator hinten im Ofen, der die Hitze in den Backofen leitet.Die meisten Backrezepte basieren auf Ober- und Unterhitze–und auf mittlerer Schiene. Backen mit Umluft hat allerdings auch einige Vorteile. Die Wärme wird gleichmäßiger im Innenraum des Ofens verteilt. Deswegen kann man auch mehrere Bleche übereinander auf mehreren Ebenen backen, zum Beispiel, wenn man größere Mengen bäckt."},{"question":"1958年のノーベル文学賞に選ばれたものの、ソ連政府により受賞を辞退させられた、小説「ドクトル・ジバゴ」の作者は誰でしょう？","answer":"ボリス・パステルナークです。"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഖണ്ഡിക പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക:  പതിനാലാമത്തെ വയസ്സിലാണ്‌ അക്ബർ ചക്രവർത്തിയായി സ്ഥാനമേറ്റത്. തന്റെ ചക്രവർത്തിപദം അന്വർഥമാക്കുന്നതിന് അക്ബറിന് ഒരു പുതിയ സാമ്രാജ്യം കെട്ടിപ്പടുക്കേണ്ടിയിരുന്നു. ഇന്ത്യയിലെ ഒരൊറ്റ പ്രദേശമോ നാടുവാഴിയോ അക്ബറെ അംഗീകരിക്കുവാൻ ആദ്യം കൂട്ടാക്കിയില്ല. തന്മൂലം അക്ബർക്ക് ഏതാണ്ട് ജീവിതകാലം മുഴുവൻ തന്നെ യുദ്ധത്തിലേർപ്പെടേണ്ടിവന്നു. അക്ബർക്ക് ആദ്യം നേരിടേണ്ടിവന്നത് ആദിർഷാ സൂറിന്റെ മന്ത്രിയായിരുന്ന ഹിമുവിനെ ആയിരുന്നു. ആഗ്രയും ഡൽഹിയും പിടിച്ചെടുത്ത് ഹിമു ഇതിനകം തന്നെ 'വിക്രമാദിത്യൻ' (വിക്രംജിത്) എന്ന പേര് സ്വീകരിച്ചിരുന്നു. ബൈരം ഖാനോടൊത്ത് അക്ബർ ശത്രുസങ്കേതത്തിലെത്തുകയും 1556 നവംബർ 5-ന് നടന്ന","answer":"രണ്ടാം പാനിപ്പത്ത് യുദ്ധത്തിൽ ശത്രുവിനെ വധിക്കുകയും ചെയ്തു. ഡൽഹിയും ആഗ്രയും അതോടെ അക്ബർക്കു അധീനമായി. മാൻകോട്ടിൽ എതിർത്തുനിന്ന സിക്കന്തർസൂറും അക്ബർക്കു കീഴടങ്ങി (1557). മാൻകോട്ടുവച്ചുതന്നെ അക്ബർ 15-ാം വയസ്സിൽ പിതൃസഹോദരന്റെ പുത്രിയെ വിവാഹം ചെയ്തു."},{"question":"蚊子發出的“嗡嗡”的聲音是由於？","answer":"翅膀震動，一般蚊子飛行時每秒翅膀震動594次左右。"},{"question":"Bàn bindkat moo bind \\"reseñ wu naqar\\"; di ab téere bu'y nettli wenn askan wu ndóol ca ndóol gu mag ga ?","answer":"John Steinbeck"},{"question":"রাইবোসোমের বর্ণনা দাও।","answer":"সাইটোপ্লাজমে মুক্ত অবস্থায় বিরাজমান অথবা অন্তঃপ্লাজমীয় জালিকার গায়ে অবস্থিত যে দানাদার কণায় প্রোটিন সংশ্লেষণ ঘটে তাই রাইবোসোম। রাইবোসোম অত্যন্ত ক্ষুদ্র এবং প্রায় গোলাকার। সাধারণত অমসৃণ এন্ডোপ্লাজমিক রেটিকুলামের উভয় দিকে এরা সারিবদ্ধভাবে অবস্থিত থাকে। যে কোষে প্রোটিন সংশ্লেষণের হার বেশি সে কোষে বেশি সংখ্যক রাইরোসোম থাকে। সাইটোপ্লাজমে মুক্ত অবস্থায়ও রাইবোসোম থাকে। ৭০এস রাইবোসোম আদি কোষের একটি উল্লেখযোগ্য বৈশিষ্ট্য। রাইবোসোমের কোনো আবরণী নাই। সাইটোপ্লাজমে একাধিক রাইবোসোম মুক্তোর মালার মতো অবস্থান করলে তাকে পলিরাইবোসোম বা পলিসোম বলে। E. coli-এর কোষে এদের সংখ্যা প্রায় ২০,০০০ এবং শুষ্ক ওজনের প্রায় ২২%। আদি কোষ ও প্রকৃত কোষ এই উভয় প্রকার কোষেই রাইবোসোম উপস্থিত থাকার কারণে রাইবোসোমকে সর্বজনীন অঙ্গাণু বলা হয়।"},{"question":"Yusufeli Barajı nereler sular altında kalacak?","answer":"Yusufeli'nin eski ilçe merkezinin yanı sıra Irmakyanı, Yeniköy, Çeltikdüzü, Kınalıçam ve Meşecik köyleri de tamamen baraj suları altında kaldı. Borçka'dan gelen Malik Erdoğan, yeni ilçe merkezini görmek için bulundukları bölgede eski ilçe merkezinin tamamen sular altında kaldığına şahit olduklarını söyledi."},{"question":"Ar éirigh le Monica Loughman an fhuascailt sin a thabhairt slán ina léiriú den ‘Nutcracker’, sa Convention Centre Droim-Ar-Ais-Cois-Life, díreach ansin roimh Nollag?","answer":"Sin ceist, go háirithe agus an seó céanna ag an Moscow City Ballet in Amharclann an Bhoird Gháis, ón gCéadaoin seo chugainn ar aghaidh.Ní chuig na Rúisigh sin chugainn a thógaim an bata tomhais, ach don gcompántas logánta.Ní hé nár aimsigh Joan Denise Moriarty, ceannródaí na bpumpaí bróg, beannacht Dé lena saoranam, damhsóirí den scoth fadó – Lavinia Anderson, ina measc siúd.Taibheoirí a bhí in ann an fód a sheasamh ar comhchéim le haon aoídhamhsóir rabairneach fireann ar dhul Domy Reiter-Soffer na hIosráile, mar shampla."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੪ ॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਸੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਦਾ ਨਾਲਿ ਹੈ ਸੁਆਮੀ ਕਹੁ ਕਿਥੈ ਹਰਿ ਪਹੁ ਨਸੀਐ ॥ਹਰਿ ਆਪੇ ਬਖਸਿ ਲਏ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਾਚਾ ਹਰਿ ਆਪਿ ਛਡਾਏ ਛੁਟੀਐ ॥੧॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਜਪਿ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਮਨਿ ਜਪੀਐ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਸਰਣਾਈ ਭਜਿ ਪਉ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨਾ ਗੁਰ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪੀਛੈ ਛੁਟੀਐ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਸੇਵਹੁ ਸੋ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਸ੍ਰਬ ਸੁਖਦਾਤਾ ਜਿਤੁ ਸੇਵਿਐ ਨਿਜ ਘਰਿ ਵਸੀਐ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜਾਇ ਲਹਹੁ ਘਰੁ ਅਪਨਾ ਘਸਿ ਚੰਦਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਜਸੁ ਘਸੀਐ ॥੨॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਜਸੁ ਊਤਮੁ ਲੈ ਲਾਹਾ ਹਰਿ ਮਨਿ ਹਸੀਐ ॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਆਪਿ ਦਇਆ ਕਰਿ ਦੇਵੈ ਤਾ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਚਖੀਐ ॥੩॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਨਾਮ ਬਿਨਾ ਜੋ ਦੂਜੈ ਲਾਗੇ ਤੇ ਸਾਕਤ ਨਰ ਜਮਿ ਘੁਟੀਐ ॥ਤੇ ਸਾਕਤ ਚੋਰ ਜਿਨਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਿਸਾਰਿਆ ਮਨ ਤਿਨ ਕੈ ਨਿਕਟਿ ਨ ਭਿਟੀਐ ॥੪॥ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਸੇਵਹੁ ਅਲਖ ਨਿਰੰਜਨ ਨਰਹਰਿ ਜਿਤੁ ਸੇਵਿਐ ਲੇਖਾ ਛੁਟੀਐ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭਿ ਪੂਰੇ ਕੀਏ ਖਿਨੁ ਮਾਸਾ ਤੋਲੁ ਨ ਘਟੀਐ ॥੫॥੫॥੧੯॥੫੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 170 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਉਹ ਸੁਆਮੀ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ) ਨਾਲ (ਵੱਸਦਾ) ਹੈ । ਦੱਸ ਉਹ ਕੇਹੜਾ ਥਾਂ ਹੈ ਜਿਥੇ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਨੱਸ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ ?ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਸਾਡੇ ਅਉਗਣ) ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਹਰੀ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਪੰਜੇ ਤੋਂ) ਛਡਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਉਸੇ ਦੀ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਸਦਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਜਪ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਸਦਾ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਜਪਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਜਾ ਪਉ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲਿਆਂ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਬੰਧਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚ ਜਾਈਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਸਾਰੇ ਸੁਖ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰ, ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਚ ਕੇ ਅੰਤਰ ਆਤਮੇ ਟਿਕ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ) । (ਹੇ ਮਨ !) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਆਪਣਾ (ਅਸਲ) ਘਰ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਲੱਭ ਲੈ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ) । (ਜਿਵੇਂ) ਚੰਦਨ (ਸਿਲ ਨਾਲ) ਘਸ ਕੇ (ਸੁਗੰਧੀ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਿਵੇਂ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨਾਲ) ਘਸਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਗੰਧੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ) ।੨। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਖੱਟੀ ਖੱਟ ਕੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਦੋਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਦੋਂ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਚੱਖ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਭੁਲਾ ਕੇ ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹੋਰ ਪਾਸੇ ਰੁੱਝਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਟੁੱਟ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਮ ਨੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਘੁੱਟ ਲਿਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਥੋੜ੍ਹ-ਵਿਤਾ ਬਣਾ ਦੇਂਦੀ ਹੈ) । ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਸਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ, ਉਹ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਜਕੜੇ ਗਏ, ਉਹ ਰੱਬ ਦੇ ਚੋਰ ਬਣ ਗਏ । ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁਕਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ।੪। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰ ਜੋ ਅਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ (ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦਾ) ਲੇਖਾ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੰਸਕਾਰ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ) । ਹੇ ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਮੁਕੰਮਲ ਸੁੱਧ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਤੋਲਾ ਭਰ ਇਕ ਮਾਸਾ ਭਰ ਰਤਾ ਭੀ ਕਮਜ਼ੋਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ ।੫।੫।੧੯।੫੭।\\""},{"question":"Ahitsio ireo diso tsipelina ao anatin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Velon-kira ny vorna, niaraaba ny maraian'ny andro vaovao.\\"","answer":"Ity ilay fanambarana miaraka amin'ny tsipelina efa voahitsy \\"Velon-kira ny vorona, niarahaba ny marainan'ny andro vaovao.\\""},{"question":"Liste 3 músicas populares de Cazuza.","answer":"\\"Exagerado\\", \\"Codinome Beija-Flor\\", \\"O Tempo Não Para\\"."},{"question":"Šios valstybės diplomatinė atstovybė vadinasi nunciatūra, ji yra ir Lietuvoje – Vilniuje, T.Kosciuškos gatvėje. Tos valstybės vadovas, 2018 m. rugsėjį lankydamasis Lietuvoje, nakvojo ne viešbutyje, o būtent nunciatūroje. Parašykite, arba kuo vardu tas valstybės vadovas, arba kokia tai valstybė. Ši valstybė yra kitos valstybė viduje.","answer":"Popiežius Pranciškus, valstybė – Vatikanas."},{"question":"නාම විශේෂණ පදයි.ක්‍රීයා  විශේෂණ පදයි ටිකක් කියන්න කෝ","answer":"නාම විශේෂණ පද: දිග ,උස, මහත, හොඳ, කාරුණික, නපුරු ඔහොම කෙළවරක් නෑ.ක්‍රීයා  විශේෂණ පද: වේගයෙන්, හෙමින්, විමසිල්ලෙන්, දුකෙන්, සතුටින්, බයෙන්"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي شروط وجوب الزكاة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الإسلام، الحرية، بلوغ النصاب، تمام الملك، مضي الحول إلا في خارج الأرض"},{"question":"Continua il seguente paragrafo:\\"Piedras è un film del 2002 diretto da Ramón Salazar. La pellicola ha partecipato al Festival internazionale del Cinema di Berlino del 2002...\\"","answer":"\\"... ed è stata candidata alla vittoria dell'Orso d'oro. Per questo lungometraggio il regista ha ottenuto la nomination per il Premio Goya per il miglior regista esordiente nel 2003.\\""},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਧੰਨੁ ਇਹੁ ਥਾਨੁ ਗੋਵਿੰਦ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਏ ॥ਕੁਸਲ ਖੇਮ ਪ੍ਰਭਿ ਆਪਿ ਬਸਾਏ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਬਿਪਤਿ ਤਹਾ ਜਹਾ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨੁ ਨਾਹੀ ॥ਕੋਟਿ ਅਨੰਦ ਜਹ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਨ ਗਾਹੀ ॥੧॥ਹਰਿ ਬਿਸਰਿਐ ਦੁਖ ਰੋਗ ਘਨੇਰੇ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭ ਸੇਵਾ ਜਮੁ ਲਗੈ ਨ ਨੇਰੇ ॥੨॥ਸੋ ਵਡਭਾਗੀ ਨਿਹਚਲ ਥਾਨੁ ॥ਜਹ ਜਪੀਐ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕੇਵਲ ਨਾਮੁ ॥੩॥ਜਹ ਜਾਈਐ ਤਹ ਨਾਲਿ ਮੇਰਾ ਸੁਆਮੀ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਕਉ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਅੰਤਰਜਾਮੀ ॥੪॥੮੯॥੧੫੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 197 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਗੋਬਿੰਦ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਵਿਆਂ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ) ਇਹ ਹਿਰਦਾ-ਥਾਂ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਜਿਸ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਆ ਵੱਸੀ, ਉਸ ਵਿਚ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਆਪ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੁਖ ਸਾਰੇ ਆਨੰਦ ਲਿਆ ਵਸਾਏ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਬਿਪਤਾ (ਸਦਾ) ਉਸ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ (ਵਾਪਰੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ) ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਨਾਮ) ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਏ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਥੇ ਕ੍ਰੋੜਾਂ ਹੀ ਆਨੰਦ ਹਨ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦਾ ਨਾਮ) ਵਿਸਰ ਜਾਏ, ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਦੁੱਖ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਰੋਗ (ਆ ਘੇਰਦੇ ਹਨ) । (ਪਰ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਜਮ (ਮੌਤ ਦਾ ਭਉ) ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁੱਕਦਾ (ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ) ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਉਹ ਹਿਰਦਾ-ਥਾਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਹਿਰਦਾ ਸਦਾ ਅਡੋਲ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ,ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਜਿਧਰ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਉਧਰ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਾਲਕ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਲ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਸਭ ਦੇ ਦਿਲ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਆਪਣੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਨੂੰ) ਨਾਨਕ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ ।੪।੮੯।੧੫੮।\\""},{"question":"Yintoni into engathanga ngqo kunye nemizekelo?","answer":"Into engathanga ngqo (ekwabizwa ngokuba yiNgcaciso engathanga ngqo) ngumsebenzi wolungelelwaniso owabelwe umamkeli wesenzo. Ngokulungisa isenzi, siya kuhlala sikhona kwisivisa sesivakalisi. Umzekelo: Uvavanyo ndalunika utitshala."},{"question":"\\"बौद्ध स्तूप\\" को महत्व र ध्यान र आध्यात्मिकता मा तिनीहरुको भूमिका व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"बौद्ध स्तूपहरू पवित्र संरचनाहरू हुन् जुन ध्यान र आध्यात्मिक प्रतिबिम्बको लागि प्रयोग गरिन्छ, बौद्ध धर्मको सारलाई मूर्त रूप दिन्छ।"},{"question":"Katmandou mooy péeyu man réew?","answer":"Katmandou mooy gëblag réewum Népal."},{"question":"ధాతువుకు తే, ఐతే అనే ప్రత్యయాలు చేరే అసమాపక క్రియను ఇలా పిలుస్తారు?A) క్వార్థకంB) చేదర్థకంC) శత్రర్థకంD) నిషేధార్థకం","answer":"చేదర్థకం"},{"question":"Lan moo féete Senegaal soww ?","answer":"Sseyaa atalantig moo féete Senegaal co soow bi."},{"question":"*Кыздуу үйдө кыл жатпайт* деген макалды түшүндүрүп бер?","answer":"Бул макал менен кыздарды өзүнө тың болууга, тазалыкка үндөгөн макал. Чачтарын кырк көкүл кылып өрүп коюшкан үйгө кыл түшпөсүн деп."},{"question":"ஒரு சிறப்பு வரிசையில் ஒன்றாகச் செல்லும் விஷயங்களின் பட்டியலை உருவாக்கவும்.வரப்போகிறேன், இல்லாமல் இருக்கிறது, கொஞ்சம் அதிகம், முன்னுக்குப் பின், மறக்க நினைக்கிறேன்.","answer":"வருவது என்பது ஏதோவொன்றை அல்லது யாரையாவது நெருங்கி வருவது அல்லது வருவதைக் குறிக்கிறது. இல்லாதது என்றால் அங்கு இல்லை அல்லது காணவில்லை. கொஞ்சம் அதிகமாக இருந்தால் தேவைக்கு அதிகமாக இருப்பது அல்லது ஏதாவது ஒன்று அதிகமாக இருப்பது. முன்னும் பின்னுமாக திரும்பத் திரும்ப ஒரு இடத்திலிருந்து இன்னொரு இடத்திற்குச் செல்வது. மறப்பது என்பது எதையாவது உங்களை மறந்துவிடுவது அல்லது நினைவில் கொள்ளாமல் இருப்பது என்று நான் நினைக்கிறேன்.வரப்போகிறேன்: என் நண்பன்  இன்னும் சிறிது நேரத்தில் வரப்போகிறேன் என்றான்.இல்லாமல் இருக்கிறது: எங்கள் நாடு பஞ்சம் இல்லாமல் இருக்கிறது.கொஞ்சம் அதிகம்: சங்ககாலத்தில் மன்னர்களுக்கு காதலும் வீரமும் கொஞ்சம் அதிகமாகவே இருந்தது.முன்னுக்குப் பின்: முன்னுக்குப் பின் முரணாகப் பேசுவது நன்றன்று.மறக்க நினைக்கிறேன்: எனக்கு பிடிக்காத நிகழ்வுகளை மறக்க நினைக்கிறேன்."},{"question":"Tóm tắt pahafn truyện Don Quixote đã đánh nhau với cối xay gió trong tác phẩm \\"Don Quixote\\"","answer":"Cuộc giao chiến giữa người với vật được tác giả miêu tả bằng giọng văn hài hước, hóm hỉnh. Vừa lúc nổi lên một làn gió nhẹ và các cánh quạt lớn của những chiếc cối xay gió bắt đầu chuyển động, Don Quixote liền nói: \\"Dù cho bọn ngươi có vung nhiều cánh tay hơn cả gã khổng lồ Briaro, các ngươi cũng sắp phải đền tội\\".Nói xong, ông ta nhiệt tình thành tâm niệm cầu mong \\"công nương\\" Dulcinea của mình cứu giúp cho trong lúc nguy nan này rồi lấy khiên che kín thân, tay lăm lăm ngọn giáo, thúc con ngựa phi thẳng tới chiếc cối xay gió gần nhất ở trước mặt. Ông ta đâm mũi giáo vào cánh quạt, vừa lúc gió làm cánh quạt quay tít khiến ngọn giáo gãy tan tành, kéo theo cả người và ngựa ngã văng ra xa.Trong tác phẩm, không ít lần Don Quixote hành động ngớ ngẩn như vậy: gặp đám kỵ binh hộ tống một chiếc xe chở một phu nhân, ông ta nghĩ ngay đến một nàng công chúa bị bắt cóc đang cần giải cứu; gặp một đàn cừu, ông cho rằng đây là đoàn hùng binh của vị hoàng đế oai quyền nhất thiên hạ, lập tức ông kêu Sancho Panza dừng lại tiễn đoàn hùng binh của vị hoàng đế oai quyền nhất thiên hạ.Câu chuyện kết thúc khi một người cạnh nhà Don Quixote hóa trang thành hiệp sĩ để đánh với ông ta với điều kiện \\"nếu ta đánh thua, ta sẽ không làm hiệp sĩ nữa và nếu ngươi thua thì ngươi không được làm hiệp sĩ nữa\\". Don Quixote thua nên ông ta trở về nhà.Gần chết, Don Quixote nhận thức được tai hại và sự nhảm nhí của những cuốn truyện hiệp sĩ mà mình từng đọc. Ông ta viết di chúc rồi qua đời.Thông qua tác phẩm, nhà văn Cervantes chế giễu những tàn dư của lý tưởng hiệp sĩ phiêu lưu thời phong kiến, đả kích một thị hiếu tầm thường đang phổ biến trong công chúng. Ông thể hiện khát khao hướng đến một xã hội hậu phong kiến công bằng và nhân đạo hơn."},{"question":"Tambaya: yaushe ne sojojin Amurka suka fara amfani da M16?","answer":"Amsa: Shekara ta 1964"},{"question":"What was the first Disney animated feature movie that was not based on an already existing story?","answer":"The Lion King"},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Cuántas películas de Mortal Combat hay?. ","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es identificar la cantidad de películas de Mortal Combat. "},{"question":"أجب على السؤال 'كم كان عدد قضايا جرائم الحرب التي أقامتها النيابة العامة الإسبانية على سوريا ؟' بشكل مطول:","answer":"أُحيلت خمس قضايا -من بين القضايا التسع التي حقق فيها المدعي العام حتى الآن- من قبل الدول المعنية، وأحال مجلس الأمن اثنين منهم، وفوّضت الدائرة التمهيدية بفتح تحقيق في قضيتين منهم بناء على المعلومات الواردة من مصادر أخرى."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau:\\"Với chiều cao 3,9 m và chiều dài 11,6 m, bộ xương hóa thạch TRX-293 TRINITY gồm 293 chiếc xương được thu thập từ 3 bộ xương hóa thạch khác nhau của loài khủng long T-Rex được phát hiện trong thời gian từ năm 2008 đến 2023 tại các bang Montana và Wyoming (Mỹ).Đây là bộ xương hóa thạch T-Rex hoàn chỉnh thứ ba trên toàn thế giới và là bộ đầu tiên ở châu Âu được đưa ra bán đấu giá. Hơn một nửa số xương của bộ xương hóa thạch này được giữ nguyên gốc. Phần còn lại là những chiếc xương thay thế được làm từ thạch cao và khuôn đổ keo epoxy.Ngoài bộ xương nói trên, hai bộ xương khủng long T-Rex hóa thạch khác được phát hiện ở khu vực Bắc Mỹ, có tên gọi Sue và Stan, cũng đã được bán với giá lần lượt là 8,4 triệu USD và 31 triệu USD trong các năm 1998 và 2020.\\"","answer":"Hóa thạch khủng long giá hơn 6 triệu USD"},{"question":"Địa danh nào ở tỉnh Hưng Yên được mệnh danh là \\"Tiểu Tràng An\\"?A. Phố NốiB. Phố HiếnC. Mỹ Hào","answer":"B. Phố HiếnGiải thích: Phố Hiến rộng khoảng 5 km2, là một di tích lịch sử ở TP Hưng Yên, tỉnh Hưng Yên. Theo trang Thông tin Đối ngoại tỉnh Hưng Yên, sử sách ghi lại, những điều kiện thuận lợi về địa hình dòng chảy của các con sông như sông Hồng, sông Thái Bình, sông Đáy đã giúp Phố Hiến trở thành trung tâm chính trị, kinh tế, văn hóa của xứ Đàng ngoài vào khoảng thế kỷ XVII - XVIII.Với vị trí trung chuyển và là cửa ngõ của mọi tuyến giao thương từ vùng biển Bắc Bộ đi sâu vào đất liền tới kinh thành Thăng Long và các vùng sâu hơn của xứ Đàng trong, Phố Hiến thời bấy giờ đóng vai trò như một thương cảng quan trọng bậc nhất với cảnh trên bến dưới thuyền, các thuyền buôn nước ngoài với trọng tải lớn thường xuyên đậu kín sông Xích Đằng."},{"question":"Pasitọ Sakala ni ki wọn sin oun laaye, oun yoo ji lọjọ kẹta bii Jesu, afi bo ṣe ku patapata","answer":"Njẹ ẹ gbọ nipa pasitọ kan to ni oun nigbagbọ ninu Jesu, ọmọ ẹyin rẹ tootọ loun n ṣe. Pasitọ to ni ki wọn sin oun laaye, oun yoo ji dide ninu oku lọjọ kẹta bii Jesu, pasitọ ọhun ti ku lẹyin ti wọn gbe e sin laaye o.Pasitọ James Sakala lọkunrin naa n jẹ, ọdọmọde pasitọ ni, nitori ọjọ ori ẹ ko ju mejilelogun lọ (22).Orilẹ-ede Zambia ni ṣọọṣi rẹ wa, orukọ ṣọọṣi naa ni Zion Church.Awọn to mọ ọn sọ pe igbagbọ rẹ le pupọ, wọn ni ko si ara ti ko le da, nitori ohun to maa n sọ ni pe bẹẹ ni Jesu ṣe to fi ṣe aṣeye, ti gbogbo aye fi n wari fun un.Laipẹ yii ni wọn lo bẹrẹ iwasuu òdì kan, to bẹrẹ si i beere lọwọ awọn ọmọ ijọ rẹ pe ṣe wọn nigbagbọ ṣa. Wọn ni Pasitọ Sakala sọ pe njẹ wọn mọ pe bi wọn ba gbe oun sin laaye, oun yoo ji dide ninu oku lọjọ kẹta, gẹgẹ bi Jesu ṣe ṣe nigba aye ẹ.Awọn ara ṣọọṣi ti igbagbọ wọn ko gbe e sọ fun un pe awọn ko fẹ ko tiẹ dan iru rẹ, wo, bo ti wu ki kinni ọhun da a loju to, wọn ni ko ma ṣe bẹẹ rara. Ṣugbọn awọn kan ko fẹẹ kọrọ si i lẹnu, wọn ni ẹni mimọ ninu Oluwa ni, ko si le sọ ohun ti ko da a loju. Koda, awọn kan beere lọwọ Sakala pe ki lo de to fi fẹẹ gbe igbesẹ to lewu yii, ohun to sọ fun wọn ni pe Jesu ni kawọn ọmọ ẹyin oun maa ṣeranti oun boun ba lọ tan, o ni ajinde rẹ pada lo n wi, ki i ṣe ki wọn kan maa lọọ jẹ akara alaiwu ni ṣọọṣi nikan.Wọn ni Pasitọ James Sakala sọ pe ‘Ẹyin ti igbagbọ yin lẹ yii, ẹ gbe Sakala yii sin laaye, ẹ o si ri i pe yoo ji dide pada ninu oku, yoo si maa mi pada gẹgẹ bii alaye.Bẹẹ lo si ṣe ti awọn ọmọ ijọ ti wọn fẹẹ wo miraku, iyanu nla ẹlẹkeeji lẹyin iku Jesu, gbe pasitọ wọn si koto to ti gbẹ silẹ.Wọn ni aṣọ funfun ni Sakala fi pakaja bii Jesu, o si wọ bata rọba alawọ buraun si i, o dubulẹ sibẹ, wọn n rọ yẹẹpẹ bo o looye, awọn ọmọ ijọ rẹ si n kọrin ogo fun un bi wọn ṣe n sin in, wọn fijo yẹ ẹ si de ajule ọrun.Nigba tọjọ kẹta pe e, wọn ko yẹpẹ kuro lori Pasitọ Sakala, oorun buruku lo kọkọ bẹrẹ si i bo wọn. Ọkunrin naa ti ku sabẹ yẹẹpẹ, o ti n jẹra.Wọn ni wọn ri ẹjẹ lara rẹ, wọn ri ikun pẹlu, o jọ pe nibi to ti n gbiyanju ati jade labẹ ilẹ ni ikun imu rẹ ọtun ti bọ si tosi, to pọ rẹpẹtẹ, to yi i lara nibi to ti n gbiyanju lati bọ lọwọ iku.Ṣọọṣi rẹ ti dahoro wayi, iyẹn nikan si kọ, awọn ọlọpaa  Geza Phiri to ti ṣẹlẹ ṣi n wa awọn ọmọ ijọ to lọwọ si isinku abaadi naa, wọn ni mireku buruku ti wọn fẹẹ ri ni wọn tori ẹ pa pasitọ wọn nipa gbigbe e sin laaye."},{"question":"Rispondi alla seguente domanda:Cosa si intende per valore aggiunto in economia politica?","answer":"In economia politica, il valore aggiunto è la variazione di valore di un bene al termine di un processo produttivo. Si calcola prendendo il prezzo del bene finito e sottraendo il prezzo dei beni intermedi che sono serviti a produrlo. Il valore aggiunto è dunque l’incremento del valore di una merce quando essa è uscita da un processo produttivo."},{"question":"Completa la siguiente frase : Asignado al Grupo 5 durante la... ","answer":"Invasión alemana de Noruega en abril de 1940, el \\"Blücher\\" sirvió como buque insignia del contralmirante Oskar Kummetz. El crucero lideró la flotilla germana que penetró en el fiordo de Oslo la noche del 8 de abril para apoderarse de Oslo, la capital de Noruega, pero dos viejos cañones de costa de la fortaleza de Oscarsborg dispararon contra el barco a muy poca distancia y le causaron dos impactos. Dos torpedos lanzados adesde baterías terrestres también le hicieron blanco y provocaron un gran incendio a bordo del \\"Blücher\\" que no pudo ser controlado. Tras una explosión de sus almacenes de munición, el barco escoró lentamente y se hundió, con la pérdida de gran cantidad de vidas. Su pecio permanece en el fondo del fiordo de Oslo."},{"question":"2023 ஆம் ஆண்டின் சீனியர் நேஷனல் ஹாக்கி சாம்பியன்ஷிப் பட்டம் வென்ற அணி.1)ஹரியானா2)பஞ்சாப்3)தமிழ்நாடு4)கர்நாடகா","answer":"விடை-   2) பஞ்சாப்2023  ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான தமிழகத்தில் நடைபெற்ற 13 வது  இந்தியா சீனியர் ஆண்கள் தேசிய சாம்பியன்ஷிப்  ஹாக்கி போட்டியில்  பஞ்சாப் ஹாக்கி அணி ஹரியானாவை வீழ்த்தி தங்கப் பதக்கம் வென்றது. சீனியர் தேசிய ஹாக்கி சாம்பியன்ஷிப்  போட்டி என்பது இந்தியாவின் விளையாட்டு நிர்வாக அமைப்பான ஹாக்கி இந்தியாவின் கீழ் மாநில சங்கங்கள் மற்றும் அரசு நிறுவனங்களால் நடத்தப்படும் மாநில அளவிலான தேசிய ஆடுகள ஹாக்கி போட்டியாகும்."},{"question":"විසන්ධි කරන්න..අරුණලුනිරානන්දඇදුරිදුකුමාරෝදයදිගැසියෙන්රාජාවලියසියලඟ","answer":"අරුණ+අලුනිර්+ආනන්දඇදුරු+ඉඳුකුමාර+උදයදිගු+ඇසියෙන්‍රාජ+ආවලියසියල්+අඟ"},{"question":"السؤال: اشرح عن class variable؟","answer":"الإجابة: تمثل المتغيرات ذاكرة الطبقة ، والتي تشاركها مع كل حالة."},{"question":"Мотивация (түрткү) бере турган сөздөр менен бөлүш !","answer":"Жөнөкөй адам кантип убактысын өткөрүүнү ойлойт, ал эми акылдуу адам кантип аны пайдаланууну ойлойт ."},{"question":"السؤال: اذكر ما هي الحقوق العامة؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي حقوق تتسم بالطابع الجماعي"},{"question":"Thông điệp của tác giả gửi gắm ở bài thơ \\"Bánh trôi nước\\" là gì?","answer":"bài thơ Bánh trôi nước được sử dụng cho phần tự học, sách giáo khoa Ngữ văn lớp 7 tập 1 (Nhà xuất bản Giáo dục Việt Nam). Theo tóm tắt của sách này, với ngôn ngữ bình dị, bài thơ cho thấy Hồ Xuân Hương rất trân trọng vẻ đẹp, phẩm chất son sắt của người phụ nữ Việt Nam ngày xưa. Đồng thời, bà bày tỏ lòng cảm thương sâu sắc cho thân phận chìm nổi của họ.Theo sách Phân tích, bình luận tác phẩm học trong nhà trường, tác phẩm không thuộc thể loại thơ thường thấy của Hồ Xuân Hương: Thanh mà tục, tục mà thanh. Một cách kín đáo, tế nhị, tác phẩm vẫn gợi lên hình ảnh một người con gái mà thân xác đáng yêu và đáng thương có thể cảm giác được bằng thị giác và cả xúc giác.Cũng theo sách này, trong xã hội rối ren, đen bạc, lừa đảo như cuối thế kỷ 18 và đầu thế kỷ 19, trong cuộc đời long đong chìm nổi như chính cuộc đời của Hồ Xuân Hương. Việc giữ được lòng kiên trinh, chung thủy, giữ được bản chất tốt đẹp của mình rất khó.Bài thơ có nghĩa đen và nghĩa bóng. Chính tầng nghĩa bóng này đã phản ánh lòng khát khao giữ gìn và vươn tới cái đẹp, cái thiện của Hồ Xuân Hương và những người con gái chịu số phận bất hạnh như bà. Giá trị nhân đạo và hiện đại của bài thơ chính là ở điểm đó."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Jakie są najczęstsze objawy demencji?","answer":"Oto niektóre z objawów demencji:- Zapominanie niedawnych zdarzeń, imion i twarzy.- Zadawanie wciąż tych samych pytań.- Chowanie przedmiotów w niewłaściwych miejscach.- Trudności z koncentracją.- Trudności z ustaleniem bieżącej daty.- Gubienie się w nowych miejscach.Przyczyną demencji mogą być różne choroby. U większości osób z demencją występuje choroba Alzheimera lub demencja naczyniowa, ale istnieją również inne rodzaje demencji. Te choroby powodują zmiany w różnych częściach mózgu, stąd na każdą osobę wpływają one inaczej."},{"question":"குற்றியலுகரம், முற்றியலுகரம் இவற்றின் வேறுபாட்டை எழுதுக.","answer":"குற்றியலுகரத்தில் வரும் “உ” கரமானது தனக்குரிய ஒரு மாத்திரையில் இருந்து அரை மாத்திரையாக குறுகி ஒலிக்கும்.முற்றியலுகரத்தில் வரும் “உ” கரமானது தன் ஒரு மாத்திரை அளவில் குறையாது ஒலிக்கும்."},{"question":"英語China是中國的意思，那么，china是什麼意思呢？","answer":"瓷器"},{"question":"Muotoile seuraava lause uudelleen. Kirjoita, kuin neuvoisit ystävääsi: Jos kerrot ongelmastasi huumevirastolle, he vetäisivät sinut pois jutusta.","answer":"Jos kerrot huumevirastolle ongelmastasi, on mahdollista, että he siirtävät sinut syrjään tästä jutusta."},{"question":"Ngiwedlule-ke lo mfula. Ngithi ukuqalaza emuva ibanga esengilihambile,yize kungekho nakubona kahle ngenxa yobumnyama lobu. Cha,sengihambile nokho. Amamayela ayishumi aphelile ngihamba. Ungicasulilenje naloya muntu wemoto obengikhwezile ukuthi sengimkhokhele yonkeimali yakhe athi ngeke akwazi ukungiwelisela esitobhini kwaChonco.Bekuzoba lula ukufika ngokushesha kuNokwazi. Manje ngihlalelwe ngukuthiuma ngifika kubo ngilokhu nginyonyoba ukuze umkhwe wami ngingathukisengizithela kuye1. Chaza kafishane ngecala elenziwa ngumlingiswa omkhulunokwaholela ekutheni aze aboshwe.","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo:• USipho wahamba emsebenzini esebonile ukuthi imaliyasemsebenzini ibekwaphi. Ngelanga ayezontshontsha ngaloimali akekho owayesebenza, wavula ngokhiye ayesewebile.• Esephuma wabonwa unogada owamdubula nokho wabalekanemali wayifihla, yikho ukulimala okwambambisa, wabanjwa,wagwetshwa waboshwa."},{"question":"ਬਿਸਤ ਦੋਆਬ ਵਿਚ ਬਿਸਤ ਤੋਂ ਕੀ ਭਾਵ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਬਿਆਸ ਅਤੇ ਸਤਲੁਜ ਦਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਸ਼ਬਦਾਂ ‘ਬਿ’ ਅਤੇ ‘ਸਤ’ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਾ ਕੇ ਬਿਸਤ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਬਣਿਆ ।ਦੁਆਬਾ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਸ ਅਤੇ ਸਤਲੁਜ ਦਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਿਸਟ ਦੁਆਬ ਜਾਂ ਜਲੰਧਰ ਦੁਆਬ ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਹੁਸ਼ਿਆਰਪੁਰ, ਕਪੂਰਥਲਾ, ਜਲੰਧਰ, ਸ਼ਹੀਦ ਭਗਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਨਗਰ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਦੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦੁਆਬੀਏ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੋ+ਆਬ ਮਤਲਵ ਦੋ ਪਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਧਰਤੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਣਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ 35% ਅਬਾਦੀ ਪਛੜੀਆਂ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀਆਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਐਨਆਰ ਆਈ ਦਾ ਇਲਾਕਾ ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਆਮ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਦੁਆਬੇ ਦੇ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਨੂੰ ਮੰਜਕੀ, ਦੋਨਾ, ਧੱਕ, ਸਿਰੋਵਾਲ, ਕੰਡੀ ਅਤੇ ਬੇਟ ਵੰਡਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। "},{"question":"\\"කෘතිම බුද්ධියේ පියා\\" ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"John McCarthy බොහෝ විට \\"කෘතිම බුද්ධියේ පියා\\" ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලබන්නේ ඔහුගේ පරිගණක විද්‍යාව සහ AI හි පුරෝගාමී කාර්යය නිසාය. ඔහු 1950 ගණන්වල \\"කෘතිම බුද්ධිය\\" යන යෙදුම නිර්මාණය කළ අතර එය \\"සුහුරු යන්ත්‍ර සෑදීමේ විද්‍යාව සහ ඉංජිනේරු විද්‍යාව(the science and engineering of making machines that are smart)\\" ලෙස අර්ථ දැක්වීය. මැකාති AI ක්ෂේත්‍රයට සැලකිය යුතු දායකත්වයක් ලබා දුන්නේය."},{"question":"Pytanie jaki jest najwyższy szczyt Bretanii?","answer":"Odpowiedź: Najwyższy szczyt Bretanii to Roc’h Ruz. MA on wysokość 385 metrów nad poziomem morza."},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Bagaimana untuk mengelakkan kemalangan yang berpunca daripada keadaan jalan?A. Memandu perlahan dan membunyikan hon sepanjang jalanB. Memandu dengan cepat dan memotong kenderaan di kawasan laranganC. Menyesuaikan kelajuan kenderaan anda mengikut keadaan jalan.","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C. Menyesuaikan kelajuan kenderaan anda mengikut keadaan jalan."},{"question":"Awọn tọọgi kọlu awọn oluwọde l’Ekiti, ni Fayẹmi ba ti ileewe pa","answer":"Wahala nla lo ṣẹlẹ lọṣan-an ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, niluu Ado-Ekiti, ti i ṣe olu-ilu ipinlẹ Ekiti, pẹlu bi awọn tọọgi ṣe kọ lu awọn to n ṣewọde ta ko SARS niluu naa.Awọn tọọgi ọhun tawọn eeyan fura si gẹgẹ bii ọmọ ẹgbẹ onimọto lo ko ada, igi atawọn nnkan ija oloro mi-in, ti wọn si kọ lu awọn oluwọde lagbegbe Adebayọ.Awọn afurasi ọhun la gbọ pe wọn n binu si bi idaduro ṣe ba eto ọrọ-aje ipinlẹ naa.Niṣe lawọn oluwọde to laya koju awọn tọọgi ọhun, tawọn ti ko le duro si sa asala fẹmi-in wọn, eyi si fa ipalara fun ọpọlọpọ eeyan, eyi to fi mọ awọn to kan n kọja lọ.Nigba ta a pe Alukoro ọlọpaa Ekiti, Sunday Abutu, o ni wọn ko ti i sọ iṣẹlẹ naa foun.Ẹwẹ, ijọba ipinlẹ Ekiti ti kede pe gbogbo ileewe ti di titi pa lati asiko yii lọ titi di ipari ọse yii.Kọmiṣanna feto ẹkọ, imọ sayẹnsi ati imọ ẹrọ, Ọmọwe Ọlabimpe Aderiye, lo kede ọrọ naa. O ni igbesẹ naa waye lati daabo bo ẹmi awọn olukọ ati akẹkọọ, gbogbo wọn yoo si wọle lọjọ Aje, Mọnde to n bọ."},{"question":"Ile-ẹjọ yẹ aga nidii aṣofin APC ni Kwara","answer":"Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, nile-ẹjọ to n gbọ ẹhonu ibo, to fikalẹ siluu Ilọrin kede oludije ẹgbẹ PDP, Ọnarebu Salihu Muhammad Yahaya, gẹgẹ bii ẹni to jawe olubori ninu atundi ibo sileegbimọ aṣofin Kwara lati ṣoju Patigi, eyi to waye lọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu kẹta, ọdun 2020.Ọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu kẹta, ọdun yii, ni ajọ eleto idibo kede oludije APC, Adam Ahmed Rufai, bii ẹni to jawe olubori atundi ibo naa, ṣugbọn Yahaya to ṣoju PDP tako o, o si gba ile-ẹjọ lọ.Dokita Abdulazeez Iṣhọla Musbau, ti Fasiti Ilọrin kede nigba naa pe Rufai ni ibo to le lẹgbẹrun mẹwaa lati fagba han awọn ẹgbẹ rẹ marun-un yooku ti wọn jọ dupo naa.Rufai lo dije lati rọpo ẹgbọn rẹ, Ọnarebu Saidu Ahmed Rufai, to n ṣoju Patigi tẹlẹ, ẹni to doloogbe loṣu kejila, ọdun 2019,  lẹyin aisan to ba a finra.Awọn ẹgbẹ oṣelu mẹfa to kopa ninu atundi ibo naa ni; AAC, ADC, APC, APM, NNPP ati PDP tajọ INEC kede pe o ṣe ipo keji.Ẹwẹ, Alaga ẹgbẹ PDP, Ọnarebu Kọla Ṣhittu, ti gboṣuba fun ile-ẹjọ lori idajọ naa. O ni yoo mu ki araalu tubọ nigbagbọ ninu eto idajọ.O waa ke si ile aṣofin Kwara lati bura wọle fun Ọnarebu Raheem Agboọla, ẹni tile-ẹjọ ti kede ṣaaju pe o jawe olubori gẹgẹ bii oludije to n ṣoju ẹkun Ilọrin South, nileegbimọ aṣofin."},{"question":"Unsa nga adlaw nag sunod sa Sabado?","answer":"Ang Sabado gi sundan ug Dominggo."},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Belize nékk","answer":"Réwum Belize mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Amerique"},{"question":"Күлкү ден соолукка кандай салым кошот?","answer":"Күлкүнүн ден соолукка ар кандай пайдасы бар, анын ичинде стресс гормондорун азайтат, жүрөк-кан тамыр системасынын иштешин жакшыртат, иммунитетти көтөрөт."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو اسم وكالة الفضاء الأمريكية؟","answer":"الإجابة: ناسا"},{"question":"கேள்வி: சிற்றிலக்கியங்களின்  தோற்றம் வளர்ச்சி குறித்து எழுதுக.","answer":"பதில் :சிற்றிலக்கியம் :முன்னுரை:தமிழ் மொழியில் அமைந்த இலக்கிய செல்வங்களுள் ஒன்றாக திகழ்வது தான் சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் ஆகும். தமிழில் நெடும் பாடல்களாக அமைந்த பிரபந்த வகைகளைச் சிற்றிலக்கியம் என்பர்.இதன் வித்தும் வளர்ச்சியும் சங்ககாலத்தில் உள்ளது. ஆற்றுப்படை ஒரு துறையாகவும், தனிப்பெரும் பாடல்களாகவும் அன்றே வளர்ச்சி பெற்றன.தொல்காப்பியம், பாட்டு தொகை, பதினெண் கீழ்க்கணக்கு, ஐம்பெருங்காப்பியங்கள், ஐஞ்சிறு காப்பியம், பக்தி பாடல்கள், இசை நாடக இலக்கியங்கள் இதற்கு சான்றாகின்றன.இத்தகைய சிற்றிலக்கியங்களின் தோற்றமும் வளர்ச்சியும் பற்றி இக்கட்டுரையில் காண்போம்.சிற்றிலக்கியம்:குறைந்த எண்ணிக்கையுடைய பாடல்களைக் கொண்டு படைக்கப்படும் இலக்கிய வகைகளை சிற்றிலக்கியம் என்பர். அகப்பொருள் அல்லது புறப்பொருளில் ஏதேனும் ஒரு துறையைப் பற்றியதாக அமையும். அறம், பொருள், இன்பம், வீடு ஆகியவற்றில் ஒன்றோ பலவோ குறைந்துவரின் இவை சிற்றிலக்கியம் எனவும் விளக்கம் கொடுக்கலாம். வடமொழியில் பிரபந்தம் என்று அழைக்கப்படுவதை நாம் சிற்றிலக்கியங்களாகக் கொள்கின்றோம்.பிரபந்தம்:சிற்றிலக்கியங்களை வடமொழியில் பிரபந்தங்கள் என அழைக்கிறார்கள். பிரபந்தம் என்பதனை தமிழில் யாப்பு என்ற சொல்லோடு ஒப்பிடலாம். இரண்டும் கட்டுதல் என்ற பொருளிலேயே வழங்கப்படுகின்றன.பாட்டியல் நூல்களின் படி 96 வகைப் பிரபந்தங்களில் காப்படி புராணம், சிறு நூல்கள் என அனைத்தும் இடம்பெற்றமை அறியலாம்.காலம்:ஆற்றுப்படை இலக்கியங்கள் தோன்றிய சங்க காலத்திலிருந்தே சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் தோற்றம் பெற்றாலும் சிற்றிலக்கியம் உச்ச நிலையில் இருந்த காலத்தை நாம் கணக்கில் கொள்ள வேண்டியுள்ளது.பல்லவர் காலத்தை காப்பிய காலம் என்றும் இடைக்காலச் சோழர் காலத்தை காப்பியக் காலம் என்றும் அதன்மேலோங்கிய தன்மையால் கூறுகிறோம். அதுபோல நாயக்கர் காலத்தைச் சிற்றிலக்கிய காலம் என்று அழைக்கலாம் என்கிறார் டாக்டர் தமிழண்ணல்.  அவ்வகையில் கி.பி 15, கி.பி 16, மற்றும் 17 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுகளை நாம் சிற்றிலக்கிய காலமெனக் கூறலாம்.அமைப்பு:சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் அளவில் சிறியதாக அமைகின்ற பல் துறை சார்ந்த பெரிய நூல்கள் போல் அமையாமல் ஒரு சில துறைகளை ஆழமாக பார்ப்பவையாக அவை அமைகின்றன.அறம், பொருள், இன்பம், வீடு என்னும் நான்கு உறுதிப் பொருள்களுள் ஏதேனும் ஒன்றை தருவதாக அமைவது சிற்றிலக்கியம்.  பாடப்பெறும் கடவுள் அல்லது மன்னன் அல்லது வள்ளல் ஆகியோரை சிறப்பிக்கும்.   உதாரணம் உலா – இதில் தலைவன் உலாவரும் காட்சியை மட்டுமே சிறப்பித்துப் பாடப்படும்.முடிவுரை:சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் மூலம் ஓரளவு தமிழ்ப் பண்பாட்டினை தமிழக வரலாற்றையும் அறிய முடிகின்றது. கற்பனை ஆற்றலைப் பெருக்குவதில் சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் பேருதவியாக அமைகின்றன.அளவில் சிறியதாயினும் பெரும் சுவையைத் தருவனவாக சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் காணப்படுகின்றன. பள்ளு போன்ற சிற்றிலக்கியங்களின் மூலம் அக்கால மக்களின் சமூக வாழ்வியலை நம்மால் அறியமுடிகின்றது.தெய்வங்கள் மீது அமைந்துள்ள சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் மூலம் ஊர், வரலாறு, புராணக்கதைகள், மக்களின் வழிபாட்டு முறைகள் ஆகியவற்றை நாம் அறிந்துகொள்ள முடிகின்றமை சிறப்பிற்குரியதாகும்."},{"question":"అవయవదానంపై ఒక వ్యాసం వ్రాయండి.","answer":"ఉపోద్ఘాతం : పుట్టుకతోనే అవయవ లోపాలతో కొందరు పుడుతూ ఉంటే, ప్రమాదాల్లో అవయవాలు పోగొట్టుకునేవారు కొందరు. కన్ను, ముక్కు, చెవి, కాళ్ళు, చేతులు – వీటిలో ఏ అవయవం లేకపోయినా బాధాకరమే.విషయ విశ్లేషణ :మన చుట్టూ ఉన్న ప్రకృతిలోని అందాలను చూసి ఆనందించాలన్నా, చక్కని సంగీతం వినాలన్నా, సుందరమైన ప్రదేశాలకు వెళ్ళాలన్నా కళ్ళు, ముక్కు, కాళ్ళు చేతులు తప్పనిసరి. ఇవేకాదు మూత్రపిండాలు ఊపిరితిత్తులు వంటి అవయవ భాగాలు ముఖ్యమైనవే. రక్తం అవయవ భాగం కాకపోయినా, అవయవమంత ప్రాముఖ్య మున్నదే.కళ్ళు, మూత్రపిండాలు, ఊపిరితిత్తులు, రక్తం వంటి వాటిని దానమిచ్చి మన చుట్టూ ఆయా అవయవాల లోపంతో బాధపడేవారిని ఆదుకోవడమే మానవజన్మకు సార్థకత.జీవించి ఉండగానే, కళ్ళు, మూత్రపిండాలు వంటివి దానం చేయవచ్చు. మరణించాక కూడా జీవించి ఉండటానికి మార్గం అవయవదానం.తమ మరణానంతరం, తమ కళ్ళను దానం చేస్తామంటూ, ఎంతోమంది నేటికాలంలో ముందు కొస్తున్నారు. అలా నేత్రదానంతో ఎంతోమంది అంధులకు వెలుగునిస్తూ, మరణించాక కూడా జీవించడం గొప్ప విషయం.అలాగే ఇటీవల బెంగుళూరుకు చెందిన వ్యక్తి గుండె చెన్నైకి చెందిన మరొక వ్యక్తికి మార్పిడి చేయడం ద్వారా ఆ వ్యక్తికి ప్రాణం పోశారు. అలాగే ఇటీవల విజయవాడకు చెందిన మణికంఠ, మరొక యువకుడు దానం చేసిన గుండె, నేత్రాలు, మూత్రపిండాలు, ఊపిరితిత్తులు, కాలేయం మరికొందరివి జీవించగలిగేటట్లు చేశాయి.ముగింపు :ఇలా అవయవ దానం వల్ల కొంతమంది జీవితాల్లో వెలుగులు నింపవచ్చు. ఇటువంటివారు రాబోయే తరాలకు స్ఫూర్తిదాతలు."},{"question":"\\" જ્યાં સંપ ત્યાં જંપ \\" વાર્તા લખો.","answer":"એક હતો ખેડૂત. તેને પાંચ દીકરા હતા. તે બધા બળવાન અને મહેનતુ હતા. પણ તેઓ અંદરોઅંદર એકબીજા સાથે લડતા-ઝઘડતા રહેતા હતા.ખેડૂતની ઈચ્છા હતી કે પાંચેય દીકરા ઘરમાં સંપીને શાંતિથી રહે. એટલે તે એમને ખૂબ સમજાવતો. પરંતુ ખેડૂતની સલાહની દીકરાઓ પર કોઈ અસર થતી નહિ. તેથી ખેડૂત હંમેશા ચિંતાતુર રહેતો.એ રોજ વિચાર કરતો કે આ છોકરા સંપીને રહે તે માટે શું કરવું જોઈએ? એક દિવસ અચાનક તેને ઉકેલ મળી ગયો. તેણે પાંચેય દીકરાને પોતાની પાસે બોલાવી કહ્યું: ‘જુઓ આ લાકડાની ભારીમાંથી એક પણ લાકડી કાઢ્યા વિના આખી ભારી તમારામાંથી કોણ તોડી શકે છે?’ખેડૂતના દરેક દીકરાએ વારાફરતી લાકડાની એ ભારી હાથમાં લીધી. દરેકે તે ભારીને તોડવા બળપૂર્વક ખૂબ પ્રયત્ન કર્યો. પરંતુ એમાંથી કોઈ પણ એ ભારી તોડી ન શક્યો.પછી પેલા ઘરડા ખેડૂતે કહ્યું: ‘ચાલો લાકડાની ભારી છોડી નાખો અને તેની લાકડી એક પછી એક તોડી નાખો.’ દરેકે એક પછી એક લાકડી હાથમાં લીધી અને સરળતાથી તોડી બતાવી.પછી ખેડૂતે સલાહ આપતાં કહ્યું:‘એક એક લાકડી સહેલાઈથી તૂટી ગઈ કેમકે તે મજબૂત નહોતી. પણ એ જ લાકડીઓ જ્યારે ભારીમાં બંધાયેલી હતી ત્યારે ખૂબ જ મજબૂત હતી. તમે પણ પાંચેય જણ સંપથી રહેશો તો મજબૂત બનશો પરંતુ લડી ઝઘડીને અલગ અલગ રહેશો તો કમજોર બની જશો.’"},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. Rafiq tidak dapat melupakan _______ dia menerima Anugerah Murid Cemerlang di sekolahnya. Pilihan:  A) masa-masaB)  tahu-tahuC) saat-saatD) minit-minit","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C) saat-saat"},{"question":"కింది పేరాను చదివి, ఐదేసి ప్రశ్నలు తయారుచేయండి.చైనా తత్త్వవేత్త కన్ఫ్యూషియస్. ఆయన చాలా తెలివైనవాడు. ఒక రాజుగారు అతణ్ణి గురించి విని తన సభకు పిలిపించుకున్నాడు. మూడు పంజరాలు చూపించాడు. మొదటి పంజరంలో ఒక ఎలుక, దాని ఎదురుగా తినే పదార్థాలు ఉన్నాయి. రెండో పంజరంలో పిల్లి ఉంది. దాని ఎదురుగా పళ్ళెంలో పాలు ఉన్నాయి. మూడో పంజరంలో ఒక గద్ద ఉంది. దాని ఎదురుగా తాజా మాంసం ఉంది. కానీ ఎలుక ఏ పదార్థం తినటం లేదు; పిల్లి పాలు ముట్టుకోవడం లేదు; గద్ద కూడా మాంసం ముట్టడం లేదు. దీనికి కారణమేమిటి? అని అడిగాడు రాజు. తత్త్వవేత్త ఇలా సమాధానం ఇచ్చాడు- “పిల్లిని చూసి భయపడి ఎలుక ఆహారం తీసుకోలేదు. పిల్లి ఎలుకమీద ఆశతో పాలు ముట్టుకోలేదు. పిల్లిని, ఎలుకను ఒకేసారి తినాలనే ఆశతో గద్ద మాంసం ముట్టుకోలేదు. అలాగే భవిష్యత్తు మీద ఆశతో ప్రజలు వర్తమానాన్ని విస్మరిస్తున్నారు. సుఖానికి దూరమవుతున్నారు. ఈ సమాధానానికి సంతృప్తిపడి రాజు కన్ఫ్యూషియకు విలువైన బహుమానాన్ని ఇచ్చాడు.","answer":"ప్రశ్నలు:కన్ఫ్యూషియస్ ఎవరు? ఆయన ఎలాంటివాడు?మొదటి, రెండు, మూడు పంజరాలలో ఏమేమి ఉన్నాయి?మూడో పంజరం ఎదురుగా ఏమి ఉంది?రాజు ఏమని ప్రశ్నించాడు?రాజు అడిగిన ప్రశ్నకు తత్త్వవేత్త ఏమి సమాధానమిచ్చాడు?"},{"question":"Trong tiểu thuyết \\"Những cuộc phiêu lưu của Tom Sawyer\\", cậu bé Tom Sawyer được miêu tả với tính cách gì nổi bật?","answer":"Tom Sawyer là cậu bé nghịch ngợm, thông minhNhững cuộc phiêu lưu của Tom Sawyer là tiểu thuyết của Mark Twain, xuất bản năm 1876. Tác phẩm được viết với bút pháp độc đáo, miêu tả tâm lý, cử chỉ, hành động của một chú bé sống tại ngôi làng nghèo bên sông Mississippi.Tác giả đã miêu tả tính cách, tâm lý, hành động của Tom Sawyer một cách xuất sắc, thể hiện sự thông minh, nghịch ngợm nhưng dũng cảm và nhân hậu."},{"question":"WhatsApp silinen sohbet geri gelir mi?","answer":"2- Google Play Store'dan WhatsApp'ı tekrar cihazınıza yükleyin. 3- WhatsApp'i açıp telefon numaranızı girin. 4- WhatsApp yedeğini geri yüklemeyi isteyip istemediğinizi soracaktır. Sohbet yedeğini geri yükleyerek silinen mesajları görebilirsiniz."},{"question":"Est-ce que tu peux me raconter une blague ?","answer":"D'accord, voici une blague :Question: Qu’a dit le requin après avoir mangé le poisson-clown ?Réponse: Ça a un drôle de goût."},{"question":"KEDỤ NDỊICHE DỊ N’ETITI MKPỤRỤEDEMEDE NA MKPỤRỤỤDAASỤSỤ?","answer":"Mkpụrụedemede e nwere n’asụsụ Igbo dị iriatọ na isii. Ọ bụkwanụ n’elu mkpụrụedemede ndị ahụ e nwere ka a naagbado ụkwụ na-ede asụsụ Igbo. Mmụta mkpụrụedemede asụsụ Igbo bụ mmalite mmụta asụsụ Igbo. Mana, ọ ga-adị mma ka anyị ghọta na mkpụrụedemede na mkpụrụụdaasụsụ abụghị otu. E nwere ndịiche dị n’etiti ha abụọ. Ọkpụrụkpụ ndịiche dị na ha bụ na mkpụrụedemede na-anọrọ onwe, na-akwụrụ onwe ya were bụrụ mkpụrụedemede mana mkpụrụụdaasụsụ anaghị akwụrụ onwe ya tupu ọ zawa mkpụrụụdaasụsụ. Mkpụrụụdaasụsụ bụ n’ime mkpụrụokwumaọbụ okwu ka a na-anọ na-achọpụta ya. Mkpụrụụdaasụsụ agaghị akwụrụ onwe ya dị ka mkpụrụedemede. Ọzọ kwa dị ka ibe ya bụ na a kọwara na mmalite ihe ọmụmụ a na mkpụrụedemede dị iriatọ na isii mana mkpụrụụdaasụsụ enweghị ọnụọgụ ole a ga-asị na ọ bụ ya ka ọ dị. Mkpụrụụdaasụsụ na-enyere aka n’ụzọ nke ya na nghọta n’okwu Igbo. Anyị ga-aghọtakwa na ọ bụ n’ime okwu ka a na-enweta ma naachọpụta mkpụrụụdaasụsụ. Mana ọnọdụ dị otu a adịghị na mkpụrụedemede. Mkpụrụedemede bụ nke ọ na-abụ ọ kwụpụta a mara ya ozigbo. E deputa mkpụrụedemede, a na-amata na edepụtala mkpụrụedemede ma marakwa na ọ bụ mkpụrụedemede. Mana mkpụrụụdaasụsụ bụ site n’ụda ka e si amata ya. Ọ bụrụ na e si n’okwu wepụta mkpụrụụdaasụsụ, a ga-etinyerịrị ya ihe nhụbaama ijiri gosi na ọ bụ mkpụrụụdaasụsụ, na ọ bụghị mkpụrụedemede. Akara nhụbaama a na-amakwụnye mkpụrụụdaasụsụ n’olu ma e si n’okwu ọ nọ na ya wepụta ya bụ iji mee ka nkọwa ya doo anya. Ọkpụrụkpụ ihe ọzọ dịkwa mkpa anyị kwesịrị ịmata dị kandịiche dị n’etiti mkpụrụedemede na mkpụrụasụsụ bụ na ọ bụrụb na mkpụrụedemede adịghị, a gaghị enwe mkpụrụụdaasụsụ. Ọ bụ site n’ụda na nghọta mkpụrụedemede na-etinye na mkpụrụokwu ọ nọ na ya ka e si enweta mkpụrụụdaasụsụ. Mana mkpụrụụdaasụsụ anaghị emebe mkpụrụedemede maka na mmiri anaghị ekwoghachi azụ. A bịa na mkpụrụedemede na mkpurụụdaasụsụ nke na-emebe ibe ya, anyị achọpụtala ma hụkwa na ọ bụ naanị aka nri na-akwọ aka ekpe. N’ọnọdụ dị otu a, aka ekpe agaghị akwọnwu aka nri. "},{"question":"Lasiko ti Atẹrẹ n gbe ọmọ rẹ to n saisan lọ sọsibitu ni wọn ji i gbe n’Ilọrin","answer":"Awọn ajinigbe ti wọn to mẹfa to ji baale ile ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlaaadọta kan, Alhaji Musa Garba Atẹrẹ, gbe niluu Ilọrin ti kan si mọlẹbi rẹ lati beere fun miliọnu ọgbọn naira owo iyọlọfin rẹ.Atẹrẹ toun pẹlu iyawo ati ọmọbinrin rẹ kan to n ṣe aarẹ n lọ silewosan ko sọwọ awọn ajinigbe ni nnkan bii aago mẹfa aarọ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, lọna Ogundele si Madi, nijọba ibilẹ Ilọrin West.Iyawo ọkunrin naa ti ko fẹ ka darukọ oun ṣalaye pe awọn ajinigbe naa ni dandan, awọn gbọdọ lọọ wa owo naa ko too di pe wọn le yọnda ọkọ oun.Nigba to n sọ bi iṣẹlẹ naa ṣe ṣẹlẹ, obinrin yii ni ṣadeede lawọn ajinigbe naa da awọn lọna, ti wọn si beere fun owo lọwọ awọn.O ni gbogbo owo to wa lọwọ awọn ati dukia mi-in lawọn ko fun wọn ki wọn le baa fi awọn silẹ, sibẹ, wọn wọ ọkọ oun tuurutu wọ inu igbo lọ.O ni oju kan naa toun duro si loun ti n wo wọn bi wọn ṣe n wọ ọ, ṣugbọn ko si ẹnikẹni nitosi lati ran awọn lọwọ.Titi di bi a ṣe n kọ iroyin yii ko sẹni to mọ pato ibi ti wọn gbe ọkunrin naa lọ. Awọn ẹbi naa ni awọn ti fi iṣẹlẹ ọhun to agọ ọlọpaa to wa lagbegbe Adewọle, niluu Ilọrin, leti fun iwadi.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Kwara, Ajayi Ọkasanmi, to fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ ni iwadi ti n lọ lori ẹ."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన తాత్పర్యం వచ్చేలాగా ఒక పద్యాన్ని రాయండి:నందీశ్వరుడు తనను చూసి అపహేళన చేసి నవ్వుతున్న రావణుని చూసి కోపముతో ఇలా అన్నాడు.","answer":"ఇవ్విధంబునఁ దనుఁజూచి నవ్వుచున్నయతి విమూఢుని దశకంఠు నట్టె చూచియపర శివుఁడైన నందీశుఁ డాగ్రహము వహించి కటతటమదరఁగా నిట్టులనియె."},{"question":"اكتب نسخة أطول من الجملة دي: الاتصال بالعيون والتعبيرات الوجهية بتوفر معلومات اجتماعية وعاطفية مهمة.","answer":"بطبيعة الحال، نسخة أكثر تعقيدًا من الجملة هي \\"تواصل العين والتعبيرات الوجهية بيوفر معلومات اجتماعية وعاطفية مهمة ؛ الناس ، ربما من غير القيام بذلك بوعي ، يبحثون في عيون ووجوه بعضهم البعض عن علامات مزاجية إيجابية أو سلبية\\"."},{"question":"ਵਰਗ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ।","answer":"ਕਾਰਲ ਮਾਰਕਸ ਨੇ ਹਰੇਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋ ਵਰਗਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਿਵੇਚਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ । ਉਸਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹਰੇਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ-ਵਰਗ-ਇੱਕ ਸ਼ੋਸ਼ਣ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਅਤੇ ਦੂਜਾ ਸ਼ੋਸ਼ਿਤ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਵਰਗ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰਕਸ ਵਰਗ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਕਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਸ਼ੋਸ਼ਣ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਪੂੰਜੀਪਤੀ ਵਰਗ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਧਨ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਰ ਵਰਗਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦਬਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਦੂਜਾ ਵਰਗ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰ ਵਰਗ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਕੋਲ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਕੋਈ ਸਾਧਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੇ । ਉਸਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਰੋਟੀ ਕਮਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਵੇਚਣ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਹੋਰ ਕੁੱਝ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਵਰਗ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਵਰਗ ਤੋਂ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਸ਼ੋਸ਼ਿਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਵਰਗਾਂ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਚਲਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸੇ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਮਾਰਕਸ ਨੇ ਵਰਗ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"A o fẹ Wakili l’Ayetẹ mọ o, awọn alalẹ ilẹ yii o ni i jẹ ka tun riru ẹ n’Ibarapa mọ – Ọba Ayetẹ","answer":"Asawo tilu Ayetẹ, Ọba Emmanuel Okeniyi, ti sọ pe awọn o ni i gba ki afurasi ọdaran Fulani, Iskilu Wakili, ti wọn mu laipẹ yii, atawọn ẹmẹwa ẹ to ṣẹku tun pada sagbegbe naa mọ, bẹẹ lọba alaye naa ni iyalẹnu ni bi ijọba ṣe sọ awọn ọmọ OPC to mu Wakili satimọle, o ni igbesẹ naa ku diẹ kaato.Ninu ọrọ to ba ALAROYE sọ lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, lori foonu nipa awọn iṣẹlẹ to waye lagbegbe naa, ati wahala tawọn ọmọ-ẹyin Wakili n da silẹ lẹyin ti wọn ti mu ọga wọn, lo ti sọ pe akoba gidi ni igboke-gbodo awọn Fulani nilẹ Ibarapa, o ni wọn ti mu ki owo ounjẹ gbowo lori bayii.Aṣawo ni, “Ki i ṣe ọrọ ọdun marun-un ti Wakili ti n ṣẹ Yoruba, to n huwa ibi nilẹ Yoruba, pẹlu boun atawọn ẹmẹwa ẹ ṣe n fi maaluu jẹ oko awọn agbẹ, to n ba ire-oko wa jẹ. Ọmọ wa kan dako bii eeka mẹẹẹdogun lọdun mẹta sẹyin, awọn ọmọ Wakili si lọọ fi maaluu jẹ oko paki rẹ to fi jẹ pe ọmọ naa ko ri ẹyọ paki kan mu ninu oko naa. A fọlọpaa mu un, ko da awọn ọlọpaa lohun, a si sọ pe ko kuro lori ilẹ wa, niṣe lo ta ku to loun o nibi kan an lọ. A tun pe e lẹjọ, ile-ẹjọ ni ẹnikan o le le ẹnikan kuro nibi kan, ẹ o ri iya ti wọn fi n jẹ wa.“Tori ẹ lo fi jẹ pe igbesẹ tawọn OPC gbe yii, o dun mọ mi gidi, o si tẹ mi lọrun pẹlu, a ti gbiyanju titi, ta o ri Wakili mu, ti ko si lọ, a waa jaja ri ẹni ba wa ṣi i nidii, a o ni i jẹ ko tun pada sori ilẹ yii mọ, awọn alalẹ ilẹ yii o ni i jẹ ka tun ri Wakili atawọn eeyan ẹ lagbegbe Ibarapa, ki i ṣe Ayetẹ nikan, ni gbogbo agbegbe Ibarapa ati Oke-Ogun pata ni, eegun rẹ ko gbọdọ tun ṣẹ nilẹ yii mọ.“Wakili ti ko arajẹ ba wa lori ilẹ awọn baba wa. Ẹni to ba n febi paayan, tọhun fẹ keeyan ku ni, awa ta a o niṣe meji ju iṣẹ agbẹ lọ, ẹ wo iye ti wọn n ta apo paki bayii, o ti di ẹgbẹrun lọna mẹẹẹdọgbọn naira, baafu ẹ ti di ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa naira, baafu kan pere, awọn Fulani lo sọ wa dẹni ti o ri paki jẹ. O ti ju oṣu meji lọ bayii ti ọpọ agbẹ ti lọ soko gbẹyin.“Iyẹn lo fi jẹ pe o ya mi lẹnu gidi nigba tẹnikan n ba tiwa jẹ, tawọn ọmọ wa si dide, ti wọn mu onitọhun, ti wọn o lu u, wọn o pa a, wọn fa a le ijọba lọwọ ni, to si yẹ kijọba ṣe ẹtọ lori ẹ, to tun waa jẹ awọn ọmọ waa naa ni wọn ti mọle. Bi wọn ṣe ti awọn ọmọ OPC mọle yẹn ku diẹ kaato, ko tiẹ daa rara. Ọrọ ijọba nigba mi-in, nnkan ni.”Ọba Okeniyi tun sọ pe awọn lade-lade nilẹ Ibarapa lo dunnu si bi wọn ṣe mu Wakili. O lawọn ọba naa si n kọminu si bijọba to wa lode yii ṣe n dọgbọn huwa bii ẹni n ṣatilẹyin fawọn Fulani ti wọn n ṣe wa ni ṣuta."},{"question":"RAG MAXAA LAGU RAACAA?","answer":"RAG MAXAA LAGU RAACAA?Ragga iyo dumarku way ku kala duwan yihiin marka laga eego sifooyinka la'isku doorto xilliga guurka. Rasuulkeennu (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) waa kii yiri : (Naag waxa loo guursadaa maalkeeda, quruxdeeda, sharafteeda iyo diinteeda), taasi oo ina tusaysa in maalka iyo quruxdu ay 50% ka yihiin sababaha dumarka loo guursado, ha yeeshee kolkay arrintu joogto ninka isagu doonaya inuu guursado, qimeyntiisu taa ka duwan.Diinteenna Islaamku waxa ay xaddidday laba shardi oo haddii ninka lagahelo ay tahay in markaa inanta uu soodoontay loo guuriyo, labadaasi shardi oo kala ah; Din iyo Dabeecad. Rasuulka suubbani (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) waxa uu xadiis ku leeyahay: (Hadduu idin yimaado nimaad diintiisa iyo dabeecaddiisa u bogtaan u guuriya, haddii kale xumaan iyo dhibaato weyn baa dhulka ka dhacaysa). Xadiiska waxaad ka garan kartaa in dabeecadda qofku aanay ku xirnayn diintiisa, maxaa yeelay si kasta oo qofku uu diinta u yaqaan, haddana dabeecad wanaagga, degganaanta iyo qabowga iyo waa loo kala dhashaa dabeecad xumida, xanaaq dhowaanta iyo kulaylka joogtada ah.Rasuulku (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) kuma aanu soo hadal qaadin xadiiskiisa qurux iyo maal looga baahan yahay ragga guurdoonka ah toona.Haddaba sababtu waxa weeyaan, aynu ku horreeyno quruxda eh, ninka raggaah waxaa qurux ugu filan ragannimadiisa, oo kol hadduu waxgarad yahay, geesi yahay, caqli iyo kartina leeyahay, waxay ila tahay qurux ay dumar ku raacaan00 u harsani ma jirto. Dhanka kale, marka diinta Islaamka laga hadlayo, maalkukamid ma aha shuruudaha guurdoonka lagu xiray. Ninkii din (aqoon iyo kudhagan) iyo dabeecad wanaag isku darsada, Eebbe asagaa xagga maalka ka kafaalad qaaday. Waxana taasi marqaati ka ah Aayadda oranaysa: (Haddaysabool yihiin eebbe asagaa deeqdiisa ku hodminaya)."},{"question":"Protestanci w sporach teologicznych z katolikami odwoływali się do rozstrzygnięć przyszłego soboru powszechnego. Władcy katoliccy łudzili się, że sobór przywróci jedność religijną i doprowadzi do porozumienia, a reformy i likwidacja nadużyć uzdrowią Kościół od wewnątrz. Sobór otwarto 13 grudnia 1545 roku. Toczył się na nim spór o nadrzędność władzy papieża i soboru. Przy czynnym udziale jezuitów uchwały soboru zostały dostosowane do życzeń papieskich. W uchwałach zamknięcia, które nastąpiło 6 grudnia 1563 roku, zwrócono się o potwierdzenie postanowień soborowych do papieża, podkreślając tym samym jego wyższość nad soborem.Dokończ zdanie. Wybierz właściwą odpowiedź spośród podanych.Sobór, o którym mowa w tekście,A. przywrócił jedność religijną w Europie.B. wprowadził zasadę tolerancji religijnej w Europie.C. przyczynił się do wzmocnienia władzy papieskiej w Kościele katolickim.D. zakończył spór papieża i cesarza o dominację nad światem chrześcijańskim.","answer":"Prawidłową odpowiedzią jest C."},{"question":"ලෝක දෑත් සේදීමේ දිනය","answer":"ඔක්තොම්බර් 15"},{"question":"නර්වාල්වරුන් මුහුණ දෙන තර්ජන මොනවාද?","answer":"තෙල් හා ගෑස් සංවර්ධනය සහ දේශගුණික විපර්යාස නර්වාල් තල්මසුන්ටද තර්ජන එල්ල කරයි. බහුල වශයෙන් වන මුහුදු යාත්‍රික ගමන් , සාගර දූෂනයට වැඩි අවස්ථා නිර්මාණය කිරීම සහ තල්මසුන් අතර සන්නිවේදනයට බාධා කළ හැකි දිය යට ශබ්දය වැඩි වීම නිදසුන් ලෙස පෙන්විය හැක. "},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Hon blev programledare för Filmkrönikan år 2007 efter att ha medverkat i tidigare säsonger av programmet, då som gästrecensent. Har tidigare lett filmprogram i TV400. Reuter är också producent för långfilmen (2020) om konstnären Tove Jansson. Filmen är","answer":"den mest sedda finlandssvenska filmen någonsin och blev även Finlands Oscarsbidrag 2021."},{"question":"Ithetha ukuthini ukuzalwa ngokutsha komKristu? impendulo idibanise ibhayibhile.","answer":"Ithetha ukuthini ukuzalwa ngokutsha komKristu? umgca oqhelekileyo phaya ebhayibhileni ophendula lombuzo ngu Johane 3:1-21. INkosi uYesu Kristu uthetha no Nicodemus, uMfarasi nelungu le Sanhedrin elaziwayo (ibhodi yamaJuda elawulayo). U Nicodemus weza nemibuzo ethile ngobunye ubusuku.Wayesithi uYesu xa ethetha no Nicodemus, \\"Ndikuxelela inyaniso, akekho oyakububona ubukumkani bamazulu ngaphandle kokuba uzelwe ngokutsha.\\" ‘Umntu angazalwa njani xa sele emdala?’ Wabuza uNicodemus. ‘Ngokuqinisekileyo akanakukwazi ukubuyela esibelekweni sika nina okwesibini ukuze azalwe!’ UYesu waphendula, ‘Ndikuxelela inyaniso, akekho oyakubungena ubukumkani bamazulu ngaphandle kokuba uzelwe ngamanzi nangoMoya. Inyama izala inyama, kodwa uMoya uzala umoya. Awufanelanga kukothuswa koku ndikuthethayo, \\"Kufuneka uzalwe ngokutsha\\" (Johane 3:3-7).Eligama \\"zalwa ngokutsha\\" lithetha ukuthi \\"ukuzalwa okusuka phezulu.\\" U Nicodemus waye enemfuno ngenene. Kwakufuneka atshintshe intliziyo yakhe — uguquko lwasemoyeni. Uzalo olutsha, ukuzalwa ngokutsha, sisenzo sika Thixo apho ubomi obungunaphakade bufakwa emntwini okholelwayo (2 Amakorinte 5:17; Tito 3:5; 1 Petros 1:3; 1 Yohane 2:29; 3:9; 4:7; 5:1-4, 18). Yohane 1:12, 13 kubonakalisa ukuba xa \\"uzelwe ngokutsha\\" uyabonakala ukuba \\"ube ngumntwana ka Thixo\\" ngokuthembela egameni lika Yesu Kristu.Umbuzo onzima wokuqiqa uyavela, \\"Kutheni kufuneka umntu azalwe ngokutsha?\\" UMpostile uPaulos kwabase Efese 2:1 uthi, \\"Yaye unidlise ubomi, nifile nje ziziphoso nezono enanifudula nihamba nihamba kuzo ngokwesimo sehlabathi\\" (NKJV). Kuma Roma ubhale, \\"Kubo bonke aboni nabo bangafikelelanga kuzuko luka Thixo\\" (kumaRoma 3:23). Aboni \\"bafile\\"; emoyeni; xa befumana umoya wobomi ngokukholelwa kuKrestu, ibhayibhile ithanda ukuyibiza ngokuba luzalo olutsha. Kwabo bazelwe ngokutsha kuphela abayakuxolelwa iizono zabo yaye babe nobudlelwane noThixo.Yenzeka njani le nto? kwabaseEfese 2:8-9 bayachaza, \\"Kungenxa yenceba ukuba usindiswe, nangokholo — yaye oku akuphumi kuwe, sisipho sika Thixo — hayi ngenxa yemisebenzi, ukuze kungabikho uqhayisayo.\\" Xa ethe omnye wasindiswa ethe wazalwa ngokutsha, ehlaziyekile emoyeni, yaye engumntwana kaThixo ngoku kuba ezalwe ngokutsha. Ukuthembela ngo Yesu Krestu noyena ongumhlawuleli wamatyala ezono xa wayesifa emnqamlezweni, ithetha ukuthi \\"ukuzalwa ngokutsha.\\" \\"Ngoko ke, ukuba umntu ukuKrestu, usisidalwa esitsha: omdala umkile, omtsha ufikile!\\" (2 Amakorinte 5:17).Ukuba akuzange wathembela kwi Nkosi uYesu Kristu njengomsindisi wakho, uyakuva kushukuma umoya oyingcwele xa ethetha entliziyweni yakho. Uyakulangazelela ukuzalwa ngokutsha. Ingaba uyakuthandaza umthandazo wenguquko nokuba ubesisidalwa esitsha kuKrestu namhlanje? Kubo bonke abamamkelayo, kwabo bakholelwa ngegama lakhe, unika imvume yokuba babe ngabantwana baka Thixo – abantwana abangazalwanga ngokwendalo yomhlaba, okanye bengazalwanga ngabantu ngokuthanda kwendoda koko bezelwe ngokuka Thixo (Yohane 1:12-13).Ukuba ufuna ukwamkela uYesu Kristu njengomsindisi wakho nokuba uzalwe ngokutsha, nanku umzekelo womthandazo. Khumbula ukuthandaza lomthandazo okanye omnye umthandazo akunakukusindisa. Kukuthembela kuKristu kuphela okunokukusindisa ezonweni. Lomthandazo yindlela elula yokubonakalisa ukholo lwakho kuThixo kuye nokumbulela ngokukunika intsindiso. \\"Thixo ndiyazi ndonile phambi kwakho yaye ndifanelwe ukuba ndohlwaywe. Kodwa uYesu Krestu wasithatha isohlwayo esasifanela mna ukuze ngokukholwa kuye ndixolelwe. Ndibeka ithemba lam kwintsindiso yakho. Ndiyabulela ngenceba yakho entle noxolelo — Isipho sobomi obungunaphakade! Amen!\\"Sele usenzile isigqibo ngoKristu ngenxa yoku okufunde apha? Ukuba kunjalo, nceda ucofe kwiqhosha elingezantsi elithi “Ndiyamamkela uKristu namhlanje”."},{"question":"Menene ake kira mutumin da ke yin aiki a kotu domin bayar da kariya?","answer":"Lauya ko kuma barista"},{"question":"How did early studies in 1929 document children's moviegoing habits, and what were the notable findings regarding the exposure of children to screen experiences beyond their years?","answer":"A study conducted in 1929 meticulously documented the moviegoing habits of 10,052 children in the Chicago area. The findings revealed that nearly all children attended movies and were often exposed to content that surpassed their age, raising concerns about the appropriateness of the material."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Musiktidskriften \\"Pandore\\" skrev efter premiären: \\"under en lång tid har upplysta kritiker trott att det vid sidan av den gamla \\"tragédie lyrique\\" var möjligt att ha ett mer realistiskt och naturligt drama som skulle passa denna teaters värdighet.\\" Operan förekom Gioacchino Rossinis","answer":"opera \\"Wilhelm Tell\\" med ett år och hade en uttalad inverkan hos både Giacomo Meyerbeer (\\"Robert le Diable\\", 1831) och Richard Wagner. Den senare noterade 1871 i sin \\"Minnen av Auber\\" att operan \\"vara blotta närvara hade orsakat revolutioner sågs som en tydlig förelöpare tillJulirevolutionen, och sällan har en artistisk skapelse stått närmare en världshändelse\\". \\"La Muette\\" fick nypremiär i Paris omedelbart efter den franska julirevolutionen 1830."},{"question":"څومره ورزش د ښه بدن لپاره کافي دی","answer":"د \\"ښه بدن\\" مفهوم موضوعي دی او په انفرادي اهدافو، غوره توبونو او د بدن ډولونو پورې اړه لري. په هرصورت، د مختلف روغتیا او فټنس ګټو ترلاسه کولو لپاره د تمرین فریکونسۍ او شدت لپاره عمومي لارښوونې شتون لري.د عمومي روغتیا او هوساینې لپاره:د روغتیا نړیوال سازمان (WHO) په اونۍ کې لږترلږه 150 دقیقې د اعتدال شدت ایروبیک فعالیت یا د 75 دقیقو قوي شدت ایروبیک فعالیت وړاندیز کوي. دا کیدای شي په څو ورځو کې خپور شي یا حتی د فعالیت په لنډو برخو ویشل کیدی شي.برسېره پردې، دوی د عضلاتو پیاوړتیا فعالیتونه وړاندیز کوي چې لږترلږه په اونۍ کې دوه ځله د عضلاتو ټول لوی ګروپونه پکې شامل وي.د عضلاتو د جوړولو او پیاوړتیا لپاره:د مقاومت روزنه چې وزنونه، د بدن وزن تمرینونه، یا په اونۍ کې 2-3 ځله د مقاومت بانډونه پکې شامل دي سپارښتنه کیږي.په مرکب تمرینونو تمرکز وکړئ چې په یوځل کې د عضلاتو ډیری ګروپونه کار کوي، لکه اسکواټونه، سږي، پش اپ، او قطار.په تدریجي ډول وزن، سیټونه، یا تکرار زیات کړئ لکه څنګه چې تاسو پیاوړي کیږي.د زړه د روغتیا د ښه والي لپاره:د زړه تمرین لکه منډه کول، لامبو وهل، سایکل چلول، یا نڅا کول په هره اونۍ کې لږترلږه د 150 دقیقو لپاره په منځنۍ شدت کې سپارښتنه کیږي.تاسو کولی شئ د وقفې روزنې هم شامل کړئ، کوم چې د لوړ شدت او منځنۍ شدت فعالیت بدیل دورې شاملې دي.د وزن مدیریت لپاره:د وزن مدیریت لپاره اړین تمرین اندازه ستاسو د انفرادي کالوري اړتیاو او اهدافو پورې اړه لري.د مقاومت روزنې سره د زړه د تمرین ترکیب اکثرا د وزن کمولو او سالم وزن ساتلو لپاره ترټولو مؤثره ستراتیژي ده."},{"question":"වී යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගොයම් ගසේ ඵලය වී නම් වේ. ආහාරයට ගන්නා බත් පිසීම සඳහා අවශ්‍ය සහල් ලබාගන්නේ වී වලින් ය. එහි විද්‍යාත්මක නාමය ඔරයිසා සැටයිවා වේ."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණය පැවති වසර","answer":"1947"},{"question":"வினா:“பொருப்பிலே பிறந்து தென்னன் புகழிலே கிழந்து சங்கத்து“ – என்ற பாடலடி வருகின்ற நூல் எது?","answer":"விடை:“பொருப்பிலே பிறந்து தென்னன் புகழிலே கிழந்து சங்கத்து“, என்ற பாடலடி வருகின்ற நூல் ,வில்லி பாரதம் ஆகும் ."},{"question":"பெற்றோர் ஆசிரியர் கூட்டத்தில்   ‘சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பேணுவதே இன்றைய அறம்’ என்ற தலைப்பில் பேசுவதற்கு உரைக்குறிப்பு ஒன்றை உருவாக்குக.","answer":"சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு பற்றிய கட்டுரைசுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு என்பது சுற்றுச்சூழலின் தரத்தை மேம்படுத்துதல், பாதுகாத்தல் மற்றும் பராமரித்தல். சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பின் முக்கிய முறைகள் மறுசுழற்சி, மறுபயன்பாடு மற்றும் குறைத்தல்; இருப்பினும், பசுமை ஆற்றல் உற்பத்தி, பசுமை போக்குவரத்து மேம்பாடு மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் நட்பு தொழில்மயமாக்கல் போன்ற வேறு சில முறைகளும் உள்ளன. சுற்றுச்சூழலை மேம்படுத்த குடியிருப்பாளர்கள் மட்டுமல்ல, வணிகங்கள் மற்றும் தொழில்துறைகளும் தங்கள் அடிப்படை பாத்திரங்களை வகிக்க வேண்டும்.சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பின் வரலாறு மனித இனம் எப்போதும் சுற்றுச்சூழலில் அக்கறை கொண்டுள்ளது. பண்டைய கிரேக்கர்கள் சுற்றுச்சூழல் தத்துவத்தை முதன்முதலில் உருவாக்கினர், மேலும் அவர்கள் இந்தியா மற்றும் சீனா போன்ற பிற முக்கிய நாகரிகங்களால் பின்பற்றப்பட்டனர். சமீப காலங்களில், சுற்றுச்சூழல் நெருக்கடி பற்றிய விழிப்புணர்வு அதிகரித்து வருவதால், சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கான அக்கறை அதிகரித்துள்ளது. கிளப் ஆஃப் ரோம், ஒரு சிந்தனைக் குழு, அதன் அறிக்கையான \\"வளர்ச்சிக்கான வரம்புகள்\\" (1972) இல் அதிக மக்கள்தொகை மற்றும் மாசுபாட்டின் ஆபத்துகள் குறித்து உலகை எச்சரித்ததில் முதன்மையானது.சுற்றுச்சூழலின் ஆரம்ப நாட்களில், மனிதர்கள் சுற்றுச்சூழலை சீர்குலைக்காத பகுதிகளை ஒதுக்கி வைப்பதே இயற்கையைப் பாதுகாக்க சிறந்த வழி என்று மக்கள் நினைத்தார்கள். பாதுகாப்பு என அழைக்கப்படும் இந்த அணுகுமுறை, 1916 இல் தேசிய பூங்கா சேவை நிறுவப்பட்டதன் மூலம் அமெரிக்காவில் ஒரு பெரிய ஊக்கத்தை அளித்தது.1960 களில் சுற்றுச்சூழலில் மனிதர்களின் எதிர்மறையான தாக்கம் பற்றிய கவலைகள் அதிகரிக்கத் தொடங்கியபோது நவீன சுற்றுச்சூழல் இயக்கம் தொடங்கியது. இந்த கவலைகளுக்கு பதிலளிக்கும் விதமாக, உலகெங்கிலும் உள்ள அரசாங்கங்கள் சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான சட்டத்தை இயற்றத் தொடங்கின. உதாரணமாக, யுனைடெட் ஸ்டேட்ஸில், சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு நிறுவனம் (EPA) 1970 இல் நிறுவப்பட்டது.சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பின் கோட்பாடுகள்சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பில் மூன்று அடிப்படைக் கொள்கைகள் உள்ளன:முன்னெச்சரிக்கை கொள்கை: ஒரு செயல்பாடு சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கு தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் திறன் கொண்டதாக இருந்தால், அந்த செயல்பாடு சேதமடைகிறது என்பதற்கான தெளிவான சான்றுகள் இல்லாவிட்டாலும், அந்த பாதிப்பைத் தடுக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டும் என்று இந்த கொள்கை கூறுகிறது.மாசுபடுத்துபவர் பணம் செலுத்துகிறார் கொள்கை: மாசுபாட்டை ஏற்படுத்துவதற்கு பொறுப்பான கட்சி அதை சுத்தம் செய்வதற்கு பொறுப்பேற்க வேண்டும் என்று இது கூறுகிறது.கொள்கையை அறிந்து கொள்வதற்கான பொது உரிமை: சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கு ஏதேனும் சாத்தியமான அச்சுறுத்தல்கள் மற்றும் அவற்றை நிவர்த்தி செய்ய என்ன செய்யப்படுகிறது என்பதைப் பற்றி அறிய பொதுமக்களுக்கு உரிமை உண்டு என்று இந்தக் கொள்கை கூறுகிறது.சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பின் குறிக்கோள்கள்சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பின் மூன்று முக்கிய குறிக்கோள்கள் உள்ளன:மனித ஆரோக்கியத்தைப் பாதுகாக்க: இது சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பின் மிக முக்கியமான குறிக்கோள், ஏனெனில் ஆரோக்கியமான சூழல் இல்லாமல் மனிதர்கள் வாழ முடியாது.சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்புகளைப் பாதுகாக்க: சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்புகள் பூமியில் வாழ்வின் அடித்தளமாகும், மேலும் அவை சுத்தமான காற்று மற்றும் நீர், உணவு மற்றும் நார் போன்ற பல நன்மைகளை மனிதர்களுக்கு வழங்குகின்றன.நிலையான வளர்ச்சியை ஊக்குவிக்க: நிலையான வளர்ச்சி என்பது எதிர்கால சந்ததியினர் தங்கள் சொந்த தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்யும் திறனை சமரசம் செய்யாமல் நிகழ்காலத்தின் தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்யும் வளர்ச்சியாகும்.சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு பற்றிய கட்டுரைசுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு என்பது தனிநபர்கள், நிறுவனங்கள் மற்றும் அரசாங்கங்களின் கைகளில் இருந்து இயற்கை சூழலைப் பாதுகாப்பதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு நடைமுறையாகும். பூமியின் சுற்றுப்புறச் சூழல் நாளுக்கு நாள் சீரழிந்து வருவதே காலத்தின் தேவை, அதற்குக் காரணம் மனிதர்கள்தான். அவர்கள் தங்கள் தேவைகளை பூர்த்தி செய்ய பூமியின் சூழலை தவறாக கையாளுகிறார்கள். இப்படியே போனால், வருங்கால சந்ததியினர் வாழ்வதற்கு பாதுகாப்பான சூழல் கிடைக்கும் என்று சொல்வது கடினம்.சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பின் முக்கியத்துவத்தை இக்கட்டுரையின் மூலம் அறிந்துகொள்வீர்கள்.சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு பற்றிய ஒரு நீண்ட கட்டுரைநமது இயற்கைச் சூழலை சீர்குலைக்காமல் பாதுகாப்பது இன்றியமையாதது, அதற்கான ஒரே வழி சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்புதான். இந்த செயல்முறை தாமதமாகிவிடும் முன், ஒவ்வொரு நாடும் கூடிய விரைவில் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டும். இந்த செயல்முறையின் நோக்கம் அனைத்து இயற்கை வளங்களையும் பாதுகாப்பது மற்றும் பழுதுபார்க்கக்கூடிய சுற்றுச்சூழலின் சில பகுதிகளை சரிசெய்ய முயற்சிப்பது. அதிகப்படியான நுகர்வு, மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் விரைவான வளர்ச்சி ஆகியவற்றின் காரணமாக உயிர் இயற்பியல் சூழல் நிரந்தரமாக சீரழிந்து வருகிறது. இந்த நடவடிக்கைகளை கட்டுப்படுத்தும் விதத்தில் செயல்படுவதற்கு அரசாங்கம் உத்திகளை வகுத்தால் இதை நிறுத்த முடியும். மாணவர்கள் தாங்கள் வாழும் சூழலைப் புரிந்துகொள்ள இந்த சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்புக் கட்டுரை பெரும் உதவியாக இருக்கும்.தன்னார்வ சுற்றுச்சூழல் ஒப்பந்தங்கள்பெரும்பாலான தொழில்துறை நாடுகளில் தன்னார்வ சுற்றுச்சூழல் ஒப்பந்தங்கள் பிரபலமாகி வருகின்றன. சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு குறித்த இந்த இலவச கட்டுரையின் மூலம், இந்த வகையான ஒப்பந்தத்தைப் பற்றி ஒருவர் மேலும் அறிந்து கொள்வார். இந்த ஒப்பந்தங்கள், சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கான குறைந்தபட்ச ஒழுங்குமுறை தரநிலைகளுக்கு அப்பால் நகரும் நிறுவனங்களுக்கு அங்கீகாரம் அளிக்கும் தளத்தை வழங்குகின்றன. இந்த ஒப்பந்தங்கள் சிறந்த சுற்றுச்சூழல் நடைமுறைகளில் ஒன்றின் வளர்ச்சியை ஆதரிக்கின்றன. எடுத்துக்காட்டாக, இந்திய சுற்றுச்சூழல் மேம்பாட்டு அறக்கட்டளை (EIT) இந்த சுற்றுச்சூழல் துறையில் 1998 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் செயல்பட்டு வருகிறது. இந்த சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு கட்டுரையின் மூலம், ஒருவர் கற்றுக் கொள்ள நிறைய கிடைக்கிறது.சுற்றுச்சூழல் அணுகுமுறைசுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பிற்கான ஒரு சுற்றுச்சூழல் அணுகுமுறையானது, குறிப்பிட்ட சிக்கல்கள் மற்றும் சவால்களில் கவனம் செலுத்துவதை விட முடிவெடுக்கும் செயல்முறைக்கு ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பின் சிக்கலான தொடர்புகளை கருத்தில் கொள்வதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு கட்டுரை எழுதுவது இந்த அணுகுமுறையின் துல்லியமான கண்ணோட்டத்தை வழங்கும். சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கான அணுகுமுறையானது, தகவல் பரிமாற்றத்தை சிறப்பாக ஆதரிப்பது, மோதல்களைத் தீர்க்கக்கூடிய உத்திகளை உருவாக்குதல் மற்றும் பிராந்திய பாதுகாப்பை மேம்படுத்துவதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. இந்த அணுகுமுறை சுற்றுச்சூழலை பாதுகாப்பதில் பெரும் பங்கு வகிக்கிறது. சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாப்பதில் மதங்களும் முக்கியப் பங்கு வகிக்கின்றன என்றும் இந்த அணுகுமுறை கூறுகிறது.சர்வதேச சுற்றுச்சூழல் ஒப்பந்தங்கள்தற்போதைய சூழ்நிலையில், மனிதர்கள் மற்றும் பல்வேறு நாடுகளில் சுற்றுச்சூழலின் மீதான அவர்களின் கவனக்குறைவு காரணமாக பூமியின் பல இயற்கை வளங்கள் பாதிக்கப்படக்கூடியதாக மாறியுள்ளது. இதன் விளைவாக, பல நாடுகளும் அவற்றின் அரசாங்கங்களும் இயற்கைச் சூழலின் மீதான மனித தாக்கத்தைக் குறைப்பதற்கும், அது சீரழிந்துவிடாமல் பாதுகாப்பதற்கும் பல்வேறு ஒப்பந்தங்களை மேற்கொண்டுள்ளன. ஆங்கிலத்தில் இந்த சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு கட்டுரையின் மூலம், இந்த விஷயத்தில் ஒரு தெளிவான பார்வை கிடைக்கும்.பல்வேறு நாடுகளின் வெவ்வேறு அரசாங்கங்களுக்கிடையே செய்து கொள்ளப்படும் ஒப்பந்தங்கள் சர்வதேச சுற்றுச்சூழல் ஒப்பந்தங்கள் என்று அழைக்கப்படுகின்றன. இந்த ஒப்பந்தத்தில் காலநிலை, கடல்கள், ஆறுகள் மற்றும் காற்று மாசுபாடு போன்ற காரணிகள் அடங்கும். இந்த உடன்படிக்கைகள் சில சமயங்களில் சட்டப்பூர்வமாக பிணைக்கப்படுகின்றன, மேலும் அவை பின்பற்றப்படாவிட்டால், அது சில சட்டரீதியான தாக்கங்களுக்கு வழிவகுக்கும். இந்த ஒப்பந்தங்கள் 1910 ஆம் ஆண்டில் ஐரோப்பா, அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் ஆப்பிரிக்காவில் செய்யப்பட்ட சில பன்னாட்டு ஒப்பந்தங்களுடன் நீண்ட வரலாற்றைக் கொண்டுள்ளன. கியோட்டோ புரோட்டோகால் மற்றும் பாரிஸ் ஒப்பந்தம் ஆகியவை மிகவும் பிரபலமான சர்வதேச ஒப்பந்தங்களில் சில. இந்த சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு கட்டுரையின் மூலம், சுற்றுச்சூழல் பிரச்சினையை தீர்க்க அரசுகள் நடவடிக்கை எடுத்து வருகின்றன, ஆனால் அது போதுமானதாக இல்லை என்பது தெளிவாகிறது.ஆங்கிலத்தில் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு பற்றிய ஒரு சிறு பத்திபூமி வாழ்வதற்கு ஒரு அழகான இடம், உயிரினங்களுக்கு மிகவும் சாதகமான சுற்றுச்சூழல் நிலைமைகள் உள்ளன. ஆனால் மனிதர்களாகிய நாம் அதை பாதிப்படையச் செய்கிறோம் மற்றும் அதிகரித்த விகிதத்தில் மாசுபாட்டை ஏற்படுத்தும் செயல்களால் எங்கள் சொந்த வீடுகளை அழித்து வருகிறோம். சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாக்கும் இந்த கட்டுரையில், சுற்றுச்சூழலை எவ்வாறு பாதுகாப்பது என்பது குறித்து 200 வார்த்தைகள் சரியாக விளக்கப்படும்.நாளுக்கு நாள் அழிந்து வருவதால் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு என்பது காலத்தின் தேவையாகிவிட்டது. எனவே, சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாக்கக்கூடிய உத்திகளைக் கொண்டு வருவதற்கு அரசாங்கங்கள் கொள்கைகளை உருவாக்குகின்றன மற்றும் பிற நாடுகளுடன் ஒப்பந்தங்கள் செய்து வருகின்றன. சில நிறுவனங்கள் மனிதர்களின் செயல்பாடுகளிலிருந்து சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாக்கும் அதே நோக்கத்தைக் கொண்டுள்ளன.சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு குறித்த இந்த சிறு கட்டுரையில், திடீர் நடவடிக்கைகள் எடுக்கப்படாவிட்டால், நமது வருங்கால சந்ததி மாசுபட்ட சூழலில் வாழ வேண்டியிருக்கும், இது மிகவும் கடினமாக பாதுகாக்கப்படுகிறது. வாழ்வதற்கு அழகான சூழலுடன் கூடிய பாதுகாப்பான மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பான எதிர்காலத்திற்கான திறவுகோல் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு ஆகும். முடிவுரைஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் மாசு அதிகரித்து, இயற்கைச் சூழல் சீர்குலைந்து வருவதால், இயற்கைச் சூழலைப் பாதுகாக்க நடவடிக்கை எடுக்க வேண்டியது அவசியம். இந்தப் பிரச்சனைகளுக்கெல்லாம் காரணம் மனிதர்கள்தான் என்பதை நாம் அறிந்திருப்பதால், சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்குக் கேடு விளைவிக்கக் கூடிய அவர்களின் செயல்பாடுகளைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தும் கொள்கைகளை அரசுகள் உருவாக்க வேண்டும். அவற்றை அவசரமாக நிறுத்தாவிட்டால், வரும் ஆண்டுகளில் உலகம் சில பேரழிவுகளைக் காணக்கூடும். உதாரணமாக, காலநிலை மாற்றம் ஒரு பெரிய பிரச்சனையாக உள்ளது, மேலும் இது மாசு அதிகரிப்பதற்கான காரணங்களில் ஒன்றாகும். பாதுகாப்பான எதிர்காலம் ஒட்டுமொத்த சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பொறுத்தது.          \\"சுற்றுச்சூழல் மாசுபடுவதைத் தடுக்கச் சட்டங்கள் இயற்றப்பட்டிருந்தாலும், ஒவ்வொருவரின் உள்ளத்திலும் ஏற்படும் மாற்றமே சுற்றுச்சூழலைப் பாதுகாக்கும்\\""},{"question":"Heesta HaboonCabdiqaadir Juba.","answer":"cirkoo gaaxday roobkiyosaymihii ku raarnaarabi nooga shubayoorabtii ay warshiikh ahaydku rusheeyay reedahaoo wali rogaal celinkolba si u ruqaansigaraynkiyo gufaacadaka ridaaya dhinacyadasida loogu reeyaanhaboon kuu riyaaqayonaftaad raaligaliseeintaad duljoogo raas aduunhaboon ma rabo ruux kalefaceed ka rooneey soo rucleeadaa rasmigii ruuxay aheedhulka rays qaboobiyoreexaan udgoonliyodhirtu rucub magooliyoramaskio dogiirasmii ugu soo baxayoo ramadka geeliyoriyihii iyo lo,doo dhalayrugtii wabiga jawharreedaha ay daaqaansida loogu reeyaanhaboon kuu riyaaqayooadaa ii rafiiqeeintaan dul joogo raas aduunhaboon ma rabo ruux kalefaceed ka rooneey soo rucleeadaa rasmigii ruuxay ahee"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'katak hendak jadi lembu'? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud ingin melakukan sesuatu yang melebihi kesanggupan sendiri, hendak menyamai orang besar (orang kaya dan sebagainya) Contoh ayat:  Sikap Bendtner seperti katak hendak jadi lembu itu memeningkan kepala pengurus pasukannya."},{"question":"දොර පිල යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගේකට ඇතුළුවෙන තැන දොරකඩ. ගෙපිල තරමක් උසට හදන නිසා මේ ගෙපිලට නගින්න දොර ළඟ පඩියක් හදල තිබ්බ. ඒක තමයි දොරපිල. "},{"question":"Ascariasis","answer":"Ascariasis jẹ́ àrùn tí kòkòrò ajọ̀fẹ́ tí a npé ní aràn alára rógódó Ascaris lumbricoides nṣe òkùnfà rẹ̀. Àkóràn àrùn náà kò ní ààmì àìsàn kankan lára marundinlaadọrun nínú ọgọrun (85%) àwọn ènìyàn tó ti ní àrùn náà, pàápàá bí iye àwọn aràn náà bá kèrè. Àwọn ààmì àìsàn a má a pọ̀ síi pẹ̀lú iye aràn tó wà lára, lára irú àwọn ààmì bẹ́ẹ̀ sì ni àìlèmíkanlẹ̀ àti ibà ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ àìsàn náà. Àwọn ààmì àìsàn bíi inú wíwú, inú rírun àti ìgbẹ́ gbuuru lè tẹ̀lé èyí. Àwọn ọmọdé ni ó má a nsábà ní àkóràn àrùn náà, láàárín àwọn ọmọdé bẹ́ẹ̀, àkóràn àrùn náà tún lè ṣe òkùnfa àìlẹ́ranlára, àìtó èròjà oúnjẹ lára àti àwọn ìṣòro nípa ẹ̀kọ́-kíkọ́.Àkóràn àrùn náà a má a wáyé nípasẹ̀ jíjẹ oúnjẹ tàbí mímu omi tí ẹyin aràn tí à npè ní Ascaris náà, èyítí ó ti inú ìgbọ̀nsẹ̀ jáde wá, bá ti kó sí, tí ó sì ti sọ di àìmọ́. À ó pa àwọn ẹyin náà nínú ìfun, àwọn aràn náà a sì gbẹ́ ihò sínú ògiri ikùn ènìyàn, wọn a sì gba ibẹ̀ lọ sínú àwọn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró nípasẹ̀ ẹ̀jẹ̀. Níbẹ̀ wọn yóò wọ inú àwọn àpò atẹ́gùn inú ẹ̀dọ̀fóró, wọn yóò sì ṣàn lọ sókè nínú ọ̀nà-ọ̀fun, níbití a ó ti wú wọn jáde bí ikọ́, tí a ó sì gbé wọn mì. Àwọn ìdin náà yóò sì gba inú ikùn kọjá fún ìgbà kejì sínú ìfun níbití wọn yóò ti dàgbà sí aràn nlá.Ìdènà àrùn náà níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ìmọ́tótó, èyítí ó kan mímú ìlọsíwájú bá níní ànfàní sí ilé-ìyàgbẹ́ àti dída ìgbẹ́ nù ní ọ̀nà tí ó tọ́. Ọwọ́-fífọ̀ pẹ̀lú ọṣẹ farahàn bí ààbò tó péye. Ní àwọn agbègbè ibití iye ènìyàn tó ju méjìlélógún nínú ọgọrun (20%) lọ ti ní àkóràn àrùn náà, a dámọ̀ràn pé kí a ṣe ìtọ́jú gbogbo ènìyàn láti ìgbà dé ìgbà ní tẹ̀lé-n-tẹ̀lé. Wíwáyé àrùn náà lára ẹnití ó ti níi rí jẹ́ ohun tí ó wọ́pọ̀. Kò sí àjẹsára. Àwọn ìtọ́jú tí Àjọ Ìlera fún Àgbáyé dámọ̀ràn ni àwọn egbògi bíi albendazole, mebendazole, levamisole tàbí pyrantel pamoate. Àwọn egbògi mìíràn tó tún má a nṣiṣẹ́ ni tribendimidine àti nitazoxanide.Àtànká àti Ìṣàkóso àtànká àrùnIye àwọn ènìyàn tó tó bílíọ̀nù 0.8 sí 1.2 káàkiri àgbáyé ni ó ní àrùn ascariasis, tí àwọn àwùjọ tó sì ní àrùn náà púpọ̀ jùlọ sì jẹ́ àwọn ará Gúsù Sahara Afirika, Amẹrika Latini, àti Eṣia. Èyí mú kí àrùn ascariasis jẹ́ ẹ̀yà àkóràn aràn ajọ̀fẹ́ nípasẹ̀ iyẹ̀pẹ̀ ilẹ̀ tó wọ́pọ̀ júlọ. Ní ọdún 2010, ó ṣe òkùnfà ikú àwọn ènìyàn tó tó 2,700, èyítí ó wálẹ̀ láti ènìyàn 3,400 tó kú ní ọdún 1990. Oríṣi aràn Ascaris mìíràn a má a ran àwọn ẹlẹ́dẹ̀."},{"question":"Body modification  කියන එකට දෙන්න පුලුවන් සිංහල වචනය මොකක්ද.ශරීරට වෙනස් කිරීම කියන එකට වඩා වෙනස් වචනයක් තියේද සිංහලෙන්","answer":"බදරූගැන්වීම, බඳ නවීකරණය, අංගවිච්චූරණ"},{"question":"问：什么是烹饪的五大基本口味？","answer":"答：烹饪的五大基本口味是甜、咸、酸、苦和辣。"},{"question":"‘ਦਾਨ’ ਪਿਛੇਤਰ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਵਿਚ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਸ਼ਬਦ ਅੱਖਰਾਂ, ਲਗਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਲਗਾਂਖਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੇਲ਼ ਨਾਲ਼ ਬਣਦੀ ਹੈ। ਅਰਥਾਂ ਦੇ ਪੱਧਰ ਤੇ ਇਹ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਦੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਤੋਂ ਛੋਟੀ ਇਕਾਈ ਹੈ ਜਿਹੜੀ ਬੋਲੀ ਅਸੀਂ ਬੋਲਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਜਾਂ ਲਿਖਦੇ ਹਾਂ, ਉਸ ਵਿਚ ਵਰਤੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਮੁੱਖ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਦੋ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ।ਮੂਲ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਅਤੇ ਰਚਿਤ ਸ਼ਬਦ। ਦਾਨ’ ਪਿਛੇਤਰ ਉਰਦੂ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਵਿਚ ਆਇਆ ਹੈI"},{"question":"Hlaloša seka se: o na le leleme","answer":"Ke motho wa go rata maaka"},{"question":"రాజ్యం, ప్రభుత్వం మధ్యగల వ్యత్యాసాలను గుర్తించండి.","answer":"రాజ్యం:రాజ్యం శాశ్వతమైన రాజకీయ సంస్థ. మానవ సమాజం ఉన్నంతకాలం అది ఉంటుంది.రాజ్యమునకు 5 లక్షణాలుంటాయి. ప్రజలు, ప్రదేశం, ప్రభుత్వం, సార్వభౌమాధికారం, అంతర్జాతీయ గుర్తింపు దాని లక్షణాలు.రాజ్యము యజమాని వంటిది.రాజ్యానికి సార్వభౌమాధికారం సహజంగానే ఉంటుంది. అది ఉన్నతాధికారాలు చెలాయిస్తుంది.ప్రపంచంలోని అన్ని రాజ్యాలకు ముఖ్య లక్షణాలు ఒక్కటే.పౌరులంతా రాజ్యంలో సభ్యులే. రాజ్యంలో ప్రజలకు సభ్యత్వం, తప్పనిసరిగా ఉంటుంది.రాజ్యానికి స్వతసిద్ధమైన రూపం లేదు. అది ప్రభుత్వ రూపంలోనే కనిపిస్తుంది.రాజ్యానికి ప్రదేశము ఒక ముఖ్య లక్షణము. ప్రదేశంలేని రాజ్యం ఉండదు.ప్రజలకు రాజ్యాన్ని వ్యతిరేకించే హక్కు లేదు.రాజ్యానికి మౌలికమైన అధికారాలున్నాయి.ప్రభుత్వం:ప్రభుత్వం ఎన్నికల వలనగానీ, విప్లవాల వలనగానీ మారవచ్చు. అందువలన అది శాశ్వతమైనది కాదు.ప్రభుత్వం, రాజ్య లక్షణాలలో ఒకటి మాత్రమే. అది రాజ్య ప్రతినిధి, ఒక భాగము.ప్రభుత్వం రాజ్యానికి సేవకుని వంటిది. రాజ్యం పనులను ప్రభుత్వం చేస్తుంది.ప్రభుత్వం రాజ్యం తరపున సార్వభౌమాధికారాన్ని చెలాయిస్తుంది.ప్రపంచంలో ప్రభుత్వాలన్నీ ఒకే విధమైనవి కావు. ఉదా: పార్లమెంటరీ, అధ్యక్ష తరహా యూనిటరీ, సమాఖ్య మొదలగు ప్రభుత్వాలు.ప్రభుత్వంలో కొద్దిమంది మాత్రమే సభ్యులు. సభ్యత్వం తప్పనిసరి కాదు.ప్రభుత్వము ఒక స్పష్టమైన రూపంలో కనిపిస్తుంది.ప్రభుత్వం నిర్దిష్ట ప్రదేశం లేకుండా పనిచేస్తుంది. అది ఎక్కడినుండైనా పనిచేస్తుంది.ప్రజలు తమకు నచ్చని ప్రభుత్వాన్ని ప్రతిఘటించ గలరు. న్యాయస్థానాల ద్వారా కూడా వ్యతిరేకించగలరు.ప్రభుత్వానికి రాజ్యాంగము ఇచ్చే అధికారాలే ఉంటాయి."},{"question":"સુરતના પ્રખ્યાત સ્થળો જણાવો.","answer":"1. ડચ ગાર્ડન2. ડુમસ બીચ3. હજીરા ગામ4. અંબાજી મંદિર5. સરદાર પટેલ મ્યુઝિયમ"},{"question":"لومړۍ جمله: باچا د جمعې په ورځ ژوبڼ ته لاړ. دوهمه جمله: باچا د جمعې په ورځ ناروغه وو. آیا دواړه جملې یو له بل سره موافق دي؟","answer":"نه، دوی د یو بل سره په تضاد کې دي."},{"question":" Waxyaalaha Ilaahay faray dadka inay sameeyaan maxaa ugu muhiimsan?","answer":"Waxaa ugu muhiimsan \\"TawxiidkaAlle\\" oo ah in isaga kelidii la caabudo."},{"question":"கேள்வி: இராணுவத்தின் கிளைகள் எப்போது நிறுவப்பட்டன? விடை:","answer":"1775 ஆம் ஆண்டு நிறுவப்பட்டன"},{"question":"¿Donde está ubicada la ciudad de Rionegro, Antioquía?","answer":"Está localizada en el valle de San Nicolás, también conocido como el Altiplano del Oriente, en la subregión Oriente, y es la ciudad con mayor población y la que concentra el movimiento económico de la subregión. Está ubicada a tan solo 35 minutos de Medellín, capital del departamento, gracias al túnel de interconexión Aburrá-Oriente. Su nombre oficial es Ciudad Santiago de Arma de Rionegro"},{"question":"இந்தியாவிற்கு வந்த முதல் அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி யார்? \\tஅ.ஜார்ஜ் வாஷிங்டன்ஆ.டேவிட் ஜசன் ஹோவர் இ.ரீகன் ஈ.ஜான் எஃப். கென்னடி பதில்:ஆ.டேவிட் ஜசன் ஹோவர் ","answer":"இந்தியாவிற்கு வந்த முதல் அமெரிக்க ஜனாதிபதி ஆ.டேவிட் ஜசன் ஹோவர்.டுவைட் டேவிட் ஐசனாவர் (அக்டோபர் 14, 1890 - மார்ச் 28, 1969) 1953 முதல் 1961 வரை ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்காவின் 34ஆவது குடியரசுத் தலைவராக இருந்தார். இரண்டாம் உலகப் போரில் நட்பு அணி இராணுவத்தின் சிறந்த தலைவர் ஆவார். தலைவராக இருக்கும்பொழுது இவர் கொரியப் போரை நிறுத்தினார். இடைமாநில நெடுஞ்சாலை முறையும் அமெரிக்காவின் விண்வெளி திட்டமும் இவராலேயே தொடங்கப்பட்டன."},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Người Sán Chỉ có nét văn hóa đặc trưng gì?A. Hát XoanB. Hát Soóng CọC. Hát Then","answer":"B. Hát Soóng Cọhát Soóng Cọ là nét văn hóa đặc trưng của người Sán ChỉTheo cổng thông tin điện tử tỉnh Quảng Ninh, người Sán Chỉ là một trong hai nhánh cùng với nhánh người Cao Lan thuộc dân tộc Sán Chay.Hội hát Soóng Cọ, hay còn gọi là hội hát tháng 3, là nét văn hóa đặc trưng của người Sán Chỉ. Soóng Cọ có nghĩa là ca hát, hát xướng, giao duyên. Đây là một loại hình sinh hoạt văn hóa dân gian để thể hiện và giao lưu tình cảm giữa các nhóm cộng đồng Sán Chỉ. Từ xa xưa cứ vào tháng 3 âm lịch, mỗi phiên chợ ở huyện vùng cao Bình Liêu lại trở thành hội hát Soóng Cọ.Hát Soóng Cọ là cách hát đối gồm một bên nam và một bên nữ đối diện và có thể cùng một lúc có nhiều tốp hát đối với nhau. Lời bài hát sâu lắng, tình cảm, nội dung bài hát phong phú, đa dạng, uyển chuyển, phản ánh cuộc sống lao động sản xuất, ca ngợi thiên nhiên, đất nước, con người, tình yêu đôi lứa."},{"question":"Những câu thơ sau nằm trong bài thơ nào của Tú Xương?Nhà kia lỗi phép con khinh bốMụ nọ chanh chua vợ chửi chồng","answer":"đây là bài 'Đất Vị Hoàng'Vị Hoàng là tên cũ của làng quê Tú Xương, cũng là tên con sông đào chảy qua làng. Sông Vị trước năm 1894 có vị trí đặc biệt với tỉnh Nam Định và cả vùng đồng bằng Bắc Bộ. Khi chưa có cảng biển Hải Phòng, Nam Định là đầu mối giao thông lớn nhất nhì miền Bắc, không thể thiếu con sông Vị.Vì vậy, đất Vị Hoàng vừa chỉ làng quê nhà thơ, vừa chỉ cả thành Nam, tỉnh Nam. Qua sự thay đổi làng quê của mình, Tú Xương cảm nhận được số phận chung của cả miền, đất nước khi đó. Bài thơ Đất Vị Hoàng từng được sử dụng trong phần đọc thêm sách giáo khoa Văn học lớp 11 giai đoạn 1990-2006.Có đất nào như đất ấy không?Phố phường tiếp giáp với bờ sôngNhà kia lỗi phép con khinh bốMụ nọ chanh chua vợ chửi chồngKeo cú người đâu như cứt sắtTham lam chuyện thở rặt hơi đồngBắc Nam hỏi khắp người bao tỉnhCó đất nào như đất ấy không?Bài thơ này đã vạch ra những thay đổi theo chiều hướng tiêu cực, suy thoái đạo đức xã hội một cách đầy đủ, đồng thời nhà thơ bộc lộ sự đau xót trước sự thay đổi đó.Chiếm Nam Định, Pháp mở rộng phố cũ, lập phố mới. Con sông Vị bị lấp dần rồi lấp hẳn. Làng Tú Xương bỗng dưng xoay ra phố (Phố phường tiếp giáp với bờ sông), kéo theo bao nhiêu đổ vỡ về đạo lý, nếp sống và bản chất con người.Lối sống đô thị đã làm lung lay luân lý đạo đức, phá vỡ đạo lý cổ truyền của dân tộc là con trọng cha mẹ, vợ chồng hòa thuận. Có thể nói, bài thơ là câu hỏi cháy lòng về tình trạng suy thoái đạo đức ở làng quê.Nhà kia lỗi phép con khinh bốMụ nọ chanh chua vợ chửi chồng"},{"question":"کیا ہم واقعی کچھ بھی جان سکتے ہیں، یا تمام علم شکوک و شبہات کا شکار ہیں؟ یقین اور علم کی نوعیت کو دریافت کریں۔","answer":"یہ سوال علم کے مطالعہ سے متعلق علمی علم میں شامل ہے۔ فلسفیانہ شکوک و شبہات بعض علم کے امکان کو چیلنج کرتا ہے، اس بات پر زور دیتا ہے کہ تمام عقائد شک کے تابع ہیں۔ تاہم، بہت سے ماہر علمیات کا استدلال ہے کہ اگرچہ قطعی یقین مضحکہ خیز ہو سکتا ہے، پھر بھی ہم تجرباتی شواہد، دلیل اور قابل اعتماد ذرائع سے جائز عقائد حاصل کر سکتے ہیں۔"},{"question":"السؤال: من هي المرأة التي كانت ابنة نبي وزوجة نبي ؟","answer":"الإجابة: زوجة سيدنا موسى عليه السلام ابنة سيدنا شعيب عليه السلام"},{"question":"“竹林七贤”指谁？","answer":"竹林七贤指的是三国魏正始年间，嵇康、阮籍、山涛、向秀、刘伶、王戎及阮咸七人，因常在当时的山阳县 （今河南辉县一带 ）竹林之下，喝酒、纵歌，肆意酣畅，世谓七贤，后与地名竹林合称。"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Năm 1975","answer":", Nguyễn Mạnh Quang sang định cư tại Hoa Kỳ. Trong vòng chỉ vài tháng, ông được Sở Học Chánh Tacoma (Tacoma Public Schools) mướn làm việc từ tháng 9/1975 – 9/1998. Trong thời gian 23 năm này, ông đã dạy các trường Trung học cấp III: Stadium High School, Lincoln High School, và Wilson High School. Ông phụ trách giảng dạy các môn: Lịch Sử Hoa Kỳ (American History), Những Vấn Đề Khó Khăn Trên Thế Giới (World Problems), Sử Tiểu Bang Washington, Công Dân (Civics), Địa Lý Thế Giới (World Geography)"},{"question":"வினா: உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய தீவு எது?","answer":"விடை: கிரின்லாந்து"},{"question":"Fenoy ity ohabolana ity: \\"Izay sahy maty ihany no ___\\"","answer":"\\"Izay sahy maty ihany no mifono lamba mena.\\""},{"question":"هل من الممكن شرح عن كيفية عمل الزربيان العدني؟","answer":"بالتأكيد. المكوّنات: أربعة صدور من الدجاج منزوع العظم. حبتان من البطاطا المقلية والمقطّعة إلى مكعبات متوسّطة الحجم. ثلاثة أكواب من أرز بسمتي المغسول والمنقوع لمدّة نصف ساعة. بصلة مفرومة فرماً ناعماً. رأس من الثوم المفروم فرماً ناعماً، والمخلوط مع ملعقة كبيرة من الهيل المطحون. ملعقتان كبيرتان من لبن الزبادي. بهارات الدجاج: رشة من كلّ من الكركم، والقرنفل، والفلفل الأسود، والهيل، والكمون، والكزبرة المجففة على أن تكون جميع هذه المكونات مطحونة. بهارات الأرز: خمس حبات من االهيل، وعود من القرفة، وورقتا غار، وعودان من القرنفل، وزيت أو سمن، وملح ومرقة دجاج -حسب الرغبة-. طريقة التحضير:  قلي البصل في القليل من الزيت الساخن حتى يذبل. إضافة الملح، ثمّ الدجاج، والتقليب من وقت إلى آخر حتى يتغيّر لون الدجاج. إضافة خليط الثوم، والتنكيه ببهارات الدجاج، ثمّ وضع الزبادي، وغمر الدجاج بالماء المغلي. ترك المزيج على حرارة منخفضة حتى ينضج الدجاج. وضع البطاطا، وترك المزيج حتى ينضج جيداً. إضافة مرق الدجاج في قدر وغليها، وذلك لتحضير الأرز، ثمّ إضافة بهارات الأرز. إضافة الأرز، وتركه لينضج نصف استواء. تصفية الأرز، وإضافته إلى مزيج الدجاج، ثمّ تغطية القدر بورق القصدير، وترك المزيج على نار هادئة لمدة تتراوح ما بين 6-10 دقائق. ملاحظة: يمكن الاستغناء عن قلي البطاطا وسلقها بدلاً من ذلك مع الدجاج، كما يمكن استبدال الدجاج باللحم، واتباع نفس الخطوات."},{"question":"Ọkunrin to wa latimọle ni Mariam n fi kula gbe igbo lọ fun tọwọ fi tẹ ẹ","answer":"Maria Drissu lorukọ obinrin ẹni ọdun marundinlogoju yii, abiyamọ to n fọmọ lọmu lọwọ ni, ṣugbọn o ti dero ahamọ awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ajọ NDLEA bayii, ibi to ti n fi kula ounjẹ gbe egboogi oloro ti wọn pe ni igbo lọ fun afurasi ọdaran kan to lọgba ẹwọn lọwọ ti tẹ obinrin naa, o ni wọn bẹ oun koun ba wọn ra a ni.Ọgbẹni Fẹmi Babafẹmi, Alukoro ileeṣẹ to n gbogun ti okoowo ati ilo egboogi oloro nilẹ wa, NDLEA, lo fi atẹjade nipa iṣẹlẹ yii ṣọwọ s’ALAROYE lọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, o ni ọkan lara awọn ọgba ẹwọn to wa niluu Benin, nipinlẹ Edo, lọwọ ti ba obinrin naa.Babafẹmi ṣalaye pe lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ti aṣiri Mariam tu, kula ounjẹ lo gbe dani, o ni ẹlẹwọn kan loun ba gbe ounjẹ ọhun wa, ounjẹ ilẹ Ibo ti wọn n pe ni Akpu lo wa ninu rẹ.Ṣugbọn nigba ti ọkan lara awọn ẹṣọ ọgba ẹwọn fi ṣibi yẹ ounjẹ naa wo, wọn ri i pe nnkan kan tun wa nisalẹ kula naa, ti wọn di pamọ sinu lailọọnu funfun, nnkan ọhun si yatọ si ounjẹ Akpu ti wọn ri tẹlẹ. Lẹyin ayẹwo, akara tu sepo, wọn ri i pe igbo (marijuana) ni wọn di sinu lailọọnu naa.Loju-ẹsẹ ni wọn ti fi pampẹ ofin gbe iya ikoko, o di ọfiisi ajọ NDLEA, ibẹ lo ti jẹwọ fawọn agbofinro pe loootọ loun di igbo pamọ sisalẹ ounjẹ toun ra, o ni ẹlẹwọn to ran oun lounjẹ lo ni koun ba oun ra igbo bọ, bo si ṣe maa n ran oun niyẹn.Babafẹmi ni iwadii ṣi n tẹsiwaju, o lafurasi ọdaran naa ti n ṣalaye ibi to ti n ra igbo ati ẹni to n ta a fun un, o si ti juwe ọdaran-mọran ẹlẹwọn to bẹ ẹ nigbo.Laipẹ, gẹgẹ bi wọn ṣe wi, obinrin naa yoo dero ile-ẹjọ."},{"question":" No basquete, quantos pontos vale a cesta quando a bola é arremessada de fora do garrafão?","answer":"3 pontos."},{"question":"2006年のトリノオリンピックには年齢に足りないため代表資格を得られなかった女子フィギュアスケートの選手といえば誰。","answer":"浅田真央です。"},{"question":"Тарыхта кыргыздын көрүнүктүү жазуучулары жана акындары кимдер болгон?","answer":" Кыргыздын көрүнүктүү жазуучулары менен акындарынын арасында Чыңгыз Айтматов, Алыкул Осмонов, Касым Тыныстанов бар."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: HLV Hà Nội và SLNA tranh cãi về quyết định rút thẻ đỏ của trọng tài","answer":"Phút 49, trọng tài Nguyễn Mạnh Hải rút thẻ đỏ trực tiếp cho Olaha. Trọng tài xác định tiền đạo SLNA có hành động đánh nguội với Đậu Văn Toàn. Sau trận đấu, huấn luyện viên hai đội có chia sẻ trái chiều về quyết định này. HLV Nguyễn Huy Hoàng (SLNA) nói: \\"Tôi nghĩ ban tổ chức cần đề nghị tổ trọng tài xem lại tấm thẻ đỏ. Olaha chỉ giơ tay, không phải vung tay biểu hiện đánh trỏ. Tôi sẽ làm đơn khiếu nại trọng tài với hai tình huống. Đầu tiên, Olaha không cố ý đánh nguội, cùng lắm thẻ vàng. Thứ hai là quả phạt đền. Bóng chạm đầu rồi mới xuống tay Bá Sang. Tôi sẽ khiếu nại, trọng tài nên xem lại vì Olaha không có hành động phi thể thao\\". Trong khi đó, trợ lý Lê Đức Tuấn họp báo thay HLV trưởng Chun Jae Ho đang cách ly vì nhiễm COVID-19. Ông Tuấn có suy nghĩ khác với HLV Huy Hoàng. \\"Hành động của Olaha rất không fair-play diễn ra ngay trước ban huấn luyện Hà Nội FC. Trước khi bật nhảy, Olaha đã vung tay vào mặt Văn Toàn. Hành động phi thể thao đó bị nghiêm cấm trên thế giới\\", trợ lý Lê Đức Tuấn nói. \\"Tình huống ngay trước mắt nên chúng tôi nhìn rất rõ. Trước khi nhảy lên, Olaha đã quan sát và cố tình đánh nguội. Trận đấu căng thẳng, hai đội phối hợp tốt và trọng tài làm tốt nhiệm vụ của mình\\". Chính Olaha là người ghi bàn mở tỉ số trận đấu ngay phút thứ 4. Tuy nhiên, tấm thẻ đỏ của anh cùng pha để bóng chạm tay dẫn đến phạt đền của Thái Bá Sang khiến trận đấu đảo chiều. Phút 52, Siladji dứt điểm chính xác đánh bại Văn Hoàng trên chấm 11m. Đến phút 76, Tonci Mujan làm tường kiến tạo để Thành Chung dứt điểm quyết đoán trong vòng cấm ấn định tỉ số 2-1. HLV Huy Hoàng đánh giá: \\"Nếu chúng tôi có đủ người thì khác. Hà Nội toàn tuyển thủ, đều các tuyến. Không riêng SLNA mà các đội khác cũng gặp khó khăn trước Hà Nội. Tất cả phải tập trung cao độ. SLNA đá hiệp một tốt cả ở phòng ngự lẫn tấn công cùng hiệu ứng khán giả\\". Với kết quả này, SLNA vẫn đứng thứ hai trên bảng xếp hạng với 16 điểm sau 9 trận, bằng Đà Nẵng và Hoàng Anh Gia Lai nhưng xếp trên do hơn hiệu số bàn thắng bại. Trong khi đó, Hà Nội FC giữ vững ngôi đầu bảng với 20 điểm. \\"Mới đá 9 trận, chúng tôi chưa nói trước được gì về cơ hội vô địch. Chúng tôi luôn tôn trọng mọi đối thủ\\", trợ lý Lê Đức Tuấn nói."},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் பறக்கும் சீக்கியர் என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":"விடை: மில்கா சிங்"},{"question":"Manampy ny olona te hanena vatana ve ny fihinanana sakafo ara-pahasalamana? Valio Eny na Tsia.","answer":"Eny, Manampy ny olona te hanena vatana ny fihinanana sakafo ara-pahasalamana.  Mila hita anaty sakafo hoanina isan’andro avokoa ireo otrik’aina ilain’ny vatana mba hahasalama sy hampatanjaka azy. Tsara kosa raha atao voalanjalanja tsara izany. "},{"question":"ලෝකයේ ශක්තිමත්ම ගස කුමක්ද?","answer":"දකුණු ඇමරිකාවේ නිවර්තන කලාපවල දක්නට ලැබෙන Quebrancho (Schinopsis spp.), ලෝකයේ ශක්තිමතම දැව ලෙස සැලකේ.  ගසේ විෂ්කම්භය මීටර් 1 ක් පමණ වන අතර උස මීටර් 9-15 කි.තවත් ශක්තිමත් ගසක් වන්නේ Primorsky ප්‍රදේශයේ වර්ධනය වන Birch Schmidt ය.  එහි දැව යකඩවලට වඩා 1.5 ගුණයක් ශක්තිමත්.කෙසේ වෙතත්, ශක්තිය විවිධ ආකාරවලින් මැනිය හැකිය.  උදාහරණයක් ලෙස, Baobab ගස එහි ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධය.  එහි පොත්ත ගිනි ප්‍රතිරෝධී වන අතර වියළිම නියඟයට ඔරොත්තු දිය හැකි අතර මෙම සමහර ගස් වසර දහස් ගණනක් පැරණි විය හැකිය"},{"question":"வினா: அந்தாதித் தொடையில் முதலில் இடம் பெற்ற நூல் எது? ","answer":"விடை:  பதிற்றுப்பத்து –நான்காம் பத்து"},{"question":"Görsel sanatlar bölümü sayısal mı sözel mi?","answer":"Görsel sanatlar bölümü sözel bir bölümdür."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු උපකුලපතිවරයා කවුද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු උපකුලපතිවරයා වූයේ ශ්‍රීමත් අයිවෝ ජෙනිස් මහතාය."},{"question":"句子1: 约拿在鱼腹里度过了三天, 耶稣将在坟墓里度过三天. 句子二:耶稣在鱼的肚子里呆了三天; 约拿将在坟墓里呆三天. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'minta nyawa'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud memohon supaya tidak dibunuh, meminta belas ihsan. Contoh ayat: Pencuri itu minta nyawa daripada ahli rukun tetangga yang menangkapnya ketika sedang memecah masuk rumah Pak Jamal."},{"question":"வினா:எந்த நாடு  உலகின் நிலைப் பேறுடைய நகரம் என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது?","answer":" விடை:ரோம் நாடு  உலகின் நிலைப் பேறுடைய நகரம் என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"டிடி கோசாம்பியின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"அடுத்தடுத்து வரும் ஆதிக்க வெறி தலைக்கேறிய பித்தர்களின் பெயர்களும், பெரும் போர்களுமே வரலாறு என்றால் அப்படிப்பட்ட இந்திய வரலாற்றை எழுதுவது கடினமாகும். ஒரு மன்னனின் பெயரை அறிவதைவிடவும் விவசாயம் செய்வதற்கு மக்களிடம் ஏர் இருந்ததா, இல்லையா என்பதே சரித்திரம் என்றால், அப்படிப்பட்ட சரித்திரம் இந்தியாவுக்கு உண்டு."},{"question":" உடலின் அனிச்சை செயலான, மூச்சு விடுதல், இதயத்துடிப்பு ஆகியவை எதனால் கட்டுப்படுத்தப்படுகிறது?","answer":"முகுளம் இதய துடிப்பு மற்றும் சுவாசம் போன்ற முக்கிய செயல்பாடுகளை ஒழுங்குபடுத்துகிறது."},{"question":"Kholowa ndi chani?","answer":"Kholowa ndi masamba a mbatata. Ndipo akhoza kudyedwa ngati ndiwo. Kholowa limagwirisa ntchito zambiri nthupi, potengera ndi zomwe azaukhondo amanena."},{"question":"Pourquoi le cheval remue-t-il la queue ?","answer":"Dans les champs, l’été, les insectes sont très nombreux… Le cheval remue la queue pour chasser les mouches ou les taons, sortes de grosses mouches, qui essaient de le piquer. Sa queue remplace ses mains !"},{"question":"Gịnị ka ajụjụ a bụ: \\"Oriri Nsọ nke bu Eucharistic adoration na oyibo bụ omume na Chọọchị Roman Katọlik, na ole na ole Anglican na Lutheran ụka, nke a gọziri agọzi sacrament na-ekpughe na-efe ofufe site na ndị kwesịrị ntụkwasị obi\\"? Isiokwu ya bụ ofufe nke Oriri Nsọ.","answer":"Gịnị bụ ofufe Oriri Nsọ?"},{"question":"प्रश्न: भारत की आर्थिक स्थिति और विकास के बारे में जानकारी दें।","answer":"भारत एक तेजी से विकसित होती हुई अर्थव्यवस्था है, जिसमें कृषि, विनिर्माण, और सेवा क्षेत्रों में व्यापक विकास हुआ है। भारत दुनिया के प्रमुख आईटी और सॉफ्टवेयर सेवा प्रदाताओं में से एक है। इसके अलावा, भारत ने इन्फ्रास्ट्रक्चर, शिक्षा, और स्वास्थ्य सेवाओं में भी महत्वपूर्ण प्रगति की है, जिससे इसकी आर्थिक वृद्धि और सामाजिक विकास में मदद मिली है।"},{"question":"Jaki amerykański polityk z Tennessee urodzony 13 grudnia 1943 roku jest spokrewniony z byłym kongresmenem Stanów Zjednoczonych Haroldem Fordem Jr. oraz byłym kongresmenem Haroldem Fordem Sr.?","answer":"Jest to Emmitt H. Ford."},{"question":"ઉનાળા માટે ભારતમાં મુલાકાત લેવાનું શ્રેષ્ઠ સ્થળ","answer":"કુર્ગ : કર્ણાટકમાં મનોહર હિલ સ્ટેશનઅલ્મોરા : કુમાઓન સાંસ્કૃતિક હૃદયડાલહૌસી : હિમાચલ પ્રદેશમાં થોડું સ્વર્ગશિમલા : મનોહર રમકડાની ટ્રેન સવારી માટે લોકપ્રિયદાર્જિલિંગ : પર્વતોની જાજરમાન રાણી."},{"question":"Ndeipi emoji inomiririra zuva rine denga rakajeka?","answer":"☀️"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Nebigii Ugu Danbeeyey Ee Reer Banii Israa’iil?","answer":"Jawaab: Wuxu Ahaa Nebi Ciise CS."},{"question":"Вариация деген эмне ?","answer":"Вариация (лат. variatio өзгөртүү)музыкада музыкалык теманын, обондун же анын жалпы коштолуш түрүнүн өзгөрүшү;балетте жеке адам аткаруучу виртуоздуу классикалык чакан бий. Жандуу, тез темп менен аткарылат."},{"question":"Sheeg Imisa Kiilo Meter (KM) Ayey Isu Jiraan Washinton Iyo New York?","answer":"Waxay Isku Jiraan 6000-Km,"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air di daun keladi\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah tidak mendengar nasihat."},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da Tunísia?","answer":"0,731."},{"question":"வள்ளுவம் காட்டும் வாழ்வியல் நெறி குறித்து கட்டுரை வரைக.","answer":" முன்னுரை:திருக்குறள் நீதி நூல் மட்டுமன்று அது ஒரு வாழ்வியல் நூல். இரண்டாயிரம் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முற்பட்ட மனிதனுக்காக மட்டுமல்ல, இருபத்தோராம் நூற்றாண்டின் புதிய தலைமுறையினர்க்கும் வழிகாட்டும் புரட்சி நூல். வள்ளுவத்தின் பொருண்மை காலந்தோறும் புதிய புதிய கருத்தாக்கங்களைத் தந்து, இனம், மொழி, நாடு என்னும் எல்லைகளைக் கடந்து மனித வாழ்க்கையை வளப்படுத்துகிறது.பொருண்மைச் சிறப்புசங்க காலத்தைத் தொடர்ந்து தமிழுக்கும், தமிழர்க்கும் கிடைத்த அரிய களஞ்சியமான வள்ளுவத்தில் உலகளாவிய சிந்தனைகளும் மனிதனை உயர்த்தும் உயரிய நோக்கும் காணப்படுகிறது. வள்ளுவம் ”தமிழனுக்குரியது” என்னும் நிலையைக் கடந்து உலகத்தவர் அனைவர்க்கும் உரியதாக உள்ளமையை உணர்ந்த பாரதி ”வள்ளுவன் தன்னை உலகினுக்கே தந்து வான்புகழ் கொண்ட தமிழ்நாடு”, எனப் புகழ்ந்துரைத்தார். வள்ளுவப் பொருட் சிறப்பை அறிந்த மதுரைத் தமிழ் நாகனார் ”எல்லாப் பொருளும் இதன் பால் உள” என்று தெளிந்துரைத்துள்ளார். இவை வள்ளுவத்தின் காலமும் எல்லையும் கடந்து நுண்பொருட்ச் சிறப்பை உணர்த்துவன.வாழ்வியல் பதிவுவள்ளுவம் தான் தோன்றிய காலத்தோடு நின்று விடாமல் இந்த நூற்றாண்டு மனிதனுக்கும் வாழச்சொல்லிக் கொடுக்கிறது. வாழ்க்கையைச் சொல்லிக் கொடுக்கிறது. வள்ளுவம் இலக்கியம் என்னும் நிலையில் நின்று விடாமல் மனித வாழ்வியல் கூறுகளை காட்டும் பதிவுகளாக உள்ளது.இதனைசராசரி மனிதன் அன்றாட வாழ்க்கையில் ஒழுகவேண்டிய நெறிமுறைகளின் தொகுப்பாகத் திருக்குறள் படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.என்னும் அறிஞர் கருத்தினால் அறியலாம். வள்ளுவத்தில் உள்ள ஒவ்வொரு குறளும் மனித வாழ்க்கையின் நெறிகளை, வழிமுறைகளைத் தருவன.மானிடப் பண்பு இயல்புகளுக்கு ஓர் உறைவிடமாய் – வாழ்க்கை, வழி நெறிமுறைகளுக்கான வழிகாட்டியாய் அமைந்துள்ளது திருக்குறள்என்னும் முத்தமிழ் அறிஞரின் கருத்தும் வள்ளுவம் ஒரு வாழ்வியல் நூல் என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்துகிறது.முதன்மைப் பயன்உயிரினத்தின் உச்சியில் வாழும் இன்றைய மனிதனை, அவனது வாழ்க்கையைப் பகுத்து நோக்கி, அறம், பொருள், இன்பம் ஆகிய முதன்மைப் பயனை அறிய வைத்துப் பயனுடைய வாழ்க்கை வாழ வள்ளுவம் வழி காட்டுகிறது. எதிலும் விரைவும், ஓட்டமும் காட்டும் இந்த நூற்றாண்டு மனிதனுக்கு உள்ளத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்தவும் வாழ்வியல் பொருண்மைத் தெளிவுபெறவும் வள்ளுவர் வாக்கு ஊன்றுகோலாய் இருக்கிறது.பன்முகப்பார்வைதனி மனிதநிலை, குடும்ப நிலை, உறவினர் நிலை, சமூக உறுப்பினர் நிலை, குடிமக்கள் நிலை என்னும் தளங்களில் மனிதர்கள் பாதுகாக்க வேண்டிய பண்புகள், ஆற்ற வேண்டிய பணிகள், எனப் பன்முகக் கூறுகளை ஒழுங்குற அமைத்து ஒரு முழுமையான வாழ்வியல் கருத்தாக்கத்தை வள்ளுவம் தந்துள்ளது.தமிழ்ச் சமுதாயத்தில் காலங்காலமாய் இருந்து வந்த மரபுத்தளைகளை உடைத்து, மனிதப் பழக்க வழக்கங்களை மாற்றித் தனிமனிதத் தூய்மையை உருவாக்க வள்ளுவர் முயன்றுள்ளார்.மரபுகளைத் தகர்த்தல்மது அருந்துதலும் புலால் உண்ணுதலும் ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளப்பட்ட ஒழுக்கம் என்னும் நிலையை மாற்றி மனித மனத்தினை, வாழ்வின் பயனைத் தடம்மாற்றும் தவறுகள் என வள்ளுவர் சுட்டிக் காட்டியுள்ளார்.இலங்கு இழை மகளிர் பொலங் கலத்து ஏந்திய மணம் கமழ் தேறல் மடுப்ப நாளும் மகிழ்ந்து இனிது உறைமதி பெரும எனவும்சிறியகட் பெறினே எமக்கீயும் மன்னே பெரியகட் பெறினே யாம்பாடத் தான் மகிழ்ந்தது உண்ணும் மன்னேஎன்றும் கள்ளுண்டுகளித்தலையும், கள்ளுண்ணல் பெருமித வாழ்வாக இருந்த மரபுகளையும் பின்பற்றக் கூடிய ஒழுக்கமாய்க் காட்டும் வழக்கினை மாற்றி அதனைச் சமுதாயத் தீமையாக உரைத்தவர் வள்ளுவர்.”உண்ணற்க கள்ளை” என்றும் அது ”ஈன்றாள் முகத்தேயும் இன்னாதது” எனவும் ”நஞ்சுண்பார் கள் உண்பவர்” என்றெல்லாம் மது அருந்துதலின் தீமையை உணர்த்தித் தனிமனித வாழ்வு சிறக்கும் நெறியைக் காட்டியுள்ளார் வள்ளுவர் எனலாம்.புலால் உண்பது மனித நெறி அல்ல என்பது வள்ளுவரின் கருத்தாக உள்ளது. இன்றைய மனிதர்களின் உணவு முறையில் சைவ உணவே சிறந்தது என்பதை அறிவியல் ஆய்வுகள் மூலம் மேலைநாட்டு உணவியல் வல்லுனர்கள் தெளிவுபடுத்தியுள்ளனர். தெய்வப் புலவர் வள்ளுவர் ”புலால் மறுத்தல்” என்னும் அதிகாரத்துள் இரண்டாயிரம் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பே இதனை விளக்கமுறச் செய்துள்ளார்.கொல்லான் புலாலை மறுத்தானைக் கைகூப்பிஎல்லா உயிரும் தொழும்என்னும் குறட்பா மனிதன் உயர்வதற்கான வழியைக் காட்டுகிறது. இன்றைய தமிழக அரசு உயிர்க்கொலை, உயிர்ப் பலி கூடாது எனச் சட்டம் கொண்டு வந்துள்ள நிகழ்காலச் சூழலில் வள்ளுவரின் வாழ்வியல் நெறி வெற்றி பெற்றுள்ளதாகவே கருதலாம். அன்பு, பண்பு, நட்பு போன்ற வாழ்வியல் இலக்குகளை எளிய முறையில் மனித மனம் ஏற்கும் வகையில் உரைத்துத் தனி மனித வாழ்க்கையை வள்ளுவர் பண்படுத்தியுள்ளார்.அறநெறிப்பட்ட வாழ்க்கைமனித வாழ்க்கை ஒரு குறுகிய வட்டத்திற்குள் நின்றுவிடாமல் விரிந்து பரந்து முக்கியத்துவம் மிக்கதாக அமைய வேண்டும். மனித மனங்களை விரிவுபடுத்தி அறவழிப்பட்ட சமுதாயத்தை உருவாக்குவது திருக்குறளின் நோக்காகவும் உள்ளது.மனமாசின்றி வாழும் வாழ்க்கை சிறப்புடையது. அதுவே அறங்களில் முழுமை. மனித வாழ்க்கை நெறி என்கிறார்.மனத்துக்கண் மாசிலன் ஆதல் அனைத்தறன்ஆகுல நீர பிற.என்னும் குறட்பா இதனை உணர்த்துகிறது. அறம் என்பது பற்றிய இலக்கிய மரபுசார் கருத்தாக்கத்தை வள்ளுவர் மாற்றியமைக்கிறார்.அறமெனப்படுவது யாதெனக் கேட்பின் மறவாத இதுகேள் மன்னுயிர்க் கெல்லாம் உண்டியும் உடையும் உறையுளும் அல்லது கண்டது இல்என்னும் காப்பியக் கருத்தினை மறு ஆய்வு செய்து அறத்திற்குப் புதிய விளக்கங்களைத் தந்தவர் வள்ளுவர். மனத்தூய்மை, ஈகை, காதல் என்னும் தூயநெறிகளை வாழ்வியல் அறமாகக் கொள்ள வேண்டியதின் தேவையை உணர்த்தியுள்ளார்.வாய்மைதிருக்குறள் அன்பு, பண்பு, இன்சொல், நன்றியறிதல் என மனித மாண்புகளை விளக்குகிறது. இவற்றைப் பின்பற்றுவோர் பேற்றினையும் ஒதுக்கியவர் அடையும் இழிவினையும் திறம்படக் காட்டுகிறது. ”வாய்மை” என்பதே தலையாய அறம் என்கிறது வள்ளுவம். பொய்மை கோலோச்சும் இக்கால மனித சமுதாயத்திற்கு வள்ளுவர் கருத்துக்கள் மலர்ச்சியை உண்டாக்கும் மருந்தாகக் கொள்ளலாம். அறங்களில் எல்லாம் வாய்மையே சிறப்புடையது என்பதைபொய்யாமை பொய்யாமை ஆற்றின் அறம்பிறசெய்யாமை செய்யாமை நன்றுஎன்னும் குறட்பாவால் அறிய முடிகிறது.மும்மை அறம்மனிதர்களின் வாழ்க்கை நெறியை உயர்த்தும் கோட்பாடாக வள்ளுவம் மூன்று அறங்களைப் பின்பற்றுமாறு வலியுறுத்துகிறது.1. ஆன்மீக அறம்; 2. ஈதல் அறம்; 3. காதல் அறம்கடவுளை ”அறிவு, ஆற்றல், அப்பாற்பட்ட நிலை” என்றும் கருதுகோள் நிலையில் வைத்து மனித ஒருமைக்கும் சமுதாய அமைதிக்கும் வள்ளுவர் குறள் வழிக் குரல் கொடுத்துள்ளார். முதற் குறட்பாவில் ”உலகு” என நினைவூட்டி உலகளாவிய நேயத்தை மறைமுகமாக உணர்த்தியுள்ளார். கடவுளின் பெயரால், மதத்தின் பெயரால் சண்டையிட்டுக் கொள்ளும் மனிதனுக்கு, அவனது மனமாற்றத்திற்கு வள்ளுவம் ஒரு புதிய ஆன்மீக அறத்தை தந்துள்ளது. இதனை,வள்ளுவம் கடவுளை நம்புகிறது. ஆனால் அது ஆணும் அல்ல; பெண்ணுமல்ல. வள்ளுவம், காட்டும் கடவுளுக்குக் கோபுரங்கள், கோட்டைகள் இல்லை. வள்ளுவத்தின் கடவுளுக்குக் கணக்கும் இல்லை; வழக்கும் இல்லை. அது பேரறிவு; தூய்மையான அறிவு; குணங்களின் திருவுரு; இன்பத்தின் திருவுரு; அன்பின் திருவுரு; அறத்தின் அடையாளம்! என்னும் அறிஞர் கருத்தும் இதனைத் தெளிவுபடுத்தும்.ஈதலறம்மனிதப் பண்பினை உயர்த்தும் ஒரு நெறி ஈகை. பிறருக்குக் கொடுத்து மகிழும் மனம் பெற்றால் மனிதன் பக்குவம் அடைந்தவனாகிவிடுவான். போட்டியும், பொறாமையும் அடுத்தவர் பொருளைக் கவரும் எண்ணமும் மனிதனை மிருக நிலைக்குக் கொண்டு செல்லும். ஈகைக் குணம் ஒன்றே மனிதனை மாண்புடையவனாக்கும். வள்ளுவர் ஈகைக் குணமே உயிரின் ஊதியம் என்பர்.ஈதல் இசைபட வாழ்தல்; அதுவல்லஊதியம் இல்லை உயிர்க்குகொடுத்துப் புகழடையும் வாழ்க்கையே பயனுடைய வாழ்க்கை என்பதைக் குறள் உணர்த்துகிறது.காதலறம்காமத்துப்பால் அறவழிப்பட்ட காதலுறவுகளை எடுத்துரைத்துள்ளது. காதலையும், ஆண்-பெண் உறவையும் வள்ளுவர் நெறிப்படுத்தியுள்ளார். காமத்துப்பாலில் காதல், காதலர் உறவு நிலை ஆகியவற்றை இனிமை பயக்கப் பாடி, அன்பெனும் நெறிக்குள், மனங்களின் சங்கமத்திற்குள், மாசுபடாத வாழ்வியல் படிநிலையை வடித்துத் தந்துள்ளார். களவையும் கற்பையும் வகைப்படுத்தி ”மனிதம்” அடையும் வாழ்க்கை நெறியை வள்ளுவர் தந்துள்ளார்.பிறன்மனை நயத்தலையும், பரத்தையர் உறவையும், பெருங்குற்றமாகச் சொல்லி அன்புடைய காமத்தைச் சமுதாய அறமாகத் தந்துள்ளார்.ஆண் – பெண் சமனியம்ஆண் – பெண் உறவு நிலை, திருமணத்திற்கு முன்னும் பின்னுமாகக் காதல் நிலை ஆகிய செய்திகளைக் குறள் விரிவாகப் பேசுகிறது. ஆண் – பெண் சமத்துவம் வள்ளுவரின் கொள்கையாகக் காணப்படுகிறது.ஆண் மேலாதிக்க காலத்தில், அதற்கெதிரான, துணிவுடைய சிந்தனைகளை வழங்கியுள்ள வள்ளுவரின் அணுகுமுறை புரட்சிகரமானது. பெண்களின் உரிமைக்காகவும், உலகியல் மாற்றத்திற்காகவும் அவர் பாடுபட்டுள்ளார். பெண் ஆணுக்கு இணையானவள். ஆற்றல் மிக்கவள் என்பதை,சிறைகாக்கும் காப்பு எவன்செய்யும் மகளிர்நிறைகாக்கும் காப்பே தலை என்று ஆற்றலும் அறிவும் நிறையும் மிக்க பெண்களை உலகுக்கு உருவாக்கித் தந்தவர் வள்ளுவர் எனலாம். இத்தகைய வள்ளுவரின் வழிகாட்டல்தான் பிற்காலத்தில் பாவலன் பாரதியை ”வீட்டுக்குள்ளே பெண்ணைப் பூட்டி வைப்போமென்ற விந்தை மனிதர் தலை கவிழ்ந்தார்” என்று பாட வைத்தது எனலாம.சமுதாயக் கொடுமைகள்சாதி, மதத்தின் பெயரால் நிலவும் ஏற்றத்தாழ்வுகள் சமுதாயக் கொடுமைகள். இதனை மாற்ற வள்ளுவரின் குறட்பாக்கள் முனைந்துள்ளன. பிறப்பால் இனம் பிரித்த வருணாசிரம முறையை வள்ளுவம் எதிர்க்கிறது. பிறப்பால் அனைவரும் ஒன்றே என ஓங்கி ஒலிக்கிறது.பிறப்பொக்கும் எல்லா உயிர்க்கும்; சிறப்பொவ்வாசெய்தொழில் வேற்றுமை யான்என்னும் குறட்பா வள்ளுவரை ஒரு சமுதாயப் புரட்சியாளராக அடையாளம் காட்டுகிறது.பகுத்தறிவு நோக்குவள்ளுவரைத் தமிழ்கூறும் உலகில் தோன்றிய முதல் ”பகுத்தறிவாளர்” எனக் கூறலாம். எந்தவொரு கருத்தையும், சிந்தனையையும் உள்ளவாறு ஏற்காமல் பகுத்து நோக்கி, உள்ளத் தெளிவு பெற்று ஏற்க வேண்டும் என்பதே வள்ளுவர் கொள்கை.எப்பொருள் எத்தன்மைத் தாயினும் அப்பொருள்மெய்ப்பொருள் காண்பது அறிவுஎப்பொருள் யார்யார்வாய்க் கேட்பினும் அப்பொருள்மெய்ப்பொருள் காண்பது அறிவுஎன்னும் குறட்பாக்கள் இதற்குச் சான்றாகும்.மானுடத்தின் மலர்ச்சிவள்ளுவரின் நெம்புகோல் அடிகள் மானுடத்தின் மலர்ச்சி எனலாம். மரபுகளைத் தகர்த்துப் புதுமையை நிலை நிறுத்துவது வள்ளுவரின் சமுதாயப் பணியாக இருக்கிறது.அந்தணர் என்போர் அறவோர்முடிவுரை:அன்பின் வழியது உயிர்நிலைமனநலம் மன்னுயிர்க்குக் காக்கம்அறத்தால் வருவதே இன்பம்என்றெல்லாம் உயரிய சிந்தனைகளை வழங்கி மனித வாழ்க்கையை மலர்ச்சியடையச் செய்தவர் வள்ளுவர் ஒருவரே எனலாம்."},{"question":"வினா: கோவலன் கொலைக்களப் பட்ட இடம் ?","answer":"விடை: கோவலன் பொட்டல்"},{"question":"Viết 1 bài nghị luận xã hội khoảng 300 chữ nêu suy nghĩ của anh/chị về tình người trong hoạn nạn khó khăn trong tác phẩm vợ nhặt.","answer":" Truyện ngắn “Vợ nhặt” được xây dựng trên bối cảnh đời sống nói trên đã tái hiện chân thực nạn đói năm 1945. Từ bối cảnh đó, tác giả đi sâu miêu tả đời sống nhân dân nước ta. Những kiếp người bần cùng, khổ cực đang ngày đêm mong chờ, khát khao ánh sáng Cách Mạng. Rực sáng lên trong tác phẩm là vẻ đẹp tình người; trong đói khổ, thậm chí là kề cận bên cái chết, người ta vẫn cưu mang nhau.      Bối cảnh câu chuyện vô cùng ảm đạm. Dưới sự thống trị của thực dân Pháp và Nhật, năm 1945, hơn 2 triệu người dân Việt Nam đã bị chết đói. Sự kiện bi thảm này đã được đề cập tới trong nhiều tác phẩm của các nhà văn, nhà thơ như: Tô Hoài, Nam Cao, Nguyên Hồng,… Ngay sau sự kiện ấy, nhà văn Kim Lân đã viết tập truyền dài có nhan đề truyện “Xóm ngụ cư”.“Xóm ngụ cư’’ – nơi tập trung của những con người đói nghèo phải rời bỏ quê hương, đi tha phương cầu thực, mong tìm được miếng cơm manh áo là tiền thân của tác phẩm Vợ nhặt. Với nhan đề độc đáo này, Kim Lân đã gợi được sự quan tâm, chú ý của người đọc, đồng thời cũng làm nổi bật rõ được tư tưởng, chủ đề của truyện ngắn. Ở đây, từ “nhặt” vốn là một động từ đã được nhà văn sử dụng như một tính từ.     Chỉ qua nhan đề “Vợ nhặt” thôi, Kim Lân cũng nói lên được việc bế tắc, đen tối của xã hội và thân phận rẻ rúm của con người. Xưa nay, việc dựng vợ gả chồng là công việc của cả đời người. Thế nhưng vào thời điểm này, người ta có thể dễ dàng “nhặt” vợ, giống như là nhặt cái rơm cọng rác bên đường vậy.Nhà văn Kim Lân đã sáng tạo được một tình huống truyện độc đáo, mới lạ. Đó là tình huống nhân vật Tràng (con trai bà cụ Tứ) lấy vợ hay nói đúng hơn là nhặt được vợ: “giữa cái cảnh đói sầm lại vì đói khát ấy, một buổi chiều, người trong xóm bỗng thấy Tràng về với một người đàn bà nữa”. Việc dựng vợ gả chồng là một quy luật bình thường của cuộc sống con người. Nhưng đặt vào bối cảnh của Tràng thì lại là một chuyện lạ đời. Bởi lẽ Tràng là một anh nông dân nghèo, xấu trai, lại là dân ngụ cư. Nạn đói đang hoành hành dữ dội, người chết đầy đường đầy chợ. Trong khốn khó con người còn có thể nghĩ về nhau. Có lẽ chính tình huống truyện đặc sắc như trên đây đã giải thích vì sao nhà văn Kim Lân lại lấy nhan đề là “Vợ nhặt”. Qua cái nhan đề này, tác giả không chỉ nói lên là sự đen tối của xã hội cũ mà còn gợi lên được rất nhiều về hoàn cảnh, số phận người nông dân trong tác phẩm.      Tràng là nhân vật chính của truyện. Ngay từ đầu tác phẩm, tác giả Kim Lân đã dựng được bức tranh ảm đạm của làng quê Việt Nam vào thời kì đói kém. Từng đoàn người lũ lượt bồng bế, dắt díu nhau lên thành phố. Những bóng dáng xanh xám như những bóng ma. Hoặc là nằm ngổn ngang khắp lều chợ. Người chết đói như ngả rạ. Nhiều đến nỗi cứ đi làm đồng về, người ta lại bắt gặp ba, bốn cái thây nằm cong queo bên đường. Tiếng quạ gào lên từng hồi “thê thiết”. Không khí vẩn lên mùi khen khét của đống rấm, mùi thối của rác rưởi và mùi gây gây của xác người…Có thể nói vào thời điểm đó, không ai là không nghĩ đến cái chết. Ngay cả lũ trẻ con thường ngày vốn nghịch ngợm vô tư, giờ cũng ủ rũ không buồn nhúc nhích. Một hớp cháo cám nhạt cầm hơi lúc này cũng là niềm ước ao của chúng. Cuộc sống “tối sầm” lại vì đói khát và chết chóc. Cảnh trần gian mà cứ ngỡ như chốn địa ngục tối tăm.       Trong hoàn cảnh túng đói ngặt nghèo đấy, tình yêu, hạnh phúc cũng trở nên đượm màu chua chát, xót xa. Như anh Tràng – một thanh niên nhà nghèo xấu xí thậm chí còn có vẻ ngoài ngờ nghệch, dở hơi mà còn “nhặt” được vợ. Mà đúng là “nhặt được thật”. Anh hỏi vợ bằng mấy lời chọc ghẹo, bông đùa vu vơ. Bốn bát bánh đúc thay cho lễ cưới đơn sơ đến chua chát. Thế là Tràng được vợ. Quả thực, trong nạn đói, giá trị con người quá ư rẻ rúng.Ngày anh Tràng có vợ không bình thường nên buồn hay nên vui? Cảnh bữa cơm ngày đói đón nàng dâu mới thật thảm hại, tội nghiệp. Ai cũng thấy ngượng ngùng . Đuốc tân hôn, của đôi vợ chồng trẻ là ngọn đèn dầu yếu ớt. Cả nồi chè khoán (không phải nhà nào cũng có) của cụ bà Tứ trong thật tội nghiệp. Tràng ăn thấy đắng ngắt và nghẹn ứ trong cổ,…       Toàn những chi tiết cười ra nước mắt của một cảnh túng đói đến sâu sắc tội ác của bọn thực dân Pháp và phát xít Nhật. Mặc dù trong suốt cả truyện ngắn, đã không hề thấy bóng dáng của một tên thực dân hay phát xít nào. Thế nhưng tội ác của chúng vẫn hiện lên rất rõ nét. Việc lấy vợ của Tràng lại trở thành một sự kiện lớn của xóm ngụ cư nghèo. Tràng lấy vợ vào thời điểm khó khăn, cùng quẫn nhất. Khi mà người ta không biết có thể qua nổi cơn đói kém này không thì anh lại lấy vợ. Cái anh nông dân nghèo, xấu xí, dở hơi, lại là dân ngụ cư ấy lại lấy được vợ. Xóm ngụ cư chưa hết ngạc nhiên thì lại xót xa cho đôi vợ chồng trẻ ấy. Một cuộc gắn kết thầm lặng khiến ai cũng thấy ngậm ngùi, không biết nói gì hơn.        Qua “Vợ nhặt”, nhà văn đã tái hiện sâu sắc, chân thực xã hội Việt Nam vào thời kì đen tối, cùng quẫn nhất. Toàn bộ cuộc sống nghèo khổ, bế tắc của những người nông dân bị dồn đến bước đường cùng, không có lối thoát được dựng lại sinh động hết sức. Ngay từ đầu tác phẩm, tác giả đã hắt vào truyện thứ ánh sáng của hoàng hôn xám xịt. Theo bước chân Tràng từ phố chợ đến miền quê. Người chết rải rác nằm cong queo bên lề đường. Người sống thì đi lại dật dờ, mặt mày xanh xám như những bóng ma. Những đứa trẻ của xóm ngụ cư ngồi ủ rũ ở những xó đường không buồn nhúc nhích. Không khí vấy lên mùi ẩm thối. Trên cây gạo đầu làng tiếng quạ gào lên từng hồi thê thiết. Cả một vùng như biến thành bãi tha ma trong không gian đầy mùi tử thi. Một cõi dương có hơi ấm cõi âm.         Thời gian và không gian nghệ thuật là một tín hiệu thẩm mĩ đặc sắc. Nó báo rằng đó là thời điểm con người đang đứng ở ranh giới giữa ánh sáng và bóng tối, giữa trần gian với địa ngục. Cả dân tộc đang đứng trước hoàng hôn của cuộc đời, đứng mấp mé bên bờ vực thẳm. Điều đó cho thấy sự tàn phá ghê gớm của nạn đói, một hiện thực thê thảm.     Trong hoàn cảnh ấy, thân phận con người thật là bèo bọt. Người đàn bà Tràng gặp ngoài kho thóc quần áo rách tả tơi, thân hình gầy sọp vì đói. Người đàn bà này theo không Tràng mà chẳng còn chút sĩ diện, danh dự. Đó là một sự thật, một hiện thực mỉa mai, cay đắng mà cũng đầy xót xa. Thân phận con người chẳng khác gì cỏ rác. Mẹ con Tràng chỉ còn cháo cám cầm hơi. Nhà cửa chẳng khác gì gia cảnh của chị Dậu (Tắt đèn – Ngô Tất Tố). Họ đứng trước tương lai mờ mịt, nạn đói đang đe dọa đến sinh mạng. Đó là hiện thực về thân phận bọt bèo, hẩm hiu của người lao động trước Cách mạng. Theo bước chân Tràng, truyện mở ra một hiện thực thê thảm. Đó là một thế giới điêu tàn xác xơ vì sự phá hoại của nạn đói. Số phận cả dân tộc thật hắt hiu, buồn não.     Truyện ngắn “Vợ nhặt” còn mang một giá trị nhân đạo sâu sắc. Trong tác phẩm này, Kim Lân đã nói lên được nỗi khổ của người dân lao động. Ông bày tỏ nỗi niềm đồng cảm, chia sẻ với họ. Nhưng điều đáng quý nhất ở đây là nhà văn vẫn thấy trong những con người đáng thương ấy vẫn có đời sống tâm hồn phong phú, những phẩm chất tốt đẹp. Họ vẫn yêu thương, đùm bọc nhau trong cơn hoạn nạn. Giữa lúc khó khăn, đói kém nhất, việc anh Tràng cưu mang và nhận một cô gái về làm vợ. Trong khi cô gái có hoàn cảnh quần áo rách tả tơi, mặt gầy sọp hẳn đi vì đó. Đó là một cử chỉ cao thượng, hào hiệp, không phải ai cũng làm được.       Như vậy, cho dù luôn bị cái chết rình rập, đe dọa, phải sống như loài vật nhưng nó không thể dập tắt được cái phần rất con người ở Tràng, ở bà cụ Tứ cũng như người “Vợ nhặt”. Họ vẫn hướng tới tương lai, khát khao hạnh phúc của cuộc sống gia đình. Phát hiện, trân trọng và đề cao vẻ đẹp tình người trong nghịch cảnh khắc nghiệt có lẽ là điểm nổi bật của nhà văn, cái làm nên giá trị phi thường trong tác phẩm này."},{"question":"வினா: எடுத்துக்காட்டு உவமை அணியை விளக்கிக் கீழ்க்காணும் குறளுக்கு இவ்வணியைப் பொருத்தி எழுதுக.துஞ்சினார் செத்தாரின் வேறு அல்லர் எஞ்ஞான்றும்நஞ்சுஉண்பார் கள்உண் பவர்.","answer":"விடை:  எடுத்துக்காட்டு உவமை அணி. \\"துஞ்சினார் செத்தாரின் வேறு அல்லர் எஞ்ஞான்றும்நஞ்சுஉண்பார் கள்உண் பவர்.\\"அணிவிளக்கம் :உவமை ஒரு வாக்கியமாகவும் உவமேயம் ஒரு வாக்கியமாகவும் உவம உருபு மறைந்து வருவதால் எடுத்துக்காட்டு உவமை அணி எனப்படும்.உவமை : துஞ்சினார் செத்தாரின் வேறுஉவமேயம் : நஞ்சுஉண்பார் கள்உண் பவர்உருபு : மறைந்துள்ளது.பொருத்தம்:உறங்கியவர், இறந்தவரைவிட வேறுபட்டவர் அல்லர். அதுபோல கள் உண்பவரும் நஞ்சு உண்பவருக்குச் சமமே என்பதை விளக்குவதால் இப்பாடல் எடுத்துக்காட்டு உவமை அணி ஆகும்."},{"question":"クツワムシの語源であるクツワは、一般的にどんな動物に噛ませる器具のことでしょう？","answer":"馬"},{"question":"வினா:வினைத்தொகை சொற்களை  வாக்கிங்களில்   பொருத்தி எழுதுக. (வளர்தமிழ், விளைநிலம், குளிர்காற்று, விரிவானம், உயர்மதில், நீள்வீதி,  மூடுபனி, வளர்பிறை, தளிர் பூ)","answer":"விடை:• வளர்பிறை நிலவுடன் விரிவானம் அழகாகக் காட்சியளிக்கிறது.• தளிர்பூங்கொடிகளும், விளைநிலங்களும், மனதைக் கொள்ளையடிக்கின்றன.• நீள்வீதிகள் அனைத்தும் மூடுபனியில் மூழ்கிக் கிடக்கின்றன.• மெல்ல வீசும் குளிர்காற்றும் வளர்தமிழ் புகழ்பாடுகிறது.• தொலைவில் கலங்கரை விளக்கின் ஒளி உயர்மதில் சுவரை ஒளிரச் செய்கிறது."},{"question":"แนะนำขั้นตอนในการทำธุรกิจร้านอาหารให้หน่อย","answer":"ขั้นตอนในการทําร้านอาหาร1. ศึกษาข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับธุรกิจร้านอาหาร2. วางแผนธุรกิจและกําหนดเป้าหมาย3. กําหนดแผนการตลาด4. จัดทําแผนธุรกิจ5. จดทะเบียนธุรกิจ6. ออกแบบตกแต่งร้าน7. คัดเลือกวัตถุดิบ8. บริหารจัดการร้าน9. ฝึกอบรมพนักงาน10. ดูแลลูกค้า11. ประเมินผลการดําเนินงาน"},{"question":"ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਸਨਾ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਰੂਹਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਸ਼ਗਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਤੇਲ ਚੋਣ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਸਨਾ ਦਾ ਉੱਥੇ ਓਹੀ ਮੁਕਾਮ ਹੈ, ਜਿਹੜਾ ਇੱਥੇ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ’ਚ ਕਦੇ ਹੇਮਾ ਮਾਲਿਨੀ ਦਾ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਅੱਜ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦਾ ਹੈ। ਸਨਾ ’ਤੇ ਰੱਬ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ’ਚ ਸਾਇਮਾ ਤੇ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਮੀਰਾ ਦੀ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀ ’ਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਚੋਟੀ ਦੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਹੈ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਤੇ ਉਰਦੂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਦਿਲ ਬਣੀ ਸਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਵੀ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿਉਂ ਜੋ ਅਮਿਤੋਜ ਮਾਨ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਕਾਫ਼ਿਲਾ’ ’ਚ ਉਹ ਸੰਨੀ ਦਿਓਲ ਨਾਲ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਹੁਣ ਠਾਕਰ ਤਪੱਸਵੀ ਦੀ ਦਿਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸੀ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਨਾਲ ਪਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ’ਚ ਵੀ ਆ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਹ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਤੇਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਬਣ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਠਾਕਰ ਤਪੱਸਵੀ ਨੇ ਸਨਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਲ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਤਾਂ ਲਾਲ ਸੂਹੇ ਸ਼ਾਲੂ ’ਚ ਸੱਜਰੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਦੇ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਹੋ ਰਹੀ ਸਨਾ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ’ਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨਾ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਹੀ ਮਜ਼ੇਦਾਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਓਧਰਲੇ ਤੇ ਇਧਰਲੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ’ਚ ਕੋਈ ਫ਼ਰਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਲਿੱਪੀ ਦਾ ਫ਼ਰਕ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਜਾਂ ਫਿਰ ਵਾਹਗੇ ਵਾਲੀ ਚੰਦਰੀ ਲਕੀਰ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਦਿਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸੀ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ’ ਇਸੇ ਹੀ ਲਕੀਰ ਨੂੰ ਤੋੜਨ ਦਾ ਸੁਨੇਹਾ ਦੇ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਰੂਪ ਤੇ ਸੁਹੱਪਣ ਵਜੋਂ ਰਾਣੀ ਬਣ ਜਚਦੀ ਸਨਾ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਹੀਰੋ ਇੰਦਰਜੀਤ ਨਿੱਕੂ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਲੁਤਫ਼ ਉਠਾਇਆ। ਸਨਾ ਖੁਸ਼ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੇ ਅਕਸ਼ੈ ਕੁਮਾਰ, ਹਮ ਵਤਨ ਸਰਦਾਰ ਕਮਾਲ ਤੇ ਹਯਾ ਅਲੀ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਪਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੇ ਜਸਪਾਲ ਭੱਟੀ, ਸਰਦਾਰ ਸੋਹੀ, ਸੁਰਿੰਦਰ ਸ਼ਰਮਾ, ਹਰਮੀਤ ਗੋਰੀ  ਨਾਲ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਮੁਰਾਦ, ਅਸ਼ੋਕ ਪੁਰੀ ਤੇ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਕਪੂਰ ਜਿਹੇ ਮਹਾਰਾਥੀ ਕਲਾਕਾਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ‘ਦਿਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸੀ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ’ ’ਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੈ। ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ’ਚ ਝੱਲੀ ਹੋਈ ਸਨਾ ਇਸ ਦਾ ਸਿਹਰਾ ਠਾਕਰ ਤਪੱਸਵੀ, ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਡਾ. ਰਾਜ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਵੇਰਕਾ ਨੂੰ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ।ਸਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮੁਲਕ ਇਕਮਿੱਕ ਹੋਣ ਤੇ ਕਲਾਕਾਰਾਂ ਲਈ ਤਾਂ ਹੱਦਾਂ-ਸਰਹੱਦਾਂ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ। ਲਾਹੌਰ ਵਿਖੇ ਰਹਿ ਰਹੀ ਮੁਲਤਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਸਨਾ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਕੁਝ ਵਰ੍ਹਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ’ਚ ਹੈ। ਗਰੈਜੂਏਟ ਕੁੜੀ ਸਨਾ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਸੰਗਮ’ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ  ‘ਘਰ ਕਭ ਆਓਗੇ’ ਜ਼ਬਰਦਸਤ ਹਿੱਟ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਮੁਸਲਮਾਨ ’ਚ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਰਦਾਰਨੀ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਸੀ।ਪੀ.ਟੀ.ਵੀ. ਦੀ ਉਹ  ਖਾਸ ਸੈਲੇਬਰਿਟੀ ਹੈ।  ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ’ਚ ਅਕਸਰ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਕਰਨ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਸਨਾ ਹੁਣ ਤਕ ਦੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਤੋਂ ਸੰਤੁਸ਼ਟ ਹੈ। ਇਧਰ ਆ ਕੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਹੁਣਾਚਾਰੀ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਸਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਚਾਅ ਹੀ ਚੜ੍ਹ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਚੰਗੇ ਮੌਕੇ ਮਿਲੇ ਤਾਂ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਜਾਵੇਗੀ ਤੇ ਜੇ ਹੋਰ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ਾਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਹੱਸ ਕੇ ਸਵੀਕਾਰ ਕਰੇਗੀ। ਸਨਾ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਧੁਰੋਂ ਹੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਤੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੇਲ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ‘ਦਿਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸੀ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ’ ਉਸ ਲਈ ਰੂਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਿਲਣ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਸਨਾ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਸੀ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ  ਸਨਾ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਸੰਗਮ’ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"लक्षद्वीप समूह कोठे आहे?(A) अरबी समुद्रामध्ये(B) बंगालच्या उपसागरात(C) मन्नारचा आखात(D) कच्छच्या आखाती प्रदेशात=> ","answer":"(A) अरबी समुद्रामध्ये"},{"question":"Cho số 1,3765.  Làm tròn số này đến hàng phần nghìn ta được sốA. 1,377B. 1,376C. 1,3776D. 1,38","answer":"Trả lời:Số 1,3765 có chữ số hàng phần chục nghìn là 5 ≥ 5 nên làm tròn số này đến hàng phần nghìn ta được 1,3765 ≈ 1,377Đáp án cần chọn là: A"},{"question":"உலகில் மிகவும் பிரபலமான விளையாட்டு எது?","answer":"விடை: கால்பந்து"},{"question":"问题：三星公司的创始人是谁？","answer":"答案：三星公司的创始人是李秉喆（Lee Byung-chul）。"},{"question":"Aiza ho aiza ao an-trano no matetika ahitana ny fandriana ? ","answer":"Ao amin'ny efitra fatoriana no matetika ahitana ny fandriana ao amin'ny trano iray. "},{"question":"கேள்வி: சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பில் ஈரநிலங்களின் பங்கு என்ன, அவை ஏன் பாதுகாக்கப்பட வேண்டும்?","answer":"பதில்: அறிமுகம்சதுப்பு நிலங்கள் என்பது நிலம் நீரில் மூடப்பட்டிருக்கும் அல்லது நீர் தேங்கி இருக்கும் பகுதிகள். பல்வேறு வகையான தாவரங்கள், விலங்குகள் மற்றும் நீர்வாழ் உயிரினங்களுக்கு இது மிகவும் பயனுள்ள சூழலாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது. அவர்களுக்கு நீர் வழங்கல், விவசாயம் மற்றும் மீன்பிடி போன்ற பொருளாதார நன்மைகள் உள்ளன. பல்லுயிர் பெருக்கத்தை பராமரிப்பதில் ஈரநிலங்கள் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கின்றன, பல பறவைகள் மற்றும் விலங்குகள் அவற்றை சார்ந்துள்ளது. அவை வெள்ளக் கட்டுப்பாடு மற்றும் நிலத்தடி நீர் ரீசார்ஜ் ஆகியவற்றில் முக்கியப் பங்காற்றுகின்றன மேலும் அவை போன்ற நன்மைகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளன:நீர் ஆதாரமாக சதுப்பு நிலங்கள் - நன்னீர் முக்கியமாக ஈரநிலங்களில் இருந்து வருகிறது. அவை மழையை உறிஞ்சி நிலத்தடி நீரை நிரப்பவும், விவசாயம் மற்றும் குடிநீரை வழங்கவும் உதவுகின்றன.சதுப்பு நிலங்கள் வெள்ளம் மற்றும் புயல் தடுப்புகள் - அவை தண்ணீரை மெதுவாக மண்ணுக்குள் செலுத்துவதன் மூலம் தண்ணீரை விரைவாக உறிஞ்சுகின்றன.சதுப்பு நிலப் பொருட்கள்- நிலையான முறையில் நிர்வகிக்கப்படும் சதுப்பு நிலங்கள் பல்வேறு தாவரங்கள், விலங்குகள் மற்றும் கனிமங்களை வழங்குகின்றன. கரையோர ஈரநிலங்கள் மீன், அரிசி மற்றும் தேன் ஆகியவற்றை வழங்குகின்றன.பொழுதுபோக்கு மற்றும் சுற்றுலாவுக்கான ஈரநிலங்கள் - சதுப்பு நிலங்கள் அவற்றின் இயற்கை அழகு மற்றும் பலதரப்பட்ட தாவரங்கள் மற்றும் விலங்கினங்கள் காரணமாக சுற்றுலாவிற்கு கவர்ச்சிகரமான இடங்களாகும். ஆனால் பொறுப்பற்ற சுற்றுலா சதுப்பு நிலங்களுக்கு அதிக அழுத்தம் கொடுப்பதன் மூலம் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும்.சதுப்பு நிலங்கள் மற்றும் காலநிலை மாற்றம் - ஈரநிலங்கள் காலநிலை மாற்றத்தால் ஆபத்தில் உள்ளன, ஆனால் சில ஈரநிலங்கள் கார்பனைக் குறைக்கும் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் பசுமை இல்ல வாயுக்களை சேமிக்க முடியும். அவை தண்ணீரை உறிஞ்சி வைத்திருக்கின்றன, இது வெள்ளம் மற்றும் புயல்களைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த உதவுகிறது, காலநிலை மாற்றத்தை எதிர்ப்பதில் அவற்றை மதிப்புமிக்கதாக ஆக்குகிறது.புலம்பெயர்ந்த பறவைகளின் வாழ்விடமாக ஈரநிலங்கள் - துருவ மற்றும் மிதமான பகுதிகளில் கடுமையான குளிர்காலத்தைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்காக ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் சுமார் 2000 பறவை இனங்கள் ஆயிரக்கணக்கான மைல்கள் இடம்பெயர்கின்றன. சதுப்பு நிலங்கள் இந்த பறவைகள் இடம்பெயரும் போது ஓய்வெடுக்கவும், உணவளிக்கவும் மற்றும் இனப்பெருக்கம் செய்யவும் முக்கியமான இடமாகும். இந்திய ஈரநிலங்கள் மத்திய ஆசிய மற்றும் கிழக்கு ஆஸ்திரேலிய பறக்கும் பாதைகளை இணைக்கின்றன.இருப்பினும், பல ஆண்டுகளாக, மானுடவியல் நடவடிக்கைகள் இந்த ஈரநிலங்களின் இருப்புக்கு அச்சுறுத்தலை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளன. சதுப்பு நிலங்களுக்கு அச்சுறுத்தலை ஏற்படுத்தும் பல்வேறு காரணங்கள்:நகரமயமாக்கல் காரணமாக அதிகரித்த மாசு அளவு,பருவநிலை மாற்றம்,தீவிர மீன்வளர்ப்பு மற்றும் விவசாய நடவடிக்கைகளால் நீர்ப்பிடிப்பு சிதைவு,கட்டுப்பாடற்ற சுற்றுலா,அணைகள் கட்டுதல் போன்ற கட்டுமான நடவடிக்கைகளால் நீரியல் ஆட்சிகளில் மாற்றம்,தவறான கழிவு வெளியேற்றம்.ஈரநிலங்களை நோக்கிய இந்த அதிகரித்த அச்சுறுத்தல் காரணமாக, அவை காலப்போக்கில் சிதைந்து, அவற்றின் இருப்பை நம்பியிருக்கும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்பை பாதிக்கின்றன. கடந்த மூன்று தசாப்தங்களில் இந்தியா தனது இயற்கை ஈரநிலங்களில் கிட்டத்தட்ட 30 சதவீதத்தை இழந்துள்ளது. இந்தியா பல வகையான புலம்பெயர்ந்த பறவைகளின் தாயகமாக இருந்து வருகிறது, மில்லியன் கணக்கான புலம்பெயர்ந்த பறவைகள் இந்தியாவிற்கு வருகின்றன, மேலும் ஈரநிலங்கள் இந்த வருடாந்திர நிகழ்வுக்கு முக்கியமானவை. இந்திய ஈரநிலங்கள் இந்த புலம்பெயர்ந்த பறவைகளுக்கு தங்கும் இடங்களை வழங்குகின்றன, எனவே, இந்த ஈரநிலங்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதும், இந்த புலம்பெயர்ந்த பறவைகளின் வழியில் எந்த இடையூறும் ஏற்படாமல் இருப்பதை உறுதி செய்வதும் முக்கியம்.ஈரநிலப் பாதுகாப்புத் திட்டங்கள்இந்தியாவில் உள்ள சதுப்பு நிலங்களைப் பாதுகாக்க, சுற்றுச்சூழல், வனம் மற்றும் காலநிலை மாற்ற அமைச்சகம் ஈரநிலங்களின் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பண்புகளைப் பாதுகாக்க, நிர்வகிக்க மற்றும் பராமரிக்க உதவும் ஈரநில பாதுகாப்பு மற்றும் மேலாண்மை விதிகள், 2017 ஐ இயற்றியுள்ளது. கழிவுகளை வெளியேற்றுவது, திடக்கழிவுகளை கொட்டுவது போன்ற சதுப்பு நிலங்களை நீடிக்காமல் பயன்படுத்துவதை விதிகள் தடை செய்கின்றன. விதிகள் புத்திசாலித்தனமான பயன்பாட்டுக் கொள்கையை ஊக்குவிக்கின்றன, அதாவது அவற்றைப் பாதுகாக்கும் போது நிலையான பயன்பாடு.மத்திய மற்றும் மாநிலம்/யூனியன் பிரதேசங்களுக்கிடையில் செலவினப் பகிர்வு அடிப்படையில் செயல்படுத்தப்படும் இந்தியாவில் ஈரநிலங்களின் மேலாண்மைக்கான மத்திய நிதியுதவித் திட்டமான நீர்வாழ் சுற்றுச்சூழல் பாதுகாப்புக்கான தேசியத் திட்டத்தை (NPCA) அமைச்சகம் நிறைவேற்றி செயல்படுத்தி வருகிறது. அரசாங்கங்கள். இத்திட்டம் சதுப்பு நிலங்களை மீட்டெடுப்பதை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது, இதனால் நீரின் தரம் மேம்படும் மற்றும் பல்லுயிர் மேம்பாடு உள்ளது. அதன் நோக்கத்தை அடைய, ஈரநிலங்கள் புத்துயிர் அளிக்கும் திட்டத்தை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது. நிரல் அணுகுமுறை:ஈரநில சுருக்க ஆவணத்தை உருவாக்குதல்உள்ளூர் பங்குதாரர்களை உள்ளடக்கிய குடிமக்களின் பங்கேற்பை அதிகரிக்க ஈரநில மித்ராஸ்ஈரநில சுகாதார அட்டை, ஈரநில நிலையை கண்காணிக்கவும் கண்காணிக்கவும் உதவும்பல்லுயிர், சுற்றுச்சூழல் சேவைகள், மதிப்புகள் மற்றும் அச்சுறுத்தல்களை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதை உள்ளடக்கிய ஒரு ஒருங்கிணைந்த மேலாண்மை திட்டத்தை உருவாக்குதல்.நாடு முழுவதும் உள்ள 1000 சதுப்பு நிலங்களுக்கு புத்துயிர் அளிக்க இந்த திட்டம் திட்டமிட்டுள்ளது. பல்லுயிர் மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கான ஈரநிலப் பாதுகாப்பை உறுதி செய்வதற்காக இந்தியா பயனுள்ள சட்ட மற்றும் கொள்கை நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுத்துள்ளது. சதுப்பு நிலங்களுக்கு தொடர்ந்து அச்சுறுத்தல் இருப்பதால், இந்த சதுப்பு நிலங்களை பாதுகாப்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கதாக மாறியுள்ளது.ஈரானின் ராம்சார் நகரில் 1971 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஈரானின் மாநாடு என்று அழைக்கப்படும் ஒரு அரசுகளுக்கிடையேயான ஒப்பந்தம் ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளப்பட்டதால் பிப்ரவரி 2 ஆம் தேதி ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் உலக ஈரநில தினமாக கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது. இந்த மாநாடு நாடுகள் தங்கள் ஈரநிலங்களைப் பாதுகாப்பதற்கும் அவற்றை புத்திசாலித்தனமாகப் பயன்படுத்துவதற்கும் நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்க உதவுகிறது. சர்வதேச முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்த ஈரநிலங்கள் தொடர்பான ராம்சார் மாநாட்டின் கீழ் ராம்சர் தளங்கள் சர்வதேச முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்தவை. பிப்ரவரி 1, 1982 அன்று நடந்த மாநாட்டில் இந்தியா ஒரு கட்சியாக மாறியது. இந்தியாவில் ஏராளமான சதுப்பு நிலங்கள் உள்ளன, தற்போது 75 ராம்சார் தளங்கள் தெற்காசியாவில் ஈரநிலங்களின் மிகப்பெரிய வலையமைப்பாக உள்ளது."},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ilay manda fiarovana malaza naorina tany Shina mba hiarovana amin'ny fanafihana? ","answer":"Ny \\"Rindrina Lehiben'i Shina\\" no anaran'ilay manda fiarovana malaza naorina tany Shina."},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity.Fanambarana: \\"Nisy naka indray ny sakafoko tao anaty vata fampangatsiahana!\\"","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho hatezerana. Maneho hatezerana ilay olona satria nangalatra tao anaty vata fampangatsiahana ny sakafony atoandro."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的室內劇場是哪個？","answer":"答案：希臘的古代戲劇劇場"},{"question":"Qui était le compositeur Anton Bruckner ?","answer":"Anton Bruckner, le compositeur autrichien, est célèbre pour ses symphonies monumentales qui capturent la grandeur et la profondeur spirituelle de l'époque romantique. Ses symphonies, souvent remarquables par leurs structures expansives et leurs mélodies envoûtantes, mettent en évidence son dévouement aux thèmes sacrés et sa fascination pour l'architecture. Les compositions notables de Bruckner, telles que la \\"Symphonie n° 4\\" (surnommée \\"Romantique\\") et la \\"Symphonie n° 8\\", explorent l'interaction entre le monde terrestre et divin, invitant les auditeurs à entreprendre des voyages spirituels profonds à travers sa musique."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፡- አንደኛው የዓለም ጦርነት የጀመረው በየትኛው ዓመት ነው?","answer":"መልስ፡- 1914 ዓ.ም"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය උපුටාගෙන ඇත්තේ කුමන ටෙලි නාට්‍යයකින්ද?වන සිව්පාවුන් වැනි මිනිසුන් මැදදෙවි දේවතාවුන් වැනි මිනිසුන් ඇතඒ දේවතාවන් දිව්‍යාංගනාවන්මනු ලෝ තලයේ වාසනාවන්වල්මත් වූවන් දැක මහ වන මැදයා යුතු මාවත පෙන්වාඒ දෙස බලමින් සැනසෙන මිනිසුන්ඉටු දෙවියන් ලොව සිටිනාකඳුළු සලන්නන් කඳුළින් ගොඩ ගෙනමුවගේ හසරැළි රඳවාතුටු කඳුළින් නෙතු සරසන දෙවියන්පුද දෙමු දෙවොලට කැඳවා","answer":"ගීතය උපුටාගෙන ඇත්තේ රේඛා ටෙලි නාට්‍යයෙනි."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Trưa 31/7, Trạm CSGT Đa Phước thuộc Phòng Cảnh sát Giao thông đường bộ đường sắt (PC08) Công an TPHCM và cơ quan chức năng huyện Bình Chánh đang điều tra, làm rõ nguyên nhân vụ tai nạn giữa ô tô biển xanh và xe đầu kéo container xảy ra trên đường Nguyễn Văn Linh. Trước đó, khoảng 2h30 cùng ngày, ô tô mang biển","answer":"kiểm soát xanh 80B... do một tài xế (chưa rõ danh tính) điều khiển lưu thông trên đường Nguyễn Văn Linh, hướng từ huyện Bình Chánh về quận 7. Hiện trường vụ tai nạn. Lúc xe qua khỏi khu dân cư Dương Hồng, xã Bình Hưng (huyện Bình Chánh) khoảng 100 mét thì tông mạnh vào đuôi xe đầu kéo container đang dừng ven đường để vá lốp. Vụ va chạm khiến phần đầu của xe ô tô con bể nát, hư hỏng nặng. Hiện chưa rõ thương vong sau vụ tai nạn. Phần đầu xe ô tô biển xanh biến dạng sau vụ tai nạn. Nhận được tin báo, Trạm CSGT Đa Phước cùng cơ quan chức năng huyện Bình Chánh đã đến xử lý hiện trường và điều tra nguyên nhân tai nạn."},{"question":"Про яку подію йдеться у тексті: Расінський десант — морський тактичний десант, здійснений радянським Тихоокеанським флотом в часі радянсько-японської війни.","answer":"Про радянсько-японську війну."},{"question":"O ṣẹlẹ, awọn kan ti lọọ ta ilẹ ooṣa n’Ibadan o","answer":"Iwure ati etutu lawọn ẹlẹsin abilẹ n’Ibadan n fi gbogbo igba ṣe bayii lati pẹtu si awọn alálẹ̀ ilẹ Ibadan ninu pẹlu bi awọn ọmọ abulẹṣowo ṣe ta ilẹ ooṣa to jẹ ti gbogbo ọmọ ilu naa.Ibi kan laduugbo Àwọ́tàn, lagbegbe Apẹtẹ, n’Ibadan, nibi ti Lágelú, ẹni to tẹ ilu Ibadan do wọlẹ si ni wọn n pe nilẹ ooṣa yii. Lẹyin ipapoda baba nla awọn ọmọ Ibadan yii lawọn agbaagba ilu ya ibẹ sọtọ gẹgẹ bii ilẹ ọ̀wọ̀, eyi ti gbogbo ọmọ Ibadan mọ si Ojúbọ Lágelú, to si jẹ pe lọdọọdun ni wọn maa n lọ sibẹ lati wure fun alaafia ati idagbasoke ilu nla yii.Ilẹ ọhun ni wọn lawọn ajagungbalẹ̀ n’Ibadan ti ta yii.  Bi wọn ba ta a fẹni to mọ nipa aṣa atiṣe ilẹ Ibadan, ṣe iba san, ọmọ Ibo ni wọn talẹ̀ ooṣa ọhun fun, iyẹn si ti n kọle nla kan sibẹ lọwọ bayii.L’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, to kọja, nigba tawọn oniṣẹṣe lọ si ojubọ yii fun eto Ayajọ Iṣẹṣe to maa n waye lọdọọdun l’Ojubọ Lagelu, ṣugbọn si iyalẹnu wọn, ile nla kan ti lalẹ hu nile oriṣa naa.Eyi lo mu ki awọn agbaagba idile Lagelu rawọ ẹbẹ si Olubadan ilẹ Ibadan, Ọba Saliu Akanmu Adetunji, ati igbimọ awọn agbaagba ilẹ Ibadan lati wa nnkan ṣe sọrọ awọn to maa n talẹ onilẹ n’Ibadan wọnyi.Lara awọn to ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ yii gẹgẹ bii adari idile Lagelu ni Mọgaji idile naa, Oloye Lamidi Tiamiyu; agbẹnusọ fun idile Lagelu, Ọgbẹni Lukman Babalọla, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Ita Ẹgẹ ati Oloye Bamidele Ẹlẹrẹ Ogunjẹngbọran Ṣiyanmade to jẹ abọrẹ ojubọ Lagelu.Oloye Ṣiyanmade ti i ṣe, abọrẹ Ojubọ Lagelu ṣapejuwe iṣẹlẹ yii gẹgẹ bii iwọsi nla ati ẹgbin oniyọrọ fun ilu Ibadan, pẹlu bo ṣe jẹ pe ọga awọn ajagungbalẹ yii, ẹni ti ki i tun un ṣe ọmọ Ibadan, tun lori laya, o tun gba ki ẹni to ta ilẹ yii fun kọrukọ ẹ gadagba gadagba si ara pako pelebe kan lẹgbẹẹ ilẹ naa.O waa rọ Ọba Adetunji lati kilọ fun olori awọn talẹ̀talẹ̀ Ibadan yii, ẹni ta a forukọ bo laṣiiri, lati ṣọra ẹ gidigidi, bi ko ba fẹẹ fori gbe ẹru ti ko ni i le rori gbe."},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 石川県珠洲市やその近くでは、今月5日に大きな地震がありました。そのあとも地震が続いています。","answer":"珠洲市にある保育園は、子どもが安全に避難できるように、地震のときにしなければならないことを保育士たちとチェックしました。 園長は保育士に、地震のときは、まず自分や子どもがけがをしないようにして、それから子どもを広い部屋に連れていくように言いました。そして、保育園の近くの避難場所やそこへ行く道を知っておくように言いました。避難場所や道は、保育園の全部の部屋に地図を貼って、いつも見ることができるようにしています。 園長は「保育士が落ち着いて、大事な子どもを守ることができるように、しっかり準備しています」と話しました。"},{"question":"Responde a la siguiente pregunta. quien jugó a Uhura en el Star Trek original","answer":"La respuesta es la siguiente: Nichelle Nichols "},{"question":"Raha voalaza fa tratran'ny pogonophobia ny olona iray, inona ny zavatra atahorany izany ? ","answer":"Ny pogonophobia dia ny tahotra ny volom-bava, ka raha voalaza fa tratran'ny pogonophobia ny olona iray dia midika izany fa matahotra volom-bava izy. "},{"question":"మొదటి 10 సహజ సంఖ్యల వ్యాప్తి ఎంత ?","answer":"వ్యాప్తి = 10 -1 = 9"},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Saint-Vincent-et-les-Grenadines nékk","answer":"Réwum Saint-Vincent-et-les-Grenadines mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Amerique"},{"question":"\\"என்டேயுமுள்ள தேன் தமிழ்\\" என்பது யாரின் அறிக்கையாகும்?","answer":"இது கம்பரின் அறிக்கையாகும். "},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧਕ ਦਿਵਾਲੀਆ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਕੰਪਨੀ ਦਾ ਸਟਾਕ ਵੇਚ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਖਰਾਬ ਕਰ ਲਈ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਖਰਾਬ ਕਰ ਲਈ।"},{"question":"Чон Чжун Мён менен канчанчы орунду ээледи?","answer":"Пак 2014-жылы Түштүк Кореянын атынан кышкы Олимпиада оюндарына катышкан. Чон Чжун Мён менен мушташып, 18-орунду ээледи. Ал ошондой эле Түштүк Кореянын эстафета командасы 12-орунду ээледи."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kena-kena seperti santan bergula, tak kena-kena bagai antan pukul kepala'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sesuatu perkataan itu kalau bersalahan tafsirannya jadi melarat, jika benar jadi kebajikan"},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: An san Qatar da arzikinta saboda yawan albarkatun mai da iskar gas. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: GaskiyaEh, wannan magana gaskiya ce. Kasar Qatar dai ta shahara da dimbin arzikin da take da shi, musamman saboda dimbin arzikin man fetur da iskar gas da take da su, wadanda ke da muhimmanci wajen tafiyar da tattalin arzikin kasar da ci gabanta."},{"question":"Soomaalida ma Carab baa mise Afrikan?","answer":"Soomaalida Carab maahan Afrikan neh maahan."},{"question":"Nola eragiten du teknologia digitalak musika industrian, artista eta entzuleen arteko harremanean?","answer":"Teknologia digitalak musika eskuragarriagoa egin du, artista eta entzuleen arteko harreman zuzena sortuz. Streaming zerbitzuak eta sare sozialak musikarien lanak zabaldu eta komunikazioa erraztu dute."},{"question":"昭和４７年に『パチンコ』という作品でデビューした、タレントとしても活躍する漫画家は誰でしょう？","answer":"蛭子能収"},{"question":"Was für Software gibt es, um mit Kollegen zu chatten?","answer":"Es gibt diverse Anbieter, die Lösungen für digitale Unterhaltungen mit Kollegen anbieten. Populäre Produkte sind hierbei das von Microsoft angebotene \\"Teams\\", sowie die Lösung \\"Slack\\" der gleichnamigen Firma. Google bietet mit \\"Google Chat\\" ebenfalls eine eigene Lösung an. Als Alternative für Self-Hosting ist zudem noch die Open Source Software \\"Rocket Chat\\" erwähnenswert."},{"question":"Iza no atao hoe mpampianatra?","answer":"Ny mpampianatra dia ireo olona afaka manome fahalalana sy fahaizana  ho an'ny mpianany ka manana traikefa  sy nanaraka fiofanana manokana ny amin'izany fampianarana izany."},{"question":" Sheeg Sanadkii la qoray farta Soomaaliya?","answer":"Waxaa la qoray 12 October 1972"},{"question":"Kodi kugona kuyambira 10pm madzulo mpaka 4am m'mawa ndi bwino?","answer":"Palibe chinthu ngati \\"nthawi yokhazikika kapena yabwino\\" yogona yomwe ingagwirizane ndi anthu onse. Nthawi zambiri zimakhala bwino kugona pakati pa 10 koloko mpaka pakati pausiku chifukwa kwa anthu ambiri ndi pamlingo wokomera kugona kwa wina aliyense."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഗണിത ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: വർദ്ധിച്ചുവരുന്ന ക്രമത്തിൽ ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന സംഖ്യകൾ ക്രമീകരിക്കുക: 5, 9, 2, 7, 3.","answer":"ഉത്തരം: 2, 3, 5, 7, 9 എന്നത് വർദ്ധിച്ചുവരുന്ന ക്രമത്തിലുള്ള സംഖ്യകളുടെ ക്രമീകരണമാണ്."},{"question":" एक ज़िम्मेदार नागरिक की कहानी लिखें, जो अपने समाज में सकारात्मक परिवर्तन लाने के लिए संकल्पित है।","answer":"वह केवल एक नागरिक नहीं हैं जो सिर्फ अपने समाज में प्रभाव डालने के लिए निरंतर प्रयत्नशील रहते हैं, बल्कि उन्होंने अनेक सामाजिक मुद्दों का समाधान ढूंढने के लिए भी काम किया है। उनका योगदान समाज में सकारात्मक परिवर्तन लाने में बहुत महत्त्वपूर्ण है।"},{"question":"Ọmọ ọdun mẹẹẹdogun dero ẹwọn, nitori akẹkọọ ẹgbẹ ẹ to lu pa l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Igbẹjọ waye lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu kẹfa yii, lori ọmọdekunrin kan tọjọ ori ẹ ko ju mẹẹẹdogun lọ, ẹni ti wọn lo lu akẹkọọ bii tiẹ to jẹ obinrin pa, nitori pe o fẹẹ ba a dọrẹẹ, tiyẹn ko gba, iyẹn loṣu keji, ọdun yii. Kootu Majisreeti ti ju u sẹwọn oṣu kan gbako titi ti amọran yoo fi ti ọdọ DPP to n gba kootu nimọran wa.Adajọ Dẹhinde Dipẹolu lo gbọ ẹjọ ọmọkunrin naa, ko gba ipẹ rẹ rara, niṣe lo ni ki wọn gbe e lọ sọgba ẹwọn awọn ọmọde ti wọn n pe ni Boaster, eyi to wa niluu Abẹokuta.Ohun to ṣẹlẹ gan-an ti ọmọkunrin to jẹ akẹkọọ nileewe Reverend Kuti Memorial Grammar School, l’Abẹokuta, naa fi foju bale-ẹjọ ni pe o nawọ ifẹ sọmọbinrin tọjọ ori tiẹ ko ju mẹrinla lọ.Ọmọbinrin naa ko gba fun un bo ti daamu ẹ to, nigba to si pẹ to ti n ba a sọ ọ tiyẹn ko gba lo sọ ọ dija mọ ọmọbinrin ọhun lọwọ, niṣe lo dọdẹ ẹ, to si fi lulu ṣe ọmọ naa leṣe, iyẹn lọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu keji, ọdun yii.Lilu to lu akẹkọọ-binrin ọmọ ileewe Nawair-ud-deen naa pọ to bẹẹ to jẹ ijamba ti ṣe e ninu ara, ṣugbọn kaka kọmọ naa sọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ fawọn obi rẹ, ko tete sọ, niṣe lo n mu inira to n koju mọra.Nigba ti inira naa pọ, ọmọdebinrin yii ṣalaye ohun to ṣẹlẹ fawọn obi rẹ, wọn gbe e lọ sọsibitu Jẹnẹra, Ijaye, l’Abẹokuta kan naa fun itọju.Awọn t’Ijaye tọju ẹ titi, apa wọn ko ka a, ni wọn ba ni ki wọn maa gbe e lọ si FMC, n’Idi-Aba, nibẹ lọmọge naa si pari ẹ si, to dagbere faye.Ọrọ yii di wahala, wọn mu ọmọkunrin to fẹẹ fagidi yan an lọrẹẹ yii, wọn si ti wa lẹnu ẹ ki kootu too lọ si isinmi iyanṣẹlodi wọn.Bi wọn ṣe de pada ni wọn gbọ ẹjọ naa, Adajọ si paṣẹ pe ọmọde to daran ipaniyan yii ko gbọdọ fi oju ba ode titi di ọgbọn ọjọ si asiko ta a wa yii, nigba ti DPP to n gba kootu nimọran yoo ti ri nnkan sọ lori ẹjọ to n jẹ."},{"question":"Inona no sivilizasiona fahiny nanorina ny piramidan’i Sumer, iray amin’ireo tanàna lehibe voalohany teo amin’ny tantara, tany Mezopotamia?","answer":"Ny sivilizasiona Sumerianina fahiny no nanorina ny piramidan'i Sumer tany Mezopotamia."},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra ny \\"Hamlet\\", loza nalaza tamin'ny teatra anglisy?","answer":"\\"Hamlet\\" dia nosoratan'i William Shakespeare."},{"question":"在早餐时从来不吃的是什么","answer":"答案：午餐和晚餐"},{"question":"Sheeg sanadkii la aasaasay Jabhaddii USC iyo dalkii lagu aasaasay","answer":" Waxaa la aasaasay sanadkii 1989kii, waxaana lagu aasaasay dalka Talyaaniga"},{"question":"పొగాకును పూర్తిగా నిషేధించిన ప్రపంచంలో మొదటి దేశం ఏది?","answer":"పొగాకును పూర్తిగా నిషేధించిన ప్రపంచంలో మొదటి దేశం భూటాన్. భూటాన్ రాజ్యం దక్షిణాసియాలోని భూపర్యవేష్టిత (ల్యాండ్ లాక్) దేశం. ఇది హిమాలయాల తూర్పు వైపు ఆఖరు భాగంలో హిమాలయ పర్వత శ్రేణుల మధ్య ఉంది. పొగాకు వినియోగంతోపాటు వివిధ రకాల ఉత్పత్తుల్నీ నిషేధించిన మొట్టమొదటి దేశంగా భూటాన్ చరిత్ర సృష్టించింది."},{"question":"Ang pagdaragdag ng mga numero sa pagitan ng 1 hanggang 100 na magkakasunod (1+2+3+4+…) ay magbibigay sa iyo ng anong huling sagot?","answer":"5050"},{"question":"விஜய் ஹசாரே கோப்பை எந்த விளையாட்டு உடன் தொடர்புடையது .1)கால்பந்து2)ஹாக்கி3)கிரிக்கெட்4)டென்னிஸ்","answer":"விடை -  3) கிரிக்கெட்விஜய் அசாரே கோப்பை ரஞ்சிக் கோப்பை ஒருநாள் போட்டி என்றும்  அழைக்கப்படுகிறது . இந்த கிரிக்கெட் தொடரானது குறைந்த பட்ச ஓவர்களைக் கொண்டு விளையாடப்படும் ஒரு உள்ளூர்ப் போட்டித் தொடர் ஆகும் .இதில் ரஞ்சிக் கோப்பையில் விளையாடும் அணிகள் இந்த கிரிக்கெட் தொடரில் விளையாடுகின்றன. இது 2002- 2003 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதலாக விளையாடப்பட்டு வருகிறது."},{"question":"Miten pogostantauti todetaan?","answer":"Taudin akuuttivaiheessa otetusta verikokeesta voidaan todeta Sindbis-viruksen vasta-aineita, mutta joskus vasta-aineita ilmaantuu myöhemmin, vasta sairauden toisella viikolla. Tavallisesti otetaan kaksi verinäytettä 1–2 viikon välein, jos pogostantautia epäillään."},{"question":" Sheeg Isbitaalkii ugu Horeeyey ee Soomaaliya Ku yaala oo Wiish lagu Koray?  ","answer":" Isbitaalkii ugu Horeeyey ee Somaliya Ku yaala oo Wiish lagu Koray wuxu ahaa Isbitaalka Digfeer."},{"question":"Apakah teh ais?","answer":"Teh ais adalah satu bentuk teh sejuk, sering disajikan dalam gelas dengan ais. Ia mungkin atau mungkin tidak manis. Teh ais adalah juga satu minuman bungkus yang popular. Ia boleh dicampurkan dengan berperisa sirap, dengan perisa biasa termasuk lemon, pic, raspberi, limau, dan ceri.Selain teh sebenar, herba-herba lain adalah juga kadang-kadang disajikan dengan sejuk dan dirujuk sebagai teh ais (herba). Teh ais tidak manis kadangkala dibuat oleh satu rendaman daun teh panjang pada suhu yang lebih rendah (sejam dalam matahari lawan 5 minit pada 80-100°C). Tambahan juga, kadangkala ia adalah juga dibiarkan untuk semalaman di dalam peti sejuk."},{"question":"\\"අතේ තිබුනු රන් සුලැඟිලි තණ්ඩිය අත්තෙං අත්තට මාරු වෙනා\\"මෙහි තණ්ඩිය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"මෙහි නියම වචනය තණ්ඩිය ( දණ්ඩ යන්නෙන් ආවකි) යන්නයි. දණ්ඩ, කඳ ,ලීය එහි අරුතයි.බාලදක්ෂයින් ලෙස පුහුණු වූ අය දන්නවා ඇති ඔවුන්ට තණ්ඩි ගැටය නම් ගැටයක් උගන්වන බව. එය ගස් කපන්නන් භාවිත කරනා ගැටයක්. ඔවුන් එයට කියන්නේ කඳන් ගැටය කියායි.මේ සුළඟිලි තණ්ඩිය කියවෙන්නේ ගීතයකයි. එහි එන ආකාරයට අර්ථය දෙල් කැඩීමට ගන්නා සුළඟිල්ලක් තරම් හීන් ලීය.කලවාවලටද තණ්ඩිය යයි කියන අය ඇත. එය කඳ කලවා යන යෙදුමටම සමානය."},{"question":"పరజీవ భక్షక జీవులు జీవ నియంత్రణకారులుగా ఎలా పనిచేస్తాయి?","answer":"ఆకులు, ముళ్ళు లేని నిర్మాణం కలిగిన పియర్ కాక్టస్ మొక్కలను 1920లో ఆస్ట్రేలియాలో ప్రవేశపెట్టారు. ఫలితంగా అది అతివేగంగా అభివృద్ధి చెంది మిలియన్ల హెక్టార్ల భూమి (సహజ గడ్డిభూములు)లో వ్యాపించి అస్థవ్యస్థ పరిస్థితి కలిగించింది. చివరకు అపాయకరంగా వ్యాపిస్తున్న కాక్టస్ ను నియంత్రించడానికి కాక్టస్ను ఆహారంగా తీసుకొనే పరభక్షి (మిడత)ను ఆ ప్రదేశంలో ప్రవేశపెట్టారు. తరువాత పరిస్థితి చక్కబడింది.ఆహార జీవి జనాభాను నియంత్రించే భక్షక జీవుల సామర్థ్యాన్ని ఆధారంగా చేసుకొని వ్యవసాయ చీడల నియంత్రణలో జీవ నియంత్రణ పద్ధతులను వినియోగిస్తున్నారు."},{"question":"Oluwoo ki i ṣe apẹẹrẹ ọba ilẹ Yoruba to ṣee mu yangan, wọn ko ba Ifa sọrọ ki wọn too yan an- Ẹlẹbuubọn","answer":"Araba tilu Oṣogbo, Oloye Ifayẹmi Ẹlẹbuibọn, ti sọ pe ti wọn ba n wa ọba kan ti ko ni oye kankan rara nipa aṣa ati iṣe ilẹ Yoruba to ti jọba, Oluwoo tilu Iwo, Ọba Abdulrosheed Akanbi, ni.Nitori naa ni agbarijọpọ awọn oniṣẹṣe labẹ Iṣọkan Ọrunmila ṣe kilọ fun Ọba Akanbi lati jawọ ninu awọn iwa titẹ aṣa Yoruba mẹrẹ ko ma baa kandin ninu iyọ.Lasiko ipejọpọ ọlọjọ kan ti wọn pe ni ‘Ofa Unity Conference’, eyi to waye niluu Oṣogbo laipẹ yii ni Oloye Ẹlẹbuibọn ti sọ pe ko si ọba ti ko ni nnkan an ṣe pẹlu aṣa Yoruba, nitori Ifa lo n yan ọba sipo.O ni Oluwoo ki i ṣe apẹẹrẹ ọba ilẹ Yoruba to ṣee muyangan nitori wọn ko ba Ifa sọrọ ki wọn too yan an le awọn ara ilu rẹ lori. O ni eleyii si ti mu ifasẹyin nla ba ipo ori-ade ilu Iwo latigba to ti debẹ.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, gbogbo ilu nilẹ Yoruba ni wọn ni iledii (seclusion room), nibi ti wọn maa n fi ẹni ti Ifa ba mu pe ko jọba pamọ si fun iwọn ọjọ diẹ, nibẹ naa ni yoo si ti kọ nipa aṣa ati iṣe ilẹ Yoruba, ṣugbọn o ṣe ni laaanu pe Oluwoo ko lanfaani si iru igbesẹ bẹẹ.Fun un lati maa ṣiwa-hu nipasẹ ọlaju, Baba Ẹlẹbuibọn sọ pe eleyii fi han gbangba pe aaye nla ṣi silẹ niluu Iwo. O ni “O ṣee ṣe ko jẹ pe gbogbo awọn afọbajẹ atawọn ijoye ibẹ ti di Musulumi tabi Kristiẹni tan.“O tun n fọwọ sọya pe gomina kan lo sọ oun di ọba, ki i ṣe Ifa, o daju pe idi niyẹn to fi n huwa bo ṣe n huwa. Ara awọn ipenija ti ọlaju ati ẹsin ilẹ okeere mu ba ipo lọbalọba nilẹ Yoruba niyẹn, paapaa, bi awọn ti a gbe aṣa le lọwọ gan-an ṣe ti n ku.“Ko si ifagba-fun-agba mọ laarin awọn lọbalọba, o si gbọdọ jẹ ojuṣe gbogbo eniyan bayii lati da iyi ati ẹyẹ aṣa wa pada. Ki awọn ọba mọ ojuṣe wọn, ki awọn ijoye naa si mọ aaye wọn lai fi ti ẹsin ajeji ṣe rara”Ṣaaju ni Araba Agbaye, Owolabi Aworeni ti kilọ fun Oluwoo lati dẹkun fifẹnu yẹpẹrẹ aṣa Yoruba nitori atubọtan iru iwa bẹẹ.O ni o ti n di gbọnmọ-gbọnmọ Ọba Akanbi to jẹ pe to ba ti fẹnu saata aṣa Yoruba tan nita gbangba ni yoo maa bẹbẹ kaakiri."},{"question":"ඉරානය හැරුණුවිට , ලෝකයේ ෂියා මුස්ලිම් ජනගහණය වැඩිම රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ඉරානය හැරුණුවිට , ලෝකයේ ෂියා මුස්ලිම් ජනගහණය වැඩිම රට වන්නෙ අසර්බයිජානය ය."},{"question":"Sarımsak yemek astıma iyi gelir mi?","answer":"Sarımsak sütü astım ve alerjik nezlenin neden olduğu rahatsızlıkları gidermeye yardımcı olur. Astım hastalığı olanların günde bir bardak sarımsaklı süt içmeleri tavsiye edilir."},{"question":"Меридиан деген эмне ?","answer":"Меридиан-жердин эки уюлун туташтыруучу курчама сызык"},{"question":"సాంప్రదాయ భారతీయ కాలాలను గూర్చి ఒక పట్టిక తయారు చేయంది.","answer":"సాంప్రదాయ భారతీయ కాలాలుఋతువులు:\\tతెలుగు నెలలు (చాంద్రమాన సంవత్సరం): \\tఇంగ్లీషు నెలలు(సూర్యమాన సంవత్సరం)వసంతం:\\tచైత్రం – వైశాఖం:\\tమార్చి – ఏప్రిల్గ్రీష్మం:\\tజ్యేష్ఠ – ఆషాఢం: \\tమే – జూన్వర్ష: \\tశ్రావణం – భాద్రపదం:\\tజులై – ఆగస్టుశరత్:\\tఆశ్వీయుజం – కార్తీకం:\\tసెప్టెంబరు – అక్టోబరుహేమంత:\\tమార్గశిర — పుష్యం:\\tనవంబరు – డిసెంబరుశిశిరం: \\tమాఘం – ఫాల్గుణం:\\tజనవరి – ఫిబ్రవరి"},{"question":"Кийиктин пири кандай айтылат?","answer":"Кийиктин пири — КайберенКайберендер ээси үңкүрдү үй кылып олтурган Ак байбиче кебетесинде баяндалат. Бул боюнча төмөндөгү элестеме баян айтылат:\\"Илгери бир мергенчи бир улактуу кийикти аткан экен, ал жарадар болуп качат. Мергенчи кайра атайын десе, огу түгөнүп калып, жарадар кийиктин артынан кууп жөнөйт. Жарадар кийик качып жүрүп отуруп бир үңкүргө кирип кетет. Мергенчи артынан кирейин деп үңкүрдүн оозуна барганда, үңкүрдөн: \\"Алда, балаңды аткыр ай!\\", — деп адамча сүйлөгөн үн чыгат. Мергенчи кирип барса, бир карган ак чач байбиче экен. Туякка айран куюп берип: \\"Балам, мындан ары балалуу кайберенди атпай жүр!\\" — деп узатып жибериптир. Көрсө кемпир кайберендин ээси экен. Мергенчи бая кыл туяктагы айранды канча ичсе да түгөтө албаптыр\\".Кыргыздын мифтик түшүнүгүндө кайберендин (кийик, аркар, кулжа, бөкөн ж.б.) ээси, сактоочусу, калкалоочусу, көбөйтүүчүсү болот деп каралган. Кайберендин ээси мергенчини жазалоо, каргоодон мурун, ага эскертме белги берет имиш. Ал белгисинин бирөө \\"оңко туруу\\" экен. \\"Оңкоо тургузуу\\" эскертмеси бир мергенчи өмүрүндө аткан кайберени миң башка жеткенде, ошол миңинчи кайберенди атканда \\"адамча өйдө тура калат экен\\", ошондо мергенчи кайберендин ээсинин эскертүүсүнө тил алып, экинчи аңга чыкпоосу керек экен. Экинчи эскертүү белгиси, кайберендин бирөөнү адамча сүйлөтүү же кайберенге мергенди ээрчитип келип, өзү көзүнө көрүнүп эскертүү насаат айтат экен. Ага да болбой, тил албай, кайберендерди кыруу ниетинен кайтпаса, кайберен ээси мергенчини жазалап, каргап, мертинткен же күлпөттү башына салган."},{"question":" O Jorge é o meu pai. A Teresa é filha do Jorge. A Marta é tia da Teresa. O que é Teresa é minha?","answer":"A Teresa é tua tia."},{"question":"\\" ઝાલર વાગે ને \\" લોકગીત લખો.","answer":"ઝાલર વાગે ને વા'લો હરિરસ ગાય                                            કાન ગોપીઓનો છેડો સાહ્યમેલો મેલોને  કાનુડા અમ્મારા ચીર                                      અમે ગોપીયું છીએ નિરમળા નીરછેડો ફાટ્યો ને ગોપી રાવે ગઈ                                              જશોદા મંદિર જઈ ઊભી રહીમાતા જશોદા  તમ્મારો કાન                                                   નિત્ય મારગડે માંગે છે દાણદાણ માંગે ને વળી લૂંટી ખાય                                                ઈ તે ગોકળિયામાં કેમ રે'વાયજાવ જાવ ગોપીયું તમ્મારે ઘેર                                                 આવે કાનો તો  માંડુ  વઢવેડસાંજ પડી ને કાનો આવ્યો છે ઘેર                                          માતા જશોદાએ માંડી  વઢવેડભાઈ કાનુડા તારે આવડી શી હેર                                        નિત્યના કજિયા લાવે મારે  ઘેરમાતા જશોદા તમ્મારી આણ                                              જુઠુ બોલે ગોપી ચતુરસુજાણવનમાં ચારું  હું  એકલો ગાય                                              ચાર-પાંચ ગોપીયું ભેળી થાયપરથમ આવે ને મારી ઝાલર બજાય                                   બીજી આવે ને મારો મુગટ ઘેરાયત્રીજી આવે ને મારી તૃષ્ણા કરે                                             ચોથી આવે ને મારે ચરણે પડેએટલી વપત્ય મને વનમાં પડે                                          તો યે ગોપીઓ મારી રાવ જ કરે!"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: KẾT QUẢ bóng đá U16 Việt Nam 5-1 U16 Singapore, U16 Đông Nam Á","answer":"KẾT QUẢ bóng đá U16 Việt Nam 5-1 U16 Singapore, U16 Đông Nam Á. Cập nhật kết quả bóng đá, bảng xếp hạng, lịch thi đấu và trực tiếp bóng đá U16 Đông Nam Á. Trực tiếp Thanh Hoá vs Viettel - On Sports trực tiếp bóng đá V-League (18h00, 31/7)Trực tiếp Thanh Hoá vs Viettel - On Sports trực tiếp bóng đá V-League (18h00, 31/7). Xem trực tiếp bóng đá Thanh Hóa vs Viettel. On Sports trực tiếp bóng đá hôm nay. (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});  * 15h00, 31/7: U16 Việt Nam 5-1 U16 Singapore (A) * 20h00, 31/7: U16 Indonesia vs U16 Philippines (A)  (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); Hết giờ! U16 Việt Nam giành chiến thắng 5-1 trước U16 Singapore. 90+3': VÀO 5-1 cho U16 Việt Nam. Công Hậu điền tên lên bảng tỉ số. 55': VÀO! Tỉ số là 4-1 cho U16 Việt Nam. Cầu thủ ghi bàn là Văn Danh.  Hiệp 2 bắt đầu! +U16 Việt Nam thi đấu áp đảo trong hiệp 1         +Hiệp 1 kết thúc. U16 Việt Nam dẫn trước 3-1.  45+2': VÀO! Xuân Toàn ghi bàn. U16 Việt Nam vươn lên dẫn trước 3-1. 45': VÀO! U16 Singapore có bàn thắng rút ngắn tỉ số xuống 1-2. Muhammad Rasul Ramli là người lập công. 23': VÀO! Đức Thiên ghi bàn nhân đôi cách biệt cho U16 Việt Nam. Tỉ số là 2-0 cho U16 Việt Nam. 9': VÀO! Tỉ số là 1-0 cho U16 Việt Nam. Hữu Trọng ghi bàn mở tỉ số. HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn: \\"U16 Việt Nam tôn trọng đối thủ ở vòng bảng U16 Đông Nam Á 2022\\"  Sáng 30/7 tại Jogyakarta, buổi họp báo trước các trận đấu tại bảng A VCK U16 Đông Nam Á 2022 đã diễn ra. Đại diện cho U16 Việt Nam, HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn đánh giá cao công tác tổ chức giải cũng như bày tỏ sự tôn trọng với tất cả các đối thủ ở cùng bảng như Indonsia, Singapore và Philippines. Phát biểu trong buổi họp báo, HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn nói: \\"Trận mở màn bảng A diễn ra vào chiều 31/7 sẽ rất quan trọng, đối với những đội bóng trẻ của Việt Nam, Indonesia, Singapore hay Philippines. Chúng tôi đã có sự chuẩn bị và sẵn sàng cho cuộc so tài với U16 Singapore. Tôi nghĩ tất cả các đội ở bảng A đều có trình độ tương đương nhau. Cơ hội vào bán kết dành cho tất cả là như nhau. Tất nhiên, U16 Indonesia có lợi thế được chơi trên sân nhà. Họ nhận được sự cổ vũ của khán giả. Đó là điểm mạnh của Indonesia\\". Ông Tuấn tiếp tục nói: \\"Ban huấn luyện U16 Việt Nam luôn nhắc nhở các cầu thủ tuân thủ đúng yêu cầu, quy định cầu BTC đề ra. Với U16 Việt Nam, chúng tôi giáo dục cầu thủ với phong cách chơi bóng hiện đại, tôn trọng đối phương và phục vụ cho giải đấu thành công. Về phía BTC giải, tôi nghĩ sự chuẩn bị cho giải đấu lần này rất tốt. Các cầu thủ U16 Việt Nam được tạo điều kiện ăn ở, đi lại và sân tập chất lượng. Người hỗ trợ theo đoàn cũng rất nhiệt tình\\". Trước câu hỏi của phóng viên Indonesia về việc U19 Việt Nam gặp những khó khăn nhất định ở VCK U19 Đông Nam Á 2022 cách đây vài tuần, trước sức ép của cổ động viên Indonesia, khi U19 Việt Nam và U19 Thái Lan loại U19 Indonesia ngay từ vòng bảng, HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn nói: \\"Tôi nghĩ cổ động viên Indonesia cuồng nhiệt. Họ say mê bóng đá, luôn cổ vũ với tinh thần hừng hực khí thế. Chúng tôi hiểu được vấn đề này và cố gắng vượt qua. Đội cũng trang bị tâm lý cho các cầu thủ để chuẩn bị cho từng trận đấu\\". Về phần mình, HLV Angel Toledano của U16 Singapore – đối thủ của U16 Việt Nam cho hay: \\"Tôi rất vui khi đến Indonesia. Đây là một đất nước đẹp. Người hâm mộ nơi đây cổ vũ cuồng nhiệt. U16 Singapore chuẩn bị cho giải đấu này vào giữa tháng 6. Chúng tôi có một số trận giao hữu với các đội địa phương. U16 Singapore sẽ cố gắng bằng tất cả những gì có thể. Ở bảng đấu này, tất cả các đội đều mạnh. Chúng tôi tôn trọng tất cả. Ở trận đấy tới, U16 Singapore sẽ gặp U16 Việt Nam. Tôi sẽ cố gắng tập trung cho trận ra mắt này\\". +Việt Nam và Thái Lan là hai đội vô địch nhiều nhất ở giải U16 Đông Nam Á. Mỗi bên đều đã 3 lần đăng quang.  +Tại giải U16 Đông Nam Á 2022, U16 Việt Nam nằm cùng bảng với U16 Indonesia, U16 Singapore và U16 Philippines.  Hiệp 1 bắt đầu! U16 Việt Nam khởi động  +Đội hình ra sân của U16 Singapore   +Đội hình ra sân của hai đội  +Chùm ảnh U16 Việt Nam tập luyện trước trận gặp U16 Singapore           Vào lúc 15h00 ngày 31/7, U16 Việt Nam sẽ chính thức bước vào Giải vô địch U16 Đông Nam Á 2022, với trận ra quân gặp U16 Singapore trên sân Sultan Aung. U16 Việt Nam và các đội bóng đã không được tập làm quen sân vận động này. Theo lý giải của BTC U16 Đông Nam Á 2022, họ muốn đảm bảo chất lượng sân thi đấu ở thời điểm diễn ra giải. Về lộ trình, khoảng cách từ khách sạn đóng quân của U16 Việt Nam (Prime Plaza) đến sân Sultan Aung chừng 16 km, với tổng thời gian di chuyển có thể lên đến 40 phút. Việc đi lại với xe cỡ lớn chở đội U16 Việt Nam sẽ còn gặp thêm khó khăn khi đường đi khá nhỏ nhưng mật độ phương tiện tham gia giao thông lại lớn.  Đấy không phải là thách thức duy nhất mà U16 Việt Nam sẽ phải trải qua khi thi đấu ở sân Sultan Aung. Bởi chất lượng mặt cỏ sẽ là điều mà thầy trò HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn trăn trở hơn cả. Trong chiều 30/7, HLV Nguyễn Quốc Tuấn đã cắt cử 2 trợ lý kiểm tra mặt sân Sultan Aung. Theo đánh giá của các trợ lý, kích thước sân vận động này đảm bảo đúng tiêu chuẩn. Tuy nhiên, mặt sân lại không được như kỳ vọng. Đánh giá từ các trợ lý của U16 Việt Nam, mặt sân Sultan Aung không đều. Cỏ được trồng tới 3-4 loại khác nhau với chiều cao chỗ thấp, chỗ cao. Ngoài ra, vì các loại cỏ khác nhau nên có khu vực mặt sân cứng nhưng có chỗ mặt sân lại mềm. Nhiều chỗ lõm, mấp mô, gồ ghề. Điều này ảnh hưởng trực tiếp đến việc di chuyển, chạy chỗ của các cầu thủ U16 Việt Nam. Bởi nó sẽ ảnh hưởng đến việc trụ chân ở từng khu vực (mềm, cứng). Thậm chí, các cầu thủ có thể bị lật cổ chân khi thi đấu trên mặt sân này. Theo đánh giá, chất lượng mặt sân Sultan Aung không bằng so với sân tập mà U16 Việt Nam đã rèn luyện tại trường quốc tế Jorgiakarta những ngày qua.  Sơn Tùng"},{"question":"Castries mooy péeyu man réew ?","answer":"Castries mooy péeyu réewum Sainte-Lucie."},{"question":"Nitori pe o darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu mi-in, awọn tọọgi ṣa Taye pa n’ldanre","answer":"Ọrọ oṣelu to n lọ lọwọ nipinlẹ Ondo gbọna mi-in yọ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, pẹlu bi awọn ọdọ kan ṣe fẹhonu han lori ọrọ omokunrin kan ti wọn pa lalẹ Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii.Ọmọkunrun ti wọn porukọ rẹ ni Taye yii lawọn tọọgi kan ti wọn ni wọn jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC ṣe akọlu si ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an alẹ ọjọ naa latari bo ṣe kuro ninu ẹgbẹ wọn, to si lọọ darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu ZLP.ALAROYE gbọ pe ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC ni wọn pe oloogbe ọhun tẹlẹ ko too kuro, to si lọọ darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ PDP.Laipẹ yii lo tun sa kuro ninu ẹgbẹ PDP, to si ba ẹgbẹ ZLP lọ.Fila ẹgbẹ tuntun to lọọ darapọ mọ yii to de sori lalẹ ọjọ iṣẹlẹ naa ni wọn lo bi awọn tọọgi APC ninu tí wọn fi kọlu u lagbegbe Sabo, niluu Alade-Idanre.Loootọ lo kọkọ ja fitafita, to si gbiyanju lati sa mọ wọn lọwọ, ṣugbọn ti ko ti i raaye sa jinna tọwọ awọn to n le e fi pada tẹ ẹ, ti wọn si ṣa a pa mọ inu igbo to sa wọ.Eyi naa lo ṣokunfa bawọn ọdọ kan ṣe binu fọn sì igboro ilu naa laaarọ kutukutu Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, pẹlu aake, ada, atawọn nnkan ija mi-in lati fẹhonu han ta ko iku oloogbe ọhun.Ṣe ni wọn sun taya ọkọ si gbogbo oju ọna abawọlu Alade, ti wọn si n fa awọn posita oludije ẹgbẹ APC ti wọn ba ti ri ya."},{"question":"Apakah soalan untuk: \\"Menggunakan konsep daripada sistem hiperteks terdahulu seperti ENQUIRE, jurutera British, saintis komputer dan pada masa itu pekerja CERN, Sir Tim Berners-Lee, kini Pengarah World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), menulis cadangan pada Mac 1989 untuk apa yang akhirnya menjadi World Wide Web\\"? Topiknya ialah World Wide Web.","answer":"\\"Bilakah web dicipta?\\""},{"question":"5: Beeycatu Al-Nisaa bacda fatxu Makka Nabiga (scw) wuxuu yiraahday (Walaataqtuluu oowlaadakum) Hidu Bintu Cutba waxaay tiraahday Caruurtii aan korinay oo weeynaaday waxaad ku laayseen digaal, Ee waxaad sheegtaan wiilkeedii lagudilay digaalkii Badar magaciisa?","answer":"5: Wuxuu ahaa Handhala binu Abii sufiyaan oo curadkii Hinda bintu Cutba ahaa, Suuratul AL-Mumtaxina Aayada ugudanbeeysa ayaa tilmaameeysa waxaadna ka heleeysaa Tafsiirka Al-Qurdhubi. Maka heleesiid Ibnu kathiir, Jalaaleeynka iyo Dhabari.Dagaalkii Badr waxaa lagu diley Hind aabaheed Cutba inb Rabiica, adeerkeed Xudeyfa ibn Rabiica iyo walaalked Waliid ibn Cutba ee ma garanayo meel wiilkeeda lagu diley Badr. Wiilkeeda Mucaawiya ibn abii Sufyaan waa ninkii bilaabey xukunkii Ummawiyiinta."},{"question":"¿De qué categoría es esta pregunta?: ¿Está casado el vocalista de Metálica?.","answer":"La categoría de la que surge la pregunta es la música."},{"question":" ما هو إسم المرأة التي حاولت قتل النبي صلى اللهعليه وسلم بالسم ؟","answer":"- زينب بنت الحارثة (( يهودية ))"},{"question":"アメリカ生まれの指先で回して遊ぶ、２０１７年に流行したおもちゃは何スピナーでしょう？","answer":"ハンドスピナーです。"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki yang bertemakan permainan berikut: Roda yang bukan ada di kenderaan, dan apabila ia putar, orang akan bersorak sambil tepuk tangan.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah roda impian. "},{"question":"Sengedlula kulezo zinto Sifiso.''Umama wakho uyayazi kodwa le ndaba?''Uyayazi ndoda. Angiyazi uyizwe kanjani, ngobani. Okubi-ke nje akafuni nakuyizwa.''Uzokwenzenjani-ke wena?''Ngingenzenjani Sifiso. Sesithandene phela noTholakele.''Kahle wena bo! Kanti akusikho nokuthi useshela?''Angeshelanga. Sabonisana. Sathola ukuthi siyathandana. Izimo zethu zazifana.Ushonelwe yindoda; ngifuna umakoti.'Behlukaniswa ukukhala kwensimbi uBheki noSifiso. UBheki wabona ukuthi kubi umanomngani wakhe emlahla. Nokho-ke wazitshela ukuthi umona nje obusa uSifiso.Umuntu owayeyinkinga kakhulu unina. Wayengazi ukuthi ekhaya uzofike athini. Wakewacabanga nokungayi ekhaya.'Angingayi kumama ngoba okwamanje anginayo impendulo. Angiyozihlalela esitolokuyoze kufike uTholi.'1. Ubaba kaBhekani wakukhombisa kanjani ukuthi akamfuni uTholakele?","answer":"Wafika kaningi kuBhekani ngephupho exosha/evimba owesifazanewezingubo ezimnyama ukuba angangeni esangweni lomuzi wakhe.  Wayefika ngephupho ebambe uLindiwe ngesandla.  Waphupha exosha intokazi egqoke izingubo ezimnyama ngomkhonto. Waphupha engenisa abantu esangweni kanti sekungena intokaziegqoke izingubo ezimnyama wavala isango. "},{"question":"කායුජ්ජුකතාව හා චිත්තුජ්ජුකතාව  චෛතසික ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"ශෝභන චිත්ත සම්ප්‍ර‍යුක්ත චෛතසිකයන් ගේ සෘජුත්වය හෙවත් ඇද නැති බව කායුජ්ජුකතාවය. ශෝභන චිත්තයාගේ සෘජුත්වය චිත්තුජ්ජුකතාවය. චිත්ත චෛතසිකයන්ගේ වංක භාවය අපරිශුද්ධ භාවය මායා සාඨෙය්‍යාදි ක්ලේශයන් නිසා සිදුවන්නකි. මේ චෛතසිකයෝ දෙදෙන ඒ මායා සාඨෙය්‍යාදීන්ට ප්‍ර‍තිපක්ෂ ධර්ම දෙකකි. කළ වරද, ඇති වරද, සඟවා රවටන ස්වභාවය මායා නමි. නැති ගුණ දක්වා රවටන ස්වභාවය සාඨෙය්‍ය නමි. කායුජ්ජුකතා චිත්තුජ්ජුකතා චෛතසික දුබල තැනැත්තාගේ සිත කුශල පක්ෂයේ දී විසම පැවතුම් ඇත්තේ ය. එය විටෙක උත්සාහවත් වේ. විටෙක පසු බසී. විටෙක අකුශල පක්ෂයට වැටේ. ඒවා බලවත් වූ තැනැත්තාගෙ සිත කුශල පක්ෂයේ මැනවින් පවතී.ගෝමුත්‍ර‍ වංකය ය, චන්ද්‍රලේඛා වංකය ය, නංගල කෝටි වංකය යයි වංකය තුන් ආකාර වේ. ගමන් කරමින් මුත්‍ර‍ පහ කළ ගවයා ගේ මුත්‍රයෙන් පොළොවෙහි ඇතිවුණු රේඛාවේ ඇදය ගෝමුත්‍ර‍ වංකය යි. අමාවක පසු වී සමීපයේ පායන සඳට චන්ද්‍රලේඛාව යයි කියනු ලැබේ. එහි ඇදය චන්ද්‍රලේඛා වංකය යි. නගුල් දණ්ඩ සෘජුය. එහෙත් එහි කෙළවර වියගහ බඳින තැන මඳ ඇදයක් තිබේ. එය නංගලකෝටි වංකය යි. මනුෂ්‍යයාගේ සිත් වල ඒ තුනට සමාන වූ වංකයෝ වෙති. ඒවාට ද ඒ නම් ම ව්‍යවහාර කරනු ලැබේ.පව් කොට “මම පව් නො කරමි” යි කියමින් පාපය සඟවන තැනැත්තා කිරීම් වශයෙන් පව් මඟ ඉදිරියට ගමන් කොට, නො කරමියි කියමින් පාපයෙහි ම පසු බසින්නෙකි. දෙපසට යාම ඇති ඔහුගේ ඒ ගතිය ඉදිරියට පස්සට විටින් විට ගමන් කර තිබෙන ගෝමුත්‍ර‍ රේඛාව බඳු බැවින් එයට ගෝමුත්‍ර‍ වංකය යි කියනු ලැබේ.ඇතැම්හු පව් කරමින් පව් කිරීමට බොහෝ බිය ඇති බව කියති. පව් නො කරන්නට අනුන්ට අනුශාසනය කරති. පව් කරන්නවුන්ට ගර්හා කරති. ඔවුන්ගේ ඒ ස්වභාවය චන්ද්‍රලේඛාවේ ඇදය මෙන් ඉතා ම වක් බැවින් එයට චන්ද්‍රලේඛා වංකතාවය යි කියනු ලැබේ.ඇතැම්හු පව් කරමින් ම කවරෙක් පවට බිය නො වෙත්ද? යනාදීන් පර්‍ය්‍යායයෙන් තමන් ගේ ශුද්ධත්වය ලොවට පවසති. තමන් ගේ ශුද්ධත්වය කෙලින් ම නො කියති. ඔවුන් ගේ ස්වභාවය පව් කරමින් නො කරමිය කියන්නා ගේ ස්වභාවය තරමට ඇද නැති බැවින් ඒ මඳ ඇද ගතිය නංගල කෝටි වංකතාවය යි කියනු ලැබේ.යමෙක් තුන් දොරින් ම පව් කෙරේ නම් සෑම තැන ම ඇදය ඇති ඔහුගේ ඒ ස්වභාවයට ගෝමුත්‍ර‍ වංකතාවය යි කියනු ලැබේ. යමෙක් යම් කිසි දෙදොරකින් පමණක් පව් කෙරේ නම් ඔහු ගේ ස්වභාවයට චන්ද්‍රලේඛා වංකතාවය යි කියනු ලැබේ. යමෙක් දෙදොරක් පිරිසිදු කර ගෙන එක දොරකින් පමණක් පව් කෙරේ නම් ඔහු ගේ ඒ ස්වභාවයට නංගලකෝටි වංකතාවය යයි කියනු ලැබේ. කායුජ්ජුකතා චිත්තුජ්ජුකතා චෛතසිකයෝ ඒ තුන් ආකාර වංකතාවයනට ප්‍ර‍තිපක්ෂයෝ ය."},{"question":"ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਕੇਂਦਰ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਥੇ ਕੀ-ਕੀ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ?","answer":"ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਮੁੱਖ ਕੇਂਦਰ ਹਨ-    -ਭੋਜਨ ਦੀ ਤਿਆਰੀ,    -ਭੋਜਨ ਪਕਾਉਣਾ ਤੇ ਵਰਤਾਉਣਾ ਅਤੇ    -ਹੌਦੀ  ।1. ਭੋਜਨ ਦੀ ਤਿਆਰੀ – ਭੋਜਨ ਪਕਾਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸਬਜ਼ੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਛਿੱਲਣ, ਕੱਟਣ, ਚੁਣਨ ਆਦਿ ਦੀ ਤਿਆਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਖਾਣਾ ਪਕਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਹੋਰ ਸੰਬੰਧਤ ਕਾਰਜ ਵੀ ਇੱਥੇ ਹੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਰਸੋਈ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੀ-ਡੁੱਲ੍ਹੀ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ । ਸਮਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਬਚਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਖਾਣਾ ਪਕਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਨੇੜੇ-ਨੇੜੇ ਹੋਣੀਆਂ ਚਾਹੀਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਰੈਫਰੀਜ਼ਰੇਟਰ ਦਾ ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ਾ ਜਿਸ ਪਾਸੇ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹਦਾ ਹੋਵੇ ਕਾਊਂਟਰ (ਸ਼ੈਲਫ) ਵੀ ਉਸੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਹੀ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ।2. ਭੋਜਨ ਪਕਾਉਣ ਅਤੇ ਵਰਤਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਥਾਂ – ਰਸੋਈ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਵਿਚ ਖਾਣਾ ਪਕਾ ਕੇ ਗਰਮ ਗਰਮ ਵਰਤਾਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇੱਥੇ ਬਿਜਲੀ ਦਾ ਚੁੱਲਾ, ਗੈਸ, ਸਟੋਵ ਜਾਂ ਅੰਗੀਠੀ ਆਦਿ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਆਲੇ-ਦੁਆਲੇ ਜਗਾ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੀ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਜੋ ਖਾਣਾ ਪਕਾਉਣ ਵੇਲੇ ਸੌਖ ਰਹੇ | ਖਾਣਾ ਪਕਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਰਤਨ ਇਸ ਜਗਾ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਹੀ ਸ਼ੈਲਫ਼ ਪਾ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੀ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਬਣਾ ਲੈਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ । ਕੜਛੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਚਮਚ ਆਦਿ ਟੰਗਣ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਖੁੰਟੀਆਂ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ ਹੋਣੀਆਂ ਚਾਹੀਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।3. ਹੌਦੀ  – ਹੌਦੀ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ ਬਰਤਨ ਸਾਫ਼ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਰੈਫਰੀਜ਼ਰੇਟਰ ਵਿਚ ਭੋਜਨ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਰੱਖਣ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਧੋਣ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ | ਖਾਣਾ ਪਕਾਉਣ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਤਿਆਰੀ ਵੇਲੇ ਵੀ ਪਾਣੀ ਇੱਥੇ ਲੱਗੀ ਟੂਟੀ ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੌਖੀ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਅੰਦਰ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ, ਖੂੰਜੇ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ । ਹੌਦੀ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਬਰਤਨ ਤੇ ਲੋੜੀਂਦਾ ਸਮਾਨ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਵੀ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ । ਆਸੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਦਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਨੁਚੜ ਕੇ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਪੈਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Kedụ mgbe éjị eme emumme Kayo-Kayo?","answer":"A na-eme emumme a n'ọnwa mbụ nke kalenda islam maka ncheta 'Yaom-al Ashura' ụbọchị iri nke Muharram na kalenda Alakụba, nke bụ ihe dị ka otu ọnwa ka emechara ememme Muslim nke Eid-El-Kabir ."},{"question":"Combien d’éléments y a-t-il dans le tableau périodique ?","answer":"Il y a 118 éléments connus dans le tableau périodique."},{"question":"Quốc hoa Campuchia có màu đặc trưng là gì?","answer":"Quốc hoa của Campuchia là loài hoa có màu vàng đặc trưng tên là Rumdul.Một số thông tin thêm:- Năm 2005, Rumdul chính thức trở thành quốc hoa của Campuchia và là biểu tượng bảo vệ môi trường của chính phủ. Loài hoa này phổ biến tại Campuchia, tượng trưng cho bản chất lương thiện, tích cực của người dân.- Cây Rumdul có thể cao từ 8 đến 12 m, đường kính thân 20-30 cm, lá đơn mọc so le. Mùi thơm của hoa rumdul có thể ngửi thấy từ xa, nên có thể tạo sáp thơm. Trong y học cổ truyền, hoa rumdul được dùng để chữa chóng mặt, có ích cho tim mạch, huyết áp."},{"question":"‘ਯਾਰ ਅਣਮੁੱਲੇ’ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਭਾਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਨੇ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਰਪੱਕ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਲੋਹਾ ਮਨਵਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਜ਼ੀਮ ਫ਼ਨਕਾਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਜਾਣੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹੰਸ ਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਦੇ ਪੁੱਤ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਨੇਹੀ ਯੁਵੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ, ਦਾ ਸੁਪਨਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਵਾਂਗ ਸੰਗੀਤਕ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੁਲੰਦੀਆਂ ਸਰ ਕਰਨਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਉਹ ਤਨਦੇਹੀ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਅਤੇ ਰਿਆਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਅੰਜ਼ਾਮ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਸਬੱਬ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੀ ਰਾਹ ਵੱਲ ਮੋੜ ਲਿਆਏ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਛਾਣ ਇਸ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮਵਰ ਅਤੇ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਕਲਾਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਰਵਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਨਅਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਪੈੜ੍ਹਾਂ ਸਥਾਪਤ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਨਾਲ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਪਹਿਲੂਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਹੋਈ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਹਨ ਸੰਖੇਪ ਅੰਸ਼:ਸਵਾਲ: ਸੰਗੀਤਕ ਰਾਹਾਂ ਤੈਅ ਕਰਦੇ-ਕਰਦੇ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵੱਲ ਕਿੰਜ ਮੁੜੇ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਇਹ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਸਹੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੇਰਾ ਮੂਲ ਰੁਝਾਨ ਪਿਤਾ ਜੀ ਵਾਂਗ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕਪ੍ਰਿਯਤਾ ਦੇ ਨਵੇਂ ਆਯਾਮ ਕਾਇਮ ਕਰਨਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਪਰ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਅਨੁਰਾਗ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਜੀ ਅਤੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ‘ਯਾਰ ਅਣਮੁੱਲੇ’ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਅਤੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਰੱਖੀ, ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖਦਿਆਂ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਹੌਸਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਿਆ।ਸਵਾਲ: ‘ਯਾਰ ਅਣਮੁੱਲੇ’ ਦੀ ਕਾਮਯਾਬੀ ਨੇ ਗਾਇਕ ਯੁਵੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਕੁ ਬਦਲਿਆ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸ਼ੁਕਰਗੁਜ਼ਾਰ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਦਾ ਹੱਕਦਾਰ ਬਣਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੈਂ ਕਦੇ ਕਲਪਨਾ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਮਿਲੇ ਇਸ ਸਨੇਹ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਕੁਝ ਸਮੇਂ ਲਈ ਦੂਰ ਤਾਂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਮੈਂ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਖੇਤਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਾਹੁਣ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਆਸਾਵਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਖ਼ਰਾ ਉਤਰਨ ਦੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਾਂਗਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਤਜਰਬਾ ਕਿੱਦਾਂ ਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਬੇਹੱਦ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ, ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ਦੇ ਕਾਬਿਲ ਅਤੇ ਯੁਵਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣਾ ਸ਼ੁਮਾਰ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਅਨੁਰਾਗ ਸਿੰਘ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਟੀਮ ਹਰੀਸ਼ ਵਰਮਾ, ਆਰੀਆ ਬੱਬਰ ਆਦਿ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਹੀ ਆਧਾਰਤ ਰਹੀ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਸਾਂਝ ਬਣਾਉਣੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਯਾਦਗਾਰੀ ਤਜਰਬਾ ਰਿਹਾ, ਇਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਕੁਝ ਸਿੱਖਣ, ਸਮਝਣ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤਰਜੀਹ ਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹੋ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਮੇਰੀ ਤਵੱਜੋਂ ਕੇਵਲ ਉਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਹਨ, ਜੋ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਦੀ ਤਰਜਮਾਨੀ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ਮਕ ਵੀ ਹੋਣ। ਇਸੇ ਲਈ ਗਿਣੀਆਂ-ਚੁਣੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਸਵੀਕਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਆਗਾਮੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਜੈਕਟ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਆਪਣੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਖੇਤਰ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਲੇਠੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਐਲਬਮ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੰਜ਼ਾਮ ਦੇ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾ, ਜੋ ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਪੱਧਰ ’ਤੇ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਣ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਉਮੀਦ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਇਸ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਸਰੋਤਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਮਣਾਂਮੂੰਹੀ ਪਿਆਰ-ਸਤਿਕਾਰ ਹਾਸਲ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਇਸ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਐਲਬਮ ਦੀ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ਤਾ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਾਪਦੰਡ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਮਿਆਰੀ ਲੀਹਾਂ ਸਥਾਪਤ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਰਹਿਣਗੇ। ਇਸੇ ਸੋਚ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਜ਼ਾਮ ਦਿੰਦਿਆਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਇਸ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਐਲਬਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਗੀਤ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਮਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਤਰਜਮਾਨੀ, ਭੰਗੜੇ ਦੀ ਤਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਸੂਫ਼ੀਆਨਾ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਦੇ ਹਰ ਰੰਗ ਸੁਣਨ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣਗੇ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਹੰਸ ਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਰੁਝਾਨ ਸੂਫ਼ੀਆਨਾ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਵੱਲ ਰਿਹਾ। ਇਸ ਦਾ ਅਸਰ ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ’ਤੇ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਕੁ ਹਾਵੀ ਰਹੇਗਾ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਪਿਤਾ ਜੀ, ਵਾਂਗ ਮੈਂ ਵੀ ਸੂਫ਼ੀਆਨਾ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਪਸੰਦ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਜ਼ ਵੀ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਮੋਂਹਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਮੇਂ-ਸਮੇਂ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਤਾਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਬਣਾਵਾਂਗਾ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਵੀ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਗੀਤ, ਸੰਗੀਤ ਦੀ ਰੰਗਤ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀਅਤ ਕਦਰਾਂ-ਕੀਮਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ਬੂ ਡੁੱਲ੍ਹ-ਡੁੱਲ੍ਹ ਪਵੇਗੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਐਲਬਮ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋਣ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਇਸ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਐਲਬਮ ਦੇ ਗੀਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਰਚਨਾ ਕੁਮਾਰ, ਜੱਗੀ ਮੁੰਬਈ, ਧੰਮੀ ਹੇਰਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਅਤੇ ਪਿਰਥੀ ਸੀਲੋ ਵਾਲਾ ਨੇ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਗੁਰਮੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਐਲਬਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਅੱਗੇ ਯੋਜਨਾ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਕੁਝ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰਾਂਗਾ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਝ ਕਰ ਗੁਜ਼ਰਨ ਲਈ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਯੋਜਨਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਜ਼ਾਮ ਦੇਵਾਂਗਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਸ ਮੁਕਾਮ ਤੱਕ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਅਹਿਮ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹੋ?ਯੁਵਰਾਜ: ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਤਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਹੰਸ ਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ, ਮਾਤਾ ਰੇਸ਼ਮ ਕੌਰ, ਵੱਡੇ ਭਰਾ ਨਵਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਦੁਆਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਥੋਂ ਤੱਕ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ ਲਈ ਸਿਜਦਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਅਨੁਰਾਗ ਸਿੰਘ, ਬਤਰਾ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਕਸ਼ਨ ਅਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਧੰਨਵਾਦੀ ਹਾਂ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧਣ ਲਈ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਹੌਂਸਲਾ ਅਫ਼ਜਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਯੁਵਰਾਜ ਹੰਸ ਦੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਨਾਮ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਮਾਤਾ ਰੇਸ਼ਮ ਕੌਰ ।"},{"question":"จงเขียนข้อความต่อจากข้อความต่อไปนี้ - ตอมา โฟชรง เกิดวันที่ 23 กุมภาพันธ์ ค.ศ. 1990 ที่เมืองแรน ประเทศฝรั่งเศส เป็นนักยิงธนูชาวฝรั่งเศส ในการแข่งขันโอลิมปิกฤดูร้อน 2012 เขาได้เข้าแข่งขันให้แก่ประเทศของตนในประเภททีมชาย ซึ่งทีมฝรั่งเศสของเขาได้อันดับที่ 2 ในรอบจัดอันดับ นอกจากนี้ เขายังเข้าแข่งขันในรายการประเภทชายเดี่ยว","answer":"โดยได้พบกับวิทยา ทำว่อง ซึ่งเป็นนักยิงธนูจากประเทศไทย และตอมา โฟชรง เป็นฝ่ายชนะด้วยคะแนน 26-28, 23-27 และ 25-26 ในรอบ 32 คนสุดท้าย"},{"question":"من اول رئيس للوزراء في الباكستان؟","answer":"محمد بن جناح عام 1941م."},{"question":"Quem é a deusa grega das leis?","answer":"A deusa grega das leis é Têmis. "},{"question":" ځواب دا دی: \\"هغه د جون په 3، 2009 کې مړ شو، ظاهرا د ځان د جنسي تیري له امله.\\" موضوع ډیویډ کاراډین دی.","answer":"\\"ډېویډ کارادین څنګه مړ شو؟\\""},{"question":"විශ්වයේ වැඩිපුරම ඇති මූලද්‍රව්‍යය කුමක්ද?","answer":"හයිඩ්‍රජන් යනු විශ්වයේ වැඩිපුරම ඇති මූලද්‍රව්‍යයයි."},{"question":"न्यातापोला मन्दिर","answer":"भक्तपुरको अनुपम मन्दिर, न्याटापोलाको शाब्दिक अर्थ ‘पाँच तले’ भन्ने हो र सहरको परिदृश्यबाट माथि उठेको एउटा उल्लेखनीय स्थलचिन्ह हो। यसले सन् १९३३ को विनाशकारी भूकम्पको सामना गर्ने विशिष्टता पनि छ। एक तान्त्रिक देवीलाई समर्पित, मन्दिरमा जाने सिढीहरूमा देवताहरू र पौराणिक जनावरहरूको ढुङ्गाको मूर्तिहरू छन्, प्रत्येक तुरुन्तै तलको भन्दा १० गुणा बढी शक्तिशाली छ।"},{"question":"O que é a Ilha de Fernando de Noronha?","answer":"Resposta: A Ilha de Fernando de Noronha é um parque marinho nacional brasileiro e uma reserva no Atlântico Sul Equatorial."},{"question":"Ki laa ti waa ṣeyi si, wọn tun ji agbẹ kan gbe ninu oko ẹ n’Ibadan","answer":"Inu ibẹru-bojo ikọlu awọn ajinigbe lawọn agbẹ agbegbe Moniya, niluu Ibadan, wa bayii, pẹlu bi awọn amookunṣika ẹda ṣe ji ọkan pataki ninu wọn, Ogbẹni Oluwọle Agboọla, gbe.Awọn ajinigbe ọhun ti wọn jẹ mẹfa ni wọn mura bii ọmoogun orileede yii, ti wọn si ya wọnu oko baba naa to wa lọna Abule Nagbede, lagbegbe Mọniya, n’Ibadan lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ kejidinlọgbọn, oṣu kejila, ọdun to kọja yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe ẹsẹ lawọn olubi eeyan yii fi rin wọ inu ọgba ti wọn ti n sin ẹlẹdẹ atawọn ohun abiyẹ wọnyi. Eyi ni ko jẹ ki awọn oṣiṣẹ inu oko nla ọhun gburoo awọn alejo ọran naa titi ti wọn fi kan wọn lara. Aṣọ ṣọja ti wọn si wọ paapaa ba wọn lẹru to bẹẹ ti wọn ko mọ eyi ti wọn le ṣe titi ti awọn ọdaran fi naa ṣiṣẹ ibi ti wọn waa ṣeAwọn ajinigbe ti wọn mura bii ṣọja wọnyi ko ṣe meni ṣe meji, ọdọ Ọgbẹni Agboọla ti i ṣe ọga agba oko nla naa ni wọn lọ taara, ti wọn si mu un wọnu igbo lọ. Akitiyan awọn oṣiṣẹ inu oko naa lo jẹ ki wọn mọ pe ki i ṣe awọn ṣọja lo mu ọga wọn lọ bi ko ṣe awọn ajinigbe.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, SP Olugbenga Fadeyi, sọ pe lẹsẹkẹsẹ ti wọn ti fi iṣẹlẹ yii to awọn agbofinro leti lagọọ ọlọpaa to wa ni Mọniya lawọn ọlọpaa ti fọn da sinu gbogbo igbo to yi Mọniya ka lati wa awọn gbọmọgbọmọ ọhun kan, ki wọn si gba baba ti wọn ji gbe silẹ lọwọ wọn.“Bi mo ṣe n ba yin sọrọ yii, awọn ikọ eleto aabo mi-in bii Amọtẹkun, Operation Burst atawọn ọdẹ ibilẹ naa ti darapọ mọ awọn ọlọpaa ninu igbo lati ri i pe wọn ṣaṣeyọri lori iṣẹ yii.” Bẹẹ ni SP Fadeyi lo sọ eyi fawọn oniroyin n’Ibadan."},{"question":"Con riferimento al testo seguente, rispondi alla domanda che viene presentata alla fine assicurandoti di rispondere nella stessa lingua. Testo:\\"Le Americhe costituiscono la maggior parte delle terre emerse nell'emisfero occidentale della Terra.Il punto più settentrionale delle Americhe è l'isola di Kaffeklubben, che è il punto più settentrionale delle terre emerse dell’intero pianeta. Il punto più meridionale è rappresentato dalla isola di Thule, anche se, a volte, è considerata parte dell'Antartide.Le terraferma delle Americhe rappresenta inoltre la più lunga massa continentale, da nord a sud, del mondo. La distanza tra le due estremità, la penisola di Boothia nel Canada settentrionale (a nord) e il Capo Froward nella Patagonia cilena (a sud), è di circa 14000 km.Il punto più occidentale della terraferma delle Americhe è la fine della penisola di Seward in Alaska; l'isola di Attu, più a ovest della costa dell'Alaska, è invece considerata invece il punto più occidentale in assoluto delle Americhe. Ponta do Seixas, nel nord-est del Brasile, costituisce l'estremità più orientale della terraferma, mentre Nordostrundingen, in Groenlandia, è il punto più orientale della piattaforma continentale.Domanda:\\"A quale continente si pensa che appartenga l’isola di Thule?\\"","answer":"L’isola di Thule appartiene alle Americhe, anche se a volte viene considerata parte dell’Antartide. "},{"question":"Manzon Allah Sallallahu Alaihi Wa Sallama Ya ambaci wata cikin yayansa da cewa: ita tsoka ce daga jikin Sa, Wa ce ce Ya fadi hakan a kan ta? (a) Nana Fatima (b) Nana Zainab (c) Nana Rukayya","answer":" (a) Nana Fatima"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Shin yaya za a rubuta ɗari biyu da ɗaya a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 201"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Ståhl blev sedermera Sveriges genom tiderna främste maratonlöpare med 101 genomförda lopp, 70 av dem under 2 tim 20 min. Han var svensk rekordhållare på distansen i 36 år med 2:10.38 fram till 2019-12-01 (då David Nilsson fick tiden 2:10.08 vid Valencia Marathon), vilket var hans tid vid VM i friidrott 1983","answer":", då han blev fyra."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ਮਃ ੫ ॥ਭਗਤ ਜਨਾਂ ਕਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਹਰਿ ਆਪਿ ਹੈ ਕਿਆ ਪਾਪੀ ਕਰੀਐ ॥ਗੁਮਾਨੁ ਕਰਹਿ ਮੂੜ ਗੁਮਾਨੀਆ ਵਿਸੁ ਖਾਧੀ ਮਰੀਐ ॥ਆਇ ਲਗੇ ਨੀ ਦਿਹ ਥੋੜੜੇ ਜਿਉ ਪਕਾ ਖੇਤੁ ਲੁਣੀਐ ॥ਜੇਹੇ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਵਦੇ ਤੇਵੇਹੋ ਭਣੀਐ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਕਾ ਖਸਮੁ ਵਡਾ ਹੈ ਸਭਨਾ ਦਾ ਧਣੀਐ ॥੩੦॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 316 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਭਗਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਪ ਰਾਖਾ ਹੈ, ਪਾਪ ਚਿਤਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ) ਕੀਹ ਵਿਗਾੜ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ? (ਭਾਵ, ਕੁਝ ਵਿਗਾੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ) ਮੂਰਖ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ (ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਰੂਪੀ) ਜ਼ਹਿਰ ਖਾਧਿਆਂ ਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਜਿਸ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਤੇ ਮਾਣ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਦੇ) ਥੋਹੜੇ ਦਿਨ ਆਖ਼ਰ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਪੱਕਾ ਫ਼ਸਲ ਕੱਟੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹੇ (ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਦੇ) ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਦਰਗਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ) ਉਹੋ ਜਿਹੇ ਅਖਵਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਫਲ ਪਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ) ।(ਪਰ) ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਭ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਵੱਡਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ ਦਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਹੈ ।੩੦।\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai manik putus tali\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud air mata yang bercucuran."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Cấm đỗ xe trong hẻm ở Cần Thơ: Người dân thắc mắc vì phường cấm, phường không","answer":"Thời gian qua, người dân ở phường An Phú (quận Ninh Kiều, TP Cần Thơ) phản ánh, tại nhiều con hẻm thuộc địa bàn phường An Phú đã cho đặt các biển cấm đỗ xe, khiến việc sử dụng ôtô của nhiều người gặp khó khăn. Theo ghi nhận của Lao Động, hầu hết các con hẻm ở phường An Phú như hẻm 156 (đường Mậu Thân), hẻm 123, hẻm 133 (đường Trần Hưng Đạo), hẻm 1, hẻm 105 (đường Lý Tự Trọng)… đều có đặt biển cấm đỗ xe. Tuy nhiên, việc này gần như chỉ diễn ra ở phường An Phú, còn những còn hẻm khác ở các phường lân cận thì không bị cấm. Đơn cử như tuyến đường Trần Hưng Đạo, trong khi các con hẻm thuộc bên An Phú đều có biển cấm thì bên phường An Nghiệp phía đối diện lại không đặt biển cấm đỗ xe. "},{"question":"“பலர்புகு வாயில் அடைப்பக் கடவுநர்வருவீர் உளீரோ” தொடர் விளக்கம் தருக.","answer":"தொடர் இடம்பெறும் நூல் : குறுந்தொகைதொடர் விளக்கம் : இல்லத்தில் பலரும் நுழையும் அளவிற்கு உள்ள பெரிய வாயிலை இரவில் மூடுவதற்கு முன்னர், உணவு உண்ண வேண்டியவர்கள் யாரேனும் உள்ளனரா? என்று கேட்கின்றனர்."},{"question":"Опиши Корецький замок","answer":"Напівзруйнований Корецький замок - величне видовище, що дуже відрізняється від сірих руїн решти українських твердинь. Над глибоким фортечним ровом височіє остов в'їзної вежі з червоного каменю, обабіч неї зяють порожніми віконними прорізами фасади палаців. Через міст перекинуто могутній кам'яний міст-віадук. Видно, що не гарматні ядра понівечили ці стіни, не руки ворогів перетворили фортецю на руїни. За­гибель поглинула її зсередини - язиками полум'я пожежі. Перші укріплення звів тут у XV столітті князь Федір Острозький. У XVI столітті Корець став колискою нового дворянського роду - кня­зів Корецьких, одних з перших організаторів Запорізького козацтва. Ко­рецькі не раз перебудовували замок й укріплювали його. Останню реконструкцію замку здійснили в 1780-х роках князі Чар­торийські. Вони перетворили бойову фортецю на ефектний палац у стилі бароко. Замість фортечних стін обабіч в'їзної вежі було зве­дено два палацові крила. На верхньому поверсі вежі замість грізних бійниць з'явилися куранти. Перекидний міст замінили арковим віаду­ком, більш відповідним для урочистих прийомів і гостей у розкішних каретах. Півстоліття Корецький замок слугував резиденцією шляхетського роду Чарторийських: туг влаштовували світські бали, нели політичні пе­ремовини, траплялися і любовні романи. 1832 року в Корецькому замку спалахнула пожежа, і відтоді його не відновлювали. "},{"question":"Ity misy lahatsoratra:Mitondra otrik'aina sy manome hery ny sakafo. Tsy maintsy misakafo toy ny zava-manana aina rehetra ny olombelona. Ary anisan'ny antony iasana ny fitadiavan-tsakafo hameloman-tena.Maro karazana ny sakafo.Ireo vokatry ny famabolena sy ny fiompiana toy ny vary, ny haninkotrana, ny anana, ny akoho amam-borona. Avy amin'izy ireny koa dia mbola mety ahazoana ny koba, ny lafarina, ny atody, ny ronono.Ireo sakafo namboarina avy amin'ny fanodinana ireo vokatra azo avy tamin'ny fambolena sy ny fiompiana dia ny diloilo, ny dibera, ny fromazy.Ny toetran'ireny sakafo ireny dia miankina amin'izay ao anatiny sy ny fomba nandrahoana azy, ka misy ny sakafo mahavelona toy ny ronono, ny atody; ny sakafo mahasolo hena toy ny voamaina; ny sakafo mahavoky toy ny ovy; ny sakafo maivana toy ny mofo; ny sakafo matsiro toy ny trondro, ny vorombe ary ny sakafo mahatofoka dia ireo be fofona na be menaka.Karakaraina tsara ny sakafo, atao madio sy mahate hihinana; amin'izay hazoto homana daholo na ny lehibe na ny kely.Raha io lahatsoratra io, avy aiza avy ny sakafo?","answer":"Raha io fahatsoratra io, ny  sakafo dia avy amin'ny fambolena sy ny fiompiana, ary koa avy amin'ny fanodinana ireo vokatry ny fambolena sy ny fiompiana."},{"question":" ________ канчалык жаңы болсо, ошончолук ________ болот.(А) Автомобилдин маркасы / анын баасы төмөн(Б) Телефондун модели / анын корпусу кичине(В) Китептин басылышы / анын окурмандары көп(Г) Компьютердин модели / анын түрү заманбапКайсынысы туура жооп?","answer":"Туура жооп - (Г).Толук сүйлөм мындай болот: \\"Компьютердин модели канчалык жаңы болсо, ошончолук анын түрү заманбап болот\\"."},{"question":"Maxaa ah caynabinta dhaqanka qabyoqoraalka Soomaaliya?","answer":"Caynabinta dhaqanka qabyoqoraalka Soomaaliya waxay ku jiraan heerarka hadal, suugaan, iyo heerarka dhaqanka qabyoqoraalka."},{"question":"“Tena manatsara ny fahitana tokoa ve ny karaoty?”","answer":"Eny, manankarena vitaminina A ny karaoty, izay tena ilaina amin’ny fahitana tsara."},{"question":"मित्रं प्रीतिरसायनं नयनयोः आनन्दनं चेतसःपात्रं यत्सुखदुःखयोः सह भवेत्मित्रेण तद्दुर्लभम्।ये चान्येसुहृदः समृद्धिसमये द्रव्याभिलाषाकुलाःते सर्वत्र मिलन्ति तत्त्वनिकषग्रावा तु तेषां विपद् ।।-हितोपदेश","answer":"डोळ्यांना प्रेमाचे अमृत (रसायन), मनाला आनंद देणारा, सुखदुःखात सामील होणारा असा मित्र दुर्लभ असतो. समृद्धीच्या काळात तुमच्या संपत्तीवर डोळा ठेवणारे इतर मित्र सर्वत्र मिळतात. संकट हाच त्यांची पारख करण्याचा निकष असतो."},{"question":"Татаал сын атоочтордун жазылышы кандай?","answer":"Кош сөз түрүндөгү татаал сын атоочтордун ортосуна дефисбелгиси коюлуп жазылат.М и с а л ы: чоң-чоң, сулуу-сулуу.Кошмок сөз түрүндөгү сын атоочтордун ортосуна эч кандай белгикоюлбайт.М и с а л ы: абдан сонун, эң күчтүү, чымкый кызыл ж. б"},{"question":"Zer da auzitegiko barrutia?","answer":"Auzitegiko barrutia legezko auzitegi edo epaile batek ezarritako eremua da, non auzitegi edo epaile horrek kasuak aztertzea eta epaitea izan dezakeen. Hau da, legezko gaitasunaren eremua da, eta legeak eta jurisdikzioaren sistema finkatzen du."},{"question":"Күндүн батышын көрүү үчүн эң сонун жер кайсы жерде жайгашкан?","answer":"Туркияда, Фетхие Жер Ортолук деңиз жана Эгей деңизинин ортосундагы жээкте, карагай жана кедр токойлору менен капталган тоолордун этегинде жайгашкан."},{"question":"Uyiphathise omkhulu umyalezo,Kashongo njalo okaBush!Uyididiyele ntokazi yase-Afrika,Wayijuba mame omnyama,Kwagxabhazela izisu emadodeni.Udidiyele kwaphela izinsekaZobumame obamumatha izinyanga,Abantwana babantu abazocoboshiswa.Uyiphakile Nozidumo wakithi,Wanamathela kwabakhulu bakho,Wayikhomba engahlehliyo,Wayisingisa kuNtshebendeIphume ekamabuyaze eyakho,Wayisingisa koSadamuNgolaka nesankahlu seluxu,1. Hlobo luni lwenkondlo lolu? Sekela impendulo yakho.","answer":"-ephiki ngoba ikhuluma ngokuhlabana kweqhawekazielinguNozidumo."},{"question":"Inona ary izany:  anaty rano tsy lena, an-tanety tsy malazo?","answer":"aloka"},{"question":"සප්‍රතිඝ කියන්නේ මොකද්ද ?","answer":"ද්වේශය, තරහව හෝ කළකිරීම සහිත බව"},{"question":"Phân tích một số chi tiết cụ thể (suy nghĩ, cách nhìn nhận về thầy Ha-men và thái độ đối với việc học tiếng Pháp) để làm rõ diễn biến tâm trạng của nhân vật “tôi” trong “buổi học cuối cùng” Ngữ văn lớp 7.","answer":"- Diễn biến tâm trạng của nhân vật “tôi” trong Buổi học cuối cùng” được thể hiện:+ Suy nghĩ:* Cái đầu rỗng tuếch của em trước đó không có chỗ cho những cuốn sách, giờ đây những cuốn sách trở nên thân thiết như người bạn cố tri. * Nếu được chuộc lỗi dù chỉ một lần, một lần tỏ ra không phụ công thầy giáolà “đọc thật to, thật dõng dạc, không phạm một lỗi nào” cái quy tắc về phân từ khi thầy gọi đến thì dù “có phải đánh đổi gì cũng cam”+ Cách nhìn nhận thầy Ha-men:* Cách ăn mặc của thầy: long trọng, trang nghiêm đến mức thầy phải mặc áo rơ-đanh-gốt, đội mũ tròn bằng lụa đen thêu (thường chỉ dùng vào những hôm có thanh tra hoặc phát phần thưởng).* Bài giảng của thầy hôm nay khúc chiết, trong sáng (kể cả môn ngữ pháp rắc rối), như rót vào tai học trò, biến cái khó thành cái dễ một cách đáng ngạc nhiên.* Người thầy “muốn truyền thụ toàn bộ tri thức của mình, muốn đưa ngay một lúc tri thức ấy vào đầu óc chúng tôi”.* Đồ dùng dạy học được thầy chuẩn bị kĩ càng: những tờ mẫu mới tinh, những con chữ viết bằng chữ “rông” của thầy thật đẹp.+ Thái độ học tiếng Pháp:* Chuẩn bị buổi học thì có ý định trốn đi chơi.* Khi nghe thầy nói buổi học cuối cùng được học tiếng Pháp thì Phrăng có phần ăn năn hối lỗi, phải dừng lại một môn học chỉ “mới biết viết tập toạng”…* Trong giờ ngữ pháp hôm nay, chính Phrăng đã kinh ngạc thấy mình sao lại hiểu nhanh đến thế."},{"question":"ما اسم خازن النار؟","answer":"\\tمالك."},{"question":"Eyi ni idi ti mi o fi le sọtan igbesi aye mi- Ibrahim Babangida","answer":"Bi ayẹyẹ ominira ọgọta ọdun Naijiria si ṣe n tẹsiwaju, aarẹ orilẹ-ede yii nigba kan, Ibrahim Babangida, ti tu aṣiri ohun to fa a ti iwe itan igbesi aye ẹ, ati bo ṣe ṣejọba Naijiria ko ṣe ti i jade.Babangida sọ pe o pẹ ti oun ti n ko iwe itan oun jade, ṣugbọn ẹru ile-ẹjọ to ṣee ṣe ki awọn eeyan kan wọ oun lọ gan-an lo n ba oun ti iwe naa ko fi ti i jade.Lọdun 1985 ni Ibrahim Babangida gbajọba lọwọ Aarẹ Muhammed Buhari to wa nipo aarẹ alagbada bayii. Ọkunrin aloku ṣoja yii ṣi wa nipo ọhun titi di ọdun 1993, ko too gbe e fun ijọba fidi-hẹẹ.Ninu awọn aarẹ orilẹ-ede yii ti awọn ọmọ Naijiria yoo nifẹẹ si lati ka itan igbesi aye ẹ ni ọkunrin ologun yii, ṣugbọn Babangida ti sọ pe ko si ki awọn eeyan ma gbe oun lọ sile-ẹjọ, nitori pe o ṣee ṣe ki awọn eeyan kan ṣi oun gbọ, tabi ki wọn sọ pe oun ko kọ nipa awọn bi ọrọ ṣe jẹ gan-an.Babangida ni, ti eyi ba waye, o ṣee ṣe ki oun maa pooyi kootu, bẹe lawọn le fa a fun ọdun marun-un.Lori tẹlifiṣan kan lo ti sọrọ yii nigba ti wọn n bi leere nipa ipo ti Naijiria wa loni-in.Babangida fi kun ọrọ ẹ pe ti oun ko ba lanfaani lati ṣe e nigba aye oun, awọn ọmọ oun le ṣe e daadaa lọjọ iwaju.Bakan naa ni aarẹ tẹlẹ yii ti sọ pe ki ẹnikẹni ma ṣe bu ẹnu atẹ lu awọn ṣoja pe awọn ni wọn ba ijọba Naijiria jẹ. O ni loootọ ni ṣoja ṣe olori orilẹ-ede yii daadaa, ṣugbọn pupọ ninu awọn ileeṣẹ ijọba, awọn alagbada lo n dari ẹ.O ni ti a ba ri ibi to ti ku diẹ kaato, ko ni i dara ti awọn eeyan ba n naka aleebu ẹ si ijọba ṣoja, nitori awọn araalu ti wọn jẹ alagbada gan-an lo n dari pupọ ninu ileeṣẹ ijọba."},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள் :- ஹண்டர் விளையாட்டரங்கம்,அல்லது நியூகாசில் பன்னாட்டு விளையாட்டு மையம்  என்பது ஆத்திரேலியாவின் நியூகாசில் நகரில் அமைந்துள்ள ஒரு பல-நோக்கு விளையாட்டரங்கம் ஆகும். இங்கு நியூகாசில் நைட்சு அணி (ரக்பி), நியூகாசில் ஜெட்சு அணி (காற்பந்து விளையாட்டுகளும் விளையாடப்படுகின்றன. நியூ சவுத் வேல்ஸ் மாநில அரசுக்குச் சொந்தமான இவ்வரங்கத்தை ஹண்டர் பிராந்திய விளையாட்டு ஆணையம் நிருவகித்து வருகிறது. இவ்வரங்கத்தின் முன்னைநாள் நல்கையாளர்களின் விளம்பரங்கள் கருதி, இவ்வரங்கிற்கு முன்னர் \\"மாரத்தான் விளையாட்டரங்கம்\\" , \\"எனர்ஜிஆத்திரேலியா விளையாட்டரங்கம்\\", \\"ஆஸ்கிரிட் விளையாட்டரங்கம்\\"  ஆகிய பெயர்கள் இருந்தன. ஆசியக் கால்பந்துக் கூட்டமைப்பின் 2015 ஆசியக் கிண்ணப்","answer":"போட்டிகளின் போது இது நியூகாசில் விளையாட்டரங்கம் எனவும் அழைக்கப்பட்டது."},{"question":"Rumuskeun eusin pikeun patarosan ieu: Saha anu ngarahkeun pilem Enter The Dragon?","answer":"Anu ngarahkeun pilem Enter The  Dragon nyaéta Robert Clouse."},{"question":"什麼是電擊文庫？","answer":"電擊文庫是1993年6月由MediaWorks創立的輕小說文庫系列。後期合併後，現在為角川公司的文庫書系之一。"},{"question":"Nàn la kurel u basket u Amerig bi gën a siiw tudd ?","answer":"NBA"},{"question":"Las emisiones en definición estándar de BSkyB son compatibles con DVB MPEG-2, con los canales Sky Movies y Sky Box Office, opcionalmente con las bandas sonoras de películas recientes en Dolby Digital, aunque estas solo son accesibles con un descodificador de Sky+. El material de Sky+ HD se emite con MPEG-4 y la mayor parte del material en alta definición utiliza el estándar DVB-S2. Los servicios interactivos y la guía electrónica de programas de 7 días usan el sistema comercial OpenTV, con descodificadores con módems para la ruta de retorno. Sky News, entre otros canales, proporciona un servicio interactivo de pseudovídeo bajo demanda difundiendo secuencias de vídeo en bucle.Genera una pregunta del pasaje anterior.","answer":"¿Qué estándares y tecnologías utiliza BSkyB para transmitir sus emisiones de televisión, tanto en definición estándar como en alta definición, y qué opciones adicionales ofrece para acceder a contenido específico como bandas sonoras de películas en Dolby Digital y servicios interactivos?"},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn ji agunbanirọ atawọn mẹjọ mi-in gbe ni Zamfara","answer":"Ọmọbinrin ẹni ọdun mọkandinlọgbọn kan, Jennifer Iorliam Awashima, agunbanirọ to ṣẹṣẹ n lọ sibi ti wọn yan an si lati ṣiṣẹ sinlu rẹ, ti dero inu igbo, awọn janduku agbebọn ni wọn ji i gbe loju ọna l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii.Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa (NAN), ṣalaye pe akẹkọọ to ṣẹṣẹ gboyejade ninu imọ ede Gẹẹsi lati Fasiti ipinlẹ Benue wa lara awọn ti wọn yan lati ṣiṣẹ sinlu rẹ nipinlẹ Kebbi, ibẹ naa lo n rin irinajo lọ tawọn janduku agbebọn fi ṣakọlu si bọọsi elero mejidinlogun to wọ lagbegbe kan nijọba ibilẹ Tsafe, nipinlẹ Zamfara, ti wọn si ji i gbe.Ẹgbọn ọmọbinrin naa, Arabinrin Awashima, sọ fun Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa (NAN) pe “Awọn agbebọn kan ti ṣakọlu si mọto ero to n lọ si ipinlẹ Kebbi, ero mẹsan-an lo wa ninu mọto naa, gbogbo wọn ni wọn ji gbe, aburo mi si wa ninu wọn, wọn laṣọ ṣọja lawọn agbebọn naa wọ.‘‘Wọn lawakọ naa ro pe awọn ṣọja ti wọn n ṣiṣẹ aabo lagbegbe naa lo da awọn duro ni, eyi lo fi duro nigba ti wọn da a duro, ṣugbọn niṣe lawọn janduku to ku rọ jade lati inu igbo lẹgbẹẹ ibi ti wọn duro si, ni wọn ba ji wọn gbe.‘‘Latigba ti aburo mi ti wọ ọkọ ni mo ti n pe nọmba ẹ, o kọkọ ba mi sọrọ, ṣugbọn nigba to ya, ko sẹni to gbe ipe rẹ mọ. Ẹru bẹrẹ si i ba mi, lọjọ keji ni ọkunrin kan gbe ipe naa, o loun ni dẹrẹba to wa ọkọ naa, ati pe awọn agbebọn ti ṣakọlu sawọn, wọn si ti ji gbogbo ero inu ọkọ naa gbe, o ni nnkan bii aago mẹfa aṣaalẹ niṣẹlẹ naa waye.‘‘A ti lọọ fẹjọ sun awọn ọlọpaa, awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ati ẹka ileeṣẹ awọn agunbanirọ, awọn agbebọn naa ko ti i sọ iye tawọn maa gba rara.”Wọn ni Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa Zamfara ko ti i fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, tori ko gbe ipe rẹ."},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన గద్యాన్ని సంక్షిప్తీకరణ చెయ్యండి:ఆధునిక ప్రపంచంలో చాలా దేశాలు ప్రజాస్వామ్య ప్రభుత్వ విధానాన్ని అనుసరిస్తున్నాయి. ప్రజాస్వామ్య మనుగడకు ఎన్నికల నిర్వహణ అత్యంత ఆవశ్యకం. ఎన్నికల ప్రక్రియలో పాల్గొని తనకు నచ్చిన అభ్యర్థిని ఎన్నుకోవడానికి కావలసిన హక్కును ప్రతి ప్రజాస్వామ్య దేశం తన పౌరులకు కల్పిస్తున్నది. ఈ హక్కునే ‘ఓటు హక్కు’ అంటారు. మన దేశంలో ఓటు హక్కు పొందడానికి కావలసిన కనీస వయస్సు 18 సం.లు. మద్యము, కులము, మతము, ప్రాంతము వంటి వైయక్తిక అంశాలకూ; డబ్బు, బహుమానాలు లాంటి ఎన్నికల తాయిలాలకు లొంగిపోయి తన ఓటును అమ్ముకోకూడదు. సమర్థుడు, నీతిమంతుడు, కుల మతాలకు అతీతంగా అందరికీ అందుబాటులో ఉన్న అభ్యర్థిని గెలిపించడానికి తమ అమూల్యమైన ఓటును వినియోగించుకోవాలి. ఒకవేళ అభ్యర్థు లెవరూ నచ్చకపోతే ‘నోటా’ మీటను నొక్కి రావాలి. అంతేగాని ఎన్నికల ప్రక్రియకు మన దేశ పౌరులు దూరంగా ఉండరాదు.","answer":"నేడు ప్రపంచంలో చాలా దేశాలు ప్రజాస్వామ్య ప్రభుత్వాలను ఇష్టపడుతున్నాయి. ఎన్నికలు ప్రజాస్వామ్య మనుగడకు కీలకం. ప్రజాస్వామ్యంలో పాలకులను ఎన్నుకోవటానికి ఓటు హక్కును కల్పించింది. 18 సంవత్సరాలు నిండిన వారికి ఓటు. వేసే హక్కు ఉంటుంది. కుల, మత, ప్రాంత, డబ్బు, బహుమతులను లెక్కచేయకుండా ఓటు వెయ్యాలి. నీతిమంతుడిని అందరికి అందుబాటులో ఉండే వ్యక్తిని, సమర్ధుణ్ణి ఎన్నుకోవాలి. అలాంటివారు లేకపోతే ఓటు వేసేటప్పుడు ‘నోటా’ మీటను నొక్కాలేగాని ఎన్నికలను బహిష్కరించరాదు."},{"question":"Kedu isi obodo Bauchi Steeti?","answer":"Isi obodo Bauchi Steeti bụ Bauchi"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"anjing hitam\\"?","answer":"Orang jahat yang selalu menunjuk-nunjukkan keburukannya."},{"question":"¿Quién escribió La Odisea?","answer":"La Odisea es un poema de 24 cantos atribuído al poeta griego Homero."},{"question":"Kọ àyọkà l'órí àkòrí yìí: \\"Tinubu fi ọ̀rọ̀ ìtùnú ránṣẹ́, bí aṣọ́lé Super Falcon ṣe bú sẹ́kún torí ìjákulẹ̀ sọ́wọ́ England\\"","answer":"Ikọ̀ agbábọ́ọ̀lù obìnrin n'ílẹ̀ England ti já Super Falcons Nàìjíríà kúrò, ní ìdíje ife àgbáyé àwọn obìnrin tó ń wáyé ní ni Australia.England ló lu Super Falcons pẹ̀lú àmì ayò mẹ́rin sí méjì ní ipele Penalty l'ówǔrọ̀ ọjọ́ Ajé.Ìjákulẹ̀ yìí ló wáyé bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé Super Falcons ló fakọyọ jùlọ láti ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ pẹ̀pẹ̀ ìfẹsẹ̀wọnsẹ̀ naa, nítorí pé se ni England ń tiraka púpọ̀ láti gbéra.Àǹfààní mìíràn tí Nàìjíríà tún ní, ni ìgbà tí adarí ayò fún agbábọ́ọ̀lù England, Lauren James gbà káàdì pupa, lẹ́yìn tó tẹ agbábọ́ọ̀lù Nàìjíríà, Michelle Alozie mọ́'lẹ̀ ní ẹ̀yìn lásìkò tí ayò wọ ìṣẹ́jú mẹ́tàdínláàdọ́rǔn.Ní báyìí, England ti bọ́ sí ipele quarter final ìdíje náà."},{"question":"ማይክሮሶፍት ለዊንዶውስ-10 የሚያቀርብውን የደህንነት ጥገና መቼ አቆማለው አለ?","answer":"ማይክሮሶፍት ለዊንዶውስ-10 የሚያቀርብውን የደህንነት ጥገና በኦክቶበር 2025 ያቆማል።"},{"question":"Waarom zouden we kunstmatige zoetstoffen zoals aspartaam moeten verbieden?","answer":"Kunstmatige zoetstoffen zoals aspartaam zijn ontzettend gevaarlijk voor onze gezondheid. Er zijn talloze studies die de schadelijke effecten ervan op de gezondheid van een persoon laten zien. Een daarvan is de gezondheid van je darmen. Zoals we steeds meer weten over de gezondheid van de darmen, wordt je darmen nu ook wel je 'tweede brein' genoemd. Men zou kunnen beweren dat je zonder een gezonde darmen geen goede gezondheid kunt hebben. We weten dat kunstmatige zoetstoffen zoals aspartaam schadelijk zijn voor onze darmen en ons microbioom."},{"question":"میرے لئے زندگی میں محنت کے بارے میں ایک گانا لکھیں ","answer":"زندگی کی ہارش میں، کام کروں دیر رات تک،محنت کی راہوں میں، قدم رکھوں پاؤں مکمل۔سپنوں کی اڑان میں، جذبات کو سنگ لوں میں،ہار نہیں مانوں گا، ہمیشہ مقابلہ کروں میں۔محنت سے نہیں ہارتا، زندگی کو جیت لیں۔ہمیشہ مقابلہ کرتے جائیں، سپنوں کو پورا کرتے جائیں۔کہتے ہیں مشکل راہوں میں، پھول کھلتے ہیں زراعت کے بعد،تو کوشش کرتا رہ، ہار نہیں مانتا کبھی بھی۔محنت کی سختیوں کا، رنگ ہو جائے گا کامیابی کا،زندگی کے سفر میں، ایک نئی کہانی ہو جائے گی ہماری۔محنت سے نہیں ہارتا، زندگی کو جیت لیں۔ہمیشہ مقابلہ کرتے جائیں، سپنوں کو پورا کرتے جائیں۔ہوشیاری سے چلو، قدم بڑھاتے جائیں۔کامیابی کا راستہ ہے یہ، جس پہ ہم ہمیشہ چلتے جائیں۔محنت سے نہیں ہارتا، زندگی کو جیت لیں۔ہمیشہ مقابلہ کرتے جائیں، سپنوں کو پورا کرتے جائیں۔"},{"question":"অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন |ফরাসি পলিনেশিয়ার অন্তর্ভুক্ত ও দক্ষিণ প্রশান্ত মহাসাগরীয় দ্বীপপুঞ্জ তাহিতির জাতীয় পর্যায়ে প্রতিনিধিত্বকারী ও তাহিতি ফুটবল ফেডারেশন কর্তৃক পরিচালিত তাহিতি জাতীয় ফুটবল দল ২০১২ সালের ওএফসি নেশন্স কাপ প্রতিয়োগিতায় জয়লাভ করে, যা তাদের এ প্রতিয়োগিতায় প্রথম শিরোপা অর্জন। এরফলে দলটি ওএফসি অঞ্চল থেকে","answer":"২০১৩ সালের জুন মাসে ব্রাজিলে অনুষ্ঠিতব্য ফিফা কনফেডারেশন্স কাপে প্রতিনিধিত্ব করবে।"},{"question":"Биологиялык ар түрдүүлүк деген эмне жана ал эмне үчүн айлана-чөйрө үчүн маанилүү?","answer":"Биологиялык ар түрдүүлүк Жердеги тирүү организмдердин жана экосистемалардын ар түрдүүлүгүн билдирет. Бул экологиялык тең салмактуулукту сактоо, экосистемалык кызматтарды көрсөтүү жана планетабыздагы жашоонун туруктуулугун камсыз кылуу үчүн өтө маанилүү."},{"question":"Dime de qué categoría es esta pregunta: ¿Qué guerra duró más: la guerra de Vietnam o la Segunda Guerra Mundial?","answer":"La categoría de esta pregunta es historia."},{"question":"من أول من ركب الخيل؟","answer":"-اسما عيل عليه السلام)."},{"question":"निम्नलिखित वाक्य को पूरा करें: \\"सही मार्गदर्शन मिलने से...\\"","answer":"सही मार्गदर्शन मिलने से हमें अपने लक्ष्यों की प्राप्ति में मदद मिलती है, और हम अपने जीवन को सकारात्मक दिशा में आगे बढ़ सकते हैं। एक अनुभवी मार्गदर्शक से सिखने से हम अपने कौशलो में सुधार कर सकते हैं और नई ऊँचाइयों को प्राप्त कर सकते हैं।"},{"question":"Welk land werd uitgesloten voor het WK voetbal in 2022?","answer":"Rusland, vanwege de invasie in Oekraïne eerder het jaar."},{"question":"ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੀਆਂ ਨਹਿਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਲੰਬਾਈ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਨਹਿਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਲੰਬਾਈ 14500 ਕਿਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਹੈ !"},{"question":"भारतीय स्वतंत्रता संग्राम के महान नेता 'नेताजी' के नाम से कौन जाने जाते थे?","answer":"सुभाष चंद्र बोस भारतीय स्वतंत्रता संग्राम के महान नेता 'नेताजी' के नाम से जाने जाते थे।"},{"question":"O México venceu quantas Copas do Mundo?","answer":"O México ainda não conquistou nenhuma Copa do Mundo."},{"question":"వ్యాపార లక్ష్యాలు గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"వ్యాపార ధ్యేయాలను ఆర్థిక, సాంఘిక, మానవత మరియు జాతీయ ధ్యేయాలుగా విభజించవచ్చును.1) ఆర్ధిక ధ్యేయాలు:లాభార్జన.ఖాతాదారుల సృష్టి.సాంకేతిక అభివృద్ధి.2) సాంఘిక ధ్యేయాలు:నాణ్యమైన సరుకు అందుబాటులో ఉంచి సరఫరా చేయుట.ఉద్యోగులకు న్యాయమైన ప్రతిఫలము.ఉద్యోగ అవకాశాల కల్పన.ప్రభుత్వానికి సహకారము.సాంఘిక సంక్షేమము.3) మానవత ధ్యేయాలు:యాజమాన్యానికి, పనివారికి మధ్య సహకారము.పనివారి సంక్షేమము.మానవ వనరుల అభివృద్ధి.యాజమాన్యములో పనివారు పాల్గొనుట.4) జాతీయ ధ్యేయాలు:జాతీయ అవసరాలకు అనుగుణముగా వస్తువుల ఉత్పత్తి.సహజ వనరుల అభిలషణీయమైన వినియోగము.వెనుకబడిన ప్రాంతాల అభివృద్ధి.చిన్నతరహా పరిశ్రమల అభివృద్ధి.ఎగుమతులను పెంచి, దిగుమతులను తగ్గించుట."},{"question":"Tại sao ngoài con sáo, tác giả bài thơ Gấu con chân vòng kiềng còn đưa thêm chi tiết “Cả đàn năm con thỏ” cùng nhận xét về “chân vòng kiềng” của gấu con?","answer":"Tác giả muốn người đọc thấy được rằng dường như ai cũng chê bai, cười nhạo đôi chân vòng kiềng ấy khiến cho gấu con xấu hổ gấp bội, khiến cậu tự chê trách bản thân nhiều hơn."},{"question":"வைணவ நெறியைப் பின்பற்றி பக்தியில் சிறந்து விளங்கிய பன்னிரு ஆழ்வார்களுள் இளையவர் மற்றும் இறுதியானவர்","answer":"திருமங்கையாழ்வார் பன்னிரு ஆழ்வார்களுள் இளையவர் மற்றும் இறுதியானவர்."},{"question":"Unsa ang gigamit ni Samson aron sa pagpamatay sa daghang kaaway?","answer":"Si Samson gigamit og iyang gamay nga kusog sa iyang buhok aron sa pagpamatay sa daghang kaaway."},{"question":"I wonder నాయుడుపేట మండలంలో మొదటగా స్థాపించిన మొదటి బ్యాంకు ఏది ?","answer":"నాయుడుపేట, ఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్రములోని శ్రీ పొట్టి శ్రీరాములు నెల్లూరు జిల్లాకు చెందిన ఒక మండలము,మరియు శ్రీ పొట్టి శ్రీరాములు నెల్లూరు జిల్లాలోని ఒక ముఖ్యపట్టణం.ఈ పట్టణ జనాభా సుమారు 50 వేలు.ఇది నెల్లూరు నగరమునకు సుమారు 57 కిలోమీటర్ల దూరంలో ఉంది మరియు చెన్నై నుండి 108 కిలోమీటర్లు, తిరుపతి నుండి 61 కిలోమీటర్ల దూరంలో ఉంది.నాయుడుపేట పట్టణం శ్రీ పొట్టి శ్రీరాములు నెల్లూరు జిల్లాలో ముఖ్యమైన కూడలి.ఈ పట్టణం గుండా చెన్నై,తిరుపతి,నెల్లూరు వంటి నగరములకు రోజూ అధిక సంఖ్యలో ప్రయాణీకులు వెల్తుంటారు.వ్యవసాయంఈ మండలంలో ప్రధాన వానిజ్య పంట చెరకు.దీనితోపాటుగా వరిని కుడా సాగు చేస్తారు.వ్యవసాయానికి కావలిసిన మొటర్శ్ నూ ఎ.కే.బీ బేరీపేట వారు తక్కువ దరకు అద్ద్సారువిద్యా సౌకర్యాలునాయుడుపేటలో మొత్తం 15 పాఠశాలలు ఉన్నాయి. వాటిలో ముఖ్యంగా ఎ.ఎల్.సి.ఎమ్ ఉన్నత పాఠశాల చాలా ప్రత్యేకత సంతరించుకుంది. కారణం ఆంధ్రకేసరి టంగుటూరి ప్రకాశం పంతులు ఈ పాఠశాలలో కొంతకాలం విద్యాభ్యాసం చేశాడు.[1] అలాగే ఒక ప్రభుత్వ జూనియర్ కళాశాల, 1983లో స్థాపించిన ఒక ప్రభుత్వ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల మరియు 6 ప్రైవేట్ జూనియర్, డిగ్రీ కళాశాలలు ఉన్నాయి. ఇక్కడ రెండుగ్రంథాలయాలు ఉన్నాయి.విద్యకు సంబంధించి నాయుడుపేట పట్టణమునకు శ్రీ పొట్టి శ్రీరాములు నెల్లూరు జిల్లాలో మంచి గుర్తింపు ఉంది.రవాణా సౌకర్యాలునాయుడుపేట చెన్నై-కోల్ కతా జాతీయ రహదారి (NH-5) మీద చెన్నై-నెల్లూరు ల మధ్య ఉంది. తిరుపతి,నెల్లూరు, విజయవాడ, చెన్నై, హైదరాబాదు, కర్నూలు, కడప, అనంతపురం, ఒంగోలు, విశాఖపట్నం, బెంగళూరు .. మొదలగు ప్రదేశములకు ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్ర రోడ్డు రవాణా సంస్థ బస్సులు విరివిగా ఉన్నాయి.ఇక్కడ నుంచి చెన్నైకి ప్రతి 20 నిమిషాలకు బస్సు సౌవుకర్యం కలదు,మరియు బెంగళూరుకి కూడా ఆదిక సంఖ్యలో బస్సు సౌకర్యం ఉంది.ఇంకా ప్రముఖ నగరమైన తిరుపతికి ప్రతి 5 నిమిషములకు బస్సులు విరివిగా ఉన్నాయి.పవిత్ర పుణ్యక్షేత్రమైన తిరుమలకు విరివిగా బస్సులు ఉన్నాయి.నాయుడుపేట చెన్నై-విజయవాడ రైలు మార్గములో ఒక స్టేషను. ఇక్కడ నుండి విజయవాడ, చెన్నై, హైదరాబాదు, .. మొదలగు ప్రదేశములకు నిత్యం రైళ్ళ రాకపోకలు ఉన్నాయి.నాయుడుపేట స్టేషనులో ఆగు రైళ్ళు:హైదరాబాద్ ఎక్స్ ప్రెస్.చార్మినార్ ఎక్స్ ప్రెస్.లక్నొ ఎక్స్ ప్రెస్.సర్కార్ ఎక్స్ ప్రెస్.జమ్ము-తావి ఎక్స్ ప్రెస్.డెహ్రడూన్ ఎక్స్ ప్రెస్.నదులుఈ ఊరు స్వర్ణముఖినది ఒడ్డున ఉంది. ఈ నది శ్రీకాళహస్తి మీదుగా..."},{"question":"في أي قارة تقع المملكه السعودية؟","answer":"السُّعُودِيَّة (أو رَسْمِيًّا: الْمَمْلَكَة العَرَبيَّة السُّعُودِيَّة) هي دولة عربية، وتعد أكبر دول الشرق الأوسط مساحة، وتقع تحديدًا في الجنوب الغربي من قارة آسيا، وتشكل الجزء الأكبر من شبه الجزيرة العربية إذ تبلغ مساحتها حوالي مليوني كيلومتر مربع. يحدها من الشمال جمهورية العراق والأردن وتحدها دولة الكويت من الشمال الشرقي، ومن الشرق تحدها كل من دولة قطر والإمارات العربية المتحدة بالإضافة إلى مملكة البحرين التي ترتبط بالسعودية من خلال جسر الملك فهد الواقع على مياه الخليج العربي، ومن الجنوب تحدها اليمن، وسلطنة عُمان من الجنوب الشرقي، كما يحدها البحر الأحمر من جهة الغرب."},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند:  \\"... که اولین شکست قاطع برای نیروی دریایی امپراتوری ژاپن بود، دنبال شد. این نقطه عطف جنگ بود زیرا نیروی دریایی ژاپن قابلیت‌های استراتژیک تهاجمی خود را از دست داد و هرگز موفق به بازسازی نشد. نبرد میدوی در ماه مه سال ۱۹۴۲، ناموفق بودن ژاپن در شکست دادن قاطع متفقین را نشان داد. در نبرد دریای مرجان برخلاف برتری عددی ژاپن، شکست استراتژیک امپراتوری ژاپن رقم خورد. این عقب‌نشینی در ژوئن ۱۹۴۲ با از دست دادن فاجعه بار چهار ناوگان در ...\\"","answer":"نبرد میدوی ژاپن در جنگ جهانی دوم"},{"question":"Akụkọ ebe akpalaokwu pụtara ihe","answer":"Na mgbe mbụ,mgbe elu bụ ala ọsa,mgbe ezi dị n'ukwu ụkwa, ụmụ nwanyị na-enwe afọ ọnụ dị ka ụmụ nwoke. Afọ ọnụ ụmụ nwanyị na-etokwa ogologo karịa nke ụmụ nwoke. Ọ na-amakwa mma nke ukwuu ma n'eke zarị zarị. Ọ bụ otu nwanyị mere nke a jiri kwụsị n'ihi àgwà ọjọọ ya nke mere ka agba ụmụ nwanyị n'amị ziri ziri karịa ọkwụrụ. "},{"question":"(තමලු ලිය) කව්සිළුමිණේ තියෙනව මුහුලසනෙන් තමලු ලිය කියල , කොණ්ඩය තමාල වැලක් වගේ අර්ථය, ඒ මොනාද තාමාල වැල්  කියන්නෙ?","answer":"සිංහල සාහිත්‍යයේ වැඩිපුරම අවස්ථාවල තමාල හඳුන්වන්නේ වැලක් හැටියට. මේ පිළිබඳව උදාහරණ රාශියක් ඇතත් ඉන් කිහිපයක් පමණක් විමසා බලමු. දෙවිනුවර ඉරුගල් කුලයට අයත් තිලක පිරුවන් හිමි ලියූ කෝකිල සන්දේශයේ එන මාර්ග වර්ණනාවක, 42 වන කවිය, වැල්ලේමඬමින් ඹබ්බෙහි වන රොදක් අඟනකට සමාන කරමින් එහි ඇති තමලු ලිය හෙවත් වැල් ගැන සඳහන් කරනවා.විකසිත තමලු ලිය මල් බර කියඹු වැළීඅකණු නිතඹ පුල් වනඟන කරන තිළීඑක සර සරන පැහ සර රෑන සැදි කිළීදැක තට සිතෙයි සැක නොවැ ලෙළෙන මිණී වැළීසිංහල බෝධි වංසයේත් තමලු ලිය කියලයි හඳුන්වන්නේ. බුත්සරණේ “සරහා එළවන ලද්දා වූ, තමලු ලිය සේ නිල් වූ සුවඳ ඇත්තා වූ කේශ කලාපයන් ඇති” යනුවෙන් පවසමින් තමලු තද කොළ පැහැති එමෙන්ම සුවඳ හමන වැල් වර්ගයක් බව පවසනවා. තමල් ගැන සඳහන් වෙන තව එකතැනක් තමයි මුඛවෙටි තනතුරක් දැරූ අලගියවන්න ලියූ සැවුල් සංදේශයේ, කුරුවිට වන වර්ණනාවේ එන 133 වෙනි කවිය. මෙහිදී වනපෙත කාන්තාවකට සම කරමින්, වන පෙතේ තමල් නමැති නිල් වරල ගැන කියනවා.තමල් නිල් වරල් බිඹු වැළ රත අදරසුපුල් නිල් උපුල් නෙත් තිසර රතන බරකොවුල් කුල් තෙපුල් සුහුඹුල් රඹ වටොරළකල් කල් සෙදුල් වන ගළ බල මිතුරතොටගමුවේ ශ්‍රී රාහුල හිමියන් පරෙවි සන්දේශයේ, උක්ගල්බැවුල වන වර්ණනාවේ 117 කවියේ ද “සුපිපි මලී බමර දැලි තමලු වැලී මලා මැලී” කියලා තමාල වැලක් ලෙස නම් කරනවා. ශ්‍රී රාහුල හිමියන් කාව්යශේඛරයේ “තමලු” යන්න කිහිප විටක්ම යොදනවා. කාව්යශේඛරයේ දෙවැනි සගේ 26 වැනි කවියේ “තමලු ලිය සිරි රැපැයි ළකලේ” කියලා තමලු වැලක් ලෙස දක්වනවා. කාව්යශේඛරයේ සිව්වන සගේ 23 වන කවියේ තමලු වරලසට රූපකයක් ලෙස ගන්නේ “තමලු වරලස නිලුපුලන් නෙත් සුරත් බිඹු වැළ ලවනතේ” කියලා. ශ්‍රී රාහුල හිමියන් කාව්යශේඛරයේ පස්වන සගේ 18 වන කවියේ “තමලු ලියගොමු පෙළින් මනහර” ලෙස කියමින්, තමලු වැල් බවත් ඒවායින් ලියගොමු හැදෙන බවත් හඟවනවා. සිංහල බෝධි වංසයේ, “තමලු ලියෙන් සැරහුණා වූ වීථියෙහි අන්ධකාරයෙන් රාත්‍රියේ භාගයක් වැනි වූ” කියමින් මේ අඳුරු පැහැති වැලක් බව අඟවනවා. ගීත ගොවින්දයේ තමාල තද කොළ පැහැති කොළ ඇති ශාඛයක් ගැන කතා කරන බව පෙනුනත්, සිංහල සාහිත්‍යයේ තමල් කාන්තාවන්ගේ වරලසට සමාන කිරීමෙන් එය වැලක් බව ගම්‍යමාන කරනවා."},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de paragraaf: Als lid van de Republikeinse Partij van Amerika was hij in 1928 afgevaardigde op de conventie namens Rhode Island en werd tevens in dat jaar in de Senaat van Rhode Island gekozen. Hij had daarin 6 jaar zitting totdat hij zijn zieke vrouw wilde bijstaan. In 1939 werd hij gekozen als gouverneur van Rhode Island. In 1941 echter werd hij niet herverkozen door gebrek aan partijsteun en trad wederom in dienst bij de Amerikaanse Marine nu Amerika in oorlog was gekomen. Hij bereikte de rang van kapitein en diende in de Panamakanaalzone","answer":". Nadien trok hij zich terug op een boerderij in Williamstown in de staat Massachusetts waar hij uiteindelijk op 79-jarige leeftijd aan kanker overleed."},{"question":"2022 ට සාපේක්ෂව හම්බන්තොට ජාත්‍යන්තර වරායෙහි (HIP) RORO පරිමාවන් සියයට 25 කින් වැඩි වීමට හේතු වී ඇති සාධක මොනවාද?","answer":"RORO වෙළුම්වල ඉහළ වර්ධනයට හම්බන්තොට ජාත්‍යන්තර වරායෙහි කැපවීම, වෙහෙස මහන්සි වී වැඩ කිරීම සහ ජාත්‍යන්තර ප්‍රමිතීන්ට අනුකූල වන නව උපකරණ සඳහා ආයෝජනය කිරීම, RORO සඳහා ප්‍රමුඛ පෙළේ ප්‍රතිනැව්ගත කිරීමේ වරායක් ලෙස එහි ස්ථානය තහවුරු කරයි."},{"question":"David Mark","answer":"David Alechenu Bonaventure Mark (bíi ní Oṣù kẹrin Ọdún 1948) jẹ́ ológun tí ó ti fẹ̀hìntì àti olóṣèlú ọmọ orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà tí wọ́n dìbò yàn wọlé gẹ́gẹ́ bí aṣojú Ìpínlẹ̀ Benue ní ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin àgbà ti ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ aṣojú ní ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin lẹ́yìn tí ó wọlé látàrí ètò ìdìbò ti oṣù kẹrin ọdún 2007 lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú People's Democratic Party. Ó jẹ́ ààrẹ ní ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin.A bí Mark si ìlú Otukpo ní ìpínlè Benue ni osù kerin odun 1948. O lo si ilé-ìwé St. Francis Catholic Practicing ko to look since ilé-ìwé àwon ologun. Léyìn náà, o tun lo kàwé ni Nigeria Defense Academy. Wón so di 2nd Lieutenant ni odun 1970, wo si tun so di Captaini ni odun 1971, ótún padà di alaga Abandoned Properties implementation Committee ni iwo ilà oòrùn ni odun 1976.Mark jé olori Ministry of Communication àti àwon èka rè: Nigerian Telecommunications Limited(NITEL) àti Nigerian Postal Service(NIPOST).A yan Mark gégé bi ààré ilé ìgbìmò asofin àgbà ti Naijiria ní ojó kefa, osu Kefa odun 2007.David tún díje fun Senato agbègbè Benue South lekan si ni osu kerin odun 2011, a si yan fun isejoba kerin. David so pe idibo àwon eniyan ni o gbé depo, o si so fún àwon olutako rè láti sisé papò láti tún Nàìjíríà se.Nígbà ti àwon ilé ìgbìmò asofin un tún òfin Nàìjíríà se, Mark so fun àwon Senato tó kù rè láti fi àwon omo Nàìjirià si wajú ara won.Léyìn ìgbà ti àwon orílè-èdè United Kingdom satako si Nàìjirià, won si so pé wón ma se idaduro si àwon iranlowo ti wón un fun Nàìjirià. Mark so pe ki wón fi iranlowo won pa mó.Ni osu kesan odun 2018, Mark ni ipinu láti díje fun ipò ááre orílè-èdè Nàìjirià, o si yan Zainab Abdulkadir Kure ati Abba Ejemni si egbe ti o ma sé idari ipolongo ìdíje rè.O feran eré idaraya golf, tennis àti Squash. O je Christieni, èyà Idoma sì ni èyà rè. O ni ìyàwó merin sí marun.Mark ni ilé àti Helicopter ati ìbi ibalesi fún Helicopter."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'hitam-hitam tahi minyak dimakan juga, putih-putih hampas kelapa dibuang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud barang yang buruk tetapi berguna disimpan tetapi barang yang cantik tidak berguna dibuang"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిభౌతిక ప్రపంచం ","answer":"ప్రకృతిలోని మూల నియమాలు, విభిన్న దృగ్విషయాలలో ప్రత్యక్షమయ్యే వాటి స్వయం వ్యక్తీకరణలను అధ్యయనం చేసే విజ్ఞానశాస్త్రపు విభాగాన్ని భౌతిక శాస్త్రముగా పరిగణించవచ్చు."},{"question":"\\"Nahatonga ahy tara tamin'ny fivoriana ny fahatapahan'ny fifamoivoizana, ary kivy aho.\\"Ahoana no amaritan'ilay fehezanteny ny fihetseham-po?","answer":" Ny fehezan-teny dia mamaritra ny fihetseham-po ratsy toy ny mijanona amin'ny fifamoivoizana niteraka fahasorenana ary niafara tamin'ny fahatarana tamin'ny fivoriana."},{"question":"Inona no notenenin'i Kolonely Richard RATSIMANDRAVA mahakasika ny fanahy?","answer":"Hoy i Kolonely Richard RATSIMANDRAVA : \\"Ny fanahy maha olona dia nahatonga antsika Malagasy lalandava hiaro ary hanaja ny zon'olombelona rehetra na iza na iza\\"."},{"question":"ලෝකයේ මුලින්ම මුදල් නෝට්ටු භාවිතා කළ රට චීනය ජයග්‍රහණයට පියවරුන් සියයක් සිටින අතර පරාජය අනාථයෙකි","answer":"ජෝන් එෆ් කෙනඩි"},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?- Ñu ne: \\"Ñaanal nu sa Boroom mu leeral nu luy meloom\\". - Mu ne: \\"Naka Moom nee na: nag la wu gel, wu fees, woo xam ne dees na beg ci xool ko .\\".","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:- Ñu ne: \\"Ñaanal nu sa Boroom mu leeral nu lu'y meloom\\". - Mu ne: \\"Naka Moom nee na: nag la wu gel, wu fees, woo xàm ne dees na beg ci xool ko.\\"."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Den 21 februari 1998 upphöjde påve Johannes Paulus II Pujats till kardinal \\"in pectore\\"; tre år senare erhöll han Santa Silvia som titelkyrka. Han deltog i konklaven","answer":"2005, vilken valde Benedikt XVI till ny påve."},{"question":"Tunjukkan resipi untuk ayam goreng mangga dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 2 keping dada ayam, 5 sudu besar tepung gandum,  2 sudu besar tepung jagung, ½ sudu kecil lada sulah, Sedikit garam, Minyak masak untuk deep fry, 1 biji mangga muda atau separa masak, 4 biji cili padiBahan sos: 2 sudu besar sos plum, 2 sudu besar sos cili Thai, ½ cawan air, Gula dan garam secukup rasaCara penyediaan:1. Potong ayam nipis-nipis, bersihkan dan tuskan. Gaulkan ayam dengan lada sulah dan sedikit garam.Perapkan 15 minit.2. Kupas mangga muda, buang biji, kemudian sagat. Hiris nipis cili padi.3. Campurkan tepung gandum dan tepung jagung di dalam pinggan.Cara memasak:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali.2. Guling-gulingkan kepingan ayam yang telah diperap di dalam tepung, kemudian goreng secara deep fry sehingga garing.3. Angkat, tuskan dan ketepikan.4. Untuk membuat sos, campurkan semua bahan sos di dalam periuk. Masak sehingga pekat. Soshendaklah ada rasa manis, untuk mengimbangi rasa masam mangga muda.5. Setelah sos sejuk, masukkan parutan mangga dan cili padi . Gaul rata biar mesra rasa.6. Satukan semua bahan di dalam pinggan hidangan sejurus sebelum dihidang - letak ayam ke dalampinggan, kemudian letakkan parutan mangga di atas ayam, dan akhir sekali tuangkan saki baki sos."},{"question":"එක්සත් ජනපදය හෝ සෝවියට් සංගමය හැර වෙනත් රටකින් ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩා උළෙලේ වඩාත්ම ජයග්‍රහන ලබාගත් ක්‍රීඩකයා  කවුද?","answer":"එක්සත් ජනපදය හෝ සෝවියට් සංගමය හැර වෙනත් රටක ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩකයින් අතරින් වඩාත්ම දක්ෂ ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩකයෙකු වන්නේ ෆින්ලන්තයේ Paavo Nurmi ය. නුර්මි, \\"පියාඹන ෆින්\\" ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලැබුවේ, 20 වැනි සියවසේ මුල් භාගයේදී තරග වැදුණු මැදි දුර සහ දිගු දුර ධාවකයෙකි. ඔහු 1920 සිට 1928 දක්වා පැවති ඔලිම්පික් උළෙලේදී රන් පදක්කම් 9 ක් සහ රිදී පදක්කම් 3 ක් දිනා ගත්තේය.තවත් ඉහළ දක්‍ෂ මලල ක්‍රීඩකයෙක් වන්නේ ජැමෙයිකාවේ උසේන් බෝල්ට් ය. බෝල්ට් බොහෝ විට ඉතිහාසයේ වේගවත්ම මිනිසා ලෙස සලකනු ලබන අතර, ඔහු 21 වන සියවසේ ධාවන ඉසව්වල ආධිපත්‍යය දැරීය. ඔහු ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩා තුනක් (2008, 2012, සහ 2016) පුරා මීටර් 100, මීටර් 200 සහ මීටර් 4x100 සහය දිවීමේ ඉසව්වලින් ඔලිම්පික් රන් පදක්කම් 8ක් දිනාගෙන ඇත.ඔලිම්පික් උළෙලේ කැපී පෙනෙන සාර්ථකත්වයක් අත්කර ගත් විවිධ රටවල තවත් ක්‍රීඩක ක්‍රීඩිකාවන් කිහිප දෙනෙක් සිටින අතර, එය අවසානයේ රඳා පවතින්නේ පදක්කම් සංඛ්‍යාව, වාර්තා පිහිටුවා ඇති හෝ ක්‍රීඩාවට ඇති බලපෑම අනුව යමෙකු \\"වඩාත්ම සාර්ථක\\" යන්න නිර්වචනය කරන්නේ කෙසේද යන්න මතය."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నకు జవాబు ఇవ్వండి:  ‘ఫ్లయింగ్ సిక్కు’ అని ఎవరిని పిలుస్తారు?","answer":"మిల్కా సింగ్"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Aza mahatoky tena ho be _ ka hitelina _ zavoka\\" ","answer":"Aza mahatoky tena ho be vavavody ka hitelina voana zavoka.  "},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 福井県大野市にある自然保護センターでは、毎年冬の今ごろ、建物の外に「野鳥レストラン」という名前の鳥の餌の台を置いています。来た人は建物の中から窓の外の鳥をよく見ることができます。センターの周りは90cmぐらい雪が積もっています。餌を探すのが難しくなるため、「野鳥レストラン」にはたくさんの野鳥が来ます。ヤマガラやシジュウカラ、コガラが来て餌のヒマワリの種を食べていました。森の中ではほかの鳥やリスも見ることができて、遊びに来た家族などが写真を撮っていました。石川県から来た男性は「初めて来ましたが、鳥を近くで撮ることができたり、リスも見ることができたりして楽しかったです」と話していました。この「野鳥レストラン」は2月28日まで開いています。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。"},{"question":"\\"જોઈને જાણે, વાણીએ નહીં. \\" નો અર્થ શું છે?","answer":"\\"જોઈને જાણે, વાણીએ નહીં.\\" નો અર્થ: દેખાવ પરથી અંદાજ લગાવી શકાય છે."},{"question":"ما عدد عناصر العينة لتجربة سحب بطاقتين مع الإستبدال من مجموعة بطاقات مرقمة من 1 إلى 8؟(أ) 36 (ب) 45(ج) 64 (د) 80","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة (ج) 64."},{"question":"ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਵਿਗਿਆਨ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਕੀ ਮੰਨ ਕੇ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਵਿਗਿਆਨ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਰਾਜਨੀਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਲੀ ਮੰਨ ਕੇ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Ai એટલે શું? ","answer":"AIનું પૂરું નામ (Full Form) \\"Artificial Intelligence\\" છે જેનું ગુજરાતીમાં ઉચ્ચારણ \\"આર્ટિફિશિયલ ઈંટેલીજેન્સ\\" છે. AIનો અર્થ:- આર્ટિફિશિયલ ઈંટેલીજેન્સ એટલે કૃત્રિમ બુદ્ધિ, એક એવી બુદ્ધિ જેને માણસે બનાવી છે. એક એવું મશીન જેમાં કૃત્રિમ બુદ્ધિ હોય તે માણસ જેવુ જ કાર્ય કરી શકે છે અને માણસ જે કામ સોંપે તે પ્રમાણે તેનું કામ કરે છે, આ મશીન કોઈ દિવસ થાકતું નથી અને તેની જાતે જ તેને જે કાર્ય સોંપેલા છે તેને પૂરા કરે છે.એક એવું મશીન જે માણસની જેમ વર્તે છે અને માણસ તેનો ઉપયોગ કરીને પોતાનું જીવન સહેલું બનાવ છે."},{"question":"Ao amin'ny kilasy matematika, misy mpianatra telo: Alice, Bob ary Carol. Nahazo naoty ambony indrindra tamin’izy telo i Alice. Nahazo isa ambony noho i Carol i Bob.Inona no azontsika tsoahina avy amin’ireo fanambarana etsy ambony ireo?A. Carol no nahazo isa ambony indrindra.B. Nahazo isa ambony indrindra i Bob.C. Nahazo ny marika tsara indrindra i Alice.D. Bob sy Carol mitovy isa.","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia C. Nahazo ny naoty ambony indrindra i Alice."},{"question":"ইউরোপের ইতিহাস বিস্তারিত বর্ণনা করো।","answer":"ইউরোপ– বিশেষ করে প্রাচীন গ্রিস পাশ্চাত্য সংস্কৃতির পীঠস্থান। ইউরোপ পঞ্চদশ শতকের শুরু থেকে আন্তর্জাতিক বিষয়াবলিতে প্রধান ভূমিকা পালন করে, বিশেষ করে উপনিবেশবাদ শুরু হবার পর থেকে। ষোড়শ থেকে বিশ শতকের মধ্যে ইউরোপীয় দেশগুলোর বিভিন্ন সময়ে আমেরিকা, অধিকাংশ আফ্রিকা ও ওশেনিয়া এবং অপ্রতিরোধ্যভাবে অধিকাংশ এশিয়া নিয়ন্ত্রণ করে। আঠারো শতকের শেষভাগে গ্রেট ব্রিটেনে শিল্প বিপ্লব শুরু হয়। এর ফলে পশ্চিম ইউরোপ এবং অবশেষে বৃহত্তর বিশ্বে আমূল অর্থনৈতিক, সাংস্কৃতিক এবং সামাজিক পরিবর্তন ঘটে। প্রথম বিশ্বযুদ্ধ (২৮ জুলাই ১৯১৪ – ১১ নভেম্বর ১৯১৮) এবং দ্বিতীয় বিশ্বযুদ্ধ (১ সেপ্টেম্বর ১৯৩৯ – ২ সেপ্টেম্বর ১৯৪৫) মূলত ইউরোপকে কেন্দ্র করে সংঘটিত হয়, যার ফলে মধ্য বিশ শতকে বৈশ্বিক বিষয়াবলিতে, পশ্চিম ইউরোপের আধিপত্যের অবসান ঘটে এবং মার্কিন যুক্তরাষ্ট্র ও সোভিয়েত ইউনিয়ন তাদের প্রাধান্য বিস্তার করে। স্নায়ুযুদ্ধের সময়ে ইউরোপ লৌহ পর্দা বরাবর পশ্চিমে ন্যাটো ও পূর্বে ওয়ারশ চুক্তি দ্বারা বিভক্ত ছিল। ১৭৩০ সাল থেকে ইউরোপ ও এশিয়ার মধ্যে ভৌগোলিক সীমানা কোনো আন্তর্জাতিক সীমারেখা অনুসরণ করেনি। ইউরোপীয় একত্রীকরণ দ্বিতীয় বিশ্বযুদ্ধের পরে শুরু হয়। রাজনৈতিক বা অর্থনৈতিক রেখায় ইউরোপকে সংগঠিত করার প্রচেষ্টায় ভূ- রাজনৈতিকভাবে নাম ব্যবহার শুরু হয়। ১ জানুয়ারি ১৯৫৮ গঠিত ইউরোপীয় ইউনিয়ন সীমিতভাবে ২৮টি সদস্য রাষ্ট্রকে বোঝায়। আর ৫ মে ১৯৪৯ গঠিত ৪৭টি সদস্য রাষ্ট্রের কাউন্সিল অব ইউরোপ দ্বারা ব্যাপক ইউরোপকে বোঝায়। এর কিছু দেশ উরাল ও বসফরাস রেখা পার হয়ে যায়, যেগুলো সাইবেরিয়া এবং তুরস্কের অন্তর্ভুক্ত। ব্রিটিশ দ্বীপপুঞ্জের মানুষ 'মহাদেশীয়' বা 'মূল ভূখণ্ড' ইউরোপকে ইউরোপ বলে বুঝিয়ে থাকে। ১৯৯১ সালে সোভিয়েত ইউনিয়ন ভেঙে ১৫টি স্বাধীন প্রজাতন্ত্রের সৃষ্টি হয়। অনুরূপভাবে ১৯৯২ সালে চেকোস্লোভাকিয়া ভেঙে চেক প্রজাতন্ত্র ও স্লোভাকিয়া নামক ২টি রাষ্ট্র এবং ১৯৯১ সাল থেকে যুগোস্লাভিয়া ভেঙে ৭টি রাষ্ট্র পরিণত হয়। দেশগুলো হলো— ১. ক্রোয়েশিয়া, ২. স্লোভেনিয়া, ৩. মন্টিনিগ্রো, ৪. বসনিয়া অ্যান্ড হার্জেগোভিনা, ৫. মেসিডোনিয়া, ৬. সার্বিয়া এবং ৭. কসোভো।এরপর থেকে উভয় সংগঠন পূর্বদিকে বিস্তৃত হয়। ইউরোপীয় ইউনিয়ন আজকাল তার সদস্য দেশগুলোর উপর ক্রমবর্ধমান প্রভাব বিস্তার করছে। অনেক ইউরোপীয় দেশ নিজেদের মাঝে সীমানা এবং অভিবাসন নিয়ন্ত্রণ বিলুপ্ত করেছে।"},{"question":"Di mana terletaknya Tanah Tinggi Cameron?","answer":"Tanah Tinggi Cameron (bahasa Inggeris: Cameron Highlands) merupakan sebuah daerah dan pusat peranginan tanah tinggi di Pahang, Malaysia. Cameron Highland terletak setinggi 1,829 meter dari aras laut dan bersuhu antara 10°C hingga 20°C.Tanah Tinggi Cameron mula diterokai oleh Sir William Cameron sekitar tahun 1885 di mana pada ketika itu beliau sedang melakukan pemetaan persempadanan Pahang-Perak. Terdapat tiga mukim dalam daerah Cameron Highland iaitu Ringlet (5,165 hektar), Tanah Rata (2,081 hektar) dan Ulu Telom (63,981 hektar). Manakala terdapat beberapa bandar dan pekan seperti Ringlet, Tanah Rata (pusat pentadbiran tempatan), Brinchang, Lembah Bertam, Kea Farm, Tringkap, Kuala Terla dan Kampung Raja.Terletak di bahagian barat laut negeri Pahang, jarak Cameron Highlands dengan beberapa bandar utama seperti Kuala Lumpur dianggarkan sejauh lebih kurang 200 kilometer, 355 kilometer dari Kuantan atau 90 kilometer dari bandar Ipoh, Perak. Cameron Highlands boleh diakses dengan menggunakan kenderaan sama ada melalui Tapah atau Simpang Pulai dari negeri Perak, melalui Gua Musang dari negeri Kelantan atau melalui Sungai Koyan dari negeri Pahang."},{"question":"බිලියනයකට වඩා වැඩි ජනගහනයක් සිටින සහ ලෝකයේ මුළු ජනගහනයෙන් සියයට 36 ක් පමණ සිටින රටවල් දෙක කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඉන්දියාව සහ චීනය යනු බිලියනයකට වඩා වැඩි ජනගහනයක් සිටින රටවල් දෙක වන අතර, ඒවා එක්ව ලෝක ජනගහනයෙන් සියයට 36ක් පමණ වේ."},{"question":"Quem é deus grego do amor?","answer":"Eros."},{"question":"Nitori irẹsi idaji apo, awọn aṣọbode yinbọn pa Tunde ni Yewa, wọn nijọba apapọ ti ni kawọn maa pa ẹni tawọn ba ri ẹru ofin lọwọ rẹ ","answer":"Tunde Alabe ni wọn pe orukọ ẹ, gende to ṣi niyaa ati baba laye ni. O niyawo pẹlu, ṣugbọn l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu keji, ọdun 2021, ododo arẹwa ọkunrin yii rẹ danu, wọn ni awọn kọsitọọmu yinbọn pa a l’Ebute Igbo-Ọrọ, nitosi Ilaro, nipinlẹ Ogun, lasiko ti wọn ni wọn ba idaji apo irẹsi lọwọ ọdọ kan.Ohun to ṣẹlẹ gan-an gẹgẹ bi aṣofin to n ṣoju ẹkun Yewa keji nile-igbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ogun, Ọnarebu Wahab Egungbohun, ṣe wi ni pe ki i ṣe Tunde nikan ni wọn pa o. O ni awọn ọdọ mi-in naa tun wa ti wọn ba iṣẹlẹ yii rin, ohun to si fa a ko ju pe wọn ni ẹnikan ninu wọn ni idaji apo irẹsi ilẹ okeere lọwọ, ni wọn ba kọju ibọn si wọn.Egungbohun sọ pe, ‘‘Tunde lọọ ra epo bẹntiroolu ni fun jẹnẹretọ ẹ ni,  jẹẹjẹ ẹ lo n bọ ki wọn too yinbọn pa a.‘’Wọn lawọn kan gbe idaji apo irẹsi lọwọ ni wọn tori ẹ bẹrẹ si i yinbọn. Ohun tawọn kọsitọọmu yẹn sọ ni pe ijọba apapọ ti sọ pe kawọn maa pa ẹni tawọn ba ba ri ẹru ofin lọwọ ẹ. Ṣugbọn ti wọn ba n yinbọn fẹni to ni irẹsi lọwọ, kin ni wọn waa fẹẹ ṣe fẹni to gbe ibọn AK 47 dani.‘‘Awọn Fulani lo n gbe ibọn kiri yẹn, wọn ko ti i ri ẹni kan ṣoṣo mu ninu wọn pẹlu gbogbo  nnkan to n ṣẹlẹ yii, wọn o dẹ yinbọn pa wọn.‘‘Wọn ko wọnu ilu lati gba awọn ti Fulani n da laamu silẹ, ṣugbọn apapọ awọn kọsitọọmu, ṣọja ati imigireṣan yii le wọnu igbo lati maa wa onifayawọ kiri. Ẹnikẹni ti wọn ba ti ri, wọn maa yinbọn fun un ni. ‘‘Kinni yii ti n ri bẹẹ tipẹ ti ijọba dakẹ lori ẹ, ti wọn ko ṣe nnkan kan si i. Gbogbo awọn to n ṣe fayawọ yii naa kọ ni ko kawe, awọn to kawe jade nileewe giga wa ninu wọn, airiṣẹ ṣe lo jẹ ki wọn maa ṣe fayawọ kiri. Ẹyin tẹ ẹ le lọọ kogun ba onifayawọ ninu igbo, ẹ maa gbọ pe Fulani n paayan laarin ilu, ẹ o ni i lọ sibẹ. O baayan lọkan jẹ pupọ’’’Ibi kan ti wọn n pe ni Ọlajogun, ni wọn ti yinbọn pa ibẹ lawọn aṣọbode naa ti yinbọn mọ ẹni ti ko mọwọ mẹsẹ, to jẹ ile-epo lo ti n bọ jẹẹjẹ rẹ lai ba ẹnikẹni fa wahala kankan gẹgẹ bi Ọnarebu Wahab ṣe wi.Nigba to n sọrọ nipa iye eeyan to ku ninu ikọlu awọn Fulani to waye ni Orile-Igboro lọjọ Ẹti to kọja yii, Ọnarebu yii sọ pe eeyan mẹta lawọn ti ri oku wọn lọjọ Satide ti i ṣe ọjọ keji iṣẹlẹ naa.O ni awọn mẹjọ wa nileewosan nitori ada tawọn Fulani ṣa wọn. Awọn olori ilẹ kan naa wa to ni awọn ko ri, ibomi-in si wa to jẹ ọkọ ni wọn yoo ri, ti iyawo ti ba rogbodiyan Fulani naa lọ.O ni wọn dana sunle, wọn ba dukia ọpọ eeyan jẹ, wọn si ṣe bẹẹ tan, wọn na papa bora.Ọjọ ti ai le sun dọkan yii yoo dopin nipinlẹ Ogun, paapaa nilẹ Yewa, lawọn eeyan ibẹ n reti. Wọn ni bawọn ṣe n padanu ẹmi sọwọ kọsitọọmu lawọn Fulani naa n ṣe tiwọn, bẹẹ, ko jọ pe olugbeja kan wa nitosi lasiko yii, nitori awọn ko ri ọwọ ijọba lasiko iṣoro awọn."},{"question":"Yaya sunan babban kamfanin taba a duniya?","answer":"Big Tobacco"},{"question":"અહીં એક ગુજરાતી કવિતા ની શરૂઆત ની પંક્તિઓ નીચે આપેલી છે: વહેલી સવારે હું તો ભીની થઈ,બની ઝાકળ તું ક્યાં ક્યાં અડકે.વરસાદ તું ક્યાંયે ના કેમ આજે વરસે?આ કવિતા ની આગળની પંક્તિઓ લખો.","answer":"વહેલી સવારે હું તો ભીની થઈ,બની ઝાકળ તું ક્યાં ક્યાં અડકે.વરસાદ તું ક્યાંયે ના કેમ આજે વરસે?ભીની તરબોળ થઈ પાલવ નીચોવતાં,નૈનોનાં નીર બની ટપકે.વરસાદ તું ક્યાંયે ના કેમ આજે વરસે?કૂવે ગઈ’તી હું પાણીડા ભરવા,ગાગરનાં જળમાં તું છલકે.વરસાદ તું ક્યાંયે ના કેમ આજે વરસે?બળબળતા તાપમાં રણમાં ખોવાણી હું,મૃગજળનું ટીપું થઈ ચમકે.વરસાદ તું ક્યાંયે ના કેમ આજે વરસે?સાજનની વાટ જોઈ ચોમાસા વીતે,એની યાદો તો રોજ રોજ વરસે.વરસાદ તું ક્યાંયે ના કેમ આજે વરસે?શ્યામ તણો રંગ લઈ મેઘમાં છૂપાયો તું,રાધા સંગ રાસ રમી મલકે,વરસાદ તું ક્યાંયે ના કેમ આજે વરસે?"},{"question":"Siapakah digelarkan Bapa Perpaduan di Malaysia? ","answer":"Tun Hussein Onn"},{"question":"Oğlak burcunun en güzel özelliği nedir?","answer":"Oğlaklar ciddilikleri, tutuculukları ve güçlü iradeleri ile tanımlanırlar. Çalışkanlıkları ile kolaylıkla başkalarının saygısını kazanırlar. Gerçek bir Oğlak'ın iki temel özelliği vardır. Güvenilirlik ve dürüstlük."},{"question":"问题：三星耳机的连续播放时间如何？","answer":"答案：三星耳机的连续播放时间因型号和使用方式而异，通常在几个小时至数十个小时之间。"},{"question":"Abairt 1: Leabharlann na Comhdhála agus WorldCat taifid i ndáiríre don mhac (1915 - 1971 ) ainmniúil a bhaineann le Grover C. Halls agus an teaghlach araon. Baineann taifid Leabharlann na Comhdhála agus WorldCat dá mhac (1915 - 1971) go ainmniúil le Grover C. Halls agus leis an teaghlach. Ceist: An léiríonn abairt 1 agus abairt 2 an bhrí chéanna? ","answer":"Sílim go gciallaíonn na habairtí an rud céanna, ach tá easpa comhthéacs orm. "},{"question":"என் வகுப்பில் படிக்கும் அனைவரும் புதிய புத்தகம் வைத்திருந்தனர். இராமனும் புதிய புத்தகம் வைத்திருந்தான். எனவே, இராமன் என் வகுப்பு மாணவன் – இக் கூற்று.அ) உண்மைஆ) பொய்இ) உறுதியாகக் கூறமுடியாது","answer":"அ) உண்மை"},{"question":"Inona ny anaran'ny lalana arahan'ny Samurai tany Japon ? ","answer":"Ny Bushido no nanantsoina ny fitsipika sy lalana narahan'ny Samurai tany Japon. "},{"question":"全国には生き物の形をした銘菓がたくさんあります。鯛せんべいは千葉県発祥、鳩サブレーは神奈川県発祥ですが、ひよ子まんじゅうの発祥はどの都道府県でしょうか？","answer":"福岡県です。"},{"question":"\\"Ny fiandrasana tsy tapaka mba hifanaraka amin'ny fomban-drazana sy ny fomba amam-panao dia mametra ny fitomboka  maha-olona ahy.\\" Inona ny fihetseham-po lazain' io fanambarana io?","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia milaza fihetseham-po ratsy satria mamaritra ny fomba fanerena hifanaraka amin'ny fomba ny fianakaviana ka mety hanakana ny fampandrosoana manokana sy ny fanehoan-kevitra ho an' ny tena."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 暖かい海にいるジュゴンは、日本では沖縄のまわりに少しいると言われています。将来いなくなる心配がある動物です。NHKは今年8月から今月まで沖縄の伊良部島の海で、大学などと一緒にジュゴンがいるか調べました。海の中に置いたマイクに、ジュゴンが草を食べるときに出ると考えられる音が録音してありました。海にあった動物のふんから、ジュゴンのDNAも見つかりました。沖縄のまわりの海でジュゴンが写った映像などは今までもありました。しかし、1960年代にジュゴンを捕まえたという記録のあと、生活していることがわかるふんなどが見つかったのは初めてです。専門家は「ジュゴンが生活していることがはっきりわかったことは、ジュゴンを守るために大事な発見です」と話しています。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。"},{"question":"Акридоксеналар булар ...","answer":"Акридоксеналар (Acridoxena) - айман чегирткелердин бир уруусу."},{"question":"ما هي الاجابة الصحيحة لهذا السؤال: أي لعبة من ألعاب كرة القدم لشركة \\"إي أيه سبورتس\\" يظهر فيها كريستيانو رونالدو على الغلاف؟","answer":"يظهر كرستيانو رونالدو على غلاف لعبة فيفا 2018، وهي لعبة من ألعاب كرة القدم التابعة لشركة \\"إي أيه سبورتس\\".  "},{"question":" Inona no atao hoe toekarena mifantoka ary inona no fiantraikan'izany eo amin'ny fiainantsika andavanandro?","answer":"Ny toekaren'ny fifantohana dia manondro ny fifaninanana hisarihana ny sain'ny olona amin'ny toekarena nomerika, izay misy fiantraikany amin'ny fomba fanjifantsika ny vaovao sy ny fifandraisantsika amin'ny teknolojia."},{"question":"गणतन्त्रको बारेमा केहि भन।","answer":"गणतन्त्र (ल्याटिन बाट: Res Publica - जनताको तन्त्र अथवा जनताको राज्य) एउटा यस्तो देश हो जहाँको शासनतन्त्रमा सैद्धान्तिक रूपले देशको सर्वोच्च पदमा आम जनताबाट कुनै पनि व्यक्ति पदासीन हुनसक्छ। यस प्रकारको शासनतन्त्रलाई गणतन्त्र भनिन्छ। \\"लोकतन्त्र\\" अथवा \\"प्रजातन्त्र\\" गणतन्त्र भन्दा फरक हुन्। लोकतन्त्र त्यस शासनतन्त्रलाई भनिन्छ जहाँ वास्तव मै सामान्य जनता वा तिनको बहुमतका इच्छाले शासन चल्ने गर्दछ। आज विश्वका धेरैजसो देशहरू गणराज्य छन् र साथसाथै लोकतान्त्रिक पनि छन्। नेपाल सङ्घीय लोकतान्त्रिक गणतन्त्रात्मक राज्य हो।"},{"question":"'විස්මිත ගල්වඩුවාණෙනි ඔබහට අප ණයගැති නොවෙදෝ' විස්මිත යන විශේෂණය, මෙතනදී ගල්වඩුවාට ගැලපේද?","answer":"ගැලපේ. ගල් වඩුවාගේ නිර්මාණයන් විස්මයජනක නිසා ඔහුගේ නමට ඉදිරියෙන් විස්මිත යන නාම විශේශනය යෙදීම සුදුසුය."},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa yinbọn pa Baba Ifa niluu Ajaawa, wọn tun gbe iyawo ati dẹrẹba rẹ lọ","answer":"Titi di ba a ṣe n sọ yii, ara ko ti i rọ okun, bẹẹ ni ko ti i rọ adiẹ niluu Ajaawa, nijọba ibilẹ Ogo-Oluwa, nitosi Ogbomọṣọ, nipinlẹ Ọyọ.ALAROYE gbọ pe niṣe ni awọn ọlọpaa ya wọ ilu naa lalẹ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i yinbọn lakọ lakọ. Asiko ti wọn n yinbọn yii ni wọn yinbọn pa Olori awọn onifa niluu naa, Ifalẹyẹ Jayeọla, beẹ nibọn wọn tun pa ẹni kan, ti ọpọ eeyan si fara pa yannayanna.Awọn araalu naa ko tete mọ pe ọlọpaa ni wọn pẹlu bi wọn ṣe dabọn bolẹ, ajinigbe ni wọn pe wọn. Mọto Siena mẹta la gbọ pe wọn gbe wọ abule naa, bi wọn si ti debẹ ni wọn n yinbọn ni nnkan bii aago kan oru.Alaga ijọba ibilẹ Ogo-Oluwa, niluu Ajaawa, Ọgbẹni Ṣeun Ojo, ṣalaye fawọn oniroyin niluu Ibadan pe awọn eeyan ni wọn pe oun nipe ijaya pe awọn ọlọpaa ti ya wọnu ilu naa, ti wọn si n yinbọn lakọlakọ. O ni awọn ko kọkọ gbagbọ pe awọn ọlọpaa lo wọ abule naa ti wọn n yinbọn, afigba ti awọn de Area Commander, tawọn si lọ sọdọ DPO, ẹni to fidi rẹ mulẹ pe awọn agbofinro naa forukọ silẹ nibẹ ki wọn too wọ ilu Ajaawa wa lati waa ṣiṣẹ buruku naa.Ojo ni, ‘A fidi rẹ mulẹ pe ọlọpaa tootọ ni awọn eeyan naa, wọn si ni latọdọ ọga ọlọpaa patapata niluu Abuja ni wọn ti wa. Ṣugbọn o jẹ ohun to ya ni lẹnu pe awọn ọlọpaa le deede wọnu ilu bẹẹ, ki wọn si maa yinbọn ti wọn fi da wahala silẹ to fi di pe gbogbo ilu n sa kijokijo kiri.’’Alaga yii ni eyi lo mu ki oun waa fi ọrọ yii lọ lolu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to wa niluu Ibadan. O fi kun un pe eeyan meji lo ti padanu ẹmi wọn, nigba ti awọn bii mẹwaa fara pa."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe \\"mitsapa alahelo\\"?","answer":"ny atao hoe \\"mitsapa alahelo\\" dia maneho ny fiaraha-miory sy mampionona ary manome vola famangiana ho an'ny tompo manjo ny havana aman-tsakaiza"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Velona iray trano, maty iray _\\"","answer":"Toy izao  ny ohabolana feno:Velona iray trano, maty iray fasana."},{"question":"¿Quién fue Luis Antonio Calvo?","answer":"Luis Antonio Calvo (Gámbita, Santander, 28 de agosto de 1882 - Agua de Dios, Cundinamarca, 22 de abril de 1945). Fue un compositor colombiano considerado uno de los más importantes en el ámbito musical de Colombia. La obra de Luis Antonio Calvo está formada por una enorme cantidad de composiciones musicales, en diversos géneros, tanto colombianos como de otros países. "},{"question":"विश्वमा सबैभन्दा बढि कफि उत्पादन गर्ने देश कुन हो?","answer":"ब्राजिल"},{"question":"Inona no nosy lehibe indrindra eran-tany?","answer":" Greenland no nosy lehibe indrindra eran-tany."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Vào năm 1805, một đội quân do Áo dẫn đầu đã bị thất bại nhục nhã trong Trận Austerlitz","answer":"Trận Austerlitz, còn được gọi là \\"Trận Chiến Tam sự\\" hoặc \\"Trận Chiến Cánh đồng Thơm\\", diễn ra vào ngày 2 tháng 12 năm 1805 tại Austerlitz, một khu vực nằm ở Moravia, phía đông của sương mù nước Czech. Napoleon đã thông minh sử dụng thế địa và tạo ra một kế hoạch chiến lược tinh vi trong trận đánh. Ông cho quân đội của mình tấn công quân đội Nga và Áo tại một phần của chiến trường, đồng thời tập trung lực lượng chính để tấn công trực tiếp vào tâm điểm của đối thủ. Khi màn đêm đến, Napoleon đã đè bẹp các lực lượng của Áo và Nga bằng một cuộc tấn công bất ngờ và ghi được một chiến thắng quan trọng.Trận Austerlitz đã đánh dấu một bước ngoặt trong sự nghiệp quân sự của Napoleon và cũng là một trong những trận đánh nổi tiếng của ông. Sự thất bại của Áo và Nga đã làm cho Napoleon tạm thời chiếm ưu thế và tạo cơ hội cho ông mở rộng lãnh thổ và tầm ảnh hưởng của Đế quốc Pháp."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిఏ విధంగా గాజు క్వార్ట్జ్ నుంచి విభిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది?","answer":"గాజు ఒక అస్ఫాటిక ఘన పదార్థం. ఇందులో కణాల అమరిక లఘు విస్తృతి క్రమంలో ఉంటుంది.క్వార్ట్జ్ ఒక స్ఫటిక ఘన పదార్థం. ఇందులో కణాల అమరిక దీర్ఘ విస్తృతి క్రమంలో ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"Àkòrí: Ẹgbẹ́ Òṣèlú Alábùradà (PDP) ta ohùn padà sí ààrẹ̀ Buhari l'órí àwọn arìnrìnàjò Nàìjíríà ní Germany.Pẹ̀lú àkòrí yìí, ṣe àpilẹ̀kọ àyọkà kan.","answer":"Ẹgbẹ́ Òṣèlú Ẹgbẹ́ Òṣèlú Alábùradà (PDP) ta ohùn padà sí ààrẹ̀ Buhari.L'ẹ́yìn tí ààrẹ Buhari sọ nínú ọ̀rọ̀ rẹ̀ sí ààrẹ orílẹ̀-èdè Germany pé ọmọ Nàìjíríà tí ọwọ́ bá tẹ̀ nínú ìgbìyànjú rẹ̀ láti wọ ilẹ̀ Europe lọ́nà àìtọ́ ni yóò dáhùn fún ara rẹ̀.Ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú PDP fèsì sí èyí lójú òpó Twitter wọ́n wí pé \\"èyí kàn ń fi ààrẹ Buhari hàn gẹ́gẹ́ bí adarí tí kó ní ìmọ̀lára fún ẹni tí kò sì bìkítà nípa ohun tí àwọn tó ní ìfọkàn tán sí i.Sí èyí, ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ọmọ Nàìjíríà ti ń fèsì yálà ní àtìlẹ́yìn ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú PDP tàbí lòdì sí ohun tí wọ́n sọ."},{"question":"Кенжекара Калча уулу канчанчы жылдарда жашаган?а) 1851-1924-жж. б) 1878-1934-жж.в) 1859-1929-жж. г) 1800-1870-жж.","answer":"в) 1859-1929-жж."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Tikus biasanya ada empat kaki, tetapi apa tikus yang hanya ada dua kaki?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Mickey Mouse. "},{"question":"Firy ny velarantany ny nosy Bornéo?","answer":"Ny velarantany ny nosy Bornéo dia 736 000 km torandroa."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి పర్యాయ పదాలని ఇవ్వండి: ఆశ్చర్యం","answer":"వింత, విచిత్రము, విడ్డూరం"},{"question":"吉林省撫松縣被人們稱為是哪種藥材之鄉？","answer":"人參"},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Đoàn Phương Anh, 34 tuổi, trú quận Hoàng Mai, vừa bị VKSND Hà Nội truy tố về tội Cưỡng đoạt tài sản, theo Điều 170, Bộ luật Hình sự. Cáo trạng xác định, năm 2018, sau khi ly hôn vợ, anh Chiến, 37 tuổi, Tổng giám đốc một công ty kinh doanh trong lĩnh vực xây dựng, bất động sản, nảy sinh quan hệ tình cảm và sống chung như vợ chồng với Đoàn Phương Anh tại khu đô thị Times City. Trong thời gian này, hai người thường xuyên mâu thuẫn. Đến ngày 13/2/2021, anh Chiến muốn chấm dứt quan hệ tình cảm với Phương Anh nên chuyển đến nơi khác sinh sống. Phương Anh không đồng ý, nhờ người khác tác động, yêu cầu anh Chiến phải đền bù tổn thất tinh thần. Ngày 19/2/2021, hai người lập biên bản thỏa thuận chia tay, thống nhất khi nào có điều kiện anh Chiến sẽ mua cho Phương Anh một căn hộ trị giá khoảng 5 tỷ đồng, mở một cửa hàng thời trang trị giá khoảng một tỷ đồng, lập sổ tiết kiệm 2 tỷ đồng. Đổi lại Phương Anh không được làm phiền anh Chiến. Do dịch Covid-19, việc kinh doanh không thuận lợi, anh Chiến chưa có tiền thực hiện thỏa thuận. Từ tháng 5 đến tháng 11/2021, Phương Anh liên tục gọi điện, gửi hình ảnh nhạy cảm của hai người cho bạn bè, đồng nghiệp, đối tác của anh Chiến, uy hiếp buộc trả hơn 13 tỷ đồng. Ngày 22/10/2021, anh Chiến chuyển cho Phương Anh 250 triệu đồng. Ngày 2/11/2021, hai người hẹn nhau ở một chi nhánh ngân hàng quận Đống Đa. Khi Phương Anh nhận 400 triệu đồng từ anh Chiến, chuẩn bị nộp vào tài khoản cá nhân thì bị công an bắt giữ. Trong quá trình điều tra, anh Chiến đã nhận lại 400 triệu đồng và được gia đình Phương Anh trả 250 triệu đồng. Bị hại không yêu cầu bồi thường, đề nghị giảm nhẹ hình phạt cho Phương Anh *Tên bị hại đã thay đổi. Nguyễn Hưng - Hải Thư","answer":"Tung ảnh nóng tống tiền đại gia - VnExpress"},{"question":"متى تمت إعادة انتخاب الرئيس جورج بوش الابن لفترته الرئاسية الثانية؟","answer":"2004"},{"question":"السؤال: كم استمرت الدعوة السرية؟","answer":"الإجابة: ثلاث سنوات"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو تعريف الصوم لغة؟","answer":"الإجابة: مطلق الإمساك"},{"question":"Menene babban birnin kasar Nicaragua?","answer":"Babban birnin kasar Nicaragua shi ne Managua."},{"question":"Quem venceu a Liga dos Campeões de futebol de 2023?","answer":"O vencedor da Liga dos Campeões de futebol da época 2022/2023 fui o clube inglês Manchester City, tendo vencido a final contra o clube italiano Inter de Milão por 1-0. O golo foi marcado pelo jogador espanhol Rodri."},{"question":"ഞാൻ ഒരു ബൈക്ക് സവാരിക്ക് പോവുകയാണ്. ഞാൻ ഹെൽമെറ്റ് ധരിക്കണോ? ഉവ്വോ ഇല്ലയോ. ","answer":"അതെ, ഹെൽമെറ്റ് ധരിച്ച് മാത്രമേ ബൈക്ക് ഓടിക്കാവൂ. "},{"question":"' ගුණාගුණ ' කියන්නේ,ගුණ+අගුණ= ගුණාගුණ - දකාරාර්ථ වෙන්නේ නැද්ද?","answer":"ගුණ ද අගුණ ද =ගුණ අගුණ"},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து உருளைக்கிழங்கு சமோசா செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:½ கப் கோதுமை மாவு½ கப் மைதா மாவு3 உருளைக்கிழங்கு¼ கப் பச்சை பட்டாணி2 பச்சை மிளகாய்3 பூண்டு பல்1 இஞ்சி துண்டு1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி ஓமம் தூள்½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி சீரகம்½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி மல்லி தூள்½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி கரம் மசாலா½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி சீரக தூள்¼ மேஜைக்கரண்டி மிளகு தூள்½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி ஆம்சூர் தூள்தேவையான அளவு மிளகாய் தூள்தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்தேவையான அளவு உப்புசிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லி","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் பச்சை பட்டாணி, பச்சை மிளகாய், மற்றும் கொத்தமல்லியை தயார் செய்து, இஞ்சி பூண்டை பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் உருளைக்கிழங்கை வேக வைப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அதில் உருளைக்கிழங்கை போட்டு அதை சுமார் 20 லிருந்து 25 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.3. 25 நிமிடத்துக்கு பிறகு அதை எடுத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஒரு பாத்திரத்தில் வைத்து ஆற விட்டு பின்பு அதை எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து லேசாக ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் மசித்து விடவும்.4. பின்பு ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் கோதுமை மாவு, மைதா மாவு, ஓமம் தூள், சிறிதளவு உப்பு, மற்றும் 3 மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய்யை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.5. பிறகு அதில் கொஞ்சம் கொஞ்சமாக தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அதை சுமார் 6 லிருந்து 8 நிமிடம் வரை பிணைந்து அதை நன்கு சப்பாத்தி மாவு பதத்திற்கு கொண்டு வரவும்.6. பின்னர் அதை ஒரு மூடி போட்டு சுமார் 10 லிருந்து 15 நிமிடம் வரை ஊற விடவும்.7. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.8. எண்ணெய் சுட்டதும் அதில் சீரகம், நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் பச்சை மிளகாய், மற்றும் நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட்டை சேர்த்து அதனின் பச்சை வாசம் போகும் வரை அதை வதக்கவும்.9. இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட்டின் பச்சை வாசம் போனதும் அதில் நாம் உரித்து வைத்திருக்கும் பச்சை பட்டாணியை போட்டு அதை சுமார் 2 நிமிடம் வரை வதக்கவும்.10. 2 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதில் நாம் மசித்து வைத்திருக்கும் உருளைக்கிழங்கு, மல்லி தூள், கரம் மசாலா, சீரக தூள், மிளகு தூள், ஆம்சூர் தூள், கொத்தமல்லி, தேவையான அளவு உப்பு, மற்றும் அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப மிளகாய் தூளை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.11. அது வெந்ததும் அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு அதை கீழே இறக்கி வைத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விடவும்.12. இப்பொழுது நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் மாவை எடுத்து அதை சிறு சிறு உருண்டைகளாக உருட்டி கொள்ளவும்.13. பின்பு அதை சப்பாத்தி கல்லில் வைத்து அதை சிறிது அடர்த்தியாக சப்பாத்திக்கு தேய்ப்பது போல் தேய்த்து அதை பாதியாக ஒரு கத்தியின் மூலம் நறுக்கி கொள்ளவும்.14. அடுத்து நாம் பாதியாக வெட்டிய மாவை எடுத்து கூம்பு வடிவிற்க்கு அதை மடித்து அதனுள் நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் உருளைக்கிழங்கு மசாலாவை வைத்து அதை அடியில் மடித்து அதன் ஓரங்களை சிறிது தண்ணீர் வைத்து மூடவும்.15. இவ்வாறு மீதமுள்ள மாவையும் தயார் செய்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.16. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் சமோசாவை போட்டு பொரித்து எடுப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.17. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் சமோசாவை ஒவ்வொன்றாக கடாயின் அளவிற்கேற்ப போட்டு அதை நன்கு பொன்னிறம் ஆகும் வரை வேக விடவும்.18. சமோசா பொன்னிறமானதும் ஒரு ஜல்லி கரண்டியின் மூலம் அதை எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யை நன்கு வடித்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து சுட சுட கெட்சப் உடன் பரிமாறவும்.19. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் மொறு மொறுப்பான உருளைக்கிழங்கு சமோசா தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":" ஒரு நூற்றாண்டை எத்தனை மாதங்கள் உருவாக்குகின்றன?அ) 12ஆ) 120\\tஇ) 1200 \\tஈ) 12000","answer":"பதில்: இ) 1200 மாதங்கள். ஒரு நூற்றாண்டிற்கு மொத்தம் 100 ஆண்டுகளும், ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும் மொத்தம் 12 மாதங்களைக் கொண்டிருப்பதால், ஒரு நூற்றாண்டு 1200 மாதங்களைக் கொண்டிருக்கும் (100 × 12 = 1200 மாதங்கள்)."},{"question":"मल्लकालमा सबैभन्दा बढी मुद्रा निष्कासन गर्ने राज्य कुन हो ?","answer":"मल्लकालमा सबैभन्दा बढी मुद्रा निष्कासन गर्ने राज्य कान्तिपुर हो। "},{"question":"આશા ભોંસલે   વિશે વર્ણન કરો .","answer":"આશા ભોંસલે (જન્મ : ૮ સપ્ટેમ્બર, ૧૯૩૩, સાંગલી, મહારાષ્ટ્ર, ભારત) ભારતીય ફિલ્મ ઉદ્યોગની સૌથી લોકપ્રિય અને સફળ પાર્શ્વગાયિકાઓમાંની એક છે. તેમણે હિન્દી, મરાઠી, બંગાળી, ગુજરાતી, તમિલ, તેલુગુ, કન્નડ અને ઉર્દૂ સહિત ૧૫ ભાષાઓમાં ૧૦,૦૦૦ થી વધુ ગીતો રેકોર્ડ કર્યા છે. તેમને \\"સુરકંઠી\\" અને \\"કોકિલા\\" તરીકે પણ ઓળખવામાં આવે છે.આશા ભોંસલેનો જન્મ સાંગલી, મહારાષ્ટ્રમાં થયો હતો. તેમના પિતા દિનાનાથ ભોંસલે એક ગાયક અને સંગીતકાર હતા. આશા ભોંસલેએ તેમના પિતા પાસેથી ગાવાનું શીખ્યા હતા.આશા ભોંસલેએ તેમના ફિલ્મી કારકિર્દીની શરૂઆત ૧૯૪૯માં કરી હતી. તેમણે તેમના પિતા દિનાનાથ ભોંસલે સાથે \\"મૈં ગાતા ચલા આવ્યો\\" ગીત રેકોર્ડ કર્યું હતું. આ ગીત ફિલ્મ \\"શ્રી ૪૨૦\\"માં હતું.આશા ભોંસલેએ તેમના કારકિર્દી દરમિયાન અનેક સફળ ગીતો ગાયા છે. તેમના કેટલાક સૌથી પ્રખ્યાત ગીતોમાં \\"આજા મને મળ\\" (ફિલ્મ \\"દિલ\\" ), \\"મેરે પ્યારે મુન્ના\\" (ફિલ્મ \\"મુન્નાભાઈ મેમસાહબ\\" ), \\"રેશ્મી રૂમાલો\\" (ફિલ્મ \\"મંગેશ\\" ), \\"તુમ જો નહીં હો\\" (ફિલ્મ \\"ફના\\" ), અને \\"દુનિયા જો તારા ચહેરે\\" (ફિલ્મ \\"બેવફા\\" )નો સમાવેશ થાય છે.આશા ભોંસલેને તેમના કારકિર્દી દરમિયાન અનેક પુરસ્કારો અને સન્માનોથી નવાજવામાં આવ્યા છે. તેમને ૧૫ ફિલ્મફેર પુરસ્કારો, ૨ રાષ્ટ્રીય ફિલ્મ પુરસ્કારો, અને ૧૭ પદ્મ પુરસ્કારોથી નવાજવામાં આવ્યા છે. તેમને ૨૦૦૧માં ભારતના સર્વોચ્ચ નાગરિક પુરસ્કાર, ભારત રત્નથી નવાજવામાં આવ્યા હતા.આશા ભોંસલેને ભારતીય ફિલ્મ ઉદ્યોગમાં તેમના યોગદાન બદલ \\"સુરકંઠી\\" અને \\"કોકિલા\\" તરીકે ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. તેઓ ભારતની સૌથી લોકપ્રિય અને સફળ પાર્શ્વગાયિકાઓમાંની એક છે."},{"question":"*قرص شفاف يشكل الجزء الخارجي للعين ؟","answer":"القرنية"},{"question":"Caruurta uu ka daaho dhawaqa?","answer":"CARUURTA UU KADAAHO DHAWAQA.Waxaa jira calamado digniin hordhac ah oo eey tahay inuu kubaraarugsanado walidka dhawaqa caruurta Waan qaybin doona calamadaha daahida dhawaqa ee caruurta ayado loo eegayo dadooda Caruurta jira  1 sano ilaa 2 sana Hadii cunigadu jiro dada udhaxeysa 12 bil ilaa 24 bil hadana uusan dhawaq ama hadal lahayn wainaad kawalwashaa hadii aad ku aragto calamadahan: maracracayo tilmamaha sida hadii wx farta logu tilmamo ama hadii gacanta lotaago ee by by macsalamo ladhahaayo  1 sanana uu gaaray.hadii uu tilmamta iyo hadal ka uu jecel yahay  tilmaamta jirana ama garay 18 bilwuxuu wajahayaa culeys ah in uusan dhaajin karin cododka gaarayna 18 bilood waxey kutahay culeys inuu fahmo hadalada afka lagayiraa ee fudud Caruurta jira 3 sano ilaa 4 sana Dhaqtar laraadi hadii cunigada oo dhafay dada 2 sano jirka aad ku aragto astamhan wuxuu awodaa kaliya inuu dhaho ama kucelyo hadalada lomeriyo iyo ficilada lasameyo ee kaligiis ( iskiis) uguma dhawaqi karo eray ama jumlad.wuxu kucelcelinaa hadalo iyo erayo kokoban mana awodo inuu adegsado luqada afka si uu usheegto baahidisa ma awoodo inuu fahmo tilmaamaha fudud fahamka ayaa ku adag markii lofiirsho caruurta kudada ah Maxey kadhigan tahay hadii cunigada aad ku aragto calamadahan Mararka qaar hadal ka daaha ee caruurta wuxu noqda mid dabici ah sida inuu cunigada iskubrnayo 2 luqad. Lakin dahida dhawaqa ee caruurta wuxu mujiya jiritanka cudur ama dhibatoyin caafimaad sida:1= Dib udhac maskaxed, ama uu hoseyo maqalkisa, ama dhibato kaheysato dhanka luqada 2= inuu hayo cudur maskaxda ah sida cerebral palsy 3= inuu qabo Autism ( I.a Autism cudur wye maraan kahadli donaa) #muhiim in waqti hore dhaqtar logeeyo lona baro waxey sahlee in lahelo dawada TALOYIN QAABKAN ULA DHAQAN HADII CUNUGA KU ARGTO INU HDLKA KADAHY Waa talooyin ka cawinaya inuu cunigada hormariyo dhawiqisa hadii aad ku aragty astamaha daahida dhawaqa Xooga saar inaad cunigada xariir lasameyo markaad howlaha kala duwan qabaneyso heeso, codod xayawan, iyo tilmamo waxey xojinayan kalsoonida cunugada iyo xirfadisa dhawaqa U aqri cunugada sheekoyin ee beri dheh kuceli una aqri shekoyin udhigma dadiisa walbna wainad uga aqrisa buug leh sawiro iyo kartoono badan waxeey kudhira galine ilmaha yar inuu eego tasawirta marku kucelina si uu umagcwo Uwad ilmaha meelaha qaar sida dukanka super market ka ee umagacaw cuntada u sharax waxad gadanee mgcda Usharax mrkad nadifinee guriga waxad qabnee sdkle marka karine cuntada hais barbardhigin ilmahada wada dhashy waxa laga yabaa cuniga weyn ee 3 jirkaa inusan dhawiqisa fiicneyn halka midkayar ee 1 AMA 2 jirka uu fican yahy arintas waxey badinee dhibka heesta cunuga waxyna kuridee kalsoni daro arinta daahida hdalka haku edeynin naftada ama lamankada hana sababin dhibkle ee xal radiya haisku dayin inaad guriga kubarto cunigada ee geey dhaqtar kutaqusay cudurada dhawaqa iyo luqada hadhihin daweynta cunigan wa qarash badan ee geey dhaqtar Hasugin adgo dhahay hadii waqti uu jogo cuniga wuu ficnana lagybee waqtga sugeysay dhibatada ineey sibadato ee waqti hore geey isbitaal si dawadisa loo helo. "},{"question":"Sallar magariba raka'a nawa ce?","answer":"Raka'a uku ce."},{"question":"ગવર્મેન્ટ ઓફ ઈન્ડિયા એક્ટ ૧૯૧૯ જણાવો","answer":"ગવર્મેન્ટ ઓફ ઈન્ડિયા એક્ટ ૧૯૧૯ - આ અધિનિયમ મોન્ટેગ્યુ-ચેમ્સફોર્ડ સુધારા તરીકે ઓળખાય છે. ‘જવાબદાર સરકાર અને સ્વશાસનલક્ષી સંસ્થાઓનો વિકાસ’ના પાયા પર આધારિત આ એક્ટ દ્વારા બંધારણીય પ્રથામાં અગત્યના ફેરફારો થયા. જેમાં ઈન્ડિયન લેજેસ્લેટીવ કાઉન્સિલના સ્થાને ઊપલું ગૃહ અને નીચલું ગૃહ ધરાવતું દ્વિગૃહી વિધાનમંડળ અસ્તિત્વમાં આવ્યું. આંગ્લ-ભારતીય, શિખ તથા યુરોપીય અને ઈસાઈઓને અલગ પ્રતિનિધિત્ત્વ આપવામાં આવ્યું. ક્ષેત્રીય વિષયોને બે ભાગમાં વિભાજીત કરવામાં આવ્યા : આરક્ષિત અને હસ્તાંતરિત. આરક્ષિત વિષયો ગવર્નર પાસે રહેતા જ્યારે હસ્તાંતરીત વિષયો ભારતીય મંત્રીઓ પાસે રહેતા."},{"question":"Wat voor belangrijke gebeurtenis beschrijft de volgende tekst: In 2016 nam Pandev deel aan de 100 meter op de Olympische Spelen in Rio de Janeiro. Hij won de eerste voorronde, maar was daarna kansloos 9e en laatste in de tweede reeks, waarmee hij zich niet kon plaatsen voor de halve finale.","answer":"Het gaat over Pandev tijdens de Olympische Spelen."},{"question":"Qual o hino da Guiné Bissau?","answer":"Esta É a Nossa Pátria Bem Amada é o hino nacional da Guiné-Bissau. Foi escrito em 1963 por Amílcar Lopes Cabral enquanto lutava pela independência da Guiné-Bissau e de Cabo Verde. Quando visitou a China, Cabral escutou uma música criada pelo compositor local Xiao He e logo o chamou para compor a melodia do futuro hino, que foi adotado durante a declaração de independência do país, em 24 de setembro de 1974."},{"question":"Phrase 1 : Kenny Burke a produit le film avec Taylor et Brown. Phrase 2 : Le film a été produit par Kenny Burke avec Taylor et Brown. Question : Les phrases 1 et 2 expriment-elles le même sens ? Oui ou non ?","answer":"Non, les deux phrases n'expriment pas le même sens."},{"question":"12 sınıf staj ne kadar sürüyor?","answer":"1. Staj süresi; Tüm bölüm ve programlarımızda otuz (30) iş günüdür. 2. Staj hafta da en fazla 6 işgünü (48 saat) yapılabilir. Stajyer öğrencinin haftada 6 günden (48 saatten) fazla çalışması, fazla mesai yapması veya gece vardiyasında çalışması ek staj günü olarak sayılmaz."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи? ","answer":"Албетте, мындай кызыктуу факт Каньо-Кристалес дарыясы - Колумбияда агып жаткан түстүү дарыя.  Дарыянын көрүнүшү асан-үсөнгө окшош. "},{"question":"Kwaba ukwehlukana nje maqede umama wawa ngedolo ecelela izingane zakheintethelelo kuMdali ngoba bengakwazi abakwenzayo. Kanti umama akabuzangaelangeni ngakusasa ekuseni, akenzelwanga ukudla futhi kungekho angakwaziukuzilungiselela kona ngoba umalokazana wathi lokhu okusele sebokulungiselelaintambama. Lokho-ke kusho ukuthi umama wayengenakudla ayezokudla ngalelo langakuze kube ntambama bebuya emsebenzini. Wawa ngedolo umama. Kwashaya ubabawakwakhe emini ebuza impilo, wamthela ngesililo wazibonela naye engesilima ukuthikwenzekani kumkakhe.1. Bhala isisho esitholakala kuleli binzana lamagama alandelayo:Kanti umama akabuzanga elangeni ngakusasa ekuseni …","answer":"… akabuzanga elangeni"},{"question":"Phrase 1 : \\"L'amitié entre lui et Duncan a pris fin lors d'une réunion de club en 1951 lorsque les deux hommes se sont opposés lors d'une réunion annuelle et Duncan a rapporté que Greaves avait déclaré :\\" Phrase 2 : \\"L'amitié entre lui et Duncan a pris fin en 1951 lors d'une réunion de club, alors que les deux ne s'étaient pas mis d'accord lors d'une réunion annuelle. Duncan a rapporté que Greaves avait déclaré :\\" Question : La phrase 1 et la phrase 2 expriment-elles le même sens ? Oui ou Non ?","answer":"Oui, ils expriment le même sens, juste avec l'ordre des mots différents. "},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة الملقبة بسورة القتال؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة محمد"},{"question":"வைத்திருந்தனர் இச்சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது …………………………….வைத்து + யிருந்தனர்வைத் + இருந்தனர்வைத்து + இருந்தனர்வைத் + திருந்தனர்","answer":"விடை : வைத்து + இருந்தனர்"},{"question":"Magbigay ng halimbawa ng Python code na kinukuha ang kabuuan ng dalawang numero.","answer":"Kinukuha ng sumusunod na Python code ang kabuuan ng dalawang numero:num1 = 1.5num2 = 6.3sum = num1 + num2print('Ang kabuuan ng {0} at {1} ay {2}'.format(num1, num2, sum))"},{"question":"Алыкул Осмоновтун калемине таандык ырлардан жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"КАЙЫҢДЫКалды, калды Кайыңды айлым ыраактап,Мен калтардай алыс кеттим кылактап.Мүрү түшкөн жетим куштун канатынАйыктырган сууларыңа ыракмат.Кеткен жолум, күндүк эмес айчылык,Ошондуктан, бир барбадым кайрылып.Чоло тийбей, боорум, калам экөөбүзӨскөн айыл, тууган жерден айныдык.Же эр болбой, сан жигитти башкарып,Же мен болбой, күйгөн оттой каарып,Баарын билбей, жаным, калам экөөбүзБир боор эже, агаларды таштадык.Неге унуттум ууз таза күндөрдү,Кылтак менен кыргый тутуп күлгөндү,Эне-атадан, тууган достон иши жокТаштан белем Алыкулдун жүрөгү.Жок туура эмес, кайда барсам, — айлым бар,Мага эне – казак, кыргыз, орустар.Ким өмүрдө, кан кечишсе биз менен,Ошол болот мага курдаш, мага жар.Эстейм сени, Кайыңды айлым сагынам,Барбайм сага, сагынганда не кылам.Бул турмушта мен атылган күлүк ок,Деңиз, дайра, тоодон өтүп жарылам.Учам алыс, арышым бек чоюлбайт,Такам болот, тамандарым оюлбайт,Тирүү жаным буюрбаган сыяктууМен өлгөндө сөөгүм сага коюлбайт."},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la réewum Guatemala nékk?","answer":"Réewum Guatemala mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Amerique."},{"question":"\\"පන්ති නැති ඉස්කෝලෙ බිඳලා\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"පන්ති නැති ඉස්කෝලෙ බිඳලාජීවිතේ ගැන එපා ටියුෂන්හෝඩියට ආදරේ අරගෙනආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන් ආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන් ගුරුතුමනි ඔබ නො එන දවසකවෘක රෑනක් ඇවිත් මෙබිමට වසන්තය ගෙන ගියා ගොදුරටඔබේ ආදර පුංචි සිසුවියබළල් පැටියා තුරුලු කරගෙන අඬනවා හැමදාම හවසටඅඬනවා හැමදාම හවසටඇගේ හිත කියවන්න දන්නේඔබම පමණයි ගුරුතුමානනිහෝඩියම දන්නැති වුණත් ඔබහෝඩියම දන්නැති වුණත් ඔබසැඳෑ සුළඟේ සැලී වැලපෙනඅතක පොප්ලර් තුරක ශෝකයකවුරු නම් හඳුනයිද ඔබ මිසමේ මහා තණ බිමේ සැඟවුන ඔබේ උත්තම නොකී ප්‍රේමයසසල කරවයි ලොවේ හදවතහිම කුණාටුව දෙබෑ කරගෙන අස්සයා නැතිනම් පයින් වත්සහතිකයි ඔබ නැවත එන වගසහතිකයි ඔබ නැවත එන වගසහතිකයි ඔබ නැවත එන වගපන්ති නැති ඉස්කෝලෙ බිඳලාජීවිතේ ගැන එපා ටියුෂන්හෝඩියට ආදරේ අරගෙනආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන් ආයෙමත් එනවාද දුයිෂෙන්සමන් ලෙනින් රජී වසන්ත වෙල්ගම දර්ශන රුවන් දිසානායක"},{"question":"Premier League: Ta ni yóò gba Premier League láàrin Man City àti Liverpool? Ìdíje Premier League ń yeruku lala.Liverpool fẹ́ gbìyànjú l'áti di ikọ̀ agbábọ́ọ̀lù kejì nínú ìtàn tí yóò gba ife ẹ̀yẹ Premier League mọ́ ikọ̀ tó ń ṣíwájú lọ́wọ́ lọ́jọ́ tí ìdíje náà parí.Liverpool tó ń tẹ̀lé Manchester City pẹ̀lú àmì ayò kan yóò gbàlejò Wolves ní pápá ìṣeré Anfield nígbà tí Man City yóò wakọ̀ pẹ̀lú Brighton ní déédéé aago mẹ́ta ọ̀sán ọjọ́ Àìkú.Man City ti gbayò mọ́kànléláàdọ́rùún sáwọ̀n nínú ìfẹsẹ̀wọnsẹ̀ mẹ́tàdínlógóójì tí wọ́n ti gbà ní sáà yìí nígbà tí Liverpool gba góòlù méjìdínláàdọ́rùún sáwọ̀n.Bákan náà, àwọn méjéèjì súnmọ́ ara wọn pẹ́kípẹ́kí l'órí tábìlì Premier League lẹ́yìn tí Man City ń fi àmì ayò àrùnlélàádọ́rin ṣíwájú tí Liverpool sì wà ní ipò kejì pẹ̀lú àmì ayò mẹ́rìnléláàádọ́rin.Ìgbà kẹjọ rèé tí ìdíje ti ikọ̀ tó gba Premier League yóò fojú hàn lọ́jọ́ tí ìdíje náà parí.Liverpool tó ti pegedé fún àṣekágbá ìdíje UEFA Champions League kò tíì rí ife ẹ̀yẹ Premier League fún odún mọ́kànlélọ́gbọ̀n báyìí.Ẹ̀wẹ̀, Akọ́nimọ̀ọ́gbá Man City, Pep Guardiola ti sọ pé gbágbágbá bí ike l'àwọn alátìlẹyìn City yóò ṣe gbárùkù tìwọ́n nígbà tí wọ́n bá kojú Brighton.Bákan náà, ẹgbẹ́ agbábọ́ọ̀lù Liverpool sọ̀rọ̀ l'ójú òpó Twitter pé, ikọ̀ nàá ti gbìyànjú ní sáà, ohunkóhun tó wù kó ṣẹlẹ̀ lónìí.Man City yóò di ikọ̀ agbábọ́ọ̀lù àkọ́kọ́ tí yóò gba ife ẹ̀yẹ Premier League léra wọn láàrín ọdún mẹ́wàá sẹ́yìn tí wọ́n bá gba ife náà mọ́ Liverpool lọ́wọ́ lónìí.","answer":"Òní lòní ń jẹ́, ẹni a bẹ̀ lọ́wẹ̀! Lónìí ọjọ́ kejila, oṣu Èbìbí ni ìdíje Premier League yóò wá sí ìparí tí a ó sì mọ ikọ̀ agbábọ́ọ̀lù tí yóò gba ife ẹ̀yẹ náà láàrín Manchester City àti Liverpool."},{"question":"Lẹyin ọdun mẹẹẹdogun, ọba tuntun jẹ niluu Fiditi","answer":"Orin ati ijo lo gba ilu Fiditi, nijọba ibilẹ Afijio kan, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, lọjọ Aje, Mọnde yii, ọjọ naa ni Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Ṣeyi Makinde, gbe ọpa aṣẹ ati irukẹrẹ le ọba Oyewọle Sikiru Oyelere lọwọ lati sami si ibẹrẹ iṣakoso rẹ gẹgẹ bii Onifiditi ti ilu Fiditi tuntun.Eto naa waye nileejọba ijọba ibilẹ Afijio, niluu Jobele, ipinlẹ Ọyọ.Ṣaaju, iyẹn lati ọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu kẹta, ọdun 2018, ni ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ, labẹ gomina tẹlẹ, Sẹnetọ Isiaka Ajimọbi, ti buwọ lu iyansipo ọba tuntun yii, ṣugbọn eto gbigba ọpa aṣẹ rẹ ko le waye titi ti iṣakoso naa fi kogba sile lọdun 2019.Ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun 1967, ni wọn bi Ọba Oyewọle Oyelere si idile Ọmọọba Adekunle Oyelere ti i ṣe baba rẹ, ni ila idile ọlọba Asu, Sidikat Abẹkẹ Oyelere ni iya rẹ.Kabiyesi lọ sileewe pamari Baptist Nursery School, niluu Fiditi, ati AUD Primary School, niluu ọhun, ko too kọja si Saint Anthony Primary School, to wa niluu Awẹ lati pari ẹkọ rẹ.O lọ sileewe girama St. Joseph, latigba naa lo si ti n ṣiṣẹ nileeṣe mọnamọna ilẹ wa, NEPA. Ẹnu iṣẹ naa lo wa to fi lọọ kawe ni Ọṣun State College of Technology, ni Ẹsa Oke, nipinlẹ Ọṣun, o si gboye jade ninu imo iṣiro owo (Accountancy).Ko kuro nileeṣẹ NEPA ọhun to fi di ti aladaani, Power Holding Company of Nigeria, PHCN, ati Ibadan Electrical Distribution Company (IBEDC), lẹyin naa lo fẹyinti loṣu keje ọdun yii.Ọpọ ọdun ni ọkunrin naa ti fi ṣatilẹyin fun idagbasoke ilu Fiditi, o wa ninu oriṣiiriṣii ẹgbẹ idagbasoke ilu, ki ori too ṣe e loore, ti wọn yan an sipo ọba yii.Ireti awọn araalu ati adura wọn ni pe igba Ọba Oyelere yii yoo san ilu Fiditi, yoo si tuba-tuṣẹ."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa  ninkii afhayeenka u ahaa asxaabtii u hijrootay ardul Xabash?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Jacfar Bin Abii Daalib Rc."},{"question":"Joxeel péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Daldi potoxlu gìsee'k waakëram, daldi indi aw sëllu wu duuf.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Daldi potoxlu gìsee'k waakëram, daldi indi aw sëllu wu duuf.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Daldi: ADVpotoxlu: VERBgìse: VERBe'k: ADPwaakëram: NOUN,: PUNCTdaldi: ADVindi: VERBaw: DETsëllu: NOUNwu: PRONduuf: ADJ.: PUNCT"},{"question":"ある地域が共産化すると、その隣接地が連鎖反応的に共産化するという理論のことを、あるゲームに例えて何理論というでしょう？","answer":"ドミノ理論"},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng cho câu hỏi sau:Giải pháp quan trọng nhất để ngăn chặn sự 'ấm dần lên của Trái đất' hiện nay là:A. Trồng nhiều cây xanhB. Giảm sử dụng nhiên liệu hóa thạchC. Đẩy mạnh áp dụng công nghệ 4.0","answer":"đáp án BHoạt động của con người đang làm gia tăng lượng khí nhà kính, đặc biệt là lượng khí cacbonic trong không khí đã tăng gần gấp đôi so với thời kỳ đầu của cuộc cách mạng công nghiệp (khoảng năm 1750). Hiện nhiệt độ Trái đất đã tăng 1,1 độ C so với thời kỳ tiền công nghiệp.Theo các dự báo, cho đến giữa thế kỷ này, nếu cân bằng được lượng khí thải nhà kính thì nhiệt độ Trái đất bắt đầu vào thời kỳ ổn định. Khi đó, Trái đất có thể tăng từ 1,5 đến 2 độ C so với thời kỳ đầu của cuộc cách mạng công nghiệp. Nếu nhiệt độ Trái đất tăng 1,5 độ C, điều này tác động tiêu cực đến 7% hệ sinh thái, và nếu tăng ở mức 2 độ C, tỷ lệ đó sẽ tăng gần gấp đôi. Các quốc gia ký Hiệp định Paris về biến đổi khí hậu đã cam kết giới hạn mức tăng nhiệt độ toàn cầu là dưới 2 độ C, và nếu có thể sẽ ở mức lý tưởng 1,5 độ C.Hội nghị Liên Hợp Quốc về biến đổi khí hậu được tổ chức hàng năm. Mục tiêu chung về lượng khí thải nhà kính phải cắt giảm và về giới hạn nhiệt độ tăng đã đạt được từ nghị định thư Kyoto đến Thỏa thuận chung Paris. Nhưng mục tiêu cụ thể, lộ trình, hạn ngạch cắt giảm... vẫn còn chia rẽ sâu sắc (chia rẽ giữa các nước phát triển và đang phát triển, giữa nước lớn và nước nhỏ, giữa nước chịu tác động mạnh của mực nước biển dâng và nước không chịu ảnh hưởng...).Gần đây nhất, Hội nghị lần thứ 26 (COP 26) năm 2021 phút cuối đã không đạt được nghị quyết về lộ trình loại bỏ nguồn nhiên liệu than đá mà chỉ thông qua bản ghi nhớ về nó.Để đạt được mục tiêu về cắt giảm khí nhà kính bắt buộc các quốc gia phải dần thay thế nguồn năng lượng từ nhiên liệu hóa thạch bằng nguồn năng lượng tái tạo như: năng lượng mặt trời, năng lượng gió, năng lượng sinh khối... Bên cạnh đó, kết hợp với các giải pháp riêng lẻ của mỗi quốc gia như: trồng nhiều cây xanh, tái chế vật liệu, thúc đẩy công nghệ 4.0 tối ưu sử dụng năng lượng, giảm năng lượng hao phí..."},{"question":"پیدایش جشن نوروز به چه زمانی بازمی‌گردد؟","answer":"زمان پیدایش نوروز به درستی معلوم نیست، در شاهنامهٔ فردوسی، اینجشن را به تاج گذاری جمشید پادشاه اسطوره‌ای ایران نسبت می‌دهند. این جشن در زمان هخامنشیان در تخت جمشید برگزار می‌شده و پس از آن،سلسله های دیگر نیز نوروز را گرامی داشته‌اند . در هر یک از روزهای عیدنوروز، طبقه ای از مردم به دیدار شاهان می‌آمدند.در عهد باستان، خانواده‌های ایرانی بر سر سفرهٔ نوروزی به درگاه آفرینندهٔ هستی دعا می‌کردند، به یکدیگر هدیه می‌دادند و شادباش می‌گفتند."},{"question":"أجب على السؤال اللي جاي: فين رحت تشرب في وقت الحظر؟","answer":"معذرة، مش عارف السؤال بيشير لمين."},{"question":"චර්ච්-ටියුරින් නිබන්ධනය යනු කුමක්ද සහ එය ඇලන් ටියුරිංගේ කෘතියට සම්බන්ධ වන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"ඇලොන්සෝ පල්ලිය සහ ඇලන් ටියුරින් විසින් නම් කරන ලද පල්ලිය-ටියුරින් නිබන්ධනය, ගණනය කිරීමේ බලය පිළිබඳ මූලික සීමාවක් ස්ථාපිත කරයි. ටියුරිං, විශ්වීය ටියුරින් යන්ත්‍රය පිළිබඳ ඔහුගේ කෘතිය හරහා, ඇතැම් ගණිතමය ගැටලු ඇල්ගොරිතමයකින් විසඳිය නොහැකි බව පෙන්නුම් කරමින් නිබන්ධනයට දායක විය."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي تزوج اثنتين من بنات الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"الإجابة: عثمان بن عفان"},{"question":"ඔලිම්පික් බොක්සිං තරඟයක් විනිශ්චය කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු කාන්තාව කවුද?","answer":"ඔලිම්පික් බොක්සිං තරඟයක් විනිශ්චය කළ ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු කාන්තාව නෙල්කා  ශිරෝමාලා වේ.ශ්‍රී  ලංකා පොලිසිය නියෝජනය කරන කාන්තා ප්‍රධාන පොලිස් පරීක්ෂකවරියක වන ටී. නෙල්කා ශිරෝමාලා නිලධාරිනිය මේ සඳහා සුදුසුකම් ලබා තිබේ. ශ්‍රී  ලංකා පොලිස් දෙපාර්තමේන්තු ඉතිහාසයේද මෙය රන් අකුරින් සටහන් වනු ඇත.ඒ අනුව 2021 වසරේ ජපානයේ තෝකියේ නගරයේ පැවැත්වීමට නියමිත 2020 ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩා තරගාවලියේ බොක්සිං තරග තීරක හා විනිසුරුවරියක ලෙස කටයුතු කිරීමට ඇය තෝරා පත්කරගෙන තිබේ. ගාල්ල රිපන් බාලිකා විද්‍යාලයෙන් අධ්‍යාපනය ලැබූ ඇය 1997 වසරේදී ආධුනික කාන්තා උප පොලිස් පරීක්ෂකවරියක ලෙස පොලිස් සේවයට එක්වූවාය. 2021 වසරේ පොලිස් ක්‍රීඩා සමාජය නියෝජනය කරමින් ජාතික තරගාවලියකට සහභාගි වූ පළමු පොලිස් කාන්තා බොක්සිං ක්‍රීඩිකාව වන්නේද ඇයයි"},{"question":"Em Matemática, o que significa um número inteiro?","answer":"Em Matemática, um número inteiro é um número que não possui parte fracionária. Isto inclui números positivos, negativos e zero."},{"question":"Inona no endrika isehoan'ny matoanteny?","answer":"Ny endrika isehoan'ny matoanteny dia matoanteny fototeny sy matoanteny sampan-teny."},{"question":"Korona: Ijọba ko aadọta eeyan nile-ijo taka-sufee n’Ilọrin","answer":"Fun pe wọn tapa sofin to de ṣiṣi ile-ijo lasiko ajakalẹ arun Korona, aadọta eeyan lọwọ tẹ ni idaji ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, nile itura Kwara Hotels, niluu Ilọrin.  Akọwe iroyin gomina to tun jẹ alukoro igbimọ to n gbogun ti arun yii ni Kwara, Rafiu Ajakaye, lo sọrọ naa ninu atẹjade kan to fi ṣọwọ sawọn oniroyin.O ṣalaye pe Alaga igbimọ to n mojuto eto ilera, Medical Advisory Committee, Dokita Fẹmi Ọladiji, lo fi iṣẹlẹ naa to igbimọ yii leti. Dokita Ọladiji ni ni kete tọwọ tẹ wọn lawọn ko wọn si ibudo iyasọtọ to wa ni ipagọ awọn arinrinajo Hajj niluu Ilọrin. O ni igbakeji Gomina, Kayọde Alabi, to jẹ alaga igbimọ Covid-19 lo dari ikọ to lọọ fi pampẹ ọba ko awọn eeyan ọhun nibi ti wọn ti n ṣe faaji lai bikita nipa ofin to wa nita.“Ni nnkan bii aago kan oru, niroyin tẹ wa lọwọ pe awọn kan wa nile-ijo, nibi ti wọn ti n ṣe faaji nile itura Kwara Hotel. Nigba ta a debẹ a ba awọn ọkunrin atawọn obinrin rẹpẹtẹ tọjọ ori wọn ko ju ogun si ọgbọn lọ.“Arin oru yii kan naa, ni nnkan bii aago meji, la ko wọn de ibudo naa. A jẹ ki wọn farabalẹ sun mọju, a si gba ohun ta a le fi ṣe ayẹwo Korona lara wọn. A maa ṣe ayẹwo wọn lọkọọkan. A tun maa foju wọn bale-ẹjọ ki awọn eeyan le mọ pe ijọba ko ni i faaye gba titapa sofin.”O nijọba yoo gbe igbesẹ to ba yẹ lati ba awọn alakooso ile-itura naa to gba iru nnkan bẹẹ laaye wi."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Under våren 2019 debuterade","answer":"Kobayashi i det japanska seniorlandslaget och blev senare samma år uttagen till VM i Frankrike."},{"question":"Thai! Nkgokolo ya Bopedi meetse o tšea kae","answer":"Legapu"},{"question":"Žalia žolė, bet ne žolė, su uodega, bet ne pelė. Kas?","answer":"Agurkas arba bulvė."},{"question":"ఔషధాలు కృత్రిమంగాగానీ, మొక్కలు, బాక్టీరియా, జంతువులు మొదలైన వాటినుంచి గానీ (సహజసిద్ధమైన ఉత్పన్నాలు) తయారవుతాయి. కొన్ని సమయాల్లో సహజ ఉత్పన్నాల విషప్రభావాన్ని తగ్గించటానికి రసాయనికంగా మార్పులు జరుపుతారు.ఈ క్రిందివానిలో ఏవి సహజమైనవో, ఏవి కృత్రిమంగా తయారు చేయబడినవో తెల్పండి.a) పెన్సిలిన్ …………….b) సల్ఫోనమైడ్ …………….c) విటమిన్ సి …………….d) పెరుగుదల హార్మోన్లు …………….","answer":"a) పెన్సిలిన్ – సహజ ఉత్పత్తిb) సల్ఫోనమైడ్ – కృత్రిమ ఉత్పత్తిc) విటమిన్ సి – సహజ ఉత్పత్తిd) పెరుగుదల హార్మోన్లు – సహజ ఉత్పత్తి"},{"question":"Emotan","answer":"Emotan (15th century) jẹ́ obìnrin olọ́jà tí ó ná Ọjà Oba ní ayé àtijó ní Benin nígbà ìṣàkóso Oba Uwaifiokun àti Omoba Ogun, ẹni tí ó sọ ara rẹ̀ ní \\"Oba Ewuare the Great\\" lẹ́yìn tí ó di Oba of Benin. Òun ni ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ day care centre ní Ìlú Benin; Ìtàn àtenudẹ́nu sọ wípé ó ran Oba Ewuare lọ́wọ́ ní gbígba ìjọba Benin lẹ́yìn ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ọdún tí ó ti wà níta ìlú.Wọ́n bí Emotan (orúko àbísọ rẹ̀ ni Uwaraye), ní Eyaen láàrin ọdún 1380 sí 1400. Lẹ́yìn ìgbà tí ọkọ rẹ̀ kú, ó kó abà kan láti tọjú àwọn ọmọ rẹ̀."},{"question":"Inú bàbá mi kò dùn bí mo ṣe bọ́ aṣọ lórí pápá - Asisat Oshoala","answer":"Gbajúmọ̀ agbábọ́ọ̀lù ọmọ Nàìjíríà ní obìnrin Asisat Oshoala ti ní inú bàbá òun kò dùn sí ọ̀nà tí òun gbà láti fi ìdùnnú òun hàn lẹ́yìn tí òun jẹ góòlù níbi ìfẹsẹ̀wọnsẹ̀ tó bá kọjá.Ní ọjọ́bọ̀ ní ikọ̀ agbábọ́ọ̀lù Super Falcons kojú akẹgbẹ́ wọn láti orílẹ̀ èdè Australia níbi ìdíje ife ẹ̀yẹ àgbáyé àwọn obìnrin tó ń lọ lọ́wọ́ ní orílẹ̀ èdè Australia àti New Zealand.Níbi ìdíje náà ni Asisat Oshoala ti bọ́ aṣọ rẹ̀ lẹ́yìn tó gbá góòlù sáwọ̀n ilé orílẹ̀ èdè Australia láti sọ góòlù náà di mẹ́ta sí ẹyọ̀kan.Ìgbésẹ̀ Asisat Oshoala yìí sì di ohun tí ó fa awuyewuye lórí ayélujára nítorí ìgbésẹ̀ rẹ̀ yìí.Bí àwọn kan ṣe ń kan sáárá sí Asisat Oshoala ni àwọn kan ń bu ẹnu àtẹ́ lu pé kò yẹ kí ó bọ́ aṣọ rẹ̀ kó sì máa fi ara rẹ̀ hàn.Asisat fúnra rẹ̀ náà wá fi sórí Instagram rẹ̀ lọ́jọ́ Ẹtì pé bàbá òun wà lára àwọn tí inú wọn kò dùn wí pé òun bọ́ aṣọ òun lásìkò náà tí òun jẹ góòlù náà.Ó ní bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé inú bàbá òun kò dùn síbẹ̀ ọ̀kan-ò-jọ̀kan àkójọ àwọn nǹkan ìgbà ló ń jẹ́ ayé.Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn olólùfẹ́ Asisat sì ti ń kan sáárá si wí pé àwọn ma ba bẹ bàbá rẹ̀ pé inú àwọn dùn sí góòlù tí ó jẹ náà.Ṣáájú ni Asisat ti fi ìgboyà hàn pé ikọ̀ agbábọ́ọ̀lù orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà táwọn obìnrin ti ṣetán láti fi han gbogbo àgbáyé pé àwọn kẹ̀rẹ̀ rárá tó bá ti di ọ̀rọ̀ bọ́ọ̀lù àfẹsẹ̀gbá.Orílẹ̀ èdè Republic of Ireland ni Nààijíríà yóò tún kojú níbi ìfẹsẹ̀wọnsẹ̀ wọn mìíràn tó ń bọ̀."},{"question":"Wanne ne gaskiya dangane da ƙissa?A)Yara ake yi wa don koyon tarbiyyaB)Tana da alaƙa da addiniC)Dole a samu Gizo da Ƙoƙi a cikintaD)Dole a samu aljanu a cikinta","answer":"B)Tana da alaƙa da addini"},{"question":"在加拿大，G牌驾驶者，初犯者被控酒后驾驶将立即停牌三天，酒精在血液中含量达到或超过多少？","answer":"0.05%"},{"question":"Cé hé Gerhard Domagk? ","answer":"Bithcheimicí a rugadh i Łagów na Polainne (Lagow sa Ghearmáin ag an am) ab ea Gerhard Johannes Paul Domagk (30 Deireadh Fómhair 1895 – 24 Aibreán 1964). Agus é ag déanamh taighde ar líocha is ceimiceán darb ainm prontasail, ag iarraidh na baictéir streipteacocais a dhíothú, fuair sé amach gur athraigh an prontasail go sulfainilimíd sa cholainn, de bhrí go raibh airíonna ceimiteiripeacha ag sulfainilimíd.Bhí ceimiteiripe iontach nua aimsithe aige, agus chuir an t-oibreán seo go mór le teiripe ailsí ina dhiaidh sin. Bhuaigh sé Duais Nobel sa Duais Nobel na Fiseolaíochta nó an Leighis i 1939. Chuir rialtas na Gearmáine cosc air an duais a fháil an bhliain sin, ach bronnadh air é i 1947. "},{"question":"බයිසිකලය නිපදවූයේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"ස්කොට්ලන්ත කම්මල්කරුවෙකු වන කිර්ක්පැට්‍රික් මැක්මිලන්(Kirkpatrick Macmillan), 1830 ගණන්වල පළමු පැඩලයෙන් ධාවනය වන බයිසිකලය සොයා ගැනීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් බොහෝ විට ගෞරවයට පාත්‍ර වේ. නවීන බයිසිකල්වල මූලික අංගයක් වන බයිසිකලය තල්ලු කිරීම සඳහා පැඩල් කිරීම යන සංකල්පය හඳුන්වා දුන් ඔහුගේ නිර්මාණය බයිසිකල් පරිණාමයේ වැදගත් පියවරක් විය.මැක්මිලන්ගේ බයිසිකලයේ ලී රාමුවක් සහ යකඩ දාර සහිත ලී රෝද තිබුණි. ඔහු විසින් නිර්මාණය කරන ලද පැඩල් කිරීමේ යාන්ත්‍රණයට පසුපස රෝදයට සම්බන්ධ වූ දඬු සම්බන්ධ වූ අතර ඒවා ක්‍රියාත්මක වූයේ අසරුවාගේ පැත්තෙන් යම් ආකාරයක ඉහළට සහ පහළට චලනය වන චලනයකිනි. මෙය නවීන පැඩල් වල භ්‍රමණ චලිතයට වඩා වෙනස් විය.මැක්මිලන්ගේ නව නිපැයුම වැදගත් වූවත්, එය වහාම පුළුල් ලෙස සම්මත කර ගැනීමට හෝ සමාන බයිසිකල් නිෂ්පාදනය කිරීමට හේතු වූයේ නැත. බයිසිකලය සංවර්ධනය කිරීම ක්‍රමානුකූල ක්‍රියාවලියක් වූ අතර බොහෝ නව නිපැයුම්කරුවන් කාලයත් සමඟ දායක විය. පැඩල් හඳුන්වාදීම ප්‍රධාන දියුණුවක් වූ නමුත් නවීන බයිසිකලය එහි දාම ධාවකය සහ සම්මත දියමන්ති රාමුව සමඟ 19 වන සියවසේ පසුව වෙනත් නව නිපැයුම්කරුවන් විසින් සංවර්ධනය කරන ලදී."},{"question":"ઓજસ પાલનપુરી ની \\"બીજી તો કોઈ રીતે\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"બીજી તો કોઈ રીતે ના ભૂંસાય ચાંદની,ઝાકળની થોડી બુંદોથી ધોવાય ચાંદની.પીને શરબ ઉભો’તો સપનાય ના જુઓ,તરસ્યા રહીને જાગો તો પીવાય ચાંદની.તું આંખ સામે હોય તો એવુંય પણ બને,ખીલ્યો હો ચંદ્રમા ને ન દેખાય ચાંદની.તાર સ્મરણનું તેજ મને ડંખતું રહે,ઉપરથી પાછી એમાં ઉમેરાય ચાંદની.‘ઓજસ’ ધરે છે કોણ આ દર્પણ ગગન ઉપર,દિવસનું તેજ રાતે બની જાય ચાંદની."},{"question":"Crie um recado para Joana chamando ela para sair","answer":"Oie Joana,Quer sair comigo hoje? Podemos ir a um barzinho, cinema, restaurante, o que você preferir! Se quiser, pode chamar alguma amiga também. Espero te ver hoje. :)[Seu Nome]"},{"question":"\\"T\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ කී වෙනි අකුර ද?","answer":"\\"T\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ විසි වන අකුර යි."},{"question":"Qual o significado de \\"Dar uma mãozinha?\\"","answer":"Significa ajudar de forma ligeira."},{"question":"No anime Dragon Ball Z, quem é Trunks?","answer":"Trunks é o filho de Vegeta e Bulma, conhecido por seu cabelo roxo e seu papel importante em eventos futuros na história."},{"question":"Qui était l'artiste Lygia Clark ?","answer":"Lygia Clark, une artiste brésilienne associée au mouvement néo-béton, a remis en question les notions conventionnelles de l'art en créant des œuvres d'art interactives et participatives. Sa série « Bicho » se compose de sculptures métalliques flexibles que les spectateurs peuvent manipuler, brouillant ainsi la frontière entre l'œuvre d'art et le public."},{"question":"اكتب لي سؤال في السياسة مع اجابته.","answer":"اذكر رئيس للولايات المتحدة الأمريكية من غير أصحاب البشرة البيضاء؟ باراك أوباما"},{"question":"Apakah iklim di Malaysia? ","answer":"Iklim tropika"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'sarang tebuan jangan dijolok'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud jangan mencari bahaya. Contoh ayat: Ibu menasihati David supaya jangan melakukan kerja yang berbahaya kerana buruk padahnya seperti kata bidalan sarang tebuan jangan dijolok."},{"question":"පොසොන් පසළොස්වක පොහොය දින සිද්ධීන් නම් කරන්න.","answer":"පොසොන් පසළොස්වක පොහොය දින සිද්ධීන් පහත දැක්වේ.අනුබුදු මහාමිහිදු මහරහතන් වහන්සේ ප්‍රමුඛ ඉට්ඨිය,උත්තිය,සම්බල,බද්දසාල යන රහතන් වහන්සේලාත්,ෂඩ් අභිඥාලාභී සුමන සාමනේරයන්ද,භණ්ඩුක නම් අනාගාමී උපාසකවරයා යන පිරිස ධර්මවිජය පිළිබඳ අනගිතම පනිවිඩය මූර්ථිමත් කරමින් ශාන්තීය දූතයන් වශයෙන් ලංකාකවේ උතුරුමැද නිම්නයේ අනුරපුර මිස්සක පව්වට වැඩමකර බු:ව 236 දී ලක්දිව බුදුසසුන පිහිටුවීම.බුදු වී සිව්වන සතියේ රුවන්ගෙයි වැඩහිඳිමින් ධර්මය මෙනෙහි කරන බුදුරදුන්ගේ ශරීරයෙන් ප්‍රථම වරට සවනක් ඝණ බුදුරැස් විහිදීම.ලක්දිව ප්‍රථම මහණ උපසම්පදාව වන භණ්ඩුක උපාසක මහණ උපසම්පදාව සිදුවීම.දෙවනපෑතිස් රජු ඇතුළු 40,000 ක් පිරිස චුල්ල හත්ථිපදෝපම  සූත්‍රය අසා තෙරුවන් සරණ යාම."},{"question":"එ දවස් ප්‍රාත...කාලයෙහි සූවිසි කෙල ලක්ෂයක් නයින් ප්‍රතමණ්ඩිත වූ මහා කරුණා සමාපත්තියට.....( තෙවන වචනයේ හිස් තැනට එන්නේ විසර්ගය ,එම වචනයේ තේරුම කියන්න.  )","answer":"උදේ කාලය "},{"question":"नेपाली नागरिकतामा अंग्रेजी भाषामा समेत कहिलेदेखी वितरण गर्न थालियो ?","answer":"नेपाली नागरिकतामा अंग्रेजी भाषामा समेत  २०६६ मंसीर १ गतेदेखि गर्न  थालिएको हो। "},{"question":"Ma’anar Suna a Hausa?","answer":"Suna, kalma ce da ake ambaton mutum, dabba, muhalli, ko wani abu da ita. Wato kenan, duk wata kalma da ake ambato da ita, ta faɗa ajin suna kenan."},{"question":"கேள்வி :தன் வாழ்நாளில் நீரே அருந்தாத மிருகம் எது?","answer":"பதில்:கங்காரு எலி."},{"question":"什么是Spring Boot？","answer":"Spring Boot是一个基于Java的开源框架，用于创建独立的、生产级别的Spring应用程序。它旨在简化Spring应用的初始设置和开发过程。"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa calaamadaha xanuunka qaaxada ama dhaxanta (TB) iyo dadka halista ugu jira?","answer":"Waxa aynu qormadeena maanta ku falanqayn doonaa xanuunka qaaxada ama TB-da. Xanuunkani waxa uu ku dhici karaa badi xubnaha jidhkeena. Waxa aynu si gaar ah ugu eegaynaa qaybteenan maanta dhaxanta (pulmonary TB).Cudurkani waa mid ka mid ah kuwa laga bogsado isla markaana ku jira xanuunada ugu badan ee faafa, keenana dhimasho aad u badan. Cudurkani waxa uu aad ugu badan yahay qoomiyado kala duwan oo ay Soomaalidu ku jirto. Waxa ay Hay’adda Caafimaadka Adduunku (WHO) shaacisay in ku dhawaad 12,000 oo qof laga helo xanuunkan dhulka soomaalidu degto sanad kasta.Xanuunkan waxa keena nooc ka mid ah bacteria-da oo loo yiqaano mycobacterium TB. Ilma aragtaydan way ka dhib badan tahay marka loo eego difaaceena iyo habka loo baadhaba, ilma aragtayga kale. Waxa ay leedahay dux culus (xaydh) oo u sahasha In ay u adkaysato degaanka iyo weerarka hab-dhiska difaaca bini aadmiga. Waxa la aaminsan yahay in dadku ay yihiin keydka qudha ee bacteria –dan.Waxa uu xanuunkani ku fidaa hawada halkaas oo qof qaba xanuunka hindhisada ama qufaciisu ay geliyaan hawada, mid kale oo caafimaad qabaana ka qaado, sidaana ay ku tagto sambabada. Cudurkan laguma kala qaado dharka oo la wadaago, weelka cuntada,  gacan qaadka iyo wixii la midka ah.Bacteria-dan yar inaad qaado waxa jaan gooya dhawr qodob:-Xadiga bacteria da ah ee lagu sii daayay hawadaRibanaanta bacteria-daMuddada uu u bandhigmay qofku bacteria-da Difaaca qofkaDhaqankeena waxa laga aaminsanaa xanuunkan in uu ceeb yahay dadkana lagu faquuqo. Taasi waxa ay kor u qaadaa tirada uu haleelayo xanuunkani iyada oo ay ugu wacan tahay bukaanka oo is qarinaya si aan loo irdhayn.Xanuunkan waxa halis dheeraad ah ugu jira dadyawga ay ka mid ka yihiin:-Hawl wadeenada caafimaadDadka la nool macaankaDadka qaba HIV/AIDSKalyaha oo hawl gabaXubnaha oo loo beero qofkaNafaqo darradaNoocyada kala duwan ee balwadahaInaga bulsho ahaan waxa kor u qaada halista xanuunkan goobaha lagu wada qayilo/ kolayada jaadka.Marka ay soo gasho bacteria-dan jidhkeena waxa qabta difaaceena. Marka aynu eegno qofka hab dhiskiisa difaac xoog yahay, difaaciisu  waxa uu dahaadhaa unugyada ay ku jirto bacteria du si aanay u sii socon waxa kale oo uu ku wareejiyaa unugyo gaar ah oo ka tirsan difaaca. Hadii uu ka adkaado sidaas ayay ku dhimata, hadii kalena waxa ay sugtaa in mar uun uu hoos u dhaco  difaacu si ay u keento xanuunka. Qasab maaha qof kasta oo jidhkiisa ay ku jirtaa inay ka cawdaan astaamaha xanuunkan.Astaamaha xanuunkani leeyahay ayaa ah:-Qufac qalalan oo ka badan muddo 3 todobaad ahLaabta oo xanuuntaMararka qaar waxa uu tufi karaa qofku dhiigDaal badanMiisaanka oo lumaXumadQadh-qadhyoDhidid habeenkii u badanXanuunkan waxa lagu baadhaa habab kala duwan oo ay ka mid yihiin:-Dhiiga oo la baadhoRaajada laabta ( chest X-ray)Candhuufta oo la baadhoMaqaarka oo laga eegoWaxa xanuunkan lagu daweeyaa daawooyin kala duwan oo isku dhafan. Waxa ay leeyihiin hanaan gaar ah oo lagula dagalaamo in ay bacteria-du iska caabiso. Dawadan waxa lagu qaataa goob caafimaad iyada oo uu ku arkayo hawl wadeen caafimaad ( direct observed therapy).Dawooyinkan ayaa ah bilawga hore 4 dawo oo la qaato mudo laba bilood ah. Bukaanku hadii uu ku ladnaado dawooyinkaa waxa laga joojiyaa 2 ka mid ah dawooyinka TB da, waxa uuna sii wadaa 2-da kale muddo 4 bilood ah. Hadii uu qof ku ka soo rayn waayo ama baadhitaanada dambe laga helo  waxa  diirada la saaraa in ay bacteria-du dawooyinkan u yeelatay adkaysi taasi oo badalaysa nooca dawooyinka iyo muddadaba. 3 bilood oo qofka bukaanka ahi dawo qaadanayay hadii uu baadhitaanka la mariyaa soo saaro in uu weli jiro cudurkii waxa loo aqoonsadaa in uu dhicisoobay qorshe daweedkaasi , waxayna badali doontaa jihadii loo socday.Waxa qasab ah in la baro bukaanka saamaynta ay ku yeelan karaan dawooyinkani loona sheego halista ay ku keeni karaan. Qaar ka mid ah dawooyinkan ayaa waxa ay u baahan yihiin in xubno gaar ah aad loo ilaaliyo oo lala socdo hadba xaaladooda maadaama ay hagardaamayn karaan dawooyinkani.  Bukaanku waa inuu la socdaa aragiisa guud ahaan iyo midabada qaarkood gaar ahaan. Waxa uu la kulmi karaa bukaanku in ay is bedesho midabka kaadidu, kabiibyo ku timaada qaybo ka mid ah jidhka( gacmaha iyo lugaha), matag iyo yalaalugo. Dawooyin kan waa in lala isticmaalo vitaminada qaarkood si ay hoos ugu dhigaan dhibaatada dawooyinkan. Waxa ma huraan ah in aad u sheegto Dr-kaaga hadiiba ay xaalad kale kugu timaado inaad qaadato dawooyinka TB-da waayo waa ay saamayn karaan dawooyin ka kale. Waxa aad muhiim u ah in aad joogtayso dawooyinkan si aad uga baaqsato dawooyin ka dheef yar, ka dhib badan kana kharash badan. Waxa aad u kordhaya tirada dadka ku yeelanaya adkaysi dawooyinkan, waana mid ka mid ah carqaladaha ugu weyn ee hor taagan la tacaalidda cudurkan.Hababka lagaga hor tago cudurkan ayaa ah in uu jiro talaal la siiyo dadka gaar ahaan caruurta oo la tuhunsan yahay inuu hoos u dhigay noocyo ka mid ah TB da oo ay ka mid tahay qayb ka mid ah qoor-gooyaha (TB meneigitis). Waxa laga ma maarmaan ah in uu qofku yareeyo wadiiqo kasta oo halis u gelin karta inuu la kulmo cudurkan."},{"question":"Саз деген эмне ?","answer":"Саз - жер бетиндеги жер кыртышынын үстүнкү жука,катмары ашыкча нымдалышкан жерлер."},{"question":"காற்றைக் குடித்து காற்றில் பறப்பான், அவன் யார்?","answer":"விடை: பலூன்"},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： 50年前の10月28日、日本と中国が国どうしの交流を始めた記念に、中国が東京の上野動物園に2頭のジャイアントパンダを贈りました。雄の「カンカン」と雌の「ランラン」です。それから上野動物園では、全部で15頭のパンダを育てています。「トントン」は日本で生まれて、初めて元気に育ったパンダです。去年は、双子の赤ちゃんが生まれました。上野動物園は先週から、パンダが来てから50年になったことを記念するイベントを行っています。28日からは、動物園のパンダの歴史や写真などを紹介しています。30日には、専門家がオンラインで講演を行います。動物園がどんなことに気をつけてパンダを育てているかなどの話を聞くことができます。","answer":"パンダが日本に来てから50年　上野動物園がイベントを行う"},{"question":"நீதிக் கருத்துகள் மிகுந்த சிற்றிலக்கியம் எது?","answer":"நீதிக் கருத்துகள் மிகுந்த சிற்றிலக்கியம் ,சதகம் – 100 பாடல்கள்."},{"question":"Kedu uwe ndị nwunye na ndị na-alụ nwanyị ọhụrụ na-eyi n'agbamakwụkwọ Igbo?","answer":"Omenala nwanyị a na-alụ ọhụrụ na-eyi akwa mkpuchi \\"George\\" na uwe elu ya nwere ngwa ndị mara mma, ebe nwoke na-alụ nwanyị na-eyi uwe ọdịnala dịka \\"Isiagu\\" ma ọ bụ uwe."},{"question":"Qual evento importante este texto aborda: Nas edições entre 1934 e 1978, dezesseis equipes competiram em cada torneio, exceto em 1938, quando a Áustria foi dominada pela Alemanha após a qualificação, deixando o torneio com quinze equipes; e em 1950, quando a Índia, Escócia e Turquia desistiram de participar, fazendo com que o torneio fosse disputado com treze equipes. A maioria das seleções participantes era da Europa e da América do Sul, com um pequeno número de representantes da América do Norte, África, Ásia e Oceania, que não obtiveram resultados expressivos nas edições. Até 1982, as únicas equipes de fora da Europa e da América do Sul que avançaram para a fase final foram os Estados Unidos (semifinalista em 1930), Cuba (quartas de final em 1938) Coreia do Norte (quartas de final em 1966) e o México (quartas de final em 1970).","answer":"1938"},{"question":"ਜਾਤੀ ਵਿਭਿੰਨਤਾ (Species diversity) ਕੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਜਾਤੀ ਵਿਭਿੰਨਤਾ (Species Diversity) – ਜਾਤੀ ਵਿਭਿੰਨਤਾ ਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਕਿਸੇ ਇਕ ਖੰਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਜਾਤੀਆਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਕਿਸਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਜੂਦਗੀ ਤੋਂ ਹੈ । ਖੇਤਰਫਲ ਦੀ ਇਕ ਇਕਾਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਾਤੀ ਦੀ ਸੰਖਿਆ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਤੀ ਬਹੁਲਤਾ (Species richness) ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਜਾਤੀ (Species) ਪਦ (Term) ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ, ਜੀਵ ਵਿਭਿੰਨਤਾ ਦੀ ਇਕਾਈ ਨੂੰ ਦਰਸਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਸ਼ੇਰ, ਬਰਫਾਨੀ ਤੇਂਦੂਆ (Snow leopard) ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਜਾਤੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਜੀਨਜ਼ ਇਕ ਸਮਾਨ ਹਨ ।ਖੇਤਰਫਲ ਦੀ ਇਕ ਇਕਾਈ (Per unit area) ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਈਆਂ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਜਾਤੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਖਿਆ ਜਾਤੀ ਬਹੁਲਤਾ ਅਖਵਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਪਰ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਜਾਤੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਬਰਾਬਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਉੱਚਿਤੜਾ (Equitability) ਵਿਚ ਫਰਕ ਕਿਸੇ ਖੰਡ ਵਿਚ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਖਿਆ ਵਿਚ ਫਰਕ । ਕਾਰਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜੇਕਰ ਕਿਸੇ ਖੰਡ ਦੇ ਖੇਤਰਫਲ (Area) ਵਿਚ ਵਾਧਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉੱਥੇ ਜਾਤੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਖਿਆ ਵੀ ਵੱਧ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਜਾਤੀ ਅਨੇਕਰੂਪਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਵਾਧਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਹ ਵਾਧਾ ਜਾਤੀ ਦੀ ਬਹੁਲਤਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਅਜਿਹੀ ਹਾਲਤ ਦੇ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਜਾਤੀ ਦੇ ਸੰਤੁਲਨ ਅਤੇ ਉੱਤਮਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਅੰਤਰ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ | ਅਜਿਹਾ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਫਲਸਰੂਪ ਅਨੇਕਰੂਪਤਾ/ਵਿਭਿੰਨਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Voltooi de paragraaf: Dit stadion is verschillende keren uitgekozen als gaststadion tijdens een toernooi om de Gold Cup, het voetbaltoernooi voor landenteams van de CONCACAF. Tijdens de Gold Cup van 2011","answer":"en 2017 was dit stadion een van de stadions waar voetbalwedstrijden werden gespeeld."},{"question":"翻译下面的古文：帝置酒洛阳南宫，上曰：“列侯、诸将毋敢隐朕，皆言其情：我所以有天下者何？项氏之所以失天下者何？”高起、王陵对曰：“陛下使人攻城略地，因以与之，与天下同其利；项羽不然，有功者害之，贤者疑之，此所以失天下也。”上曰：“公知其一，未知其二。夫运筹帷幄之中，决胜千里之外，吾不如子房（张良字子房）；镇国家，抚百姓，给饷馈（供给军饷），不绝粮道，吾不如萧何；连百万之众，战必胜，攻必取，吾不如韩信。三者皆人杰，吾能用之，此吾所以取天下者也。项羽有一范增而不用，此所以为我所禽也。”","answer":"刘邦在洛阳南宫摆酒宴，说：“各位王侯将领不要隐瞒我，都说这真实的情况：我得天下的原因是什么呢？项羽失天下的原因是什么呢？”高起，王陵回答说：“陛下让人攻取城池取得土地，因此来亲附他们，与天下的利益相同；相与却不是这样，杀害有功绩的人，怀疑有才能的人，这就是失天下的原因啊。”刘邦说：“你只知道那一个方面，却不知道那另一个方面。(就拿)在大帐内出谋划策，在千里以外一决胜负(来说)，我不如张良；平定国家，安抚百姓，供给军饷，不断绝运粮食的道路，我不如萧何；联合众多的士兵，打仗一定胜利，攻占一定取得，我不如韩信、这三个人都是豪杰的人，我能够利用他们，这是我取得天下的原因、项羽有以为范增而不利用(他)，这就是被我捉拿的原因。”"},{"question":"Afaka mitsambikina ve ny soavaly?","answer":"Eny"},{"question":"Төмөнкү текст кандай текстке кирет?Тексттин түрүн аныктагыла. Текстке ат коюп, көчүрүп жазгыла.Бүгүн күн чайыттай ачык. Көл бетине нур чагылышат. Күнгөй, тескей килемдей кулпурат. Жакасы жашыл, тоосу көк. Ал эми тээ аркайган аскаларга карасаң! Агарган кары, жалтыраган музу көздү уялтат.","answer":"Төмөнкү текст сγрөттөөгө кирет."},{"question":" கேள்வி: விக்ரம் சாராபாய் விண்வெளி மையம் எங்கு அமைந்துள்ளது?","answer":"பதில்:விக்ரம் சாராபாய் விண்வெளி மையம்  (VSSC) கேரள மாநிலத்தில் திருவனந்தபுரத்தில்            அமைந்துள்ளது."},{"question":"Apakah maksud dengan 'dari jauh orang angkat telunjuk, kalau dekat dia angkat mata'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud jika kita berbuat salah akan diumpat orang di belakang kalau tidak di depan kita"},{"question":"칸트와 데카르트 관점에서 각각 \\"있음\\"과 \\"존재\\"의 차이를 설명해줘.","answer":"데카르트는 존재에 대해 ‘Cogito, ergo sum(나는 생각한다, 고로 나는 존재한다)’라는 말로 표현하여 인간의 내면에서부터 출발하며, 또한 외골수적으로 존재한다고 믿는 신을 전제로 하여 존재를 규정합니다.반면에 칸트는 존재를 개념적으로 이해하고자 했으며, 존재의 본질과 성질을 탐구하였습니다. 그 결과, 칸트는 존재를 ‘신촉성 있는 것’으로 정의했는데요. 즉, 존재란 후각이나 시각 등 감각을 통해 우리가 관찰할 수 있는 객체들 중에서 어떤 것이라도 존재한다는 것입니다.데카르트는 인간의 내면에서 존재를 찾으며, 칸트는 존재를 개념적인 측면에서 이해하였습니다. 이렇게 두 철학가는 그들만의 본질적 차이를 가지고 있습니다."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"மனிதனுக்கு அறிவு வளர்ச்சியும், ஆராய்ச்சி வளர்ச்சியும் இல்லாத காலத்தில்தான் கடவுள் நினைப்பு தோன்றியிருக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Cuối tuần qua Ngân hàng Nhà nước đã ngồi lại với đại diện các doanh nghiệp kinh doanh vàng lớn để đánh giá về thị trường vàng, đặc biệt là về vấn đề chênh lệch giá và vai trò của Nghị định 24 (khung pháp lý về hoạt động sản xuất, kinh doanh vàng). Tại cuộc họp này, bà Lê Thúy Hằng - Tổng giám đốc Công ty Vàng bạc đá quý Sài Gòn (SJC) đưa một thông tin đáng chú ý và tưởng như nghịch lý. Bà Hằng cho biết, số lượng vàng trên thị trường Việt Nam còn rất ít, bởi có những năm, những thời điểm, giá nguyên liệu và giá vàng SJC thấp hơn hoặc bằng, các thương hiệu trong nước nấu vàng miếng của SJC để sản xuất nhẫn và nữ trang. Đặc biệt, năm 2019, thị trường vàng xuất đi nước ngoài rất nhiều cho nên lượng vàng SJC trên thị trường hiện nay còn rất ít. Nguồn cung hiện tại không có trong khi nhu cầu thị trường có, do vậy tạo ra độ chênh về giá so với vàng thế giới, Tổng giám đốc SJC lý giải. Cao điểm trong lịch sử, vào năm 2012 thị trường Việt Nam từng ghi nhận có khoảng 20 triệu lượng vàng miếng SJC đã được đưa ra thị trường. Từ đó đến nay, Ngân hàng Nhà nước độc quyền sản xuất vàng miếng với thương hiệu SJC; SJC chục năm qua cũng không được dập một miếng vàng nào từ nguyên liệu. Với thông tin trên, lượng vàng miếng SJC hiện có trên thị trường đã giảm đi, song chưa có con số thống kê cụ thể được công bố hoặc ước lượng. Còn khớp với thông tin từ Tổng giám đốc SJC, số liệu của Tổng cục Hải quan cho thấy cũng chính trong năm 2019 Việt Nam đã xuất khẩu một lượng vàng lớn. Quy mô xuất khẩu này tiếp tục đột biến sang năm 2020. Cụ thể, theo số liệu của Tổng cục Hải quan, kim ngạch xuất khẩu mặt hàng đá quý, kim loại quý và sản phẩm từ 627,4 triệu USD năm 2018 đã tăng vọt tới 2,1 tỷ USD năm 2019; trong đó có lượng vàng miếng SJC được nấu, rồi chế tác thành sản phẩm vàng nữ trang, mỹ nghệ cho xuất khẩu. Quy mô xuất khẩu những mặt hàng này năm 2020 tiếp tục tăng lên tới 2,6 tỷ USD. Nhưng sang năm 2021 dòng chảy này thu hẹp lại còn 836,23 triệu USD; cập nhật đến giữa tháng 7 năm nay ở mức 581,72 triệu USD. Diễn biến trên, đặc biệt trong các năm 2019-2020, đã có một lượng vàng miếng SJC nấu để chuyển hóa thành vàng nữ trang, mỹ nghệ để xuất khẩu. Doanh nghiệp chuyển hóa như vậy để có vàng nữ trang, mỹ nghệ có giá trị gia tăng cao hơn; nhưng điều này cũng cho thấy họ khó khăn trong nguồn vàng nguyên liệu để chế tác cho xuất khẩu nên buộc phải nấu vàng miếng SJC. Với Nghị định 24, Nhà nước vẫn độc quyền nhập khẩu vàng, các doanh nghiệp đầu mối không được nhập vàng nguyên liệu. Vàng nguyên liệu vào Việt Nam thời gian qua được phát hiện qua nhiều vụ quy mô lớn bằng nhập lậu. Theo đó, thời gian qua cho đến nay vẫn thường có đề xuất Nhà nước mở cơ chế cho doanh nghiệp được nhập khẩu vàng nguyên liệu, phục vụ cho sản xuất vàng nữ trang, mỹ nghệ đáp ứng nhu cầu thị trường trong nước cũng như để xuất khẩu.","answer":"Nấu vàng miếng SJC để xuất khẩu"},{"question":"ਉਪਭੋਗ ।","answer":"ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਖਪਤ ਦਾ ਹੋਣਾ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਬਗ਼ੈਰ ਖਪਤ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ! ਖਪਤ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਉਪਭੋਗ ਕਰਨਾ ਤੇ ਉਪਯੋਗ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਗੁਣ ਜੋ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਯੋਗ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਹਰੇਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਕੰਮ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਖਪਤ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜ ਲਈ ਨਿਯਮਿਤ ਤੇ ਨਿਯੰਤਰਿਤ ਕਰੇ ।"},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira da Coreia do Norte.","answer":"A bandeira da Coreia do Norte consiste de um painel central horizontal vermelho que contrasta, no topo e em baixo, com uma fina faixa branca e uma faixa azul mais ampla. O painel vermelho central da bandeira inclui no lado esquerdo uma estrela vermelha de cinco pontas inserida num círculo branco.A bandeira da República Popular Democrática da Coreia é conhecida como \\"Ramhongsaek Konghwagukgi\\", que em coreano significa literalmente \\"bandeira azul e vermelha da república\\"."},{"question":"Jaka jest populacja Włoch?","answer":"Aktualnie (w 2023 roku) jest to 60 milionów."},{"question":"KuFrance kunobvepi waini yeclaret?","answer":"Waini ine mukurumbira inonzi claret inobva mudunhu reBordeaux muFrance. Bordeaux inopembererwa nekugadzira huwandu hwakawanda hwemhando yepamusoro yewaini tsvuku inokosheswa nevanoziva kutenderera pasirese."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి భావం రాయండి:తే|| యవన పుణ్యాంగనామణి వగుదుగాకహైందవులపూజ తల్లియట్లందరాదె?నీదురూపము నాయందు లేద యైనంగనని తల్లివిగా నిన్ను గారవింతు","answer":"యవన జాతికి చెందిన పుణ్యస్త్రీవి. అయినా హిందువుల పూజలను మా తల్లివలె స్వీకరించు. నీ పోలిక నాలో లేదు. అయినా నాకు జన్మనివ్వని తల్లిగా నిన్ను గౌరవిస్తాను."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو المقصود بانبعاج الأعمدة الخرسانية(buckling) ؟","answer":"الإجابة: هو عدم تحمل العمود للاحمال المسلطة عليه ويؤدي ذلك إلى حدوث فشل في مقاومة الضغط للخرسانة وفشل في مقاومة الشد لحديد التسليح الكانات."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा  घरचे झाले थोडे, व्याह्याने धाडले घोडे","answer":"स्वत:च्या कामाचा व्याप अतोनात असताना दुसर्‍यांने आपलेही काम लादणे."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\" Rafotsy be very laona, _ \\"","answer":"Rafotsy be very laona, ka miandry izay higadonany."},{"question":"Wahala n bọ o, Makinde ati Fayoṣe fẹẹ gbena woju ara wọn","answer":"Bi awọn agbaagba ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP ko ba tete wa nnkan ṣe si i, afaimọ ki ija agba to n lọ laarin Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Ṣeyi Makinde, ati gomina ipinlẹ Ekiti tẹlẹ, Ayọdele Fayoṣe ma ṣakoba nla fun ẹgbẹ naa. Eyi ko sẹyin bi Fayọṣe ṣe n kilọ fun gomina Ọyọ naa pe ko ma da si ohun to n lọ nipinlẹ oun.Ọjọbọ, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, ni Fayọse sọrọ naa niluu Abeọkuta, nipinlẹ Ogun, nibi ipade to waye lati fẹnu ko lori ẹni ti wọn yoo fa kalẹ gẹge bii igbakeji alaga fun ilẹ Yoruba ninu ibo ẹgbẹ naa ti yoo waye laipẹ. Oun lo ko ko awọn aṣoju ẹgbẹ naa atawọn alaga ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP nipinlẹ Ekiti, Ọṣun ati Eko sodi lọ si Abeokuta ti ipade naa ti waye.Fayọse fi aidunu rẹ han si bo ṣe ni Gomina Makinde n da si ọrọ to n lọ ninu ẹgbẹ naa lawọn ipinlẹ kaakiri. Gomina tẹlẹ yii ni bo tilẹ jẹ pe Makinde ni aṣaaju ẹgbẹ naa ni ilẹ Yoruba nitori ipo rẹ gẹgẹ bii gomina kan ṣoso ti ẹgbẹ naa ni nibẹ, o ni pẹlu rẹ naa, o gbọdọ fi akoso ẹgbẹ silẹ fawọn adari ipinlẹ kọọkan lati mojuto o ni. Ko ma tori ipo yii maa da si awọn ohun ti ko kan an.Ọkunrin naa ni niṣe loun yoo ba Makinde kẹsẹ bọ sokoto kan naa to ba wa sipinlẹ Ekiti waa paṣẹ onikumọ kan.Fayọṣe ni, ‘Pe o jẹ gomina ko sọ pe ki o waa maa da si ohun to n lọ nipinlẹ mi-in. Keeyan ma wa si ipinlẹ temi o, bo ba wa si ipinlẹ mi, ma a doju ija kọ ọ gidi. Ṣugbọn ma a tẹsiwaju lati maa bu ọla fun un nitori arakunrin mi ni, mo si nifẹẹ rẹ daadaa, emi naa wa ninu awọn to ṣagbara lati gbe e wọle sipo gomina."},{"question":"තම ක්‍රීඩා දිවිය තුළ වැඩිම ලකුණු සාමාන්‍යයක් හිමි ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"ස(ර්) ඩොනල්ඩ් බ්‍රැඩ්මන්"},{"question":"வினா: ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபையின் ஆட்சி மொழிகள் யாவை?","answer":"  விடை:        ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் அவையுடன் தொடர்புடைய மேலும் பல அமைப்புக்கள் உலகின் பல்வேறு இடங்களில் உள்ளன. அரசுகளுக்கு இடையிலான கூட்டங்களிலும், ஆவணங்களிலும் ஆறு மொழிகள் அலுவல் மொழிகளாகப் பயன்பட்டு வருகின்றன. இவை, அரபி, சீனம், ஆங்கிலம், பிரெஞ்சு, உருசியம், எசுப்பானியம் என்பன.        ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் சபை  என்பது சர்வதேச அமைதி மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பைப் பேணுதல் , நாடுகளுக்கிடையே நட்புறவை வளர்த்தல், சர்வதேச ஒத்துழைப்பை அடைதல் மற்றும் நாடுகளின் நடவடிக்கைகளை ஒத்திசைக்கும் மையமாகச் செயல்படும் நோக்கங்களைக் கொண்ட ஒரு அரசுகளுக்கிடையேயான அமைப்பாகும் . இது உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய சர்வதேச அமைப்பாகும்.  ஐ.நா.வின் தலைமையகம் நியூ யார்க்  நகரில்  உள்ளது, மேலும் இந்த அமைப்புக்கு ஜெனீவா , நைரோபி , வியன்னா மற்றும் தி ஹேக் ஆகிய இடங்களில் மற்ற அலுவலகங்கள் உள்ளன , அங்கு சர்வதேச நீதிமன்றத்தின் தலைமையகம் உள்ளது.       ஆறு முக்கிய செயல்பாட்டு அமைப்புகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது , பொதுச் சபை , பாதுகாப்பு கவுன்சில் , பொருளாதார மற்றும் சமூக கவுன்சில் , சர்வதேச நீதிமன்றம் ,  செயலகம் மற்றும் அறங்காவலர் கவுன்சில் , இருப்பினும் அறங்காவலர் கவுன்சில் 1994 முதல் செயலற்ற நிலையில் உள்ளது. உலக வங்கி குழு , உலக சுகாதார அமைப்பு , உலக உணவு திட்டம் , யுனெஸ்கோ மற்றும் யுனிசெஃப் உட்பட பல சிறப்பு நிறுவனங்கள் , நிதிகள் மற்றும் திட்டங்களை உள்ளடக்கியது ."},{"question":"Inona no antony mahatonga ny olona sasany tsy mihinana kisoa?","answer":"Ny olona sasany dia tsy mihinana kisoa matetika noho ny resaka fady. Misy ny fady vokatrin'ny fotom-pinoany na fivavahany, misy kosa ireo fady izay lovainy avamin'ny ray aman-dreniny."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو اسم زوجة النبي صلى الله عليه وسلم الأولى؟","answer":"الإجابة: خديجة بنت خويلد"},{"question":"Ajọ OYTMA gbẹsẹ le mọto ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ, wọn lo da gosiloo silẹ","answer":"\\"Bi gbogbo aye ba n ṣe bayii, a dun”. Eyi lọrọ ti ọpọ eeyan n sọ nigba ti ọga agba ajọ OYTMA, iyẹn, ajọ to n ri si igbokegbodo ọkọ atawọn ohun irinsẹ gbogbo ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Mọgaji Akin Fagbemi, fi panpẹ ọba gbe ọkan ninu awọn ọkọ to jẹ ti ajọ naa n’Ibadan.Ajọ OYTMA yii lo maa n fáìnì awọn awakọ to ba wa mọto gunlẹ sibi ti ko boju mu loju popo ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ti wọn si maa n wọ́ iru ọkọ bẹẹ lọ satimọle ninu ọgba ajọ naa to wa ninu sẹkiteriati ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ.L’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, to kọja lọkan ninu awọn oṣiṣẹ ajọ naa jaye ta-ni-yoo-mu-mi pẹlu bo ṣe wa mọto to jẹ ti ajọ yii gunlẹ si ibi ti ko yẹ, eyi si da sunkẹrẹ-fakẹrẹ silẹ fawọn mọto atawọn ohun irinsẹ mi-in to n kọja nibẹ laaarọ ọjọ naa.Iṣẹlẹ yii bọ si asiko ti Mọgaji Fagbemi ti i ṣe alakooso agba fun ajọ OYTROMA n pàráàro kaakiri igboro lati mọ bi awọn eeyan ṣe n tẹle ofin ìwakọ̀gúnlẹ̀ sí.Lẹsẹkẹsẹ lo paṣẹ pe ki wọn wọ́ ọkọ naa lọ satimọle pẹlu ọkọ nla ti ajọ naa fi maa n wọ awọn ọkọ to ba tapa si ofin.Bakan naa lo paṣẹ pe ki wọn faini oṣiṣẹ ajọ OYTROMA to wa mọto yii ni iye owo gan-an ti ajọ yii maa n faini awọn araalu to ba ṣẹ si ofin ìwakọ̀gúnlẹ̀.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, Mọgaji Fagbemi sọ pe gbogbo igba loun maa n kaakiri igboro bẹẹ lati mọ bi awọn awakọ ṣe n pa ofin iwakọgunlẹ mọ si, ati pe gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Ṣeyi Makinde, loun fi iwa naa jọ.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, igbesẹ ti mo n gbe wọnyi jẹ diẹ ninu awọn iṣesi ti mo kọ lara Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde. Ọpọ igba lawọn funra wọn maa n jade bẹẹ lati mọ bi gbogbo nnkan ṣe ri nigboro, ṣugbọn aarin oru lawọn (Makinde) maa n jade bẹẹ ni tiwọn, o le jẹ aago meji si mẹta laarin oru.“Nigba ti Ọlọrun yoo waa ṣe e, nigba ti mo jade lonii, ọkan ninu awọn mọto to jẹ tiwa gan-an lo ko si panpẹ ofin, o si di dandan ka da sẹria to tọ si arufin fun oun naa.”"},{"question":"List any three features of the Civil Code of 1804 usually known as the Napoleonic Code. ","answer":"It did away with all privileges based on birth. • It established equality before law and secured the right to property. • It simplified administrative divisions, abolished the feudal system and freed peasants from serfdom and manorial dues."},{"question":"सिंहदरबार आगलागी हुदा नेपालका प्रधानमन्त्री को थिए ?","answer":"क्रीतिनिधी बिष्ट (खरिदार २०६८)"},{"question":"أنا رقم مكون من ثلاثة أرقام. رقمي الثاني أكبر بأربع مرات من الرقم الثالث. رقم الأول أقل من رقمي الثاني بمقدار 3. من أنا؟","answer":"141"},{"question":"Completa la siguiente frase :  El Campeonato Mundial de Voleibol Femenino es la máxima competición internacional de voleibol disputada por los equipos nacionales femeninos miembros de la Federación Internacional de Voleibol (FIVB). La primera edición tuvo lugar en 1952 y desde entonces se realiza cada cuatro años. El actual campeón es Serbia, que ganó su primer título el torneo... ","answer":"Del 2018."},{"question":"个人吃8份快餐需10分钟,16个人吃16份快餐需几分钟","answer":"答案：还是10分钟"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bercampur gaul\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud bersama atau berdamping."},{"question":"30 මාර්තු 2022 රෑ.. මම හීනයක් දැක්කා.. බුදුන් වහන්සේ පාරේ වැඩම කරනවා.. බුදුන් වහන්සේ සමඟ සංඝයා වහන්සේලා සහ මිනිසුන් බොහෝ පිරිසක් සහිත පෙරහැරක් ගියා..  මම හිස මුදුනේ අත් තියාගෙන වැඳගෙන ඒ පෙරහැර දිහා බලාගෙන ඉඳලා, අන්තිමේ මමත් ඒ පෙරහැර පස්සෙං ගියා..(මම හඳුනන වියත් අයගෙන් මේ ගැන විමසූ විට ඔවුන් මුලින්ම අසන ප්‍රශ්නය \\"බුදුන් වහන්සේ මොන වගේද ?\\" කියලා.. පරශ්නය තිබෙන්නේ හීනය තුලදී  මට හොඳ අවබෝධයක් තිබුනා මේ දකින්නේ බුදුන් වහන්සේ බව. උන් වහන්සේගේ මුහුණ පවා මම හොඳින්ම දුටුවා. හදවතට ඒගැන හොඳින්ම දැනුනා. අදටත් මට මතකයි.. මම හිතන්නේ නෑ මට ඒ දසුන අමතක වෙයි කියලා. නමුත් මට උන්වහන්සේගේ මුහුණේ ස්වභාවය ගැන තව කෙනෙකුට පැහැදිලි කරන්න බෑ.. උදාහරණ වලින්වත් බෑ.. )මම විවිධාකාරයේ හීන දැකලා තියෙනවා. මේ කියවන ඔබත් විවිධ හීන දැක ඇතිවාට සැකයක් නෑ.  ඒ උනාට ජීවිතේ කවදාවත් මම මේ වගේ, ක්ලියර්..චිරපටයක් වගේ හීනයක් නං දැකලාම නෑ.. ඒක නිසා හිතේ සතුට වගේම නොසන්සුන් ගතියකුත් තියෙනවා... කොටින්ම කියනවා නං මේ ගෘපයට එකතුවෙලා බුදු දහම ඉගෙනගන්නත්, මම දන්නා තරමින් ඒ ගැන සාකච්චා, සංවාද කරන්නත්, මම කියවපු-අධ්‍යනය කරපු බුදු දහමේ කරුණු අන්‍ය අයත් එක්ක බෙදා හදාගන්නත් ප්‍රධානම හේතුව ඕක..නැත්තං මම සාමාන්‍යයෙන් එහෙම කෙනෙක් නෙමෙයි.. මේ හීනය ගැන මට වරින් වර මතක් වෙනවා.. කරුණා කරලා කවුරුහරි දන්නා කෙනෙක් මේ ගැන යම් පැහැදිළි කිරීමක් කර දෙන්න.","answer":"එයාගේ හිතේ තියෙන බුදුහාමුදුරුවො එයා දැක්කේ, ඒ බුදුහාමුදුරුවො නෙවෙයි කියලා වෙන කෙනෙක් කිව්වට තේරුමක් නෑමට හිතෙන්නෙ එයාට අතීත ජිවිතේක පහුකල අත්දැකීමක් හීනෙන් පෙන්නුවා කියලා. ඒකෙන් එයාගෙ සසරේ යම් පුහුණුවක් මතු කරලා දෙන්න හදනවා//කොටින්ම කියනවා නං මේ ගෘපයට එකතුවෙලා බුදු දහම ඉගෙනගන්නත්, මම දන්නා තරමින් ඒ ගැන සාකච්චා, සංවාද කරන්නත්, මම කියවපු-අධ්‍යනය කරපු බුදු දහමේ කරුණු අන්‍ය අයත් එක්ක බෙදා හදාගන්නත් ප්‍රධානම හේතුව ඕක..//අන්න ඒකයි. එයාව නැවත එයාගේ සසරේ චරිතයට පරිවර්තනය වෙමින් පවතිනවා.//ඒ ඇරුණාම මට මම මැදි වියේ, තනිකඩ පිරිමි කෙනෙක්. තෙරුවන් සරණ ගිය බෞද්ධයෙක් පමණයි.. ඒ ඇරුණාම මම සිල් සමාදන් වෙන, බුදුන් වඳින, පංසල් යන කෙනෙක් හෝ කිසිදු ආකාරයක බෞද්ධ වතාවත්/පුද පූජා සිද්ධ කරන කෙනෙක් හෝ බෞද්ධ විදියට ජීවත්වෙන කෙනෙක් නෙමෙයි.. සිල් රකින/ ධර්ම මාර්ගයේ යන උසස් අයට නැතුව, මං වගේ කෙනෙකුට ඒ වගේ හීනයක් පෙනුනේ ඇයි ? //හීන විවිධාකාරයි. ගිය ජීවිතයක සිද්ධියක මතකයක ඇසුරෙන් හෝ නැතුව මෙහෙම සංඛේත පේන්න පුලුවන්"},{"question":"Onye bụ Linda Motlhalo?","answer":"Linda Maserame Motlhalo (amụrụ n'ụbọchị mbụ n'ọnwa Julaị n'afọ 1998) bụ onye na-agba bọọlụ na South Afrika nke na-agba bọọlụ dị ka onye na-eme egwuregwu maka klọb Swedish Djurgardens na ndị otu ụmụ nwanyị South Africa. A makwaara ya dị ka 'Randfontein Ronaldinho'.A mụrụ Linda Motlhalo na Brandvlei, Northern Cape, na Jenụwarị 7, 1998. Ezinụlọ ya nwere akụkọ ihe mere eme nke bọọlụ, nna ya Johannes Motlhalo na-anwa ịghọ onye egwuregwu ọkachamara. Ọ bụ ezie na o meghị otú ahụ, nwanne ya nwoke Joseph Motlhalo ghọrọ onye na-edebe goolu maka Kaizer Chiefs FC n'etiti afọ 1970 na 1985.Motlhalo gara TuksSport High School, n'oge ahụ ọ bụ akụkụ nke South African High Performance Centre dị na Pretoria."},{"question":"በሥነ ጽሑፍ ዘርፍ በ1986 አፍሪካዊ የኖቤል ተሸላሚ ማን ነበሩ?","answer":"ዎሌ ሾይንካ እ.ኤ.አ. በ1986 የመጀመሪያው ጥቁር አፍሪካዊ የስነ-ጽሁፍ የኖቤል ሽልማት አሸናፊ ሆነ።"},{"question":"著名导演兼演员奥逊·威尔斯、著名科幻演员伦纳德·尼莫伊和巨蟒剧团喜剧演员埃里克·艾德尔在哪部电影中合作？","answer":"电影的名称是《变形金刚：大电影》，1986 年上映。"},{"question":"Mwambi: ulenje umasimba wako","answer":"Thanthauzo: sungakambe za munthu wina osakamba zako"},{"question":"Okungijabulisayo nje mngani ukuthi akubonakali ukuthi usemnyameni.Benginovalo ngithi ngizokufica uhwabhekile impela.Cha ukuthi ngazitshela Gugu ukuthi osekwenzekile kwenzekile. Kuningiokwake kwangifikela, kodwa ngathola ukuthi leyo mizindlo ayiwuphumuziumphefumulo wami.Cha usukhulile-ke mngani, uma usukwazi ukudlulisa usizi olunje.Abaningi ontanga basuke baqale phansi bafune imbangela yokufakomuntu. Babuye bakhohlwe ukuthi umuntu uyafa nje ukufa kwemvelo.Eqinisweni nje ngiyaziqinisa Gugu. Nanokuthi ngiyakhuluma kungenxayenu. Mkhulu umsebenzi enawenza ningiduduza.Sengifisa nokuthi nje abasemzini bakuphathe kahle, bakucabangele.Cha bona bandla abakakhathazi ngalutho. Kuningi futhi abakhombisangakho ukuthi bayangizwela. Angazi-ke noma bazobuye bashintshe yini.Into abangakwazi ukuyiqeda isizungu nenkumbulo kaSkhumbuzo.Njengoba usemncane kangaka-ke mngani uzogcina kanjani? Uzohlalalapha ekhaya unomphelo noma uzozama ukuqala impilo kabusha?Kulukhuni ukusho njengamanje mngani. Angithi uyabona ngisagqokeezimnyama, akulula ukuthatha izinqumo manje. Isifiso sami nokhobekuwukuba ngibuyele ekhaya. Into engingayazi-ke ukuthi abasemzinibazovuma yini.Injongo yakho ngempela yini mngani? Ngabe ufuna ukubuye uganenoma uthole umlisa ozovala isikhala sikaSikhumbuzo?Eyokugana angisayiboni mngani wami. Uthando ebenginalo luhambenowakwami lonke. Akuselula ukuba ngikwazi ukuthanda omunye umuntumanje.(Ahleke kancane) Cha ubumthanda uSikhumbuzo mngani wami. Ukufakuyinuku impela.1. Umbhali uwulandele umgomo wokubhala isingeniso. Sekela ngamaphuzuAMATHATHU.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMATHATHU kwalandelayo:• Siyamthola umlingiswa oqavile/omkhulu esingenisweni somdlalookunguThenjiwe.• Siyayithola inkinga abhekene nayo yokuphoqwa ukuthi avumeukungenwa nguDumisani.• Siyayithola imbangela yezinkinga zomlingiswa omkhuluokungukushonelwa ngumyeni wakhe.• Isingeniso siqoqekile, sibekeke ngamagama ambalwa.• Isizinda siyacaca esingenisweni, okuyindawo yasemakhaya ngesikhathisanamuhla, isimo phakathi kukaThenjiwe nabasemzini asisihle."},{"question":"ウーロン茶を漢字で書いたときに出てくる、実在する生き物と空想上の生き物をそれぞれ答えなさい。","answer":"烏と龍（カラスとドラゴン）です。"},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 1923年9月1日に関東大震災がありました。大きな地震でたくさんの建物が壊れたり火事になったりして、10万人以上が亡くなりました。この震災から今年で100年になります。気象庁は震災の被害を伝えるため、そのときの写真などを紹介するウェブサイトを作りました。東京駅の周りの写真では、火事で近くの建物などが全部焼けています。被害があった神奈川県の寺や、津波が来た静岡県の海岸の写真もあります。地震の揺れ方を記録したグラフも見ることができます。気象庁は「関東大震災の被害を知って、大きな地震のとき命を守るためにどんな準備が必要か、みなさんに考えてほしいです」と言っています。気象庁のウェブサイト「関東大震災から100年」","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండికాంతి విషయంలో డాప్లర్ ప్రభావాన్ని వివరించండి. ఎరుపు షిఫ్ట్ మరియు నీలి షిఫ్ట్ల మధ్య తేడా ఏమి? ","answer":"కాంతిలో డాప్లర్ ప్రభావం :భూమికి దగ్గరగా వస్తున్న నక్షత్రం నుండి వచ్చే కాంతి దృశ్య తరంగదైర్ఘ్యం తక్కువగా (లేదా దృశ్య పౌనఃపున్యం ఎక్కువగా) ఉంటుంది. సాపేక్ష చలనం వల్ల కాంతి దృశ్య తరంగదైర్ఘ్యం మారుతుంది. దీనినే డాప్లర్ ప్రభావం అంటారు.ఎరుపు షిఫ్ట్ :డాప్లర్ ప్రభావం ప్రకారం, నక్షత్రం దూరంగా పోయేటప్పుడు, కాంతి దృశ్య తరంగదైర్ఘ్యం పెరుగుతుంది. ఫలితంగా, దృశ్య కాంతి (VIBGYOR) లోని మధ్యస్థ తరంగదైర్ఘ్యాలు ఎరుపువైపు కదుల్తాయి. దీనినే ఎరుపు షిఫ్ట్ అంటారు.నీలి ఫిఫ్ట్ :డాప్లర్ ప్రభావం ప్రకారం, నక్షత్రం దగ్గరగా వచ్చేటప్పుడు, కాంతి దృశ్య తరంగదైర్ఘ్యం తగ్గుతుంది. ఫలితంగా, దృశ్య కాంతి (VIBGYOR) లోని మధ్యస్థ తరంగదైర్ఘ్యాలు నీలి రంగు వైపు కదుల్తాయి. దీనినే నీలి షిఫ్ట్ అంటారు."},{"question":"Siyabonana mndeni wakwaDuma.Yebo ndoda. Sengathi ngiyakwazi nje ndoda.(ngenhlonipho) Yebo baba, uyangazi. Mina ngingunogada wenkosi.(ahlahle amehlo futhi inkulumo igcwale indelelo) Yebo siyakwazi.Manje ufunani lapha?(Uthukuthele futhi ubuka uMbandlwa ngeso lengulube.) Kahle boMbandlwa! Lo muntu akezile kuwe. (Aqondise kuNogada)Usivakashele ngani muntu wenkosi?Ngithunywe nguNdabezitha kubaba uDuma.(abuyise izinhlozi maqede akhulume ngolaka) Hheyi wena, angidingemyalezo wenkosi mina lapha! Angithi yona ingisasazela ngale ndunayayo uDlamini! Angithi mina angikwazi ukwenza umsebenzi wamingenxa yayo?1. Ngokucabanga kwakho kwakuyisenzo esihle yini ukuthi uMaShezi ashiyeumyeni wakhe aphindele kubo? Sekela impendulo yakho ngamaphuzuAMABILI.","answer":"Isenzo esihle• UMaShezi wayesabela impilo yakhe. • Kwakungasekho ukubambisana nokuhloniphana nomyeni wakhe. NOMAIsenzo esinesihle• Wayephula izifungo zakhe zomshado. • Wayekhombisa ukungambekezeleli nokungamhloniphi umyeni wakhe."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe tsiny eo amin'ny malagasy","answer":"  Ny tsiny dia hery manimba mitambesatra amin’ny olona nandika fady ka mahavoa azy eo amin’ny fiainany manontolo: ny fahasalamana, ny fananany ary ny taranany."},{"question":"จบประโยคต่อไปนี้:  ประเด็นในการจัดการแข่งขันในช่วงแรกของฟุตบอลโลกที่เป็นความยากลำบากในการเดินทางข้ามทวีปและสงครามนั้น มีทีมจากอเมริกาใต้บางทีมยินดีที่จะเดินทางไปยุโรปในการแข่งขันในปี 1934 และ","answer":"1938 โดยทีมบราซิลเป็นทีมเดียวในอเมริกาใต้ที่เข้าแข่งขันทั้ง 2 ครั้งนี้ ส่วนการแข่งขันฟุตบอลโลก 1942 และ 1946 ได้มีการยกเลิกไปเนื่องจากสงครามโลกครั้งที่สองและผลกระทบของสงครามโลก"},{"question":"لخص المقال التالي: القوة تعني القدرة على التأثير في حياتك، في حين أن الضعف يعني العجز والتخاذل. مهما كانت ظروفك، ثمة أشياء يمكنك التحكم بها، وأشياء لا يمكنك التحكم بها. والمفتاح هو أن تركز على الأشياء التي \\"يمكنك\\" التحكم بها. ضع قائمة بالأمور التي تزعجك، ثم ضع قائمة بما يمكنك القيام به كي تجعل كل موقف أفضل. تقبل العناصر التي توجد بالقائمة الأولى، وركز طاقتك على القائمة الثانية.  في دراسات على أشخاص لديهم معدل مرتفع في حاصل الشدائد، لوحظ أن الأشخاص المرنين لا يجدون فقط في أي موقف جانب ما يمكنهم التحكم فيه، وإنما يشعرون أيضًا بالمسئولية تجاه اتخاذ خطوات لإصلاح الموقف، حتى إذا كانت الصعوبات التي واجهوها سببها شخص آخر. أما الأشخاص ذوو المعدل المنخفض في حاصل الشدائد يتجاهلون فرص اتخاذ إجراء ما وينصرفون عن الإحساس بالمسئولية على افتراض أنهم لم يتسببوا في خلق هذا الموقف، ومن ثم لا ينبغي أن يكونوا هم من يصلحوه. في بعض الأحيان نواجه مواقفًا نقف فيها عاجزين عن إحداث تغيير. ورغم أن هذه المواقف تكون مزعجة، فلا يزال بإمكانك التحكم في زمام الأمور لأنه مهما حدث يمكنك دائمًا التحكم في سلوكك تجاه الحياة. وكما يقول فيكتور فرانكل: \\"إننا نتذكر عندما كنا نعيش في معسكرات الاعتقال أولئك الرجال الذين كانوا يسيرون في أنحاء المعسكر يواسون الآخرين، ويعطون المحتاج آخر قطعة خبز لديهم. ربما كان عددهم قليلًا، لكنهم كانوا بمثابة دليل قاطع على أن الإنسان يمكن أن يُسلب منه أي شيء إلا آخر الحريات الإنسانية؛ حرية اختيار سلوكه في أي موقف، وأن يختار طريقته.\\" فبغض النظر عما يحدث، كن إيجابيًا.   إذا كان أحد الأشخاص يجعل حياتك مأساوية، لا تدعه يحطم روحك المعنوية. حافظ على شعورك بالفخر والأمل وتذكر أن توجهك وسلوكك تجاه الحياة شيء لا يمكن لأحد انتزاعه منك، وكم تقول إليانور روزفلت: \\"لا يمكن لأحد أن يجعلك تشعر بالدونية دون موافقتك.\\" حاول ألا تجعل أزمة ما أو الصعوبات التي تواجهها في ميدان واحد من حياتك تؤثر على المجالات الأخرى في حياتك. فإذا كنت تواجه صعوبات كبيرة في العمل، على سبيل المثال، لا تكن سريع الانفعال مع شريك حياتك عندما يحاول مساعدتك. تخلص من الآثار الجانبية للصعوبات التي تواجهها عن طريق التحكم في سلوكك. الأشخاص الذين يمتازون بالمرونة لا يحولون كل عقبة في حياتهم إلى كارثة، ولا يسمحون للأحداث السلبية أن تدمر حياتهم بأسرها. يمكنك اللجوء إلى بعض الأدعية أو الصلوات إذا كان هذا الأمر يساعدك. يرى الأشخاص الأقوياء على المستوى العاطفي كل يوم على أنه هدية، ويحاولون تهيئة حياتهم بحيث يستفيدون من هذه الهدية بالكامل. تذكر عندما كنت طفلًا وكنت تشعر بالإثارة وتستمتع بأبسط أمور الحياة، مثل اللعب بأوراق الشجر في فصل الخريف، أو رسم حيوان يبدو أقرب للطبيعة. ابحث عن ذلك الطفل بداخلك، وعد إليه، فقدرتك على البقاء قويًا عقليًا وعاطفيًا تعتمد عليه. لقد نجحت في كل ما واجهك في حياتك حتى الآن، ومن ثم يمكنك النجاح في ما أنت فيه الآن. وإذا استطعت أن تعيش الوقت بوقته، يمكنك أن تنجو مما تمر به أيًا كان. لن يكون الأمر سهلًا، وأنت لسه شخصًا لا يقهر، لذا تعامل مع الأمر خطوة خطوة. وعندما تشعر أنك على وشك أن تنهار، أغلق عينيك والتقط أنفاسًا عميقة، وتذكر هذه الأشياء:   لا تستمع إلى السلبيين في حياتك. سيكون هناك دائمًا من يشكك في قدراتك لأي سبب، ودورك في هذا الأمر أن لا تستمع إليهم، وفي النهاية أن تثبت أنهم خطأ، لا تسمح لهم بأن يسلبوك آمالك فقط لأنهم فقدوا ما لديهم من أمل. إن العالم من حولك يدعوك لأن تغيره، فماذا تنتظر؟ فكر في المرات التي نجحت فيها. استخدم هذه النجاحات لتكون بمثابة دافع لك في حياتك، سواء أكانت تلك النجاحات هي نجاح في دراستك أو في الحديث إلى شخص مهم في حياتك أو ميلاد طفلك، دع هذه الأمور تغذي رغبتك في أن تكون شخصًا أقوى وأكثر قدرة على التكيف مع ما يدور حولك. حاول وكرر المحاولة. سيأتي عليك وقت تشك فيه في نفسك لأنك حاولت وفشلت. لكن عليك أن تفكر دائمًا أن هذا جزء من الرحلة، مجرد فصل في قصة حياتك وليس القصة بأكملها، فبدلًا من الاستسلام لأنك فشلت وتنتقد ذاتك، فكر بمنظور أكبر ومن زاوية أوسع، وكرر المحاولة، واعلم أن النجاح يُبنى على سلم من الإخفاقات. هل يستحق كل أمر بسيط – كأن يطرح عليك أحد زملائك سؤالَا أو يسد سائق ما طريقك - أن يثير حنقك؟ اسأل نفسك هل هذه الأمور تهم حقًا ولماذا. حاول تحديد حياتك في عدد معين من المبادئ الأساسية التي تعني العالم بالنسبة لك ولا تقلق لما غير ذلك. وكما قالت سيلفيا روبنسون ذات مرة: \\"يعتقد البعض أن التمسك ببعض الأمور هو ما يجعلنا أقوياء، في بعض الأحيان يكون التخلي عنها هو يجعلنا أقوياء.\\" اقض الوقت مع أصدقائك ومع عائلتك ومع الأشخاص الإيجابيين في حياتك ومن يؤيدك. وإذا لم يكن أحد متاحًا لك، كوِّن صداقات جديدة. وإذا لم تجد أصدقاء، ساعد من يحتاجون المساعدة أكثر منك. في بعض الأحيان عندما نشعر أننا لا نستطيع تحسين حياتنا، نجد القوة في تحسين حياة الآخرين، وهذا أيضًا يمنحنا منظورًا آخر لرؤية حياتنا.  لا شك في أن البشر كائنات خاصة. أشارت الدراسات والعلوم إلى أن الرفاهية الاجتماعية عامل مهم في الصحة العاطفية والجسدية.   إذا شعرت أنك في حالة من الصراع الاجتماعي، حاول الحصول على بعض المساعدة، يمكنك البدء بأي مما يلي:  شارك في مناقشة رائعة مع شخص ما. تخط الأخطاء، لا تدعها تحد منك! استعد قوتك بعد أي أزمة عاطفية. تغلب على الخجل. تعامل على أنك شخصية منطلقة. يبدو هذا الأمر يسيرًا، أليس كذلك؟ هذا الأمر يغفل عنه الكثيرون لأنه صعب وليس سهلًا كما يبدو. فإما إننا نفرط في العمل بجد أو أننا نهدر الوقت ونتلكأ أكثر مما ينبغي ونتراخى حتى عن انتهاز الفرص. أما تحقيق التوازن المناسب بين العمل واللعب والراحة والنشاط، سيتيح لك أن تقدر كل وقت تمارس فيه نشاطًا بعينه. الحياة قاسية، لكن إذا نظرت إليها نظرة فاحصة أكثر، ستجد أن بها عددًا لا يحصى من الأشياء التي يجب أن تكون ممتنًا لوجودها. حتى إذا كانت الأشياء التي كانت تجعلك سعيدًا في الماضي انتهت، لا يزال في الحياة الكثير لتقدره. المتعة التي تستشعرها في العالم من حولك هي الوقود الذي يدفعك لاجتياز الأوقات الصعبة، لذا انتبه لما تملك، واستمتع به لقيمته. بالطبع قد لا يكون لديك كل ما تريد، لكنك على الأقل تجلس إلى جهاز الكمبيوتر الخاص بك، وتستمتع بإمكانية استخدام الإنترنت وتستطيع القراءة، بعض الأشخاص لا يستطيعون القراءة، وليس لديهم جهاز كمبيوتر، بل وليس لديهم منزل، فكر في هذا. كان تشارلي شابلن يعرف أمورًا عن الكوميديا، وقد قال: \\"إن الحياة عبارة عن مأساة عندما تتفحصها عن قرب، لكنها كوميديا إذا نظرت إليها نظرة كاملة من بعيد.\\" من السهل للغاية أن يغرق الإنسان في المآسي الصغيرة في حياته التي تجعل سلوكياته وردود أفعاله على نطاق محدود للغاية، لكن خذ خطوة للوراء وانظر إلى حياتك نظرة فلسفية أكثر، نظرًا أكثر رومانسية، وسترى أن عجائب الحياة وإمكانياتها غير المحدودة وعبثية الحياة بأكملها، كافية لأن تجعلك تضحك لما تتمتع به من حظ سعيد.  لا شك أن الحياة تبدو ممتعة أكثر إذا لم نأخذها على محمل الجد، ونظرًا لأن المتعة والسعادة ليسا بالطبع كل ما في جعبة الحياة لنا، فإنهما جزءًا مهمًا منها، أليس كذلك؟ إذا كنت غارقًا في حالة من الحزن أو الألم لا تستطيع التحكم بها، اترك نفسك قليلًا لهذه المشاعر. وإذا كنت تمر بفترة طويلة من الصعاب، ذكّر نفسك أن هذه الفترة أيضًا ستمر..","answer":"حسناّ، هذا تلخيص للمقال 'تذكر أنك تتحكم في زمام الأمور. اختر توجهك وسلوكك تجاه الحياة. أعد استكشاف شغفك واستمتاعك بالحياة. آمن بذاتك. اختر معاركك بحكمة. تواصل مع الشخصيات الأساسية في حياتك. حقق التوازن بين العمل واللهو والنشاط والراحة. كن ممتنًا لما بين يديك. لا تأخذ الأمور على محمل الجد أكثر مما ينبغي. تذكر أن لا شيء يدوم للأبد.'."},{"question":"සරණවි කියන පදයෙ තේරුම මොකක්ද?","answer":"සරණවි = සරණ+ අවිසරණ නැතිනම් පාදය අවිය කොට ගත්තාකුකුළා"},{"question":"நோய்நாடி நோய்முதல் நாடி அதுதணிக்கும்வாய்நாடி வாய்ப்பச் செயல் – இதில் பயின்றுள்ள அணிஅ) பிறிதுமொழிதலணிஆ) பொருள் பின்வருநிலையணிஇ) சொற்பின்வருநிலையணிஈ) சொற்பொருள் பின்வருநிலையணி","answer":"ஈ) சொற்பொருள் பின்வருநிலையணி"},{"question":"请给以下的文言文它的译文：齐大饥，黔敖为食于路，以待饿者而食之。有饿者蒙袂辑履，贸贸然来。黔敖左奉食，右执饮，曰：“嗟！来食！”扬其目而视之曰：“予唯不食嗟来之食，以至于斯也！”从而谢焉，终不食而死。","answer":"齐国出现了严重的饥荒。黔敖在路边准备好饭食，以供路过饥饿的人来吃。有个饥饿的人用袖子蒙着脸，无力地拖着脚步，莽撞地走来。黔敖左手端着吃食，右手端着汤，说道：“喂！来吃吧！”那个饥民扬眉抬眼看着他，说：“我就是不愿吃嗟来之食，才落地这个地步！”黔敖追上前去向他道歉，他仍然不吃，终于饿死了。"},{"question":"\\"Hitan'ny masoko ilay olona nangarona ny paosiko tany an-tsena.\\"Inona no mety ho fiafaran'ity tantara ity?A. Nanenina ilay mpangalatra dia naveriny ny zavatro.B. lasa nirifatra nitsaoka ilay mpangalatra.","answer":"A. no ampoizina fa mety ho fiafaran'ity tantara ity kokoa."},{"question":" ప్రత్యేకత ఉన్న ఆర్థిక సహాయ సంస్థలు అంటే ఏమిటో వివరించండి. వాటి ఆవశ్యకతల గురించి తెలపండి.","answer":"దేశములో ఆర్థిక కార్యకలాపాలు వేగముగా విస్తరించడం వలన విత్తరంగములో ఎన్నో వ్యవస్థాపూర్వక మార్పులు చోటుచేసుకున్నాయి. వర్తక, వాణిజ్యాలకు అనుగుణముగా వెంచర్ మూలధనము, క్రెడిట్ రేటింగ్, కౌలు విత్తములాంటి విత్త అవసరాలను దృష్టిలో ఉంచుకొని కొన్ని కొత్త విత్తసంస్థలు ఏర్పడినాయి. వీటిని ప్రత్యేక విత్తసంస్థలుగా వ్యవహరిస్తారు.1. IFCI వెంచర్ మూలధన నిధుల లిమిటెడ్: కొత్త ఉద్యమదారులు, సాంకేతిక నిపుణులు, వృత్తి నిపుణులు, పారిశ్రామికవేత్తలు, పారిశ్రామిక ప్రాజెక్టులను ప్రారంభించడం కోసం వారికి వడ్డీలేని ఋణాలుగాని, తక్కువ వడ్డీకి ఋణాలుగాని ఇవ్వడం ద్వారా వారిని ప్రోత్సహించే ఉద్ద్యేశముతో 1975లో భారత పారిశ్రామిక సంస్థ I.F.C.I రిస్క్ కాపిటల్ను ప్రారంభించినది. 1988 జనవరిలో రిస్క్ కాపిటల్ అండ్ టెక్నాలజీ కార్పొరేషన్ లిమిటెడ్గా మార్చడమైనది. ఈ సంస్థ ప్రాధాన్యము ఉన్న నూతన సాంకేతిక పద్ధతులు, ఉత్పత్తులు,’ ప్రక్రియలు, మార్కెట్ సేవలు, సాంకేతిక పరమైన పెంపుదల, శక్తి సంరక్షణ ఏర్పాట్లకు ప్రాధాన్యతనిస్తూ విత్తసహాయం అందిస్తుంది.2. ICICI వెంచర్ ఫండ్స్ లిమిటెడ్: 1989లో టెక్నాలజీ డెవలప్మెంట్ అండ్ ఇన్ఫర్మేషన్ కంపెనీ ఆఫ్ ఇండియా లిమిటెడ్ అనే ఒక సంస్థను స్థాపించినారు. కొత్తగా సాహసంతో ప్రాజెక్టులకు విత్త సహాయము అందించడం దీని ప్రధాన ఆశయము. కంప్యూటర్లు, రసాయనాలు, పాలిమర్స్, ఎలక్ట్రికల్, ఎలక్ట్రానిక్, టెలికాం, పర్యావరణం, ఇంజనీరింగ్ రంగాలకు సహాయాన్ని అందించినది. ప్రస్తుతం ఈ సంస్థను ICICI వెంచర్ ఫండ్స్ పేరుతో పిలవబడుతున్నది.3. టూరిజం ఫైనాన్స్ కార్పొరేషన్ ఆఫ్ ఇండియా: దేశములో పర్యాటక పరిశ్రమను ప్రోత్సహించే లక్ష్యముతో కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వము టూరిజం ఫైనాన్స్ కార్పొరేషన్ ఆఫ్ ఇండియా లిమిటెడు నెలకొల్పినది. సంప్రదాయ పర్యాటక ప్రాజెక్టులకే కాకుండా అమ్యూజ్మెంట్ పార్కులు, రోప్వలు, కార్ రెంటల్ సేవలు, నీటి రవాణా, ఫెర్రీలు లాంటి సంప్రదాయేతర పర్యాటక ప్రాజెక్టులకు కూడా ఈ సంస్థ విత్త సహాయాన్ని అందిస్తుంది."},{"question":"جزیره تنب بزرگ در کجا واقع شده است؟","answer":"جزیره تُنب بزرگ (تمب بزرگ) جزیره‌ای ایرانی در خلیج فارس است. این جزیره براساس تقسیمات کشوری بخشی از شهرستان ابوموسی در استان هرمزگان است. "},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Jack Sweeney là sinh viên 19 tuổi đứng sau tài khoản Twitter nổi tiếng @CelebJets, chuyên đăng tải các chuyến đi bằng máy bay riêng của những người nổi tiếng. Tài khoản này đã trở nên nổi tiếng vì tiết lộ lượng khí thải carbon mà những chuyến đi \\"siêu ngắn\\" này có thể tạo ra. Mới đây, thông tin về chuyến bay của tỷ phú Elon Musk đã khiến dư luận bất ngờ. Cụ thể, máy bay phản lực của tỷ phú này được phát hiện đã thực hiện những chuyến bay kéo dài 5 phút từ Sân bay Quốc tế Los Angeles đến sân bay Hawthorne, một hành trình dài 9,6 km mà nếu đi xe Tesla sẽ chỉ mất 10 phút. Thông tin này được tiết lộ bởi Jack Sweeney. Chàng trai này đã dành 30 tài khoản Twitter, bao gồm @CelebJets và @ElonJet, để theo dõi các máy bay tư nhân thuộc sở hữu của các tỷ phú, người nổi tiếng và các nhà tài phiệt. Những thông tin này sử dụng dữ liệu từ các trang web như ADS-B Exchange. Musk không đưa ra bất cứ bình luận nào về tiết lộ của Sweeney. Ngay sau khi người dân ở châu Âu và Mỹ phải hứng chịu đợt nắng nóng kỷ lục một phần là do biến đổi khí hậu, các chuyến bay tương tự như vậy nhận về phản ứng gay gắt vì thải khí nhà kính. Không lâu trước đây, nữ tỷ phú Kylie Jenner đã","answer":"\\"tậu\\" hẳn một chiếc máy bay riêng để đi du lịch cùng bạn bè và gia đình. Tờ Daily Mail đưa tin, cô bị chỉ trích vì thực hiện chuyến bay chỉ kéo dài 12 phút với quãng đường hơn 40km. Cụ thể, nữ tỷ phú trẻ đã đi máy bay từ thành phố Van Nuys, quận Los Angeles, bang California đến thành phố Camarillo, quận Ventura, bang California. Điều đáng nói là họ hoàn toàn có thể lựa chọn phương pháp di chuyển khác mà không mất quá nhiều thời gian. Bất chấp phản ứng trên mạng, Sweeney nói rằng anh không ngạc nhiên về thời gian bay của Kylie Jenner khi so sánh nó với những gì anh thường thấy từ các tỷ phú trên thế giới. Những người nổi tiếng và ông trùm kinh doanh khác có các chuyến bay ngắn cũng được Sweeney chỉ ra, trong đó có Drake. Anh bị chỉ trích vì thực hiện chuyến đi 14 phút từ Toronto đến Hamilton trong khi chỉ mất một giờ đi ô tô. @CelebJets tiết lộ chuyến bay dài 38 dặm đã tiêu tốn 402 gallon (hoặc 1.522 lít) nhiên liệu, chi phí hơn 2.700 USD. Điều này tạo ra bốn tấn khí thải CO2. Nam rapper đã giải thích rằng các máy bay phản lực chỉ thực hiện các chuyến bay như vậy để tìm nơi đậu từ địa điểm này sang địa điểm khác. Anh từng viết, \\"Đây chỉ là việc di chuyển máy bay đến sân bay để cất giữ và bảo dưỡng... không ai đi chuyến bay đó\\". Gần đây nhất, Jack cho biết anh đã xác định được một chiếc máy bay phản lực mới gắn liền với Mark Zuckerberg và lập trình lại tài khoản theo dõi. Giám đốc điều hành Meta sử dụng một chiếc máy bay phản lực do công ty của anh ấy thuê. Tuy nhiên hiện chưa có quá nhiều thông tin về những chuyến bay này. Chỉ riêng tài khoản theo dõi Musk của Sweeney đã có gần nửa triệu người theo dõi. Chủ sở hữu của nó tiết lộ đã từng từ chối lời đề nghị trị giá 5.000 USD của tỷ phú Tesla để gỡ bỏ tài khoản. Theo The Richest, NY Post"},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Zimbabwe?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Zimbabwe mu ngi tudd Harare."},{"question":"கேள்வி: ஹாட்ரன் என்னும் சொல்லை அறிமுகப்படுத்தியவர் யார்? ஏன்?","answer":"பதில்: ஹாட்ரன் என்னும் சொல்லை  என்.எல்.பி. ஒக்கன் அறிமுகப்படுத்தினார்.  விளக்கம் :முன்னணுக்கள், அல்லணுக்கள், பையான்கள், கேயான்கள் ஆகிய வலு அணுக்கரு விசை கொண்ட துகள்களால் பாதிக்கப்படும் துகள் தொகுதியைக் குறிக்க அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:శ్రీరాముని దూతగా వచ్చిన హనుమంతుడు సీతకు రామ ముద్రికను ఇచ్చాడు. సీతకు విశ్వాసము కలగడానికి హనుమంతుడు, రాముని వృత్తాంతాన్నీ, తన చరిత్రనూ విస్పష్టంగా వినయముతో ఇలా విన్నవించాడు.శ్రీరాముని వృత్తాంతము : “అమ్మ ! ‘రావణుడు రాముని మోసగించి, నిన్ను అపహరించుకొని వచ్చిన సమయంలో, నీవు నీ బంగారు నగలను ఋష్యమూక పర్వతంపై పడవేశావు. మేము ఆ నగలను తీసి దాచాము. నీ భర్త రాముడు ఆ ‘ పర్వతం దగ్గరకు వచ్చినపుడు, సుగ్రీవుడు రామునకు ఆ నగలను చూపించాడు. రాముడు వాటిని గుర్తించాడు.శ్రీరాముడు సుగ్రీవునకు అభయము ఇచ్చాడు. దుందుభి అనే రాక్షసుని శరీరాన్ని దూరంగా తన్ని పారవేశాడు. ఏడు తాడిచెట్లనూ ఒకే బాణంతో ఖండించాడు. వారిని తన అద్భుత శక్తితో కూల్చి చంపాడు. సుగ్రీవునకు తారను భార్యగా ఇప్పించాడు. అంగదుడిని యువరాజుగా చేశాడు.","answer":"రామలక్ష్మణులు ఇప్పుడు వానర సైన్యములు తమ్ము సేవిస్తుండగా, మాల్యవంతముపై ఉన్నారు. నిన్ను వెదకడానికి వానరులను అందరినీ అన్ని దిక్కులకూ పంపారు. అంగదుని నాయకత్వంలో మేము కొందరము దక్షిణ దిశకు వచ్చాము. మా వానరులు నన్ను లంకకు పంపారు. నేను సముద్రాన్ని తేలికగా దాటి, ఇక్కడకు వచ్చి లంకను అంతా వెదికి, ఇక్కడ నిన్ను చూశాను. నీతో రావణుడు క్రూరంగా పరుష వాక్యాలు మాట్లాడుతున్నప్పుడు మీది నేను ఈ చెట్టుమీద ఉన్నాను.అమ్మా ! శ్రీరాముని శరీరము నీలమేఘచ్ఛాయలో ఉంటుంది. ఆయన నేత్రములు తెల్లని పద్మపు రేకులవలె ఉంటాయి. కంఠము శంఖమువలె ఉంటుంది. అందమైన చీలమండలూ, పొడవైన బాహువులూ రామునికి ఉంటాయి. ఆయన కంఠస్వరము దుందుభి ధ్వనిని పోలి ఉంటుంది. ఆయన పాదములలో పద్మరేఖలు ఉంటాయి. రాముడు కపటము ఎరుగని సత్యవాక్యములు పలికేవాడు. రాముడు శుభలక్షణములు కలవాడు. లక్ష్మణుడు కూడా రాముని వంటి గుణములు కలవాడే కానీ, అతని దేహచ్ఛాయ మాత్రము బంగారు రంగులో ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిఉష్ణ సమతాస్థితి అనగా ఏమి? అది ఉష్ణ గతిక శాస్త్ర శూన్యాంక నియమమునకు ఎట్లు దారి తీయునో వివరింపుము. ","answer":"ఉష్ణసమతాస్థితి :రెండు వ్యవస్థల ఉష్ణోగ్రతలు సమానముగా ఉండి, వాని మధ్య ఉష్ణ ప్రసారము జరుగుటకు వీలు ఉన్నప్పటికి, ఉష్ణము ప్రవహించనప్పుడు ఆ రెండు వ్యవస్థలు ఉష్ణసమతా స్థితిలో ఉన్నవని అంటారు.ఉష్ణగతిక శాస్త్ర శూన్యాంక నియమం :రెండు వ్యవస్థలు మూడవ వ్యవస్థతో వేరువేరుగా ఉష్ణ సమతాస్థితిలో ఉన్నపుడు ఆ రెండు వ్యవస్థలు ఒక దానికొకొటి ఉష్ణ సమతాస్థితిలో ఉండును."},{"question":"هل الجزر يعطي فيتامين أ ؟ أقرأ النص التالي ثم أجب.فيتامين أ أو الريتينول  هو عائلة من مركبات قابلة للذوبان في الدهون والتي تلعب دورا مهما في الرؤية، نمو العظم، الإنجاب، الانقسام الخلوي، والتفاضل الخلوي (و الذي تصبح بواسطته خلية جزء من الدماغ، أو عضلة، أو الرئتين، الخ.). يساعد فيتامين أ على تنظيم نظام المناعة، الذي يساعد على منع أَو صد الإصابات وذلك بإنتاج خلايا الدم البيضاء التي تحطم البكتيريا والفيروسات الضارة. فيتامين أ أيضا يساعد الخلايا اللمفية، وهي نوع من خلايا الدم البيضاء، على محاربة الالتهابات بكفاءة أفضل.يهييء فيتامين أ البطانات السطحية الصحّية للعيون وأنظمة التنفس والتبول، والمناطق المعوية . عندما تحطم هذه البطانات، يصبح دخول البكتيريا للجسم والتسبب بالعدوى أسهل. يساعد فيتامين أ على الحفاظ على سلامة الجلد أيضا والأغشية المخاطية، والتي تعمل أيضا كمانع للبكتيريا والفيروسات.الريتينول Retinol هو الشكل الأنشط، أَو الأكثر استعمالا، من أشكال فيتامين أ، ويوجد في الطعام الحيواني مثل الكبد والحليب الكامل. الريتينول يدعى أيضا فيتامين أي المُشكّل وذلك لكونه يمكن أن يحول إلى حمض ريتينال Retinal أو ريتينويك Retinoic، وهي أشكل مختلفة نشيطة لعائلة فيتامين أي.بروفايتمين أي الكاروتيني Provitamin A Carotenoids يتسبب بتلوّن الصبغات على نحو غامق وتوجد في الأطعمة النباتية، وهو يمكن أن يتحوّل إلى فيتامين أ. في الولايات المتحدة، 26% و34% من فيتامين أي المستهلك من قبل الرجال والنساء، على التوالي، مصدرها هو بروفايتمين أي الكاروتيني. الكاروتينات الشائعة في الغذاء هي كاروتين بيتا beta-carotene، كاروتين ألفا alpha-carotene، لوتين lutein، زياكسنثين zeaxanthin، لايكوبين lycopene، وكرايبتوكسانثين cryptoxanthin. من الـ563 نوع من الكاروتين التي تم تميزها، أقل من 10% تنتج لفيتامين أي. من بينها، كاروتين بيتا والتي تحول بكفاءة عالية جدا إلى الريتينول. كاروتين ألفا وكرايبتوكسانثين بيتا يحوّلان أيضا إلى فيتامين أ، لكن بنصف كفاءة كاروتين بيتا. كاروتينات اللايكوبين، لوتين، وزياكسنثين ليس لها نشاط فيتامين أي، إلا أن لها فائد صحية أخرى. ومن الضروري استهلاك الثمار والخضار الغنية بالكاروتينات لما لها من منافع للجسم.","answer":"المقال لم يذكر بالتحديد أن الجزر غني بفيتامين أ."},{"question":"لدينا النص التالي: أكد أسامة الحسينى، نائب رئيس مجلس الإدارة والعضو المنتدب للشئون المالية والإدارية والموارد البشرية لشركة النصر للمبانى والإنشاءات 'إيجيكو' التابعة للشركة القابضة للتشييد والتعمير، أن الهدف من التعديلات التى تم إقرارها في قانون 203 لسنة 1991، قانون قطاع الأعمال العام، هو تعديل القانون المنظم لعمل الشركات، وبما لا يؤثر على خطة الهيكلة والإصلاح، موضحا أن هدف التعديلات الإسراع بجهود تطوير هذه الشركات وتحسين أدائها وهياكلها المالية، وحسن إدارتها والاستغلال الأمثل لأصولها، لتحقيق الاستمرارية والاستدامة لنشاطها. وأضاف الحسينى ل'اليوم السابع' أن التعديلات تهدف إلى زيادة مساهمتها في الاقتصاد القومي، وزيادة قدرتها على المنافسة بالأسواق الداخلية والخارجية، ووضع رؤية واضحة لما يمكن ان تحققه هذه التعديلات من نتائج ايجابية تنعكس لصالح العاملين ،وبما ينعكس بالإيجاب على نتائج أعمال هذه الشركات وتطورها، وما يستتبعه من زيادة عوائد الدولة في ملكيتها بهذه الشركات . وأوضح أسامة الحسينى أن التعديلات تضمنت عددا من المحاور، من أهمها تهيئة الإطار القانوني المناسب لتطوير أداء شركات قطاع الأعمال العام، وتطبيق قواعد الإدارة الرشيدة 'الحوكمة' بتلك الشركات، مع زيادة مستويات الإفصاح والشفافية بشأن أدائها، مع وضع معايير لقيام الشركات القابضة أو التابعة بالمشاركة في تأسيس شركات مشتركة جديدة ووضع إطار عام لمتابعة الشركات المشتركة. وأشار إلى أن التعديلات تتيح للشركات الالتزام بمعايير التقييم المالي ومعايير التقييم العقاري، وتحفيز العاملين ومجالس الإدارة لتحسين الأداء وزيادة أرباح الشركات، بالإضافة إلى السعي نحو تماثل قواعد وأساليب الإدارة في شركات قطاع الأعمال العام، مع الشركات الخاضعة للقانون 159 لسنة 1981 ومعالجة أوجه القصور والسلبيات التي أفرزها تطبيق القانون القائم . وحول رؤيته لاهمية التعديلات، أكد أنها ستساهم فى جذب استثمارات جديدة، وإعادة استغلال الثروات العقارية المملوكة للشركات، حيث إنه يوجد عدد كبير من الشركات التابعة لقطاع الأعمال العام، تمتلك محفظة ضخمة من الأراضى، ولكنها غير مستغلة الاستغلال الأمثل، مشيرا أن التعديلات تضمنت عددا من المحاور، من أهمها تهيئة الإطار القانوني المناسب لتطوير أداء شركات قطاع الأعمال العام، وتطبيق 'الحوكمة' بتلك الشركات، مع زيادة مستويات الإفصاح والشفافية بشأن أدائها، مع وضع معايير لقيام الشركات القابضة أو التابعة بالمشاركة في تأسيس شركات مشتركة جديدة ووضع إطار عام لمتابعة الشركات المشتركة، فضلا عن التزام الشركات بمعايير التقييم المالي ومعايير التقييم العقاري، وتحفيز العاملين ومجالس الإدارة لتحسين الأداء وزيادة أرباح الشركات.. قم بإنشاء عنوان مناسب.","answer":"النصر للمبانى: تعديلات قانون قطاع الأعمال تضمن الحوكمة وزيادة الاستثمارات."},{"question":"Séoul moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Séoul moy péeyu réwum Corée du Sud"},{"question":"滥竽充数对团队有什么影响？","answer":"答：滥竽充数的人可能会降低团队的整体效率和效果，因为他们无法为团队做出有效的贡献。同时，他们可能会破坏团队的氛围和信任，因为他们的行为可能会让其他团队成员感到不公平和沮丧。"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. බෝ පතක් වැටෙන සේනුඹ වැටී ලෙඩ ඇඳේනිසොල්මනේ ඇයි අම්මේපෙරහැරක් වගේ සිටිකොඩි වැලක් වගේ නැගිදූ පුතුන් කොහේ අම්මේ","answer":"බෝ පතක් වැටෙන සේනුඹ වැටී ලෙඩ ඇඳේනිසොල්මනේ ඇයි අම්මේපෙරහැරක් වගේ සිටිකොඩි වැලක් වගේ නැගිදූ පුතුන් කොහේ අම්මේමුතු පබළු අතේ නැතසවි බලද හිතේ නැතතනිකමද හිතින් දැරුවේකිරි සුවඳ හමා ගියමහ ගෙදර පාළු බවමව් සුවඳ වසා පැතිරේසිල් සුවඳ පිරූ සිතගුණ සුවඳ දැනේ මටපන්සලක් වගේ අම්මේසා දුකින් පෙලෙන සඳකිරි පොවා කඳුළු හෙලුනුඹ නිවන් දකින් අම්මේඅජන්තා නාකන්දලරඹුකන සිද්ධාර්ථ හිමි"},{"question":"What is the capital of Jordan?","answer":"Amman."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fahafatesana?","answer":"Ny atao hoe fahafatesana dia ny fisarahan’ny aina amin’ny vatana eo amin’ny olona iray, ny fahataperan’ny androm-piainan’ny olona eto an-tany, fihatahana na fandaozana ny fahavelomana, fiverenan’ny nofo ho vovoka. Fiampitan’ny velona mankany amin’ny tontolon’ny razana."},{"question":"ભારતનું સૌથી નાનું શહેર? ","answer":"માપદંડ પર આધાર રાખીને બદલાઈ શકે છે. જો આપણે વસ્તીને માપદંડ તરીકે લઈએ તો, ગંગોત્રી ૧૧૦ રહેવાસીઓ સાથે સૌથી નાનું શહેર છે. જો ક્ષેત્રફળને માપદંડ તરીકે લઈએ તો, માહે (Mayyazhi), જેનું કુલ ક્ષેત્રફળ ૯ ચોરસ કિલોમીટર છે, તેને સૌથી નાનું શહેર ગણી શકાય."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය රචනා ක​ළේ කවුද?මේ ඉර හඳ යට හමුවී ආදරයෙන්කතා කරපු අය සෙනේ වඩපු අයළඟ පාතකවත් නෑමේ ඉර හඳ යට හමුවීඅද නුඹ කොතැනද අද මා කොතැනදදන්නේ නෑ නුඹ මටත් හොරාජීවන මහ මග සටන් වැදී ඇතනාඳුනනා පෙම්වතුන් වෙලාදැන හඳුනා ගත් කාලේ ඉඳලාළබැඳි දයාවෙන් සිටිය නිසාඅප වෙනුවෙන් අප නමින් හෙලන්නටහෙටටත් කඳුලක් ඉතිරි වෙලා","answer":"මෙම ගීතය රචනා ක​ළේ රඹුකන සිද්ධාර්ථ හිමියන්‍ ය."},{"question":"నీ సైకిలు పోయిందని తెలుపుతూ,వెతికించమని కోరుతూ పోలీసు అధికారికి లేఖ రాయండి.","answer":"కర్నూలు,x x x x x xకె. జవహర్ రెడ్డి,పదవ తరగతి, సెక్షన్ ‘ఎ’మునిసిపల్ హైస్కూల్,గాంధీనగర్, కర్నూలు.గాంధీనగర్ పోలీసు ఇన్ స్పెక్టర్ గారికి, కర్నూలు,అయ్యా ,విషయము : సైకిలు దొంగతనం – చర్య తీసుకోవలసిందిగా విజ్ఞప్తి.నమస్కారములు,నిన్న అనగా 9 – 4 – 2016 నాడు, నేను మిత్రులతో కలసి గవర్నమెంటు హాస్పిటల్ కు, నా మిత్రుని పలకరించుటకు వెళ్ళాను. మా మిత్రులము అందరమూ, మా సైకిళ్ళను గేటు వద్ద చెట్టు క్రింద తాళం వేసి ఉంచి లోపలకు వెళ్ళాము. తిరిగి వచ్చేటప్పటికి నా సైకిలు కనబడలేదు. మిగిలిన వారి సైకిళ్ళు మాత్రం ఉన్నాయి. నా సైకిలు వివరాలు క్రింద ఇస్తున్నాను.హీరో కొత్త సైకిలు, 24, నెంబరు హెచ్ 26723. దయచేసి నా సైకిలు వెతికించవలసినదిగా మిమ్మల్ని కోరుతున్నాను.నమస్కారాలతో,ఇట్లు,మీ విశ్వసనీయుడు,కె. జవహర్ రెడ్డి,10వ తరగతి, సెక్షన్ – ‘ఎ’."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko hizkuntza: Zein da euskara batuaren jatorria?","answer":"Euskara batua, 20. mendean, euskara hizkuntzaren standardizazioa lortzeko sortu zen."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Máy bay trực thăng hai hệ thống cánh chính, thường có hai loại: loại hai cánh đồng trục và hai cánh trên hai trục song song. Khi đó, hai cánh này luôn quay cùng tốc độ nhưng ngược chiều để triệt tiêu chuyển động quay của thân.Với thiết bị bay dono: tương tự như máy bay trực thăng khi cần ","answer":"có số cánh là số chẵn: 2, 4, 6... được bố trí đồng trục và theo các trục song song, đối xứng với nhau qua trọng tâm của dono. Trong đó, mỗi một nửa quay theo hai chiều khác nhau để mô men động lượng của thân dono bị triệt tiêu. Nếu bố trí cặp cánh trên một trục thì hai cánh phải quay ngược chiều để triệt tiêu chuyển động quay của thân ngay trên mỗi cặp."},{"question":"د خوشحال خان خټک فلسفه او شعر څه شی دی؟","answer":"خوشحال خان خټک چې په اوولسمه پېړۍ کې د پښتو مشهور شاعر، جنګیالی او مشر وو، څو اړخیزه فلسفه او شاعري درلوده چې د څو مهمو موضوعاتو په شاوخوا کې ګرځي:1-پښتونولي او پښتني هويت: خوشحال خان خټک د پښتني کلتور، ارزښتونو او هويت کلک مدافع و. د هغه په شعرونو کې اکثره د پښتونولي اصول نمانځل شوي، د پښتنو دودیز اخلاق چې د میلمه پالنې، عزت او عدالت مفهومونه پکې شامل دي. هغه د پښتني دودونو په ساتلو او د بهرنیو تاثیراتو پر وړاندې په مقاومت ټینګار وکړ.2-د ظلم په وړاندې مقاومت: د خوشحال خان خټک ژوند په پښتنو سیمو کې د مغلو د امپراتورۍ د پراخیدو په وړاندې د هغه د مقاومت نښه وه. د ده په شعرونو کې د خپل ولس او خاورې څخه د بهرني یرغل څخه د دفاع لپاره د هغه هوډ څرګندیږي. هغه د خپلواکۍ په مبارزه کې د پښتنو جنګیالیو د مبارزو او قربانیو په اړه لیکلي دي.۳- له طبيعت سره مينه: د نورو پښتو شاعرانو په څېر خوشحال خان هم له طبيعي نړۍ سره ژوره مينه درلوده. د ده په شعرونو کې اکثره د پښتنو د وطن ښکلا، منظرې، سیندونه او نباتات بیانیږي. طبیعت د هغه د مینې، وطن دوستۍ او مقاومت د څرګندولو لپاره د پس منظر په توګه کار کاوه.۴- د رهبرۍ فلسفه: د خوشحال خان خټک په شعر کې د رهبرۍ او حکومتدارۍ حکمتونه شته. هغه د عادل او صالح رهبر پر ځانګړنو ټینګار وکړ، چې د خلکو د حقونو او کرامت ساتنه کوي.په لنډه توګه د خوشحال خان خټک د فلسفې او شاعرۍ بنسټ د پښتني کلتور او هویت سره د هغه په زړه پورې ژمنتیا، د ظلم په وړاندې د هغه مقاومت، طبیعت ته د احترام او د مشرتابه او اخلاقو په انعکاس کې دی. د هغه اثار د هغو کسانو سره غږیږي چې د پښتنو میراث او اصولو ته ارزښت ورکوي."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地質學中的「火山」是指什麼？","answer":"答案：火山是指地球表面的一個開口或通道，通往地球深部岩漿的進出口。當岩漿、氣體和固體碎屑從火山口噴出時，形成了火山爆發和噴發現象。"},{"question":"Mene ne Wakilin Suna a Hausa?","answer":"Walikin suna kalma ce da ake amfani da ita a gurbin da ya kamata a ce suna ne ya zo. Wato kenan idan ana cikin zance, sai aka zo wata gaɓar da ya kamata a ce an ambaci suna amma sai a ƙi ambatar sunan, sai a yi amfani da wannan kalma ta maye gurbin sunan, ka ga ke nan ta wakilce shi ba sai ya zo da kansa ba.Kalmomi irin su ni, kai, ke, nawa, naku, da sauransu, dukka wakilan suna ne. Misali, maimakon na ce, Na san Ado mutum ne mai haƙuri, zan iya cewa, na san shi mutum ne mai haƙuri. Idan aka lura za a ga cewa kalmar ni, ta wakilci sunana, shi kuma ta wakilci Ado.  Sannan kuma wasu masana sukan kira shi da Lamiri. Ita kuwa kalmar Lamiri (ضَمِيرْ), kalmar Larabci ce, kuma kai tsaye tana nufin wakili"},{"question":"கேள்வி: மாட்டுப் பொங்கல் நன்னாள் இன்று. ஏதோ மாடு வைத்திருப்பவர்களுக்குத்தான் இந்த விழா என்று நம்மில் பலரும் நினைத்துக் கொண்டிருக்கிறோம். உண்மையில், மாட்டுப் பொங்கல் எனும் இந்த நன்னாள், நம் எல்லோரும் கொண்டாடவேண்டிய பண்டிகை என்கிறார்கள் ஆச்சார்யர்கள். கீழே உள்ள பதில்களில் இருந்து இந்த வாக்கியத்திற்கு தொடர்பில்லாத வார்த்தையை தேர்வு செய்யவும்:அ) கலாச்சாரம்ஆ) திருவிழாஇ) சிறப்பு நிகழ்வுகள்ஈ) தொழில்நுட்பம்","answer":"சரியான பதில்: ஈ) தொழில்நுட்பம்"}]`),x={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:M},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:C,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},B={class:"search-container"},I={class:"card-container"},P=["disabled"],K={key:0},D={key:1};function O(e,a,s,k,t,u){const m=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",B,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",I,[(i(!0),o(c,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,d)=>(i(),j(m,{key:d,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",D,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",K,"See more"))],8,P)):f("",!0)])}const H=g(x,[["render",O],["__scopeId","data-v-12cf9af4"]]),U=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"quotes/24.md","filePath":"quotes/24.md"}'),L={name:"quotes/24.md"},W=Object.assign(L,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(H)]))}});export{U as __pageData,W as default};
